"Defiant short films
dedicated to girls in the 21st century"
"Each must bring up some issue regarding
sexuality or gender"
You know what?
Watch out for guys with David's profile.
And bald men and men growing their hair.
They think women like DV.
They make me sick.
They should just die.
All of them!
(Anytime, Anywhere)
Please, Mom Ling Xiao!
Don't bring such a scary thing in here.
Oh sorry, Tenko.
Hey, Motoshi is telling me that...
as a woman my body has to be always clean.
So I take a bath twice a day.
My body is so spongy now.
Is your brother in Fukei?
He's already out.
Mommy, what is "Fukei"?
It's a big and cool looking prison in Tokyo.
I want to go!
As freshmen, some friends stayed at my place.
Taki was sleeping next to me.
He touched my boobs.
I've never experienced groping,
but that kind of thing happens sometimes.
After Taki, it was Hijiri, Shindo,
Funaki, and a co-worker.
And Taki again.
I have small tits, so my boyfriend
doesn't touch mine even during sex.
You don't need to name everyone.
If you wanna say you're popular,
just say it.
It's just some regular guys
happened to be close to your boobs.
Say "My boobs are my identify."
I hope Taki won't leave yours
in the future.
For you, mommy.
If a guy doesn't touch small boobs...
he just wanna ejaculate.
Is that fine?
Of course I feel empty.
When he's pumping hard,
he is looking at space.
Not at me. Near climax,
he is completely in space.
When he comes, he goes beyond it.
A black hole sucks him.
I just look at it.
Space is far away, mommy.
Yes, it is.
It is.
Itsuka, does your BF give you tissue
after sex?
My BF, Kato, only wipes his
and sleeps as soon as he's done.
I normally play online games and wait
till I feel sleepy. About an hour.
Because it gets dry out while playing game,
I don't need tissue. Ecological.
Tissue paper issue.
Mine used to give some.
I only go out with guys who clean my body.
I'd rather do it myself.
Every guy does.
What is tissue paper issue?
Whether you can get tissue paper
from a guy after sex.
I don't. Do you all get some?
If not, I don't feel I'm loved.
Many stupid men don't think
women need tissue paper.
Love...
Mommy Shiino?
What?
Do you get tissue or get wiped?
Yeah, I do.
I heard Americans don't use tissue.
What do they do?
Just leave it?
They don't find it sexy.
Men and women?
I think so.
Has anyone suddenly felt
like crying at night?
No.
Yeah.
Absolutely yeah.
I don't know.
No, nothing is absolute.
We all die at the end for sure.
We die alone.
Only that is absolute...
The word "absolute" is only for that.
Absolute exists only for that.
Mothers, don't you eat chicken?
She is sleeping again. Look, Shiino.
She again fell asleep while eating.
Pigeons will poke your face.
You're drooling.
So true.
Here it is.
Tastes good.
What time did you sleep last night?
You slept late.
You rolled your eyes up sometimes.
Morning.
Chinese muffin.
Muffin?
What are you saying?
(Anytime, Anywhere)
Mucous Membrane covers a hollow organ
that leads to the outside.
Excuse me.
Can I have a light?
(Mucous Membrane)
Don't fall asleep during work.
I didn't get any sleep.
You had a guy over, right?
I didn't have one
and couldn't sleep at night.
I see.
I went for a walk and found one.
Tohko, you'll lose a lot some day.
I won't.
It's stupid to lose something just for sex.
Maybe.
Hey, have you counted the number of hair
on a guy's toes?
Why would I?
I do whenever I get a new boyfriend.
Why?
I feel relieved.
I feel relieved to think
I'm the only one...
that know the number of hair
on this guy's toes.
I know that much,
but I've forgot how to have sex.
Look, Aoba. Here's a snail.
Wow. I hadn't seen one for a while.
Is the whole body its erogenous zone?
Maybe.
Oh, you are home.
Hi.
I bought our dinner.
This is good for me.
Don't worry.
You know what?
I wanna be a snail now.
What? That's gross.
What?
Don't say that it's gross.
I quit.
I'm hungry.
Let's go have breakfast.
I don't do that kind of thing.
You are really different.
No, I'm same as you.
I'm off now.
Hey.
Can I call you again?
No.
I will when I want it.
Mucous Membrane covers a hollow organ
that leads to the outside.
Secretion of mucus helps to keep
the surface moist.
They are at several places such as at
nostrils, lips, ears, and genital area.
I'm glad we can't be someone else.
Look at this.
Your boyfriend? He loves you.
But it's creepy I'm on his wallpaper.
Let's exchange them.
That's cute.
Cute.
Cute...
Who?
Look. I like her eyes.
Yeah, she's beautiful.
Right?
I'm a dyed-in-the-wool girl.
I like this part. Look.
That owner's glasses are funny.
This is outside of stories.
(Projection)
That kind of aid is temporary one.
(Hug me.)
(Please make a movie with me.)
Nobody will.
I shoot her movie instead.
Don't. Don't post it on internet.
Give it to me.
I'll be your cameraman.
(We are extremely intimate.)
I want to touch.
After stripping underwears...
she's indivisual, and I want to
touch her through photos.
Tuck your hair behind the ear.
Left.
Look this way.
Kanako, you are beautiful.
Stand there.
It's warm.
That's the owner of Ikoi.
Didn't know he plays sports.
Ikoi?
It's a café I often go to.
(Projection)
(Love is instinctive -Katai Tayama)
(Love Desiccant)
Really? YES!!
This is so nice.
I had been waiting for this.
Something's wrong.
Is romance like this?
Mentally men are 7 years younger
than women.
That's why men are immature.
Aren't men maturer, smarter and stronger?
I don't know.
Isn't love more visible and valuable?
It's just a way to kill time.
People label themselves and play with it.
And what is value?
I reckon that you're virgin.
Had I expected too much?
Quick. Eat.
Noodles are getting soggy.
Quick.
It doesn't suit you.
(Love Desiccant to fall out of love.)
(Instructions)
(Put the desiccant into his/her bag.)
(And his/her affection will dry out...)
(... and disappear.)
Hey.
Waited long?
No.
Thanks.
Stop!
(If you cannot see the effect...)
(... increase the amount.)
People label themselves and play with it.
It doesn't suit you.
Men are immature.
I reckon that you're virgin.
Mikio, Mikio, Mikio, Mikio.
Hey.
Lara, are you up?
I hate myself.
I can't graduate.
I can't finish it.
(Out of Fashion)
You are being sloppy.
Look at yourself.
I know. I'm sorry.
"I know"? Nobody expects a charismatic
model to be this sloppy.
They expect a lot.
When are you getting a boyfriend?
You'll get old soon.
You suck.
Forget about "him."
I want a guy who thinks I'm cute as I am.
Is it a guy? It can't be.
Why don't you wear a Zara?
Modeling job?
Yep, until the last train.
You can't be sleeping. Drool!
Oh no.
Oh? Weren't you making something pink?
I tore it.
It started to look uncool.
Can you make it in time?
Do you need me again?
I'll marry you.
I'll try hard, so don't leave.
You just announced your marrige,
but your prince is here.
What? Mr. Morita?
You are too generous to her.
She'll get lost after graduating.
I know.
But I love the clothes she makes.
She's like that,
but one day she'll be recognized.
You look totally different. I'm surprised.
I'm not a student anymore.
You're modelling now, right?
Only a bit.
Wanna go pro?
Oh no. Never.
I wanna build a brand with Miyu.
Open to being an Influencer?
You're popular, so I'll give you work.
You can't be a designer,
graduating from this school.
Is that so?
Now I'm an e-commerce app designer,
influencer, influencer adviser,
and brand producer.
Thank God I noticed it.
Schools are business too, anyway.
Few can land the dream job as designer
after paying high tuition fees.
You should make connections
and start something new.
Those who consider themselves cute...
are not for making clothes
in the first place.
You need to notice harsh reality.
And girls who keep thinking like
students miss getting married.
Words are important.
Your words can hurt me...
or make me happy.
They could ruin my life.
He told me to go pro as a model.
Then he'll give me work and clients.
That's great.
No. I turned it down.
What? Why?
I'm quitting modelling.
I get hurt whenever somebody says
I'm ugly.
And Mr. Morita has become soooo boring.
He used to be so cool,
but today he kept preaching.
It's just that he gave up.
I again thought I should try my best
with you even if it's hard.
You know what?
I've been meaning to
tell you that I got a job.
You got a job?
You said we should build a brand.
That's why I'm not looking for a job.
Did you really wanna do it with me?
Yes, of course, because...
You can do it alone.
You are charismatic and loved by everyone.
You have your own way of winning.
It's your talent
that you are blessed and loved.
Each has each speed of living...
and balance of crash and prudence.
The percentage of meeting
one soul is so low.
My Muse has been you.
I'm so bad at keeping balance.
I might have ruined my own opportunities.
I don't have reasons for my dreams.
I just wanted to
live selfishly like kids.
I don't wanna be given a time limit
for being a child.
Instead, I'll be responsible for
my dreams.
I had nothing from the start.
I'm not smart enough to protect my pride
I've had, being ignorant.
I kept forgetting what I'd decided.
I see spring flashing in front of me.
I don't wanna forfeit love anymore,
so I won't tell anyone.
I got it. I was asked by Mr. Morita
to give this to Lara...
to work as an influencer.
We haven't seen her prince awhile.
She had lots going on
and didn't win any awards.
Is she disappointed?
Didn't seem like that.
When did you see her?
What?
Well, Lara's...
She made me buy this as an investment.
So she won't do modeling job anymore?
She can't help making something.
I think so too.
Hang in there.
(Fashion Design College Entrance Ceremony)
Morning.
Don't eat that.
Isn't it a big one?
I'm just taking a small bite.
I can't open this.
I'm home.
Saho.
What's wrong?
(Your Sheet)
Framed by the silver borders,
I simply stare.
I project what it is...
without agreeing with or denying it.
Stand up.
Turn around.
I am not cruel.
I am just honest.
(Mirror)
Wasn't it from today?
From tomorrow.
Done for today.
I wanted to hear your opinions.
Tell me.
I don't know.
Come on.
Give me some feedback.
Aren't you a teacher?
Even students meet deadlines.
You should too, first.
I am thinking about putting this there.
You know I won't tell you my opinions.
But you came here.
It's been a while.
Can we meet tomorrow?
Yes.
Let's have dinner together at my place.
Your attitude.
What?
Are you seeing her?
Why do you care?
You wanted to hear my opinions.
Your relationship is superficial.
You are just pressing the button.
You should remove this photo.
Are you talking about us?
No. I came here to tell you if you
are imitating the past, throw it away.
Can I take your photos now?
Before and After. How sensational.
No photo has satisfied me since then.
I need your help, Ayumu.
As you go close to water,
my face appears on it...
saying you're only seeing yourself.
I told you about the poem.
Look, I like it.
This isn't me.
It's you.
You just hate me.
No.
You do.
I didn't make our relationship clear.
I don't care now.
That must have caused problems.
It still does. All of my students
know about you, too.
But I'm not blaming you.
Because I did love you. It is true.
Then what's this face?
I'm feeling pity.
Is this "projecting as it is"?
I know.
It's short-sighted.
But this is what people like,
what they want from me.
Lesbian photographer.
They aren't my words.
You're taking advantage by not denying it.
Have you ever truly loved anyone?
For us, relationship came first.
But you are seeing them for your photos.
You can't take the real photos of me.
I know.
I loved you, Ayumu.
I knew my photos tell that I'm lesbian.
But what they see is everything,
so I don't deny it.
I did the same to be recognized.
But no photo satisfies me now.
I don't know.
It's not that I love women, only you.
What am I?
I'm not lying.
Poor Nagisa.
You cannot love anyone.
It was very good tea.
What is this?
(Sex-less, Sex-friends)
We started with sex.
But it's been 4 months
since we became sexless.
I don't know what to call us.
Then how about this?
You said you liked it before.
No?
I don't know.
It's before the start of period,
so it should feel better.
No need to do it.
But it's been a while.
But you don't feel good.
If you do, I'm OK.
No, no, no.
We used to come so much.
It was insane.
It went out of the line.
Shut up.
Let me.
Oh? Have you done it?
I have.
What?
For your girfriend?
For my sister.
Can this nail breathe?
I don't know. Maybe not.
That's not good.
What?
Help. Help.
Creepy. What's that?
This is nail.
Oh nail? Nail's voice?
Stop it.
Is it good?
This one?
Not much.
You should quit it.
It's not good but can't quit.
It's like us.
What do you mean?
We are sexless fuck budies.
Well, that's true.
Need something?
Nope.
You should quit.
Quit what?
Shall we quit?
Eww.
I...
broke up with her.
What?
When?
Last month.
Why?
What? Why would you ask that?
You are unfair.
I'm sorry.
You know I started feeling nothing, right?
At first...
it was all about being sexually
compatible. But...
I started thinking...
you have a girlfriend...
I'm just a fuck buddy
and that it will end.
Things like that.
So I started feeling nothing.
What?
It's you who are unfair.
Hey.
What?
Why don't we do it again?
From the start.
Excuese me. Can I use your phone?
Can I use your phone?
So mean. Why am I doing this?
It was in late May that I met Mitsuko.
Earlier you mentioned Mitsuko.
When she goes out to drink without me...
she comes home with scars.
The other day...
she argued with a stranger.
And his wife joined them
and it turned into a mess.
Hey, you two, please ask me about my novel.
It's about your novel as she's your muse.
My muse, huh? Without her, I wouldn't
have been able to write novels.
Can I take your photos?
You talked about me again
that I'm crazy?
I didn't.
Well, I did a bit.
Dumb-ass.
We started to see each other a lot.
You can be relaxed.
I taught myself photography.
I want to study abroad some day.
Sounds amazing.
I wanted to be with her always.
(His wife ex-model gets disorderly)
When we met for the first time,
you thought I'm a fool, right?
Is that why you wanted me as model?
You looked pretty, kind...
sensitive and smart.
My husband is a novelist.
That's when I learned that.
Really?
Most of the women in his novels...
commit suicide when they are young.
Don't you think it's guys' fantasy?
I think...
I'll go missing in the near future.
I'm always in the dark.
In life, we have to keep
moving forward, right?
There's some point in every life
when we can't move forward.
Mitsuko died in an accident.
Ms. Sonoko.
Do you doubt it was an accident?
I'm sorry.
I'm off now.
Please tell me.
I'm not coinvined. I beg you.
Oh, sorry.
You are a novelist, so...
you might find the accident ordinary.
But Mitsuko told me...
The stories about women comitting
suicides are fantasy.
So I don't think she did.
Bye.
Why don't we take a trip?
It'll be fun. We can take lots of photos.
I realized I had been in love.
You have time to cry?
I'm asking if you have time to cry.
I'm thinking.
Okay. Then start writing.
It's the setting you decided.
It is.
I thought this is the best setting
to be engaged in.
Story about an actress and a director.
I'm sorry I can't write,
but actresses play
the parts already written.
And you're a writer.
You're looking down
on those who can't write.
I'm not saying that. Just because
our positions are different...
I want you to write something unique.
I want to shoot the film.
What's something unique?
Something unseen.
But you will fall for its actress anyway.
I will.
It will ruin everything.
You can change the setting.
I don't have time.
Manage it.
I can't sleep then.
You don't know what creators are.
I can't write without sleeping.
Yesterday, I...
slept only for 20 to 30 minutes like this.
I was sleeping then.
Stop having a cigarette break.
At restaurants, whenever we are asked
if we smoke, you say we do.
But I don't. I don't smoke.
You are so crazy for putting
non-smokers in a smoking area.
I'm not a drinker.
Look at this.
This is it.
It's just amazing.
I love what you write.
Finish it soon.
I don't have money.
How are you gonna pay for this fine room?"
Fine room?
I'll pay as long as you can keep writing.
You sound as if you weren't stingy
with money regarding arts. But you...
haven't paid for the ticket for the play.
You disappeared saying you'd smoke,
and I paid for two.
I didn't disappear.
Wasn't that play so good?
You said you'd pay for me.
I didn't. I was sorry for...
inviting you for a play in a remote area.
So I said I'd pay for travel cost.
You didn't mention "for travel cost.
But you didn't reply. You just nodded.
And I meant I'd pay
if the play wasn't interesting.
I couldn't tell.
Wasn't the play great? We cried a lot.
It serves as reference.
It was great, so pay for it.
Whichever pays for it, they don't care.
I know.
I just want anything paid
by others if it can be.
Mr. Fujimura.
I wanna go out with you
even just for one day.
It can be a day trip.
It can be anywhere
like Kamakura or Disneyland.
I wanna have fun without
talking about the film.
It'll be fun.
Without business, we get along well.
You can go with some other guy.
I've been saying I wanna go with you.
Just for once.
Is something wrong?
I've been saying I can't.
Do I have to say it clearly?
Why don't you?
I could go if I try
ignoring time or our positions.
We could go out for one day.
I don't know since when...
but after graduating from college
and leaving my house...
everything is for making films.
Stories used to be extraordinary experience.
They used to take me far.
Now stories are everything.
I've been in extraordinary world,
so I can't be detached.
I don't understand.
I don't understand about you.
Why can't you do it?
I can't.
But there's nothing wrong with you.
Of course.
Why don't you start writing?
I'll write something good.
I will.
I will. I'll write something good.
I'll write something good. I will.
(I wanna be your cat)
At that time,
our lives were revolving around him.
That I will recall some day.
I hope his secret won't be revealed
by anyone.
I don't want him to be an adult
without my knowing it.
I want to hide right now.
(Spring-ing)
What's Kyushu like? Is it warm?
It's just great.
You glad to move there?
I'll miss this place,
but I'll get to see sweet viburnum.
Its flowers look like snow.
First I'll go to college
from grandma's house.
I asked Rio to come to Kyushu.
Why?
Because he said he won't go on to college.
Are you going to Kyushu?
Haru, are you writing a novel these days?
Do you still love Yumi?
Haru, you want Yumi to be gone
as soon as possible.
You two pretend to be getting along well.
When I'm with Yumi,
I can feel I'm a boy.
But when I'm with you,
I feel as if I were a girl.
What do you mean?
Rio, I'm offended. Why can't it be me?
Are you going to keep wearing it?
But I'll get to see sweet viburnum.
Its flowers look like snow.
You heard them, right?
Where are you going?
To see cherry blossoms.
I don't like cherry blossoms.
I've read Haru's novel.
I envy her for being able to write.
Yeah.
Rio, what do you wanna be in the future?
What are you gonna do from now?"
I don't have a specific dream,
but I want to save money.
What about you?
I wish I could write novels like Haru.
But now...
I wanna be a journalist because I wanna
be words myself, traveling abroad.
I didn't think you'd really come today.
Because...
I'm...
in a relationship.
Close your eyes, Rio.
If I could choose,
I'd rather not be either of them.
Half of my heart is not here.
Half of my heart is somewhere
other than here.
Ever since I was born,
I've lived only with half of myself.
It's not that I want to be loved.
I wanted something good.
I'm just me.
Aoi, stop tickling me.
Don't you ever look this way.
Okay. But you are acting weird.
We couldn't finish watching the film
again last night.
I don't remember much.
I got the feeling that we should have
finished watching the film last night.
Hey, Riku.
Have you thought about dying?
I don't know.
When I said so,
my mom laughed at me.
My mom loves me and I love her. But...
there are things we can't understand.
As if you were touching ice...
the two of us get burned at night.
We are getting burned.
We can't wait until the film ends.
And morning like daydream comes.
That's how we get it through.
Half of my heart is in the sea.
In the sea of this ceiling...
Silver fish is swimming, glittering.
When I get away from you...
I'm just myself.
(I wish you would break.)
I wish Riku would break.
That's how I feel sometimes.
There must be something wrong with it.
It's not wrong.
It happens in romance.
No matter how you try to break me,
I'll be back.
What are you saying?
Do break down.
I really want to break you.
I always feel there's something missing.
I don't have big hands
or a big back like Riku.
I can never stand against you.
But...
would you cry if I do something awful?
Would you be hurt by me?
Would you really break down?
I'll cry.
I'll break down for sure.
I'll get hurt for sure.
I really think it's fine if I break down,
being with you.
Let's live together
at the risk of our lives.
You are crazy.
There are many things I want to try.
But I always hear a voice from behind
Saying, “You are too young.
Grow up.”
Everyone tells me to face reality
and save money.
I don't wanna hear it.
There must be...
something extraordinary in this world.
Can't we keep looking for it?
Two of us.
I understand you more than
anyone else does.
I understand you...
more than anyone else.
Half of my heart is in the sea.
(reborn)
I won't read it.
Do you know how I feel?
If I open it
and I don't find my name written...
do you know how sad I'm going to be?
If you love somebody,
it's not right nor wrong, right?
I love myself the most.
And I love Hiroto for loving me.
When I was with him...
I was really happy.
I must have been the cutest in the world.
I was sparkling.
(Sparkle)
Are you crying?
Why do people cry?
The moment we sparkle most
in our lives...
could be when a girl gets a boyfriend
for the first time,
or when a girl kisses or holds hands
with a guy she loves for the first time.
More than friends, but not lovers.
Half of the word "FRIENDS" is fading,
right?
That's why.
Is there any princess without a prince?
My prince is Hiroto without doubt.
He made me a princess.
When I was with him, I was sparkling
every moment.
Hiroto was everything to me.
But suddenly he disappeared.
(Search)
I've been steeped in darkness.
He was like a little animal as my teacher.
He was my flatmate.
He was addicted to cigarette
and smartphone...
bubbly and adorable.
He got lonely easily.
We have different impressions, huh?
Chikako, how did you know him?
He was a trainee teacher
when I was a senior.
Since graduating from high school,
I'd been with him.
He suddenly disappeared.
With a guy?
I thought this could be the reason.
What are you gonna do?
I want to see him again.
Do you have any clue?"
That time capsule.
Each wrote a letter to the one we love,
and we buried them.
So did Mr. Hiroto.
We said it'd be nice if we
keep loving the same person...
even when we get old.
Love Letter
(Hiroto Tai)
How many love letters exist
in this world?
Some are discarded.
Others are treasured.
I love you. I miss you.
The words written on paper
evolve to someone's feelings.
Hiroto.
You're too excited.
It's coming-of-age ceremony.
What are you doing?
Writing a love note.
What? Let me see!
Why not?
No.
Stop.
Bang.
Ouch.
It couldn't hurt.
Whenever he did something sweet...
my heart warmed up and started pounding.
(Time Capsule)
But now...
Found it.
We did it.
Let's take it to the gym. Go.
Wow.
I'm exhausted.
What is this?
They must be having a play
at the culture fest.
I'm opening it.
Let's stop it. It's not good to peek at
love letters. It's not.
No way. You can't say that.
As much as I love him,
he loves somebody else.
The object is not me.
I'm not mature enough to get over the fact.
(Fate of Love)
No. Please don't read mine.
I want him to turn around,
look at me and say I'm cute.
I want him to say he loves me.
I want him to be mine.
Chikako must have found his.
What does it say, Chikako?
(Fantasy)
I...
I love myself most.
And I love Hiroto for loving me.
My feelings kept drifting inside myself.
I couldn't accept the fact.
I just kept drifting with pains
in my heart.
I was sparkling.
But...
Without Hiroto, I can't sparkle.
My body and my heart..
Yearn for him now.
Even if it's fantasy...
I need him.
(Parting)
There's no princess without a prince.
When Hiroto was around,
I was a princess.
My world was sparkling.
But what's the point in keeping
sparkling in fantasy?
The tear I shed disappear,
and I meet somebody else.
I might completely forget about him.
But I know I'll remember him.
The feelings I had spending time
with him then.
The sparkle.
Are you crying?
It's not the tears of sorrow...
tears of joy.
(My love won't go anywhere)
(For Lonesome Blossoms)
Since we've tread this garden
we know of our end.
We are blossoming daughters.
That's right, when the flowers...
We must soon leave this garden.
Yes, soon.
We're in a secret garden
loved by momentary seasons.
We are girls in blossoming prime.
Even laughing, I'd rather cry.
Memories of becoming myself.
We'll forget these days.
We'll forget this time.
This time.
It's over.
Even if it's my first time
I know this garden will end.
(A Record of My First Love and I)
First time in love.
First love.
My star.
My star, called first love.
Light my path.
My first love dies, I grow old.
And I watch my youth goes cold.
Just like the flowers wilt, we grow old.
We grow old.
Only women have to grow old.
That's okay.
I'm okay as a girl forever.
Even if they say, "you're no girl"
and for eternity, we'll always
be just our mother's baby girl.
For eternity.
All life is born from women.
Everyone starts their journey as a girl.
Whether a boy or a girl,
you're your mother's baby.
That's right,
I am my mother's baby girl.
Be a girl, from now on...
There is still no life.
Then we're still in a previous world.
And soon we're born on earth.
(And soon we're born on earth.)
How strange.
We can't return from earth!
Where should we go?
I'll walk my path.
(A Story of My Mother)
We speak as the earth's surface moves.
My shadow moves.
Your stomach trembles.
(A Story of My "Mother")
That's not enough.
Mother, look here.
Not enough. I need more love.
I'm a wild monster.
Seeking love is not shameful.
What a pity to do that.
I know that intensity.
I feel sorry for mom.
Her life is sacrificed
for silly me, for love.
I've never known real love.
It's a fake, to me.
Love is an illusion.
Love is a dream.
So no matter what,
we create the love we can.
Love never ceases.
Love is a lie.
We can live within limitless love.
We reach for love.
If that's the same as sadness
because love can never be divided.
No, no! Don't go in!
You love me so deeply and still hurt me?
You can't speak to my heart only in bed.
You will never truly know me,
no matter how deep you go.
And no matter how I may look for you.
You'll never know.
Am I born from that pain?
I will be a free mother.
Rise from her bondage.
No. I will be free to embrace bondage.
I can't return anything to my mother.
How much I love her.
I know. No matter how I'm loved.
All I can do to give back
to my mother is act.
Is it possible?
Don't look back!
Surely, if we go to earth, surely...
We pledge for birth,
to improve this born world.
How do you best improve the earth?
Ensure future children are free and happy.
For that?
If she loves and gives birth,
she should be free and happy.
Would any girl refuse
a free and happy mother?
Then, free and happy children
will spread across the world.
We were born seeing a mother
free and happy.
Mother, I beg you!
Make me a girl from a mother
with big dreams.
If I could look just like you...
If I could look like any place...
Your distorted meat and bones.
Because I love you.
I am perfectly born to you.
Maybe I look nothing like you.
If I looked like you
when you can't love yourself,
would I find myself too scary
to be loved?
We're too similar, it's scary.
Take a bit from those you love.
And if you love him,
I'll know right away.
At the end of this maddening love,
come find me.
Look at me, with those who care for you.
Mother, grandmother, great-grandmother...
Back one or two hundred years ago...
I want to live for the pains of
generations of mothers.
I will show mother a real girl's shape.
120 years since cinema's birth.
In other words, one woman's life.
In the 21st century, we mourn her life.
Can a true cinema be born...?
We are 21st century girls...
Pour the 3 primary colors
into the 21st century.
21 plus 3 equals 24.
Perfect, the art of the lie
24 frames per second.
Return the three colors of life
into cinema.
Let's make multi-varied lies.
And for the first time, those working in
black shadows appear.
(And for the first time, those working in
black shadows appear...)
In the shadows is full of color.
They gather and it blackens.
Ah, it turns dark.
My fingertips turn black.
In this dark world, loneliness.
Only the lonely can change the world.
So we must become even more alone.
You're still alone, even with someone.
Not just alone, but loneliness
among others... it's ephemeral.
Finding love in shared loneliness,
it's the most precious.
In that case, I'll become a blossom,
all alone in the world.
I'm not a swarm?
I don't forgive others?
You don't get it.
I'm so lonely, knowing you.
Even if we help each other,
I feel so lonely.
I want to be more alone than anyone.
Bring me greater loneliness on earth.
Wherever I may be born.
I will make art to encompass the world.
Combine love, language, religion, politics.
Search out beauty.
Combined art.
The seventh art.
Create the ultimate art.
Even if it's my first time
I know this garden will end.
And a new Spring comes.
Ah, the wind!
And we're lonesome.
Since we've tread this garden
we know of our end.
When I leapt from this garden
will we know how it starts.
For lonesome blossoms.
Let's walk the path of loneliness.
Let's feel more loneliness than anyone.
Let's find a flower more alone than me.
And we'll discover that
all of us are alone.
Born into the 21st century.
And we can see the light.
(On the screen)
Ah, it's time! Time to be born.
Time to be born on the earth.
We must become life.
We must head to our mother.
I feel like... I'm forgetting something.
One time, one time, to be forgotten.
One time, one time, to be remembered.
And as beautiful as what we can
remember, however many times.
However many times life is born.
Ah, to be born.
Ah, to be born so soon!
Ah, to be born right now!
Being born into the world now!
When I'm born onto the earth
surely
I'll make a new film.
Dedicated to my one and only mother.
Delivered to my one and only girl.
Make a film for 21st century girls.
(For Lonesome Blossoms)
"Make a film for 21st century girls!"