A small camera won't do. Has to be a big one with a flash.
Otherwise you can't make her come.
'A big camera with a big flash...'
Hey, let me buy you dinner. I found a good Korean place.
Okay.
Take some hot stuff like this, Mr Iguchi?
No.
This is fine.
Why quit? What a shame.
You always do a good job and you're cheap.
Anyway, can you deliver the stuff by tomorrow?
County Mental Health Center. What can I do for you?
Hello...
Are you there?
I'm... thinking of killing myself...
A SNAKE OF JUNE
Once you find what you really want to do, you'll be okay.
Yes...
Oh, No no...
I know what you mean. I sure do.
Go for it. Nobody can stop you.
May I help you?
I need to talk to Mrs Rinko TATSUMI.
Is there anything I can do?
I need to talk to her in person.
Eh...
I'm Mrs TATSUMI.
Mental Health Center: Telephone Counseling
So you saved her son's life!
She looked so angry so I thought she had a complaint.
Actually, I thought so too,
because I've been a bit tough on the boy.
He stopped calling me for a while.
Thank goodness...
- 'Safe,' eh? - Yeah...
- I'm home. - You scared me.
You're early today. I wouldn't have worked overtime if I had known.
Never mind.
Did you eat? I bought one only for myself.
Don't worry. I ate already.
Hey, I'll do it.Was it that dirty?
I love to do this.
- You know what? - What?
Why don't we get a dog, a big one?
Don't know.
How about a small rabbit, then?
It'll grow big.
How big do you mean?
What's up with you?
Rinko...
There you go again.
Don't you leave those books lying about, will you?
- Here. - Thanks.
YOUR HUSBAND'S SECRETS
What's that? Any news?
Nothing.
YOUR HUSBAND'S SECRETS
You've made me want to live.
I shouldn't have said I wanted to die.
I've found something to live for now. You should be happy for me.
Shigehiko was promoted again.
The new position keeps him busy, but he'll come to see you soon.
Today, Shigehiko nagged me to buy a new car
but I told him off because I bought him one recently.
He was dejected...
You know, you're right. One must find something to live for.
You... are the one calling the center...
Why don't you do what you really want?
Walk in the street, dressed in the mini skirt.
Let's walk in the street dressed in the skirt cut short,
just like when you did it alone.
Bring and change the skirt at the place where I tell you to.
Use the cell phone enclosed and follow my instructions...
Then I'll give you the negatives.
Who'd believe a sleaze like you!
I'm not asking you for sex.
I'm telling you to do what you want. Then you'll get the negatives.
You're crazy!
Please watch. Here we go.
What... again?
Let me clean it. I've got the time.
Please. I love doing this.
TO: Mr Shigehiko TATSUMI Minato-ku, Tokyo...
Forgive me, Shigehiko.
How about next Saturday?
Your husband is working, but you'll be off,
I'll call the police.
Go ahead.We'll meet in hell.
Why...Why me!
You made me want to live.
You said you only photographed still lives.
You lied.
No, I didn't.
I've changed since I got to know you.
- See you. - Have a nice day.
Let's begin.
Take the subway and get off at the fifth station.
There's a toilet just in front of the ticket booths.
That's where you should change into the skirt.
Did you change?
Look, I want to talk with you.
We can talk on the phone or maybe we can meet at a cafe.
I can't do this.
You can do it when you're alone.
You caught me the only time I did it.
Tell me what made you become so daring
at this rainy season of year.
Something has burst open in you.
Don't be afraid.You can do it.
Don't worry about how people react. Show them who you are.
I promise you'll get the negatives.
No underwear.
Just like when you did it alone.
What about a shirt, your hair and some make-up?
You should look the way you were.
I forgot.
What? Never-mind.
Walk through the arcade to the department store.
This cosmetic would go with your skin.
-Well then... - Hold on a second.
- Let's buy a vibrator now. - What?
You want it, don't you?
It's time to buy one.
I don't want it.
-Yes, you do. - No.
Please. Don't you want the negatives back?
Believe me I can't.
You told me on the phone at the center:
'You've got to do what you really want.'
What? Which one?
The bigger one?
All right.
I was wondering about you, prowling around the entrance.
So you wanted this, eh?
There is a window over your head.
Show me what you bought.
Wow, it sure looks big.
Well, the show is over now.
The negatives are...
Maybe not quite yet.
This isn't what you really wanted.
Put the vibrator in and walk in the streets.
Place the remote control at the entrance.
What about the negatives?
You promised.
I thought you're special since you saved my life.
You tell people what to do but you can't do it yourself,
You're not in touch with your husband's feelings.
Some counselor!
It seems you chose the right husband...
He isn't like your father, who was a boozer and a womanizer.
I'm not telling you to get laid.
I'm telling you to do what you want.
Let's finish this thing first.
You'll have the negatives. Be happy.
Let's do some shopping.
You'll find a grocery store soon.
Buy a cucumber, an eggplant and a banana.
Buy just one of each, okay?
I'll kill you!
One of each?
You should've told me that first.
That's 500 yen.
Well, that's enough.
You can go back to the toilet.
You'll find the negatives.
Shigehiko...
- Hello. - Hello.
Enough is enough! Now what do you want?
There's something I must tell you...
I still have a negative.
You said that's all...
Do what I say if you want this.
- You lied! - No! I didn't mean to!
- Bastard! -Then, don't listen! Anyway...
Go and see your doctor.
Yes...
Good... No, I didn't do much.
Don't mention it.
No... Please...
Well...
Nice talking to you.
"Household Medical Encyclopedia"
The Last Negative
Yes?
Pet Shop, 'Merry.'
Hey...
Umh...
How did you know about it?
Tell me how.
Well, then...
You are...
I kind of figured and I hoped I was wrong.
I've got tons of books on that 'thing.'
'Thing?'
Cancer.
I wanted to get ready to die.
When I found the last photo...
I noticed a tiny hollow in your breast.
The more I looked at it, the more I was convinced.
I wish I were wrong.
You're thinking about killing yourself.
You didn't tell me about your illness.
So it was cancer.
I thought you wouldn't listen to me...
if I told you that.
You're in too much pain to move.
You can't be a 'Peeping Tom' any more.
I won't trouble you any more.
At least, I had my last wish granted.
I'm still hanging on.
Shit! I'm going to make it.
You know...
On that day, I hammered a thick nail into my hand.
Trying to kill my stomach-ache with the pain.
It didn't work.
You won't be redeemed.
I know that.
Stupid!
You needed someone to make fun of before you died.
Someone incapable of knowing her husbands feeling
A "dummy" like me who can't do
what she really wants to do.
You're dying.
So why don't you do it alone and peacefully.
- Honey... - Yeah?
There's something I need to talk about.
What! Cut a breast off?!
It prevents the cancer from spreading.
I don't understand.Why you?!
I'll be fine.
'Fine'? You'll lose your breast.
But it'll save my life.
Let me clean.
Just leave it to me, will you?
I'm allergic to animals.
I can't stand the smell, either.
You should've told me about the hamster.
Yes.
I see.
Yes, my mother in-law is gone. I got a call from the hospital.
I can't work today.
I'll call you when I know more.
There is a child who's in a difficult situation.
Yes, that's him. Please speak carefully when he calls.
Sorry I'm stuck with my work.
Try to make it sooner, will you?
How could you miss the vigil?
You barely saw your mother when she died.
Did you have to work that late?
You arranged the funeral today
but I was afraid you might disappear during the funeral.
Were you that busy?
This is a message for Mrs TATSUMI.
An operation was scheduled for you today.
Please call us...
I'm home.
Hi, honey.
There you are.
- How were the results? - Fine.
- ls everything okay? - The doc says I don't need an operation.
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
They'll keep my breast intact.
- I'm glad to hear that. - Yeah.
Are you okay?
Of course I am.
You seem to like that cafe.
What?
You were there when your mother died.
I sympathize with your wife and your mother.
Who the hell are you?
So you take it in powder. Mine was tablets.
To get rid of the smell of your shit, you know.
Do you hate the smell of shit, too?
I used to...
We have something in common...
- Was it you who... - What?
- Never mind. - Say it.
Don't fool me.About the photos...
- Never mind. - Did you see them?
What did you say? So that was you!
Didn't you think that the water in the cafe tasted strange?
What?!
Yes... it's about my wife.
I want to know what she's up to.
Yes...Yes... I mean...
I mean... umm...
I tried not to call you
but I wanted to hear your voice.
Hey...
Umh?
Do me a favour, will you?
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
Nothing.
'Nothing?'
She says you're watching her all the time.
I don't know her.
Tell me what else you've been doing here?
You were watching her.
Don't you dare! Stop right there.
You still haven't got an operation!?
Good evening.
How many photos have you taken?
What else did you do to her?
You must have!
Does she hang around that place often?
I wonder.
Let me buy all those photos. All of them!
That place... really surprised me at first.
But I'm sure you'll get used to it quickly.
Because you're similar to me.
What I want is the photos. Nothing else.
You'll find a paper-bag at the front.
What's this? I told you I want all of them.
I saw the photos you sent her.
I want to see all of her.
You did.
Then you've seen all of her!
Take off your clothes.
On your knees.
Shigehiko... Shigehiko...
Was it your idea
not to cut off her breast?
How do you know that?
It's her doctor's decision.
Idiot!!
She's going to die soon.
Oh, I see.
That's it.
She doesn't have to mutilate herself.
She's better off dead
than living like a freak!
She asked me..
to give these photos...
to you.
Why?!
Why does she do that?
Nuns tend to suffer from breast cancer
because they repress their bodily desires.
I have something to ask you.
You think she's a nun, eh!?
Is she a nun!?
Shouldn't you have known she's sick?
You'll die here!
You don't want to see her die!
I'll take care of her!
I'll stay with her at your place.
We'll start our life together!
Give us your blessing!
I love this sound.
Stuffed sweet peppers.
Your husband's favourite.
You put those in Miso soup, eh?
Isn't it good?
I found a good old camera.
I made it when I was a kid.
With this camera, I wanted to take...
a photo of you.
Well, then...
I must be going.
All right.
I'll be going soon.
Am I in hell?
Yes.You are right.
Then...
it's...
time to go.
I'll follow you.
Give me my gun back!
Son of a bitch! My gun!!
- Give me back! - Calm down!
Open the fucking door!
He's in the house.
Get ready! Go! Go!