After pondering the situation in the worldand in our empire,
...we have decided to resort to
an extraordinary measure.
Loyal subjects, we have ordered
our government...
...to communicate tothe USA, Great Britain,
...China and the USSR,
...our acceptance of
the provisions...
...of their Joint Declaration.
To strive for the security and
well-being of our subjects...
...and for the prosperity and happiness
of all nations, is a....
...solemn obligation handed down by
our imperial ancestors.
We declared war on
the USA and Britain...
...out of a desire to ensure
the self-preservation of Japan...
...and the stability of
East Asia.
To violate the sovereignty of others...
...or to embark on
territorial aggrandizement,
...was far from our
thoughts.
Relax.
Gently. Or it will bemore difficult.
Open your mouth when I tell you.
Keep it closed now.
You are doing fine, just fine.
The pain is coming back?
Close your mouth.
Do you feel the needfor a bowel movement?
Do you?
Is that what it feels like?
Well, squeeze tightly then.
Prepare the water!
Hurry!
The light has come on again. At last.
It's a boy...
Congratulations.
On August 15 1945. Japan announced
its unconditional surrender.
Taiwan was liberated following
51 years of Japanese occupation.
The wife of older brother,
Lin Wen-heung, gave birth to a son.
They named him Kang-ming,
which means Light.
CITY OF SADNESS
Directed by Hou Hsiao-hsien
Going already?
Sorry for the mess.
We didn't give you a proper welcome.
Come again.
- Ah, hello.
- A small gift for you.
Go and play over there.
Behave or grandfather will
take a stick to you.
Yes, it's me.
Thank you, thank you.
I don't want to inconvenience you.
I am sorry to trouble you.
Thanks.
Until this evening then.
I'll be waiting for you.
Wen-heung,
...did you tell your brother
you were coming?
I wrote to Wen-ching.
He is too busy to come.
He can't come?
So who will take
the photos?
Don't worry, father.
I've arranged everything.
Who did you ask?
A photographer friend
of old Gao-kun.
He's a top-knotch photographer.
The best in the district.
Not as good as Wen-ching.
Mr Xu is here.
Show him in.
To business and to our
future prosperity.
To prosperity!
LITTLE SHANGHAI
Stay still, don't move.
Don't move.
Smile, please.
Ready?
Thanks!
20 years and 11 months of
the Showa Emperor.
Good weather, with clouds.
I took the letter of recommendation
from my father...
...to look for work at the
Kimguishiu Miners Hospital.
My brother was giving classes and...
...sent his friend Wen-ching
to pick me up.
It was cool in the mountains...
...and the view was lovely.
From now on, I will see it
every day
I feel so happy.
A photograph.
Beautiful.
Photographs of two of my older
brothers before the war.
They have still not returned. Someone in
Shanghai saw my third brother.
But we have had no news of the second,
who was sent to the Philippines.
This is the studio of Wen-ching.
Hinoe says that this is the
studio of Wen-ching.
Why isn't he here?
Where is Wen-ching?
At the back, taking photos.
Come in, please.
- After you.
- No, after you.
Are all these books yours?
Mine and Wen-ching's.
We are real
book worms.
Are you reading Marx?
Very progressive, eh?
They are all interesting, and so
we are studying them.
Mr Lin, do you remember Wen-ching?
The deaf man.
Wen-ching.
Let me introduce...
...Mr Lin.
Pleased to meet you.
My mentor.
We've heard a lot about you.
It's a pleasure.
Mr Ho, a journalist.
From the mainland.
Please sit down.
Are you familiar with China?
There's a lot for me to learn.
China is in a mess
at present.
Ever since Chen Yi became
governor of Taiwan,
...things have changed.
He thinks differently from the Japanese.
In what way?
He manages things differently
from the Japanese.
Our Japanese director had an
attack this morning...
...but he insisted on going out
after he'd had an injection.
His daughter Shizuko is very sad.
During the past 3 days,
dad has been...
...threatening to go to the south of Taiwan.
He said that Mr Chen would take him.
But he died years ago.
Dad was at his funeral.
The other day, the Japanese
Repatriation Office told us...
...that a boat would be coming to
Keelung to pick us up.
They told us not to go
too far away.
But this morning dad packed
his bags and left.
We are all very worried.
A pain... in the head.
A pain... in the stomach.
Where does it hurt?
Don't worry.
I don't think it's serious.
Thank goodness he came back.
He can recover here.
Perhaps my mother's grave is
in an unlucky location.
She died leaving four children.
My younger brother
disappeared in the Phillippines.
The youngest is deaf.
The third came back from the war but
is mad.
Wen-leung, what are you doing?
Wen-leung, quiet!
Let me be!
Wen-leung, you're mad!
Wen-leung, calm down!
Quiet! Quiet!
It's OK.
He'll be fine now.
When Taiwan was returned
to China,
...they told us we'd change flags.
The Japanese flag is white
with a red circle in the middle.
You can hang it in a way that's...
...different from the Chinese flag.
The people held discussions. Should the sun
be on the top or the bottom?
But the mayor was adamant.
It had to be on the bottom.
At daybreak, the sky is red and so
the sun had to be at the bottom.
Everyone had to have it
as he said.
But he sent someone to check.
The first people he checked had
hung it correctly,
...but not in the mountains.
Most people put the sun
on the bottom.
And so the mayor felt
vindicated.
But during the day,a man arrived from the city...
...and said he was wrong,
...and that they'd shoot him for it.
The mayor landed and gave new orders,
...but it was already sunset.
The sky was completely red.
It's extraordinary. Suddenly Japanese flags...
...were no use any more.
Only as underpants for children.
They all have red bums.
Like monkeys.
Wu too has one.
Mind what you say.
This man
is a reporter from the mainland.
Can your wife do something
with my flag?
I'll write that all the teachers...
...in Taiwan have red backsides.
Let's stop talking
and drink.
Cheers.
Let's change the subject.
Now that the war is over,
how are things inTaiwan?
Everything's fine.
We are under the Chinese flag
once more.
Reunited with the motherland.
It's a good feeling.
But to tell the truth,
...Governor Chen Yi
is a bandit...
...and I don't trust
the Nationalist government.
Enough politics!
Let's drink!
Let's drink.
Raise your glasses.
They are singing
"The Song of the Exiles".
Yes, that's right.
We mainlanders
have heard it on the radio.
Let's join in.
Yes, let's.
September 18...
Ever since that tragic day...
...I have been far from my home.
I abandoned a wealth of treasure...
...and began my wanderings...
...began my wanderings.
Far from home...
...I began my wanderings...
...began my wanderings.
In what year...
...or in what month...
...will I commence my return
to my beloved home?
In what year...
...or in what month...
...will I commence my return
to my beloved home?
Good day, Miss Shizuko.
Good day.
Is Hinomi here?
She's on duty.
I'm sorry.
- Hello, can I help ypu?
- I'd like to speak to Hinomi.
She's in the surgery.
Maybe she's finished.
Shall I find out for you?
Wait a moment, please.
This sword was the most precious
possession of my dead brother.
It's no use to him now.
Please, give it to Hinoe.
I know my brother
will treasure it.
This is a poem my brother wrote.
Hinoe was there
when he wrote it.
Please give it to him with the sword
as a memento.
Thank you.
This is for you, Hinomi.
For me?
A kimono?
It's lovely,
...but I can't accept it.
It's your most precious possession.
Please accept it.
When I am back in Japan,
...you'll think of you whenever you use it.
Shizuko...
Hinoe has been so nice
to us all these years.
We must never forget
each other.
The dragonfly, red in
the sunset.
Did I see you the other day?
When I was picking
mulberries in the fields,
...did I see you or was
it only a dream?
I'll always remember you.
The flowers are blown hither
and thither.
I'll soon follow them.
The same will come to pass for us all.
The Japanese love the sight
of cherry trees.
First, in bloom...
...and then, when the flowers fall
to earth.
They believe life
too is like that.
In the Meiji Era...
...a woman killed herself
by flinging herself into a waterfall.
In the Meiji Era...
...a woman killed herself
by flinging herself into a waterfall.
She wasn't tired of life. She hadn't
lost the will to live.
She just couldn't face the loss
of her youth.
Once lost, nothing
means anything.
Why not imitate
the cherry blossom...
...and fall when in the fullness
of our beauty?
Carried by the wind.
The note she left
was an inspiration...
...to all young people...
...during the Meiji Era.
A time of idealism
and heroic spirit.
The flowers fly hither
and thither.
And I'll soon follow them.
The same will come to pass for us all.
In which ward is Wen-leung?
I see him now.
Wen-leung, business is what men
are for, isn't it?
Men can do any kind
of work.
Now that you have recovered,
you can do anything.
You have six boats in your family,
...laden with rice and sugar...
...and ready to set sail to make a lot
of money in China.
Those boats are ideal
for smuggling.
We'd make a lot of money
with a single round trip.
What do you say?
I'll have to ask
my brother.
Ask what?
Do you consult him on everything?
Let's keep this between ourselves.
We Shanghai people are well
organized. Don't worry.
We'll take care of everything.
The rice and the sugar
are not a problem.
Come on, be shrewed.
When opportunity knocks,
it's foolish not to open the door.
Cheers!
To you, Wen-leung.
Ah-ga, enjoying the company
of the ladies, I see.
Ah-tao, look to table eight.
Excuse me.
May I present Tsun-chu
and Yen-hung.
Be nice to these mainlanders,
and see they have a good time.
What's this?
We are talking business!
What are all these women
doing here?
Come sit here.
Come.
Forget those mainlanders.
I was waiting for you.
I have a business proposal for you.
Take a good look.
Can you tell the difference?
Red Monkey, introduce me.
It's Ah-ga.
This is my girl, Ah-tsun.
Hello.
You're very beautiful.
And you're very nice.
Have a cigarette.
Let me light it for you.
Mr. Ah-ga, we were hoping
to see you more often.
You will.
Thanks.
I'm going in, Red Monkey.
These are real Japanese
banknotes.
We'll put a stamp on them
and then they can be cashed.
Is it Kimguichiu's share?
How many do you have?
A full valise.
Have you had an idea?
No problem.
Not now, Red Monkey.
I want to sleep.
Let me rest.
I don't want to do it now.
Later.
Let me sleep a while.
Who is it?
Hinomi, are you busy?
A bit.
Here.
When I was here, everyone
was so nice to me.
Take these fruits as
thanks.
My thanks to you all.
Thank you.
The mainland police killed a
cigarette vendor, did you know that?
Yes, I heard.
- You too?
- Yes.
The local people were furious.
The whole street was very tense.
Really furious.
Things were quite explosive.
The cigarettes were brought in as
contraband...
...by a senior official.
Bribery is rife.
They pursue the little fish but
leave the big fish alone.
- We don't have to smoke.
- I do.
I can't go without cigarettes.
Cigarettes are not as
important as rice.
Prices are controlled by
Shanghai...
...to keep up their profits.
The civil servants don't only deal
in contraband cigarettes.
They don't care if we have
rice and sugar,
...only money.
Under the Japanese, times were hard
but we always had rice.
In less than a year,
rice has gone up 52%.
But have salaries gone up?
You are right.
Let's face it, this is not a government;
it's a private company.
Governor Chen Yi is filling...
...his own pockets,
...not yours.
Please, eat a little of the
rice dumpling.
Hinomi made it.
Thank you.
To tell the truth, that's not
the real problem.
The real problem
is unemployment.
You're right.
Since our return to China,
...many Taiwanese have lost
their jobs.
Many of them were
intellectuals...
...who weren't easily
pacified.
With no work,
...sooner or later
there's bound to be chaos.
And not only the intellectuals.
Soldiers too.
Yes, the soldiers conscripted by
Japan can't find work now.
Someone from the mainland took over
the court...
...throwing out the locals
and replacing them with...
...his own wife, uncle and nephew.
The court has been taken over
completely...
...by his family.
They follow his orders.
The Japanese gave you...
...a slave mentality.
You have to change.
We don't even know
how to speak Mandarin.
Slaves? Dammit.
Have we sunk so low as
to want to become slaves again?
The Ching Dynasty sold us out.
Who asked us if we wanted
to be ceded to Japan?
Drink up.
If the Nationalist Government...
...doesn't change its ways,
...even though we have won the war,
...our suffering will continue.
How long before we can lift up our
heads with pride?
Who knows?
We mustn't give up hope.
That would be a waste.
If we want a future,
...the suffering masses
have to resist.
If the Nationalists carry on letting
Chen Yi do what he wants,
...there'll be problems in Taiwan.
Lao He.
There certainly will, as soon as...
...Mr Ho makes ready his pen
to tell the tale.
You are our witness
from the mainland.
It's a folksong called Lorelei,
based on a German legend.
It's about a beautiful siren
seated on a rock in the Rhine.
Sailors are so enchnated by
her singing,
...that they crash their boats into
the rock and die.
I first heard it when I was eight.
I remember the goats bleating and
the voice of an actress in the Opera.
I used to mimic her.
My teacher said I'd become an actor.
I fell from a tree, hurt my head
and caught a fever.
I couldn't walk and didn't
know I was deaf...
...until my father wrote me.
I was too young to
be upset by it.
What's the matter?
He has a fever.
Daddy loves you.
Wait for me downstairs.
Give him something for it.
And?
Here it is.
Hello, Wen-heung.
Give.
Give it me!
What's this?
What is it?
How they fuck you!
Tell your boss to come!
How they fuck you! Put it out.
Why are you smoking?
Put it out.
Are you blind? Can't you read!
Shit!
You want to die young.
How could you do that?
What do you think you're doing?
Bring your boss here!
Go and find your boss.
Don't I give you enough money
for your expenses?
If this gets out,
...a lot of people could be hurt.
And I could die!
I'll take responsibility.
You'll take responsibility?
How can you do that?
It says here that Lin Wen-heung
is in charge of the goods.
You can't take responsibility.
Don't make me sick.
And you dress like those types
from Shanghai.
The latest fashion!
Layabout!
Where's Wen-leung?
I don't know.
You're together all day...
...and you say you don't know?
Speak up.
I really don't know.
Go and call Mr Ko.
Give me Taipei 24.
Wen-leung.
Your brother found out about
the last shipment.
How could he know?
You ask him.
The shipment has been seized.
Where is Ah-ga?
Still at the warehouse.
Does my brother know
I'm involved?
I don't know. Ask Ah-ga.
Wen-leung,
...now that your brother knows about it,
...we have to go and speak to him.
I must speak to Ag-ha first.
What do we do now, boss?
Let's wait for Wen-leung
to get things organized.
Do you want to wash your hands?
Please.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you Ah-tsun?
No, you're mistaken.
Wen-leung, what's going on?
We've met before, in Chiu-fen.
Leave me alone. I told you
I'm not Ah-tsun.
Her name is Ah-man.
Leave us.
Do you have Red Monkey's money?
What are you saying?
Fool!
What's this?
Kim-tsua, it's none of your business.
Not my business, eh?
Leave us.
Ah-ga, tell Wen-leung
to come here.
Ungrateful boy!
You came back from overseas.
We gave you the chance
to reform.
But did you change? No.
You are a lowlife,
...and your friends are lowlifes.
Ah-shue, bring water.
There's blood on you and in the room.
How do you think that'll be taken?
I know.
Look at your father!
Did I ever annoy people...
...in this district? No.
Only the Japanese government.
They called me a gangster.
Me a gangster?
The Japanese government
certainly hated me.
But it was only to help
the district.
I turned big problems
into small ones,
...and got rid of small ones.
I never stole anything from anyone,
...and that's why the local gangs
supported me.
But you do nothing honestly.
It's always something dishonest.
Look at your daughter-in-law.
And at your brother.
And you, Wen-leung.
Have you fulfilled
your obligations?
Everything was clear at the beginning.
Who'd have known they'd done this.
Didn't you speak to them about it?
Of course.
Let's gather everyone together
and clarify the issues.
Ah-chuan,
...go tell your boss
I want to see him.
This is disagreeable!
Ah-ga, where are those fellows
from Shanghai?
I haven't seen them.
Damn it!
It's Wen-leung again.
As if we didn't have
enough problems.
I don't know what to say.
Leave me here.
How are you?
Where is your boss?
He went out.
Mrs Ah-Kio.
Take a seat please.
You honour me by coming
to see me.
It gives me hope.
There's nothing that
can't be repaired.
Everyone knows what
times we live in.
You all grew up together.
You shouldn't be
at odds over this.
Our Kim-tsua began this,
so he's at fault.
But the whole incident...
...began with the return of Red Monkey's
Japanese money in Chiu-fen.
Kim-tsua says...
...that Red Monkey was planning to cheat him,
...and so he went to see him.
Red Monkey didn't want
to return the money.
That's how it all began.
Kim-tsua had a woman he liked there.
Maybe Kim-tsua was
in the wrong, but...
...he would never lie to me.
Red Monkey is dead,
...and so can't give his
version of the story.
This fighting and squabbling
must end!
Have some tea.
This entire conversation
makes no sense.
The most important thing is to
take care of the money.
I think it must be
split three ways.
One part for your brother,
...one for Kim-tsua...
...and one for Red Monkey's
old mother.
Yesterday I went to Wen-ching's house,
...and so I didn't write in my diary.
Wen-sun's wife
told me things...
...about Wen-ching's childhood.
Of the brothers, Wen-sun
studied the most,
...but Wen-ching was
the most intelligent.
He said his physical problems were due
to the gods being jealous.
Wen-sun disappeared...
...in the Philippines.
His family don't think he'll return,
...but his wife cleans...
...his clinic every day.
Every day she disinfects...
...the needles and syringes.
She thinks he's still alive...
...and that he'll come home one day.
Then everything will
be as it was.
He'll look after his patients,
...write prescriptions, do injections,
...listen to music...
to Beethoven.
Brother.
Who's down below?
Soldiers from the mainland.
Get away.
What do they want with me?
Hurry up and get out.
What's going on?
They have come for Wen-heung.
They have come for us.
Go back to bed!
This is breaking and entering.
Search for him.
They told us your son
was a collaborator.
My son, a collaborator?
Somebody denounced him.
And that makes him a traitor?
We have to take him in for interrogation
to find out the truth.
Do you eat fish all day?
What kind of mayor are you?
It's not easy for us.
Then you'll never find out
the truth.
Someone denounced him.
If that makes you a collaborator,
...then I'm a gangster.
I went in and out of prison
during the Japanese occupation.
You have to find out the truth.
How does that make him
a traitor?
We'll investigate.
Investigate? What does that mean?
If he's a traitor,
then we all are!
We'll make a full
investigation.
My son and I are gangsters,
...I admit it.
But only for the good of
the entire district.
So as not to be intimidated
by the Japanese.
If that's being a collaborator,
...then you are one too.
Officer, the man who denounced him
is the collaborator.
You can't arrest everyone
who is denounced.
Who are you kidding?
Wen-leung!
"Dear uncle:
...yesterday soldiers arrested
Wen-leung.
They also went to the office
to arrest father...
...but he escaped,
and only injured a leg.
They say someone denounced
Wen-leung...
...and said he was
a collaborator.
They say he helped the Japanese...
...capture many people in Shanghai.
Even if were true, they must
have forced him to do it.
Mother says you have friends
in Taipei.
Do you know anyone who might be able
to secure his freedom?
We have money.
Please help us and get in touch
with us as soon as possible.
Ah-shue".
I know.
Are you looking for Mr Chen,
the town councillor?
It doesn't matter. We need your help.
Why does it have to be like this?
It's OK. If that's how you think,
forget it.
I'll prepare it.
I know. Someone will deliver it.
Mum.
We have guests.
I'm coming.
They'll free him?
They'll free Wen-leung?
Not yet, but I think it will turn out well.
Why haven't they released him?
Friends in Taipei have made
enquiries. Nanking says...
...that charges against Taiwanese
of collaboration will be withdrawn.
So I don't think there'll
be any problems.
But first they have to
announce...
...the new regulations.
You must help us!
Calm down.
Maybe friends in Taipei will be able...
...to obtain his release earlier.
Please, call your brother.
ÉHe'll know what to do.
Right.
Get me Taipei 24.
Please, do all you can.
Thanks, thanks.
And?
They say the law on collaboration
is going to be changed.
Damn.
They make laws, and they change laws.
This island is in a bad way.
First the Japanese,
then the Chinese.
They all exploit us and
no one gives a damn.
- What's going on?
- It's urgent.
OK, we'll talk later.
Brother.
Sit down.
Sit down, please.
I am sorry to trouble you...
...while you are enjoying yourselves.
My brother has been arrested
and imprisoned.
You know people
in power.
I need your help.
Can you arrange for him to be
set free for New Year?
Wen-heung is sorry to bother you,
...but his brother has been arrested.
He'd like your help so he
can be released for New Year.
They want Wen-leung...
...to be released before New Year.
When did they arrest him?
I knew nothing of this.
I didn't know either.
They didn't know Wen-leung
had been arrested.
How can we help?
Hippocrites! It's all your fault!
Shut up!
Idiot!
Can't you keep
your mouth shut?
Tell them...
...that I know what to do.
It's all fixed.
He says he knows
the rules.
It's all there.
He's back!
Put him down here.
Wen-leung!
Bring medicines,
...a container and a spoon!
Wen-leung,
...how could they have beat you like that?
Hurry, fetch a doctor!
Calm down.
Crying won't help.
Bring water.
Am I talking to the clinic?
Is the doctor there?
Please, hurry up.
Open your mouth.
Why is there so much blood?
He was OK in the car.
The vibrations must have made
him lose blood.
Damn.
Did you call?
Yes.
I'll call again.
Open your mouth.
Get me the Hui-an Clinic.
Tell him it's urgent!
OK!
Is that the clinic?
I'm calling from "Little Shanghai".
Is the doctor on his way?
I don't know why,
...but I have had a lot of
bad dreams lately.
They were about dad...
...tying me to a telegraph
pole when I was a boy.
Did you boil the water?
Yes.
I remember.
It was just before New Year.
When my father was young,
he loved gambling.
We had no money and mum...
...took out a gold necklace...
...and asked dad
to pawn it.
My mother was afraid that dad...
...would gamble away the money
and sent me with him.
As soon as my father had the
money in his hand,
...he persuaded me to stand
next to a telegraph pole.
He then tied me to it with his belt
and went off to bet.
It was December and
very cold.
No one went by.
It was almost 9 before someone...
...saw me and untied me.
I almost died of the cold.
After that, whenever
mum asked me...
...to go with dad, I refused.
Citizens of Taiwan:
On the night of the 27th, during
an investigation in Taipei,
...unfortunately
someone was killed.
I have already take the matter...
...in my own hands.
The people who killed others
during this incident...
...have already been brough to court
to be judged...
....and punished.
We have ordered medical attention...
...for a woman with light wounds.
I have asked for her to be treated
And I have given her money
for the sake of her tranquility.
We have to leave for Taipei.
Today, the radio spoke of
riots in Taipei...
...between Taiwanese
and mainlanders.
Taiwan is under martial law.
In the hospital we are
all scared.
One war has just ended.
Is another about to begin?
My brother came to see me.
He is going to Taipei with Wen-ching.
But this time...
...it's very dangerous to go there.
They have urgent
business there.
I'm very worried but
dare not say anything.
Wen-ching with his disability...
...you have to look after him, brother.
Where?
Death to the mainlanders!
Halt, this is a hospital.
Hurry, take him in.
This is a hospital, you can't make
a disturbance.
Get out of here.
Citizens of Taiwan:
Yesterday measures were announced...
...to control disorder,
...and I hope they were
heard and understood.
Now, to restore...
...calm and order quickly,
...I am issuing more merciful measures.
They are as follows:
First, regarding those involved...
...the government will not go ahead...
...and punish them.
Second, those arrested...
...for taking part in the disorder,
...will be set free.
They'll be taken to police
headquarters...
...where their families will be able to come by
and look for them.
To make things simpler,
...mayors will issue no guarantees.
Third, the wounded
and the dead...
...whatever their jobs,
...whether Taiwanese or mainlanders,
...will receive medical attention or
appropriate compensation.
Fourth, a special committee...
...will be set up.
It will consist of
representatives of the government,
...the judicial and
municipal authorities.
It will also include
members of the public...
...with the aim of reflecting
true public opinion.
What are you doing here?
And my brother?
Doctor! Come quickly!
Citizens of Taiwan:
Yesterday saw the temporary
reintroduction of martial law.
I want to assure all those of you
who love peace,
...that this decree is...
...for your protection.
Take no notice of rumours
about spies,
...because suspicion
leads to fear.
I assure all
citizens...
... who obey the law,
that nothing will happen to them.
Meanwhile, I am announcing
the reintroduction of martial law.
Our objective is merely to punish
rebels and traitors.
For every day they are
at large,
...peaceloving people will have
to put up with another day of disorder.
Hinoe is safe.
She asked me to come first.
Mr Lin, the teacher, is
in the special committeel.
Many in Taipei died.
People are frightened.
Dead?
Where are you from?
Where are you going?
I am... Taiwanese.
Are you from Japan?
Must be a mainlander.
What are you doing?
He is deaf.
He can't hear
what you are saying.
Wen-ching.
What's the matter, brother?
Is it fractured?
I don't know.
Lin has disappeared.
They've arrested everyone
in the special committee.
The troops of Chen Yi...
...are killing and arresting people.
Your son has come back, ma'am.
You are back!
I was so worried.
Soldiers and police
came here every day.
They were right on the doorstep.
What's wrong with your foot?
Is it serious?
What are you doing? It's good
that he's back!
You can't stay here.
I'll hide you in Lai-Liao.
Hinomi,
...I forbid you to leave the house.
I'll write to the hospital.
On 19th March,
the director of the hospital,
...took all my things.
It was my father's idea.
There was a letter from Ah-shue.
Wen-ching has been arrested.
They say it was for Mr Lin.
Wen-ching's father went around
shouting:
"They are even arresting the deaf. Where
is justice in this world?"
Justice is not important to me.
I only want to know...
...where Wen-ching is.
...if he's alive and well.
Wu Chin-wen, Tai Tung-ho,
to court.
Lin Wen-ching, to court!
Uncle, it's supper time.
Face the world
without shame.
Your father is innocent.
At this time
of difficulty...
I am apart from my loved one...
Uncle,you can't eat that.
You mustn't!
Wen-leung.
Where is Wen-ching?
He went out yesterday and hasn't come back.
And your father?
No idea. He went out this morning.
Ah-shue, where are your parents?
They left this morning.
Dad usually comes home late, drunk.
He staggers and vomits all over the house.
When did your father's club close?
In March.
It was chaotic for a while.
Many people died,
...and the neighborhood was wrecked.
Dad's friend, Mr Ko, was arrested.
Ah-shue!
Aunt Hinomi, uncle has returned.
We waited a long time, but he knew...
...which station exit to take.
Ah-shue,
...look for your brothers.
Take your time and write.
Uncle, you cannot eat that.
It's food for the altar.
You can't eat it.
You are thinner.
Are you OK?
My brother disappeared.
He was hiding in Lai-liao.
One day soldiers came.
Since then, we have had no news.
Wen-ching!
Here comes Mr Huang.
Mr Huang, this is
my good friend Wen-ching.
He was in prison with your brother...
... before he was executed.
He has come especially to see you.
Sit down.
"In life, far from the motherland.
"In death, returning to the motherland.
"Both life and death
are governed by destiny."
Hinoe got married and
lives in the mountains.
I can't tell you where.
She doesn't want her family to know.
She said, "Consider me dead.
My life belongs to the motherland.
"In prison, I swore to live, for the sake of
friends who had died."
I cannot live like before.
I want to stay here.
I know I can do whatever you ask me.
This is no place for you.
What's important are your beliefs,
not where you live or what you do.
They suggested marriage to Hinomi,
but it's you she loves.
Let me introduce my best friend,
Wen-ching.
Are you going to reopen for business or not?
Enough!
Go and play outside
Wen-leung, this is for the altar.
Eat after the prayers.
You decided to close.
Now you won't say
when you'll reopen.
Can't you make up your mind?
Shut up!
Don't argue with me!
Don't drink from the teapot!
You're setting a bad example to the children!
You're too big for such things.
Are you thirsty?
Drink properly or not at all.
Don't be ridiculous.
Look!
You were gone for days,
God knows where!
You either lock yourself in your room
or hide out where...
...nobody can find you.
I wanted you to visit mother's grave
with me. Where were you?
That's why I have such bad luck!
I am the only one of the four children...
...who visits mum's grave.
She asks me why,
...and I don't lack for words.
As for you,
...how long do you think you can go
without working?
I planned to open a photographic studio
on the side so you could run it.
We discussed it enough.
When will you give me an answer?
How can he reply? He can't hear.
Shut up!
The only thing you know
is to tell people off.
Ah-shue,you tell him.
When a young woman visits us,
...without thinking of her dignity,
...it's obvious what's going on.
Don't you understand?
What are you waiting for?
What's all the row?
Stop singing!
Damn it!
Shut up!
What's all this howling?
You are like bad spirits.
What's all the noise?
Why are you shouting?
Can't you talk normally?
What's going on?
It's useless. He seems incapable
of acting normally.
I'm sorry.
Please, carry on singing.
No, thank you.
Take no notice of him.
You sing very well.
Please, carry on.
He's as stubborn as a mule!
People like him
can't be taught anything.
Damn you!
How come you're not dead?
You really made Wen-leung
suffer.
Shame on you!
So?
What's up?
You know what you did.
Shut up or you'll be sorry.
What will you do about it?
What?
Calm down.
You don't scare me.
Pig!
You'll come to a bad end
one of these days.
Older brother!
Ah-ga.
Call a doctor!
What happened?
Kim-tsua, take that knife.
Call a doctor.
Wen-heung!
Here comes the bride.
Let's ask our ancestors...
...for children and wealth.
Bow to the ancestors.
Kneel down.
Pray.
First reverence.
Two.
Three.
Pray.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Pray.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Stand up.
Bow to each other.
Kneel.
Bride and groom, bow
to each other three times.
One.
Two.
Three.
Stand up.
It's late.
I heard the first thunder
of spring.
One clap after another,
...as if waking the hillsides
and the sea.
Someone came from the mountains.
He said my brother
needed money.
He needed it...
...to print pamphlets
to educate people.
The man said they didn't want
to be always asking...
...for help from Weng-ching.
But only when they come
to ask for money,
...do we know that they're safe
and that the struggle continues.
Only then are we satisfied.
Ah-chien can already make sounds.
Last night I thought
he was saying "mummy."
I was so happy.
I hurried to find Wen-ching...
...so he could hear too.
It was only when I saw him I realized
my stupidity. How could he hear?
Prices are rising.
The neighbours say
times will be hard.
Maybe I'm a fool.
But while I have Wen-ching
and Ah-chien...
...I think I'll be happy.
Don't run!
Still running! Shit!
Why are you shouting?
On your knees.
Heads down.
What are you looking at?
Ah-shue, your uncle Wen-ching
has been arrested.
We still don't know where he is.
At first we considered running away,
...but there was nowhere to go
I am writing this long after,
...because only now do I feel
calmer.
This photo was taken three days
before Wen-ching's arrest.
When they came for him,
...he was taking someone's portrait.
He insisted on finishing the job...
...before they took him away.
I searched and asked all over
Taipei but have no news.
Ah-chien has his first teeth.
He has a lovely smile...
and your uncle's eyes.
Please, come and see us soon.
It's fresh in Chiu-fen.
The autumn flowers
are in bloom.
The mountains are all white,
like snow.
It's time to eat.
OK. Just a moment.
Ah-chi,
...you shouldn't be watching
adults gambling.
Bring your uncle.
Uncle, it's time to eat.
Where is Uncle Wan?
He said he'd be back soon.
Wash your hands.
Help yourselves.
December 1949.
Mainland China is lost.
The Nationalist government
moves to Taiwan.
Taipei becomes
provisional capital.