Get to work, will ya?
You'd better do your work.
Don't be lazy!
Get out of here.
A date?
Surfing? Take care.
It looks like it's gonna rain.
Don't worry.
The old lady at the tobacco shop
predicted it.
Look! Is that shigeru?
It's him.
He started surfing.
Hey! Shigeru!
No use. He's deaf.
What if it hits him?
He won't be mad.
- He's gone.
- Where is he?
That one?
That's him!
Let's go. He'll get mad.
Watch out!
He doesn't have a wetsuit!
- It's cold.
- Isn't he cold?
Rather dangerous.
- He almost got it.
- He's not good at all.
Too bad!
He's trying hard.
It's broken.
Poor boy!
- He's not good enough.
- Of course not!
He's dumb!
What is it?
She wants a 25% discount.
What?
Not that much.
Come on!
Here's your pay!
Buy me a drink.
What?
You're a bachelor.
I have three kids to feed.
I can't afford four.
Shigeru!
Yamato!
Treat me.
Thank you.
Free of charge.
Thank you very much.
They came here before.
I could've given him a better price.
At Akira's shop,
they sell for 98,000 yen.
4,200 yen in all.
Give me a discount.
Wholesale prices.
- 4,200 yen.
- Akira sells them cheaper.
Then buy from him.
Not again!
Come to the sea
to coach us sometimes.
I'm busy.
Thank you!
You can't bring your surfboard.
No surfboards when it's crowded.
Sit down, young lady.
They're going to surf again.
Looks like it.
What's so great about it?
What's this for?
It goes around your ankle.
Ankle?
I'm going.
Idiot!
Have some juice.
98,000 yen?
I'll ask him.
Excuse me.
Can we get that one
with i0,000 yen?
It's a 98,000-yen surfboard.
What joke is that?
9,000 yen!
- We can buy it!
- Trash!
You got any?
Five grand.
I got it!
But it's trash.
Good for a start.
I don't have a cent left.
I'm broke, too.
How'il we get home?
You should've kept the bus fare!
This is all?
No one else?
Where's kimura?
Who knows?
They'll be late.
I'm at the back like a girl!
Change positions.
That girl was pretty hot...
What happened...
After that...
It's crowded.
Let's go there.
It's boring without waves.
Sure is.
Here he comes!
He's laughing.
Cheers.
How's business?
Dull. Because you aren't buying.
Too high prices.
Don't blame us.
The waves?
The worst.
We are bored.
How is he?
He comes every day.
He's getting much better.
He's trying hard.
He needs a wetsuit.
- He must be cold.
- Got guts.
He sure has guts.
He's improving his skills.
He must be cold.
Of course.
- Very cold.
- He's almost naked.
Bye then.
- Cold?
- Very cold.
But it's fun.
Really?
But you didn't ride.
Still it was fun.
- I'm tempted.
- Try.
- It's just great.
- Really?
- You'll see.
- It looks cold.
Oh, so cold.
Hi! Use this.
Use this.
Look...
There's a contest at chiba.
Take part in it.
Can't the three of us ride together?
That's the law.
Your driver's license.
Why not let us pass?
Your license!
Give it to me!
I am in a bloody rush.
You bastards.
I'll take you to the police station.
What the hell's wrong with you.
- What heat?
- Second.
- Against who?
- Ishikawa.
I'm in the third.
With okada and nitta.
Crap.
That's tough.
Paddle in.
Don't ride.
The first heat surfers are coming.
Didn't they ride well?
They're coming back.
The results will be announced later.
Uh! Almost.
He did it again!
I should at least
get to the semi-final.
Clumsy.
You can see
who the good surfers are.
Nine minutes gone.
Three minutes to go.
Here's the yellow flag!
- How was it?
- No good.
Why's that?
The waves weren't good at all.
The white surfer was much better.
I wish I was more consistent.
Bad riding from the start.
You give up too soon.
Hang in there.
That was all I could do.
There's some time left.
The surfers can ride again.
Here's the countdown.
Time's up.
- I'll be going.
- Good luck!
Stay on board.
I'm better than you.
Who's talking? He means it!
Prove it.
Good luck!
You wait and see!
Judge at pointa, stand by.
Okay?
Judge at point b?
Stand by for the next heat.
Here we go!
He's giving us
a real demonstration of how to ride!
Roller-coaster.
He can really ride the white water.
He's doing really great!
You're first up.
You're the best.
Riding up the wave curve.
Kicking up spray.
He's trimming to the inside.
Now he sinks into the wave.
I wish him success.
Some fine surfers today!
Look at how fast
the white surfer's going!
Flip and then into a roller coaster.
That was superb.
He's bound to get good marks.
Hello.
You're late.
The contest is over.
- How was it?
- I came in second.
Was he here? The deaf boy?
Yes, but...
He didn't hear his name called.
He missed it.
Why didn't you take care of him?
Peel it for me.
Thank you.
Shigeru doesn't
come to work anymore.
He's crazy about surfing.
Tell him to come back.
It's his job.
I'm sorry.
Or he'll be fired.
Lower your waist.
Very good.
Isn't she coming?
What are you doing?
Please stop it.
Really I said stop it!
Shigeru!
Idiot!
Don't lose your job!
Let's go.
Come on!
I bought the surfboard.
Get real. Hey.Hey.
Rock, paper, scissors.
Let me wear it.
No it's my turn.
Only for a moment.
You're selfish.
Wait, wait, wait...
Get real, I said.
- I'm wearing it.
- I'm cold. Please let me wear it.
Ouch... cramp.
It's not comfortable.
It's back to front.
Never mind. See you.
- Chief.
- Yes.
Let shigeru take
a day off tomorrow.
Why?
There's a surfing contest.
You'll have no assistant.
Is it okay?
I can do it alone.
If it's okay with you...
Is it okay?
Here he comes. He won last time.
So he'll probably win again today.
No problem I will win.
All of you.
You idiot.
He's too good.
I can't find my name.
We didn't apply.
Why are we here, then?
We have
200 participants here today.
So it'll be a fine contest.
Let's hope there won't be
any accidents...
And that everybody
enjoys themselves.
Good luck to you all!
Thank you very much.
Now the president of the jury
will speak.
President ito
will explain the rules.
Good morning, everyone.
The weather conditions are not bad.
But there might be
some problems with the wind.
Nevertheless, I hope
you'll give us a good show.
The judges are all
authorised judges.
And we will be sticking to
NSA rules.
Chikura surf classics '9i.
Second heat now beginning.
Point a, ready?
Point b, ready? Okay.
Point c, ready? Okay.
Pointa is for special class.
The experts compete here.
Point b is for class a.
And point c is for class b.
Surfers at pointa
are the most impressive to watch.
It's a real pleasure to have a
surfing contest in such fine weather.
The waves are good, too.
Everything is perfect for surfing!
Can we apply now?
Impossible.
- How was it?
- Lousy.
You were terrible.
That bad?
You weren't riding at all.
I fell off. What a drag!
Losen
shigeru! It's your turn!
You could've told him!
He's good.
- He is better than you.
- Thanks for pointing that out.
He's really good...
- But he's way better than me.
- Maybe you'll win.
- I can.
- Don't talk rubbish.
Shigeru.
You did it!
And us?
You, too.
Oh, of course.
- Well done.
- And you.
You failed.
I'm way off.
There are six judges.
The head judge and two others
marked you down for obstruction.
So you lost points.
I was faster.
You saw them on the water.
We saw you from our base.
Now, class b finals!
Stand up
for your final performance!
Ride hard!
Judges, stand by.
Class b final heat!
Look at that superb roller-coaster.
It's okay.
Yellow tabard begins his run.
His cut back is not good enough. If
he could only stay calm he'll score well.
Let's see what
the next surfers can do!
He succeed the blow.
Class b final heat.
So now the green tabard turns.
Oh great.
Keel down.
I hope he succeeds with the last
roller coaster. What will be the result?
They're not bad at all
for class b surfers!
The waves keep coming.
Who's next?
Now the red tabard comes from the rear.
Takes off down the wave.
He performed well.
Good riding red tabard.
Again he goes for it.
He finishes on a roller coaster.
I wish him success.
Oh wow the green tabard
makes a break for it.
Take off.
Ok the last wave.
Red take off.
Next time, make sure we apply.
I'll buy a surfboard, too.
Contenders in the class b finals!
A big hand for them!
Congratulations!
Next, class a finalists,
step up on the platform.
Next, special class finalists,
A big hand for them.
Fourth, tatsuya matsumoto!
Third, kaku sawai.
A big hand!
There's your trophy and souvenir.
Two more. Who will be the winner?
Second, toshimitsu kamijo!
A big hand for him.
Take the trophy and souvenir.
The special class winner
is kazuyuki chiba!
A big hand for him!
Four special class finalists!
A big hand once again!
Thank you.
Say cheese!
Eat up. Let's go.
A scene at the sea
Written and edited by takeshi kitano
produced by masayuki nor!
And takio yoshida
musiczjoe hisaishi
cinematographer:
Katsumi yanagishima
lighting: Hitoshi takaya
art director: Osamu sasaki
sound recording: Senji horiuchi
Starring: Kurodo maki as shigeru
hiroko ooshima as takako
Directed by takeshi kitano
 