BLACK ORPHEUS
Serafina, look what a beauty!
Forgive me.
Please forgive me.
You really scared me.
You're trembling, poor thing.
I can feel your heart beat
here in your hand
like a caged bird.
Let me give you something
to help you forget.
Here.
I don't know if it's very pretty.
Oh, but it is.
Thank you very much.
I can help you,
if you don't mind.
But I can't guide you too far.
I don't know Rio.
I'll manage.
I know this city
like the palm of my hand.
I can even give you directions,
if you wish.
Let's go.
Onions, onions.
Wanna buy a steak?
What a beauty!
Come walk with me, pretty girl.
The biggest necklaces around!
Who wants to buy a necklace?
Hey there, climb aboard!
This is how our love will be
Me for you and you for me
I've had enough of sadness
I'll make you happy
I want to live in peace
Hermes!
All done, Orfeu?
Gonna get your paycheck?
Hey, what are you doing?
They said to go
to the end of the line.
Well? You're looking at it.
Thank you.
- You're not from around here?
- No.
- Where are you going?
- My cousin's house.
Well, that's okay then.
Hermes, come help this girl.
She's looking for her cousin.
He'll find her for you.
He can find anything.
I gotta go get my paycheck.
One more for your collection, eh?
Cute gal.
- Just some silly girl.
- Yeah, I know you.
- Better watch out. Mira's around.
- Orfeu!
What did I tell you?
Sorry to break up your little party.
You telling her fortune?
- Why not?
- Don't bother.
With her looks,
she'll never get lucky.
And a show-off like you
doesn't deserve to get lucky.
You coming?
She's crazy.
Have you been to Carnival?
- No.
You've never been?
Is that why you've come to Rio?
- No.
You'll see.
You'll end up going.
No one can resist the madness.
Now look here.
You can't go wrong.
Just follow that path
and you'll get there.
- Thank you very much.
- My name is Hermes.
If you get lost again,
come back and see me.
I'm always here.
I'm the station guard.
Thanks.
I'll be back someday.
You're loaded!
Hand it over!
Let me see!
Did you get directions?
Yes, thanks.
- Do you know her?
- No.
- Then why all the fuss?
- 'Cause I'm a nice guy.
- A nice guy.
- Cute, isn't she?
- And I'm not? Let's go.
- Where?
Where?
You hear that, Hermes?
He has the nerve to ask where.
Did you forget
we're getting a marriage license?
Pay attention, man.
- What eyes she has.
And I have the memory
of an elephant, you know?
I know.
Hey, pass it here!
That's enough.
- Where's Court No. 5, please?
- Upstairs, second door on the right.
- Take off that cap.
- Why?
And fix your tie.
What a mess.
Let me fix your tie.
Now give me a kiss.
- People are coming.
Come on.
Marriage licenses?
I'm sorry!
This is for tomorrow.
Well, we want a license today.
We're getting married.
Are you sure?
- Of course.
- Sorry. I was just kidding.
I say that because
everybody comes here to get married.
It's a funny line!
Give me your names.
Let's start with yours.
Orfeu.
Then of course the bride
must be Eurídice.
What? My name's not Eurídice.
Why do you say that?
"Orpheus loves Eurydice."
Everyone knows that.
Do you love some girl
named Eurídice?
I don't know any Eurídice.
What is this?
Nothing.
Just an old story.
I was being funny.
It wasn't funny at all.
Not another word
about some old stories, you hear?
That's enough.
My name is Mira.
Mira, let's go!
Happy now?
You got what you wanted.
- You gonna buy the ring now?
- What ring?
We're engaged now.
You have to give me a ring.
- With what money?
- I saw your paycheck. Let's go!
You won't do it?
I've gotta get my guitar out of hock.
Tomorrow is Carnival.
A ring.
Buy your own ring.
- No, you have to give me one!
- I said I have no money!
- I can loan you some.
- All right.
But you have to get me a ring.
Come on!
Now what?
First my guitar.
104.
310.
102.
340.
350.
Orfeu.
You're gonna look like a king!
I am a king.
Sorry, but those crooks
aren't interested in this.
Hold it a minute.
It works great.
A museum would pay a lot more
than 100 cruzeiros for this.
Quiet, everyone!
Just 100 cruzeiros.
- I'm on to you.
I just need 100 cruzeiros for Carnival,
but they won't give it to me.
Here are 100 cruzeiros.
Now take this thing back!
- A hundred cruzeiros! Great!
- Take this damn thing away!
No, it's yours now.
Hold on.
The rest is yours!
You think it's funny, huh?
You got a good deal.
- Hold this piece of junk.
- Wait a minute.
Take this.
Don't get mad, all right?
Isn't it a beauty?
- It is pretty.
- But you owe me 110 bucks.
- What?
- 110 bucks.
Sad, little birdie?
Hasn't he come yet?
But he will.
Sing, bird, sing.
Serafina, some bread?
Thanks, but I spent
everything on my costume.
Chico!
Oh, it's you.
Good morning.
Come in.
This is all I need.
I thought it was him.
- Who?
- Chico Boto.
That's right —
you don't know him.
Look how handsome.
He's always on the road.
But he promised
to be here for Carnival.
- Your husband?
- No, why?
We just like each other.
And I'm all his.
You should see
the chest on this man.
But that doesn't mean
I'm not happy to see you.
Actually, since he's not here,
it works out great.
Let me guess —
you came for Carnival.
- I ran away.
- Ran away?
- I'm scared, Serafina.
- What's all this about?
Scared of what... or whom?
A man who came to the farm
and kept chasing after me.
Because you're pretty, silly.
No. I'm sure he wants to kill me.
Are you crazy?
He just wants
to get into your pants.
No, he means to kill me.
I know he does.
"I know, I know."
Tell me:
Does he know you're here?
Then put it out of your mind.
Come, you must be starving.
All I have is onions.
You got any money?
Never mind. I only ask
'cause my costume cost a fortune.
But the Portuguese grocer
will do anything for a kiss.
You really are pretty,
you know that?
Good trick.
Hello there, Benedito.
How are you?
Is that amulet for me?
No, it's for her.
You don't even know her.
But I'm going to.
Would you like this?
- Thank you, Benedito.
- You already know my name?
My name's Eurídice.
I'll keep this forever.
Even after I die?
Enough nonsense.
Run along now.
That boy has some strange ideas.
Come on.
Now give me a kiss.
- Just one!
- And for you?
Some fish.
Whoever that is,
she's gonna hit me up for credit.
Exactly. And with a new
customer like me — sassy and broke.
You'll give us a deal, won't you?
My little dumpling,
just once more, please.
Another customer for credit!
At least nobody owes me anything.
There. That should hold you
for a while.
- Much better. What about her?
- Of course.
Let's have a kiss.
Poor thing's
not used to this yet.
How 'bout a kiss from you?
Forget it.
I'd rather pay.
That's too bad, since her man —
But I better shut up.
Some women
are smarter than you.
- I don't care. That's all just talk.
- Everybody knows.
- What about you?
- Me?
If he's really getting married,
then poor guy.
- Actually, here they come now.
- Both of them?
Take anything you want.
Is everybody crazy?
I'm coming!
Isn't this beautiful?
- You're not going to see him?
- Who?
- "Who?"
- She doesn't know him yet.
But when she does,
she'll run even faster than the others.
You taking those?
- Forget it. They're still green.
Of course they're green.
You waiting for red chayotes?
It can't be. Poor baby.
Are you really getting hitched?
It's really gone to her head.
Shall I take your little fiancée
off your hands for a while?
May I?
- How did you do it?
- He kept insisting.
I'm so happy!
- You're choking me!
- I'm so happy! Give me a hug!
- What's going on?
- Oh, it's you. Nothing.
I gotta tune my guitar
for rehearsal.
- Orfeu.
- Later, later...
He doesn't want you.
Didn't I tell you?
- Idiot.
- You're the idiot.
- My costume's great!
- I like mine better.
It's so pretty.
- Where's Orfeu?
- Did he leave?
That's right.
He said he'd see us at rehearsal.
What? He could have
at least told me.
The poor thing's so excited,
you know.
Let me see your ring again.
What a beauty. Is it real?
Practically.
Isn't it pretty?
Orfeu, don't I look great?
Yeah. See you at rehearsal.
How's everybody?
How are you, Caruso?
Always cuddling, huh?
- Ask him.
- No, you ask.
I wanted to ask you something.
Can you really make the sun rise
just by playing your guitar?
- Of course I can.
- Didn't I tell you?
Could you make
the sun rise tomorrow?
Sure. Especially
since tomorrow is Carnival.
What do you play to do that?
I make something up.
Could you do that?
I think I could make up a melody.
Man, I'd love to make the sun rise.
Lend him your guitar.
Just to see.
Look here.
This guitar is very old.
- "Orfeu is my master."
- It's true.
There was an Orpheus before me,
and there may be another
after I'm gone,
but for now I'm the boss.
Understand?
Don't be sad.
If you promise not to tell,
I'll play you the new song
I just wrote.
Pretty, isn't it?
The dawn of a beautiful morn
A new song is born
It sings of your eyes
Of your laughter and your hands
One day you will come to me
From the strings of my guitar
That seeks only your love
A voice comes forth
That speaks of kisses
Lost on your lips
My heart sings
with newfound happiness
At the dawning of this new love
- What are you doing here?
- I have every right!
- Take the guitar! You didn't see me!
- Okay!
- Isn't he here?
- Who?
Was that you playing?
Orfeu taught me.
Where is he?
He just left with some woman.
What?
Now that you've got the guitar,
play something.
He'll hear me.
Even better. Play.
You again?
What are you doing here?
Ah, you didn't tell me
your cousin was Serafina.
Then we're already close friends.
What's your name?
Don't you remember?
I'm Eurídice.
Amazing!
No wonder I liked you right away.
"Orpheus likes Eurydice,"
as the story goes.
Are you Orpheus?
From head to toe.
Well... I don't like you.
Yes, you do.
Try to remember.
It's a very old story.
Thousands of years ago,
Orpheus was sad
and melancholic,
like this little bird
trapped in its cage.
But one day,
from the strings of his guitar
that sought only one true love,
a voice spoke to him of lost kisses
from the lips of Eurydice.
Eurydice's lips
trembled anxiously,
and her mouth opened slightly
like a fragrant flower —
No, you're too young
to remember.
But I do.
I remember
the words you sang.
- They were the same words.
- That's right.
But it was the melody
I liked best.
Forgive me, Eurídice.
Look.
It's them.
I need to talk to him.
No, leave them alone.
They're waiting
for you at rehearsal!
All right.
I have to go.
I know.
I'll sing and dance for you.
Will you be there?
- Yes.
Take good care of her.
Let's go.
See you later.
Thanks.
Why aren't you paying
attention to me?
I have no time for that now.
- Answer me!
- Get back to your place!
This is how our love will be
Me for you and you for me
Excuse us.
He already saw you.
He's the sun.
Look at Serafina.
She's the Queen of the Night.
Look how happy she is.
And who's she?
That's Mira.
She's the Queen of the Day.
Pretty, isn't she?
- Yes.
She's Orfeu's fiancée.
Look, he's going to kiss her.
- That's enough now!
- What's so funny?
- Nothing! That's enough!
- Why didn't you kiss me?
Leave me alone.
Have you tried on your costumes?
Oh, right. Mira's costume
is a beauty, isn't it?
It has embroidered sleeves.
Let's go see it.
Come and dance, Eurídice!
Come on!
- And who's this?
- Ask Orfeu.
- I want a costume for her, okay?
- All right.
No one dances
with the ladies like you do.
Leave me alone.
Such a pretty girl.
- Better than Mira, isn't she?
- Much better.
- Smooth operator.
- Stop babbling.
- He has good taste.
- Stop it.
- What's wrong with it?
- Where's her costume?
This is all we have.
A body like this
doesn't need a costume.
Wait. I'll look next door.
- That's right — Mira.
- What about her?
Oh, nothing.
You don't waste any time,
do you?
May I introduce my cousin?
Be good now.
Take care of her.
I want a pretty costume for her.
- Oh, you...
- I'm serious.
You don't even know her.
Yes, I do.
Look at me.
Oh, my!
Don't look like that.
It's no big deal.
Leave the girl to me.
I'll take care of her.
- I'll help.
- It's about time.
Don't just stand there.
Get going.
Hurry up now.
I'll take care of her.
- Orfeu, is Eurídice here?
- Yes. Why?
Eurídice,
someone's looking for you.
- Who?
- Some man.
- Who is he?
- I don't know. He's not from around here.
Don't be afraid, sweetie.
Tell him she's gone.
What are you waiting for?
Calm down.
It's him.
Calm down!
There's nothing to be afraid of!
Take care of her!
- What happened?
- My cousin Eurídice's frightened.
- Her name's Eurídice?
- Something wrong with that?
Orfeu!
What happened, Benedito?
I tried to catch him,
but he threw me to the ground.
- Where did he go?
- I don't know. That way.
Impossible.
There's a cliff there.
- The man ran that way.
- That way?
What's wrong with him?
Take care of him.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
Who's this Eurídice?
Did you two have an affair?
- Let me by!
- Stay here!
If you go...
Did you chase him away?
Serafina!
Eurídice!
Is that you?
Serafina, answer me!
Eurídice!
Where are you?
Idiot! You scared me!
That's a good one.
I'm the one who scared you?
- Where's my cousin?
- Your cousin?
Yes, my cousin.
Ah, that was your cousin?
- You scared her too, right?
- Who, me?
Fine.
I have to find her.
Hold it.
I came from Montevideo
just to see you.
She'll find her way.
- Where's Eurídice?
- He saw her, but she ran off.
Where?
Answer, man.
I don't know. That way.
He'll find her.
Chico!
My love!
- You're suffocating me!
No! He'll kill you!
Take care of her.
I'm not in any hurry.
We'll meet again later.
So long.
You're in my arms, Eurídice.
I'll protect you always,
from everything.
I care for you, Eurídice.
You'll never be frightened again.
Chico Boto showed up.
You want to stay here?
Yes.
You needn't be frightened here.
Look here.
They're great.
This guy here will protect you too.
He's a real beast.
And then...
there's me.
- Let go!
- Orfeu, is that you?
I swear I heard talking.
Didn't you?
- It was the dog.
- Talking?
No. But so what?
Gimme.
- She's in good hands.
- Who?
- My cousin.
- Didn't she run off?
Dummy. Open your mouth
and close your eyes.
Wider.
The dog tore
one of the little animals.
They're not animals.
They're the signs of the zodiac.
It's beautiful.
This is where I was born.
My house in the heavens.
A baby sheep?
I'll take the one next door,
so I'll always be near you.
Would you like that?
Good night.
I'll sleep outside.
I'll be closer to my house
in the heavens...
and yours.
Good night, Eurídice.
One... two... three...
- What a ruckus.
- I hope we can get some sleep.
Come here.
Come on.
Got you!
You haven't got me yet!
Come here, Serafina.
No, you come catch me.
I can't.
I'll get you!
Did I hurt you?
Poor thing.
Does it still hurt?
No, it's better now.
Wait.
I won, didn't I?
You always win.
Zeca!
Let's go. It's time.
Hurry.
All right, I'm coming.
It's too early to be up, boy.
Let us sleep in peace.
Close that door.
- Yes, Grandma.
Let's go! We're late!
What are those devils
doing at this hour?
Quiet, Caruso.
He won't find it.
We better tell him.
You're crazy.
Come on, let's watch.
What if he's asleep?
I'll knock on the door.
What did I tell you?
My happiness is dreaming
Deep within
my sweetheart's eyes
It's like this night
passing swiftly by
In search of the dawn
Speak softly, please
So she'll wake up happy
Look! It's rising!
Offering up kisses of love
It's true.
Sadness has no end
But happiness does
Happiness is like a dewdrop
On a flower petal
It shines bright and still
Then quivers lightly
And falls like a lover's tear
Serafina,
aren't you in costume yet?
No, Chico's here,
and he's always hungry!
You look beautiful!
- Wait, let me get Orfeu!
No, I'm in a hurry.
I'll run on ahead.
Thanks.
- Are you getting married today?
- Orfeu must have forgot.
Why? Didn't he invite you?
Eurídice!
So there you two are.
Quick,
get your costume on.
No, not that way!
Come this way!
- In a hurry, aren't we?
- Mira's coming.
So let her come.
Come on.
Aren't you ready yet?
- I'm in no hurry.
- Is he crazy?
Orfeu, you promised me —
I'll keep your scarf.
God, he's acting silly.
What did you do to him?
You're up.
At least say good morning.
- Who's this?
- My cousin.
Your cousin?
Don't start that again.
Go back to sleep.
- I'm hungry.
- Wait.
Always hungry.
Eat and stop bothering me.
God help me.
But what can I do?
I like him.
It happens to everybody.
You're the living proof.
Wow.
It looks great on you.
What am I supposed to drink?
Here. Now don't let me
see your face again.
- Nice costume.
- It was Orfeu's idea.
- Lucky you.
- Me?
Carnival's very nice, child,
but Chico leaves again tomorrow.
Button that.
I'd rather fool around with him.
- And I'd rather dance with Orfeu.
Orfeu, open the door!
What a fix.
Say, what if you were
to dance in my place?
Yes! That's it!
- Orfeu, open the door.
- I'm coming.
What are you doing?
Can't you see?
Do I look pretty?
- Yes.
- What's the matter?
You could at least look.
You have a sore throat?
Do you?
- Listen, Mira —
Is this new?
Looks cheap.
What are these little animals?
They're not animals.
They're signs of the zodiac.
Signs of the zodiac —
you don't say.
And the girl next door took you
to heaven last night, right?
Answer me.
Here's what I think
of that bitch's dirty rag!
I'll show you!
It's her, isn't it?
- Shut up!
- Afraid she'll hear?
Listen, if I see her with you again,
I'll kill her!
We came to help you
carry the sun.
I'll wait for you outside.
Here, take my tambourine.
You look so pretty.
- Who was that shouting next door?
- Oh, nobody.
- Mira?
- Seems you already know.
Orfeu told me everything.
He promised to talk to her.
- I understand.
- Serafina, are you coming?
- I'll be right there!
She's gonna be furious
if she finds out.
Quick, pull your veil down.
- Now?
Yes, or Mira will think
I've been playing tricks on her.
She can be really mean.
I'm coming!
Chico, wake up and give
my cousin a kiss, quick!
- Your cousin?
- Yes!
- That's her!
- You win the prize for smarts.
She's me now, so kiss her
like it was me, okay?
- Kiss her?
- Yes!
Not here! At the door!
I'm coming!
Kiss her. Hard.
That's enough!
Say something to her.
- Like what?
- What do you mean, what?
What? What? What?
I don't even know your cousin.
Look at Serafina's costume.
With all that veil,
you can't see her face.
Trust me:
It's better that way!
Orfeu, you gonna
stand there forever?
Let's go.
Run and ask Serafina
if Eurídice is coming.
Serafina, Orfeu wants to know
if Eurídice's coming.
Why do you have her amulet?
- Is it a secret?
- Yes, and only Orfeu can know.
I'll run and tell him
to wait for you.
Your attention, please.
Here comes the best!
The Portela samba school!
Zeca!
Ah, it's you. Come on.
Let's help hold the rope.
Didn't even notice, did you?
- What?
- I don't know. Look at Serafina.
- I love you.
- And I love you, Orfeu.
Let's go!
It's our turn!
Here comes
the United Babylon samba school!
This is how our love will be
Me for you and you for me
- Do you love me?
- Dance in your spot!
Answer me!
I meant to explain earlier.
Now it's too late. Go!
- Where's your cousin?
- She's there and I'm here.
How dare you!
Buy your own!
Zeca, look. Death.
That's just some guy in a mask.
Look!
My amulet!
Eurídice!
Careful, Benedito!
Grab it!
Your attention, please!
Will Orfeu,
representative of United Babylon,
please come to the jury stand.
Why did you choose Serafina
to dance with you?
Not now.
The jury's calling me.
Lourdes, come with me.
Orfeu, please report
to the jury stand.
We have to help Eurídice!
Thank you.
This belongs to everyone. Look.
I'll kill you!
Idiot!
Your attention, please!
Here comes
the Mangueira school!
Eurídice!
- Hermes!
- What's wrong, child? Calm down.
He's going to kill me.
Stop crying! Come on.
Go to my house.
You'll be safe there.
I'll tell Orfeu.
- No! I'm so scared.
Calm down, child.
I'll find him for you.
You know the way.
Go, my child.
Don't worry. Go on.
I'll tell Orfeu right away.
Go!
Eurídice, where are you?
She's mine now.
It's okay. It's nothing.
- It's over, Orfeu.
- Eurídice.
She's dead.
No! I must see Eurídice.
You can only see her dead.
They just sent her
to the morgue.
No, she's alive.
I'm going to find her.
It's true, Orfeu. Wait!
May I go?
- Yes.
Orfeu, wait!
- They all react like that at first.
- No.
They loved each other.
It was true love.
True love?
Is there such a thing?
There is.
Orfeu, wait for me!
I'd like some information.
Are you family?
If not, you can't stay here.
This is off-limits.
You can't come in.
Eurídice!
Stop!
You can't go up there!
Get out of here.
It went up.
Stop!
What do you want?
What are you doing here?
- Nothing.
- Then please leave.
You can't be here,
and we don't have time.
Don't be sad, Orfeu.
The party's over.
Party's over.
Hold this one.
What do you want?
- Hey, I know this guy.
Aren't you Orfeu
of the Babylon school?
He's incredible.
A great singer.
Sing that song of yours.
How did it go?
Sing, man.
What's your problem?
- I'm looking for a missing person.
- That's not here.
These are just brawlers.
Missing Persons is in Precinct 12.
- Where's that?
- I'll show you. Come on.
Show me that step you did.
You know, that one that —
Like this.
Okay, get out of here.
That door over there.
Beat it, kid!
Scram!
Anybody there?
What are you looking for,
brother?
The Missing Persons department.
There is such a department,
but I never saw
any missing persons there.
Just mountains of paper.
Missing Persons is right here.
See? There's no one there.
Just piles of paper.
The whole place is full of it.
Fifteen floors of paper.
All for nothing.
Can you read?
- Yes.
- I can't.
Look around if you like.
But you won't find any missing persons
among those papers.
On the contrary.
That's where they go missing.
Are you in pain, my brother?
I lost Eurídice.
It's as if she were burning
inside my heart.
Keep calling to her.
She'll come.
I've been calling to her.
Your voice alone
isn't strong enough,
and these papers
can't answer you back.
You think these papers
care about anybody?
Come, my brother.
I know where to take you.
Let's go.
Besides,
whether I sweep or not,
the paper keeps piling up.
Come, Orfeu.
Quiet!
Calm down, Cerberus.
That's right.
She received the spirit.
Call to her.
Sing, Orfeu.
Go on. Sing.
No, you mustn't
look back, Orfeu,
or you'll never see me again.
Where are you, Eurídice?
I'm getting closer, Orfeu.
Do you love me enough
to hear my voice but not see me?
I love you, Eurídice,
but I want to see you.
My arms are empty.
I want to see you
and hold you close —
No! You'll lose me forever,
Orfeu.
You're not there.
You're tricking me!
I want to see you!
Orfeu, you're killing me.
Farewell, Orfeu.
You'll never see me again.
Why did you lie to me?
You lied to me!
- Calm down, Orfeu.
Don't leave!
Hermes, that's him!
Orfeu, it's me.
Hermes is here too.
I have nothing left to live for.
I'm poorer
than the poorest of black men.
Beg for mercy, my son.
We're all poor,
and the only words left for us
are those of the poor man:
Thank you.
I beg for your mercy, Hermes.
All I can offer you
is man's mercy.
Here.
I've done
all that had to be done.
I think you'll find
true mercy there.
Thank you, Hermes.
No, my son.
Save your thanks for Eurídice.
Let's see.
Are you going
to take the body?
Because if not —
Very well.
Come with me.
Because if you don't want to,
another cadaver is always of use
to doctors and scientists.
Works out cheaper
for you too.
I only ask
because I'm required to.
And the truth is,
once you're here...
Carnival is over.
There's nothing anyone can do.
Would you like to identify her?
Careful. You'll catch a cold
dressed like that.
Death is cheap here, eh?
Careful.
You're shaking all over.
The same thing happens to me.
It's no use being careful.
I have a cold year-round.
Everything's beautiful, Eurídice.
My heart's like a bird whose thirst
is quenched by a single dewdrop.
Thank you, Eurídice.
Thank you for this new day.
It's you who's carrying me.
I rest in your arms
like a sleeping child,
and from the sweet breath
in your bosom,
I know you'll take me
where I must go.
Thank you, Eurídice.
The path you've chosen
is laden with flowers.
The sun is rising
to welcome us, my love.
Sing, Eurídice.
The happiness of the poor
Is like the great illusion of Carnival
We work all year long
You snake!
I'll kill you!
I'll grind you to dust!
I'll kill you both!
Zeca!
Hurry!
Play and make the sun rise!
- I can't.
- Sure you can.
- I don't know if I can.
You can.
Make something up.
- Come on, play.
- I don't know how.
Yes, you do. Come on.
He plays well, doesn't he?
What are you looking at?
Shut up.
He's making the sun rise.
He made the sun rise.
Wow. Just like Orfeu.
Now you're Orfeu.
Yes, you are.
Take this flower.
Play a song for me.
Come on!