Sita, go and tell Sister Clodagh
I wish to speak to her.
..therefore...
x is equal to five...
..or...
Reverend Mother wishes to speak to you,
Sister Clodagh.
Joyah!
Continue the lesson.
Sister Clodagh,
we may proceed with our plans at Mopu.
It will be called St Faith.
St Faith.
And you have been appointed
to take charge of St Faith.
I, Reverend Mother?
You.
You will be the youngest Sister Superior
in our Order.
Thank you, Reverend Mother.
The agent at Mopu is an Englishman.
He seems a difficult man.
You won't get much help from him.
Dear Madam,
My name is Dean.
I am the agent of General Toda Rai at Mopu
and I am writing to you in that capacity.
I understand the GeneraI has offered you
the oId PaIace of Mopu
to make a school
and a dispensary for the natives.
lt is not the first time he has had such ideas.
He has asked me to tell you
about the place and the people.
It's not a comfortable spot
and it's at the back of beyond.
First, you have to get to DarjeeIing
and then I have to find you ponies and porters
to take you into the hills.
Mopu is eight thousand feet up.
The peaks on the range opposite
are nearly as high as Everest.
The peopIe caII the highest peak Nanda Devi.
It means, "the bare goddess".
I live down in the valley out of the wind,
so does the GeneraI and so do the people.
Mopu Palace stands in the wind
on a shelf on the mountain.
It was buiIt by the GeneraI's father
to keep his women there.
It's called a paIace,
but there may be a sIight difference between
your idea of a paIace and the General's.
Anyhow, there it is.
The peopIe are Iike mountain peasants
everywhere, simpIe and independent.
They work because they must, smile when they
feel Iike it and are no respecters of persons.
The men are men.
No better, no worse than anywhere eIse.
The women are women,
the children, children.
Up on the mountain, above the palace,
we have our hoIy man,
who sits there, day in and day out,
in all weathers.
All the peopIe around are very proud of him
and bring him food and little offerings.
The wind up at the palace
blows seven days a week,
so, if you must come,
bring some warm things with you.
Nobody has Iived there for a Iong time,
except Angu Ayah,
who has aIways been there
and stays on as caretaker.
As a caretaker, she's a bit of a failure, but she's
a faithful, dirty old bird and goes with the place.
She lives there alone,
with the ghosts of bygone days.
(Voices overlapping) Ayah! Ayah!
(Ghostly voice) Ayah!
(Birdsong)
(Ayah squawks)
(Mimics parrot)
(Bugle fanfare)
(Fanfare continues)
(Excited shouting)
(Men call out)
(Fanfare continues)
Ayah! Ayah!
- That's Mr Dean.
- Never mind Mr Dean. He will find us.
Now, listen, Ayah,
I have invited some ladies to stay here
at the House of Women.
Ladies?
Oh, that will be like old times!
It will not be in the least like "old times".
They are not that kind of lady, at all.
- Then they won't be any fun.
- They are not coming for fun.
These are nuns.
You know what a nun is?
They pray all day
like the monks you invited last year.
I am going to give them this house
to make a school and a hospital for the people.
But you know nobody here wants a school.
And I'm sure they don't want a hospital.
How do they know what
they want untiI they try it?
The people have all kinds of diseases.
- They have ringworm...
- They don't mind having ringworm.
Then they ought to mind and it will all be free.
It was free last time and nobody came.
They will this time.
Mr Dean! You will receive them for me and you
will do everything for them that they want doing.
You, too. You will engage servants for them.
You will both look after them
until they can look after themselves.
What do they eat?
How do I know what nuns eat?
I have remembered that.
Do you see that crate?
Sausages!
They will eat sausages.
Europeans eat sausages wherever they go.
They will eat them when they come and until
they can tell the cook what else they want to eat.
(Babble of voices)
Now, remember, Ayah,
if you give any trouble, you will be sorry.
I'm sorry now!
A convent in this house!
What do you think of that?
The brothers only stayed five months.
Perhaps the sisters won't stay long, either.
The house is nine thousand feet up.
Very coId, but good air.
General Toda Rai, who has invited us to Mopu
has promised us every help.
He was a little afraid, when he learnt that
we are bound to our Order only by yearly vows.
- I explained this rule to him.
- Yes, Reverend Mother.
For more than a century, to serve voluntarily
has been one of the glories of our Order.
And our greatest strength.
Exactly.
He understands now.
- Is there anything you would like to ask?
- Who am I to take with me?
Remember, a community is not a class of girls.
The sisters won't be easy to manage.
Or to impress.
Now, let me see...
I'll give you Sister Briony.
You'll need her strength.
Thank you, Reverend Mother.
Sister Philippa for the garden.
- Sister Blanche...
- Sister Blanche.
You know what the others call her?
- Sister Honey.
- Yes, Honey.
I think you'll need Sister Honey.
She's popuIar and you'II need to be popuIar.
(Giggling)
- And Sister Ruth.
- But Sister Ruth is ill.
That is why I want her to go.
Forgive me for saying so,
Reverend Mother, but...
do you think our vocation is her vocation?
Yes, she's a problem.
I'm afraid she'll be a problem for you, too.
With a smaller community, she may be better.
Give her responsibiIities, Sister.
She badIy wants importance.
Do you think it's a good thing
to let her feel important?
Spare her some of your own importance.
If you can.
Mother, are you sorry that I have been
appointed to take charge of St Faith?
Yes.
I don't think you're ready for it.
And I think you'll be lonely.
Never forget, we are an order of workers.
Work them hard
and, remember,
the superior of all is a servant of all.
I understand.
(Bell continues to ring)
- It was a good, good idea.
One thing about 'em, they keep good time.
Go!
(Horn)
(Bell and prolonged note of horn echo)
(Wind howls)
(Local men sing)
Oh, dear. A whole garden so terribly overgrown
I don't know where to begin.
Please come and help the fat Lemini
who asks questions.
Sister Briony?
Ayah, you must learn our proper names.
- Anyway, there aren't any patients yet.
- Aren't there?
There are dozens waiting.
And more coming every minute.
(All talk at once in local language)
ALL: Ah!
Now, tell them to go away
and help me with the ones that are left.
Sister Blanche, these girls are to work in your
lace schooI. They were sent by the GeneraI.
Don't they look nice?
Oh, but, Sister, you ought to see the children.
The schoolroom is full of them already.
The little ones are so sweet.
Some of them can scarcely do more than toddle.
- Joseph Anthony has come.
- Ayah, you must knock before you come in.
- Who is Joseph Anthony?
He is the son of the General's cook. He is going
to interpret for you. He speaks English.
Come in.
Has the General sent you?
- Yes, lady.
- She isn't a lady. She is a sister.
Say, yes, Lemini.
Yes, Lemini.
I have my box and my bedding outside,
because I shall live here with you.
Oh?
Would you like to see my box
and bedding, lady...Sister...Lemini?
Would you, Auntie? They are new.
- How old are you?
- Six to eleven.
- What did you say?
- I can remember that I am six.
But my father married my mother
eleven years ago.
So I may probably be about ten.
(Knock at door)
The schoolroom is overflowing with children.
We've nothing unpacked.
No-one understands the language.
There are too many and they smell.
l don't know what to do with them.
Tell them to come back later.
Start with some of the older ones.
- They won't go away, Lemini.
- Oh, why not?
They were paid to come
and so they can't go away.
- Paid?
(Knock at door)
Sister, the General's clerk has orders to pay
everybody who comes to my dispensary.
So, of course, they all want to come.
- Excuse me, may I suggest...
- Yes, Sister?
Wouldn't it be a pity to send the children away?
- They were paid to come.
- But if they like it, they may come again.
What can you do with them?
They look very stupid to me.
They can't speak a word of Hindustani
or English.
Joseph can.
You'll help us, won't you, Joseph?
The brothers left a blackboard in the school.
I'II draw things on it in coloured chaIk.
They can tell me their name for it
and I'll tell them the English.
l can take their names
and ages and make a register.
You can hardly call that a lesson.
You can call it a very sensible idea.
Thank you, Sister Blanche.
(Men shouting)
I suppose you know who I am?
You must be Mr Dean.
I must.
And you must be the Sister Superior.
What curious feathers.
Are they all from the birds that you've shot?
I don't shoot birds.
When you've shot everything, it palls, doesn't it?
I'm the General's agent.
He welcomes you to Mopu.
I understood you wanted to see me.
We want to talk to you on business.
I didn't suppose you want to talk to me
on anything else.
Sorry. Perhaps that wasn't fair.
Mr Dean,
you know that General Toda Rai, has given us
this house for a new foundation of our Order.
We very much appreciate it.
It's very generous of him.
Yes.
You'd like the General, Sister.
He also is a superior being.
Really!
I don't know why you are being
so rude to me, Mr Dean.
I have to talk business with you,
whether I like it or not.
Well, talk it then and don't teach it me.
It's no place to put a nunnery, I can tell you that.
Difficult, but not impossible.
- Nothing is impossible...
- Is yours a contempIative order?
I mean, do you live in meditation
or whatever you call it? Do you keep solitude?
Our Order isn't in the least like that.
We are very busy people.
We're going to open a dispensary,
a school for children and a class for girls.
Good. You'll be doing me a great favour
when you begin to educate the local girls, Sister.
I have already been told, Mr Dean,
that you do not believe in solitude.
Do you know what the people call this place?
The House of Women.
The General's father
used to keep his Iadies here.
From now on,
it will be known as the House of St Faith.
Sister, will you have that picture taken down?
I give you till the rains break.
(Rhythmic drumbeat)
(Wind whistles)
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
(Knock at door)
Who is it?
(Door opens, wind howls)
- Sister Briony.
(Bells jingle)
(Drums continue to beat)
I can't sleep.
Anything wrong, Sister?
It's Sister Ruth. I've just seen her.
- How is she?
- She's sick.
She has violent pains in her joints,
a boil on her finger and headaches.
It's this wind.
And we all seem so tired.
It's the altitude.
My dispensary is more crowded than ever.
This big house to look after.
All the unpacking still to be done.
And the plumbing has broken down again.
What do you think, Sister? Perhaps Mr Dean...
Certainly not. We can manage without Mr Dean.
Yes, of course.
- Are you all right, Sister?
- Of course I'm all right.
- Show me your arm.
- I'm perfectly all right.
So, you've got them, too.
- What have I got?
- Spots.
I've got them. Every one of us has got them.
There must be something in the water here
that's very unhealthy.
- The natives drink it.
- They get sick, themselves.
Ayah has the General's ear,
the Young General. He's very ill.
Those drums are beating for him.
They beat all night while he's ill.
If you hear them stop, he's dead.
(Drums continue beating)
(Drums stop)
You!
How do you do?
What are you doing here?
Excuse Old Feltie,
I haven't a hand to take him off.
I've come to mend a loose joint in your pipe.
- You must send a plumber!
- The nearest one is in Darjeeling.
- I count plumbing among my other gifts.
- That's not...
I swear to you, it's only the pipe I'm interested in.
- I must see Sister Clodagh about this.
- All right.
I forbid you to stay in there.
All right.
We have to build a work room
and a school and, later on, a chapel.
Somebody has got to put locks
on my cupboards. I daren't unpack a thing.
And the windows don't open and the doors
don't shut and the plumbing won't work.
SISTER BRIONY:
Come in, Mr Dean.
May I go now, Sister?
Please sit down, Mr Dean.
Would you like some coffee, Mr Dean?
- Can you make it decently?
- Can I make coffee!
- Can she?
- Full of grits.
Mr Dean, Joseph tells us
that people are still being paid to come to us.
Ah, the General's a wise man.
It's only till it becomes a habit.
Let it become a habit for them to come and
they won't remember the time when they didn't.
Then, gradually, he'll leave off paying them.
Gradually, it will become a habit not to be paid.
They're like children.
He told me he was going to order them to come.
They don't know what an order is.
Then they should learn.
- Why?
- We all need discipline.
You said they're like children. Without discipline,
we should all behave like children.
Don't you like children?
(Door opens)
Thank you, Sister Briony.
Talking of medicine, Sister Briony,
if you get a bad case, one that seems to you as
though it might be dangerous or even serious,
don't take it.
- But that would be...
- It would be wise.
If you got a bad case and someone died,
you'd have all the people up against you.
Why?
Well, you must remember
they are primitive people and like...
Like children. Unreasonable children.
They've never seen medicine before.
They'd think it was magic, a new kind of magic.
So, remember, I've warned you.
By the way, how are you feeling, all of you?
Not very well. Sister Ruth is the worst.
I think the water must be bad.
Ayah says it's the water.
On the contrary, the water is too good.
It's Darjeeling tummy.
Well, I'd better get that plumbing fixed.
Sister!
What has happened, Sister?
Oh, Sister, they brought in a woman,
our first bad case.
She was covered in blood.
I've never seen such a sight.
She must have cut a vein or an artery.
I had such a time stopping it.
I've never seen bIeeding Iike that.
I didn't know what to do at first,
but, at last, I managed to stop it.
A minute would have fetched Sister Briony,
who would have stopped it at once.
- I told you to stay in bed.
- I was only trying to consider you, Sister Briony.
It might have been better to have considered
the woman, who was bIeeding to death.
Shall I wait?
We are coming in a moment.
I think you'd better go back to your room.
Goodbye, Sister. I hope your patient does well.
Who is she?
It sounded like Samuel,
but it couldn't be, could it?
Oh, Samil, she's a good old soul,
one of my best workers.
I'm very much obliged to you.
Thank you.
(Nuns gasp)
Now the old place is a pukka convent.
Hello, Sister Ruth. Going for a walk?
It's time to ring the bell.
You're slipping.
A quarter of an hour early.
Thank you.
I came to ask Mr Dean to wait in the Blue Room.
- How did you know he was here?
- I saw him from the schoolroom.
I've brought something for you.
Her name is Hirsempal, but we caII her Kanchi.
She's 1 7. She's an orphan.
And it's high time she was married.
Every evening when I come home,
I find her sitting on my veranda.
She dresses herself up, puts flowers in her hair.
Becoming an absolute nuisance.
lf she is cloistered for a few months,
her uncIe will marry her off,
but she's been behaving so badIy
that no-one wants her.
I don't think we want her, either.
Why did you bring her to us?
Isn't it your business to save souls?
You are not to speak to me like that, Mr Dean.
Sorry.
Can't she go into some sort of service?
She'd set any house by the ears.
I thought no-one would have patience with her.
Except you.
Would you ask Sister Briony
to come here, please?
(Whistles) Kanchi!
Kanchi.
(Asks her to make a salaam)
You're sure there's no question
you're dying to ask me?
None.
You wanted me, Sister?
I have agreed to have this girl with us for a
while. Can you find somewhere for her to sleep?
What is she to do?
Sister Honey can take her into the lace school.
Yes...
Tell Ayah to give her some housework.
Keep her busy.
Come along.
Well, thanks.
The Young General's death,
is the General grieving?
You can never tell with these people.
- What's the new Young General's name?
- Dilip. Dilip Rai.
He was going to Cambridge.
Now he'll be a warrior and marry young.
It'll suit him, all right,
these Rai are a fighting race.
- Gun.
CHILDREN: Gun.
Warship.
CHILDREN: Warship.
JOSEPH: Bayonet.
CHILDREN: Bayonet.
Dagger.
CHILDREN: Dagger.
- Gun.
CHILDREN: Gun.
You know, we may have
to mix something with it.
Here. Let me have a look.
Hail Mary, full of grace, blessed is the...
(Bell continues to ring)
Sister?
Did you hear the bell?
This morning, in chapel,
I suddenly had the feeling you were not with us.
- I try hard enough.
- Try what?
I used to forget everything in chapel.
I used to feel light and happy and...near God.
Let me help you.
What is worrying you?
I remember things, before I joined our order.
Things I wanted to forget.
I never thought of them until now.
I've been 21 years in the Order and...
now they come back to me.
I think you can see too far.
I look out there and...
..then I can't see the potato I'm planting.
And, after a bit, it doesn't seem to matter
whether I plant it or not.
It's this place,
with its strange atmosphere and new people.
Stay with me tonight, after chapel,
and we will pray together.
And work, Sister, work hard.
Work until you're too tired
to think of anything else.
(Remembers) Oh, isn't it a grand day, Con?
Con, isn't it a grand day?
Mm.
- What's wrong?
- Everything.
- What especially?
- Oh, nothing.
You wouldn't understand.
Is it money, Con?
Whatever else is it?
Desmond is well out of it in Michigan.
I heard from him last week.
He's been made a partner.
Just because I'm the eldest son,
I have to stay here in Ireland all my life
and hang around waiting for...this.
I'll have a little money, Con. When I marry.
It isn't "a little money" it wants, it's a fortune,
and then it would be a waste.
Clo, don't you sometimes itch to get away?
No, I don't want to go away.
I want to stay here like this for the rest of my life.
(Dog whines)
(Dog barks)
(Dog continues to bark)
MAN: Ayah! Angu Ayah!
(Horse bells jingle)
(Calls to servant)
(Dog continues to bark)
Ayah! Angu Ayah!
Salaam, my Little General.
I want to see the Reverend Sisters.
Why are they called "the servants of Mary"?
Is the Superior Sister called Mary?
Ask her. Here she comes.
Go now. I will speak to her alone.
- Good morning.
I want to see the Superior Sister.
I am the Sister Superior.
Oh.
I want to be a student here with you.
I want to study a lot of learning.
I want to study mathematics,
history, poetry and languages.
I have a note from my uncle
to ask you to encourage me.
I'm very sorry.
We only teach children and young girls.
Why?
Convents don't teach men pupils.
- That's not very polite to men.
- We don't mean it that way. It's the custom.
Convents are for girls.
The brotherhoods are for men.
Jesus Christ was a man.
He took the shape of a man.
But you don't need to count me as a man.
I'm only interested in studious things.
Please, Sister? I have written out my timetable.
May I read it to you?
5am to 7am:
algebra with the mathematical Sister.
8am to 1 0am: reIigion, especially Christianity,
with the scriptural Sister.
1 0am art.
1 pm to 3pm: French and Russian
with the French and Russian Sisters, if any.
3pm to 4pm: Physics with the physical Sister.
(The Young General calls his servant)
(Door opens)
SISTER CLODAGH:
Please wait in here, General.
Aren't you afraid
that you've let a cuckoo into your nest?
We didn't want to offend the General.
He might turn us out.
He wouldn't do that.
You may have trouble with Kanchi.
Kanchi?
She'd never dare.
After all, he is a prince
and she is...what she is.
Still, I expect she knows the story
of The Prince And The Beggar Maid.
..40, 41 , 42,
43, 44,
45, 46,
47, 48,
49.
When the General gave us the deeds,
our boundary line
was to be 500 yards round the building.
- That's right.
- So, the Holy Man is living on our ground.
He was here first.
Yes, but, Mr Dean,
I find all these things very distracting.
Distracting?
Yes. Disturbing.
This clear air
and the wind always blowing
and the mountain and the Holy Man sitting there,
day in and day out
and the people coming to see him.
They climb the path by the house
and they stop and sit and stare at us.
What do you want to do about it?
Ask the General to ask the Holy Man to move.
- I couldn't. It wouldn't be polite.
- I don't suppose the General knows he's there.
Oh, yes, he does.
That old man worries him quite a bit.
Particularly when he's in the middle of his dinner
or when he's trying on a new frock coat.
Why?
Well, I suppose he feels
he ought to go and do likewise.
Then he wouldn't turn him out?
Well, it would be a bit awkward
for the General to turn out his own uncle.
His uncle?
General Sir Krishna Rai.
KCVO, KCSI, CMG.
He has several foreign decorations, too.
He lent our General the money to buy this place.
l've never heard him talk.
They say he speaks perfect EngIish.
Several other European languages, too.
Does he never speak at all?
I've never heard him.
- When does he eat or sleep?
- No-one knows.
He's always in his place under the tree.
People come miles to see him.
Well, I really don't know what to do.
What would Christ have done?
(Bells jingle)
- Good morning, General.
- Good morning, Sister Honey.
Good morning, Sister Ruth.
(Sniffs)
Do you like it, Sister Ruth?
It's called Black Narcissus.
It comes from the Army and Navy Stores
in London.
Black Narcissus?
I don't like scent, at all.
Oh, Sister, don't you think it's rather common
to smell of ourselves?
Have you seen the Young General today?
- What's the latest?
- Emeralds. Beautiful emeralds.
The deepest, most beautiful green
l've ever seen.
At that hour in the morning,
they make me biIious.
Have you seen his coats?
A different one for every day in the year!
He's lucky he doesn't have to do
his own laundry.
Yesterday, a coat the colour of ripe corn,
patterned with flowers and damask.
His earrings were amethysts, three inches long,
and his rings were turquoise.
Today, he's aII jade and emeralds and his coat
is a most wonderfuI pattern of paIe vioIet stripes,
worked entireIy in petit point,
just Iike my grandmother's footstool!
Oh, Granny!
Turn round.
These emeralds are for you, my darling,
when you marry.
There.
(Whistling)
There's Con.
Good night, everybody!
Not too late, darling.
MOTHER: I hope they get something settled
by the winter.
Where are you, Con?
SISTER RUTH: He said it was called Black
Narcissus, from the Army and Navy Stores.
Black Narcissus!
That's what I'm going to call him.
It's a wonderful name for him.
He's so vain, like a peacock.
A fine, black peacock.
- He's not Black.
- They all Iook alike to me.
General, please conjugate s'asseoir.
Je m'assieds.
Tu t'assieds.
ll s'assied.
Er...
Nous n...
Nous nous asseyons.
Vous vous asseyez.
Ils s'asseyent.
Future tense?
ALL: ♪ Noel, Noel
♪ Noel, Noel
♪ Born is the King of Israel
♪ The first Noel
♪ The angel did say...
(Door opens)
♪ ..was to certain poor shepherds
in fields as they lay
♪ In fields where they...
- (Mr Dean starts singing)
♪ Lay keeping their sheep
♪ On a cold winter's night
♪ That was so deep
♪ Noel, noel
♪ Noel
♪ No-o-e-el
♪ Born is the King of Israel
(Prolonged note on organ)
ALL: ♪ Lullay, my liking,
my dear son, my sweeting
♪ Lullay my dear heart, my own dear darling...
♪ Lullay, my liking, my dear son, my sweeting
♪ Lullay my dear heart...
Something for you.
- For me?
- A Christmas present.
Go on. Take it.
♪ ..there was mickle melody at that child's birth
Oh, Con!
♪ All that were in heavenly bliss,
they made mickle mirth
♪ Lullay, my liking, my dear son, my sweeting...
♪ ..lullay my dear heart, my own dear darling
Sister Clodagh!
Sister, may I congratulate you
on the birth of Christ?
Thank you, General.
I hope you don't mind my coming tonight.
I am very much interested in Jesus Christ.
Have I said anything wrong?
No, but...
we don't usually speak of Him so casually.
MR DEAN: And you shouId!
He should be casual and as much
a part of life as...your daily bread.
How dare you come here like this!
How dare you come to our service tonight.
You're... You're unforgivable!
You're objectionable when you're sober
and abominable when you're drunk.
I quite agree.
If you have a spark of decency left in you,
you won't come near us again.
♪ No
♪ I won't be a nun
♪ No, I cannot be a nun
♪ For I am so fond
♪ Of pleasure
♪ I cannot be a nun!
(Drunken laughter)
Happy Christmas!
I do like his voice.
It's so nice and loud.
I think it's lovely, don't you?
- Good night, General.
- Good night, Sister Clodagh.
(Knock at door)
- Come in!
I want to talk to you.
Come and sit down.
I've been worried about you for some time.
I feel that things are not right with you.
In what way?
You Iook so ill and you've got so terribIy thin.
I know that you're trying to keep up,
for all our sakes,
but I feel that you really must go
and see the doctor.
I shan't see the doctor!
I'm perfectly well. You know it.
You're just trying to make out that...
I didn't mean...
to be rude.
I haven't been sleeping, that's all.
If you haven't been sleeping,
there must be some reason for it.
Can't you tell me?
Is something worrying you?
Yes.
Yes, that's it.
I'm worried.
Don't you think you could tell me about it?
I'd like you to tell me, if you can.
I can't speak of it.
To anyone.
Won't you try? You know you can trust me.
You didn't want me to come here.
None of you have ever wanted me here.
Don't you think
you're letting things run away with you?
I think...
..you have let yourself fall into thinking
too much of Mr Dean.
Sister...
Don't you realise what you're doing?
What you're running the risk
of losing in yourself?
Sister, you must...
I must make you see, before it is too Iate.
All the same, I've noticed
you're very pleased to see him, yourself.
If that was in your mind, it's better said.
I think you're out of your senses.
Listen to me. l don't know,
I can't decide now what to make of you.
I shall have to think.
And I want you to think, too.
As for Mr Dean...
In spite of his charm and kindliness,
he is not a good man.
You must take him for what he is and not try
to glorify him into something he is not.
When he came to chapel on Christmas night,
he was drunk.
Can I go?
I want you to write to Reverend Mother.
I shan't look at the letter
and her reply will be your own business.
Am I to write two or three pages?
Would you rather I did it now
or finish my class work first?
You may go.
(Slams door)
That parcel is mine! Give it to me.
I can't. I must give all the mail to Sister Clodagh.
It's mine. Give it to me, you little fool.
Can't you see? It's addressed to me.
I ordered it myself from Calcutta.
It's nothing to do with anyone else.
Sister Briony, do you know what's happened
to the other gold chain off this censer?
No. It was there
when we had it out at Christmas.
- Well, it isn't here now.
- Ask Kanchi if she's seen it.
(Screams)
And that...is for stealing in my house.
(Kanchi screams again)
- That's for stealing a brass chain.
That's for steaIing it in such a silly way.
And that...
(Kanchi screams again)
- ..is for getting found out.
What has the girl done?
She's a thief. She stole a brass chain
from the church to put round her dirty neck.
Finish the beating, my Little General Bahadur.
You're going to be a great man.
Not like your uncIe, oh, dear, no.
Like your grandfather.
Ha ha! He was a man.
Finish the beating and begin to be a man!
(Kanchi sobbing)
Get up.
Forget-me-not.
CHILDREN: Forget-me-not.
Sweet pea.
CHILDREN: Sweet pea.
JOSEPH: Daffodil.
CHILDREN: Daffodil.
JOSEPH: Japanese peony.
CHILDREN: Japanese peony.
JOSEPH: Chinese IiIy.
CHILDREN: Chinese lily.
- Tulip.
CHILDREN: Tulip.
Honeysuckle.
CHILDREN: Honeysuckle.
Delphin-i-um.
- Sister Honey!
CHILDREN: Delphin-i-um.
Will you find Sister Philippa for me, please?
- And the cabbage patch?
- Foxgloves.
- And the runner beans?
- Honeysuckle.
And the onions?
Tulips.
And the potatoes? All flowers?
No, not the little round bed.
And there are some more vegetables,
down by the stables, where they won't show.
But what on earth came over you...
Would you like to sit down?
Sister, I want to be transferred.
Transferred?
Yes, I want you, if you will,
to write and ask for my transfer at once.
If you will. At once.
But why?
I was becoming too fond of the place.
I was too wrapped up in my work. I...
I thought too much about it.
I'd forgotten.
Forgotten what?
What I am.
I was losing the spirit of our Order.
I've been thinking it over, you see, and...
I must go at once.
I don't see that at all.
Now that you know and you realise the danger,
you needn't go.
Surely, now is the time to stay.
I daren't stay.
I think there are only two ways
of living in this place.
Either, you must live like Mr Dean or...
or like the Holy Man.
Either ignore it or give yourself up to it.
Neither would do for us.
No.
Well, we are here and I don't think
it will help matters if we run away.
(Horn)
You know if I ask for you to be transferred,
it'll be a bad mark against you?
That's all the better.
That's what I need.
Ayah! Ayah!
(Asks question)
- What did she say, Ayah?
- Give him something.
It's Om's little brother.
Shall we give him magnesia?
Or some of the paraffin emulsion?
1 03!
That's not much in a baby, is it?
I mean, they go up and down easily, don't they?
(Asks a question)
(Replies)
He's been like it three days. This morning,
he wouldn't wake, so she brought him.
Let him sleep. Take him home
and put him on your bed and let him sleep.
(Translates instructions)
Aren't you going to give him anything?
There's nothing I can do.
But there must be something we can do.
At least, bathe his eyes
or relieve his tummy with a little oil.
I daren't touch him, Sister.
I don't think he feels any pain.
You can see how it must hurt him.
You're afraid of what Mr Dean said.
You'll give up his life without a struggle!
That's enough, Sister!
I won't have any hysteria from you.
I know what I'm doing.
The kindest thing you can do is to make her go
home where she'll be amongst her own people.
Lemini? Lemini?
Sister Ruth!
Everyone is very late this morning.
I do hope nothing's happened.
Joseph, go down the path and hurry them up.
Well, go on.
I don't want to.
- You don't want to?
- Why don't you want to?
How dare you answer me like that! Go at once.
No, I won't go.
Joseph!
Now, stand still. Tell me what's the matter!
- Don't frighten him.
- He knows something.
- Joseph, why haven't the children come?
- Where are they?
He knows why. Tell us.
I don't want to. Lemini, don't make me tell.
Joseph, you must tell us. Please, Joseph, dear.
- Tell us.
- The little baby is dead!
SISTER HONEY: Oh, no.
- Our little brother is dead.
And they say that a Lemini killed him!
ALL: Sister Clodagh!
- Nobody in the dispensary.
- No children have come.
- No gardeners.
- Kanchi has gone.
- So has the Young General.
- Not a servant in the place.
- We're all alone. There's no-one in the house.
It was my fault.
Because I loved him.
Because I couldn't bear to see him die.
I did it. I killed him!
I gave her a bottle to take away,
some cotton wool and one of our spoons.
I killed him! I killed him!
Ayah!
- Ayah, how much of this is true?
- All true. The people are very angry.
We must explain. Somebody must tell them.
The Young General, surely he hasn't run away?
No. He's run away with Kanchi.
Ayah, will you take a message to the village?
Me? No.
Well, can Joseph?
- He can go, but they won't Iet him come back.
- I'll go.
It's not safe for you to go outside the garden.
- You can't go, Sister. It's far too dangerous.
- I'm not going down.
(Animals call out)
(Bell continues to ring)
(Calls servant)
My clothing, quickly!
Well? Who was it?
Oh, you.
Mr Dean, do you think it's serious?
Don't you think they'll come back?
Sister Clodagh, the agent before my time was
riding down to the factory one day on his pony.
He let it kick an umbrella
that was lying open in the path.
There was a child asleep under it
and it was killed.
It was just an accident,
but they murdered him that night.
I'm not trying to frighten you,
but I want you to see that it may be serious.
The village seems quiet enough.
SISTER CLODAGH: Did they say anything?
- Nothing.
They listened to me and said nothing.
I saw the woman. I drank the stuff that
Sister Honey was foolish enough to give her.
You drank it?
I wanted to prove to them that I wouldn't
drop down dead. It was only castor oil.
Now, none of you must go out of the garden.
Behave as though nothing has happened.
I'll go down now and come back this evening.
Lemini?
Lemini.
- What's that for?
- For you, Lemini.
Who sent it? Sister Clodagh?
(Horn echoes)
Do you notice a change in us
since we came here?
I notice a change in you.
Am I very different?
Yes.
You're much nicer.
- Nicer?
- Mm.
You're human.
Human?
Yes, we're all human, aren't we?
When I was a girl, I loved a man.
We were children together in Ireland,
where I come from.
A little place called Enniskelly.
I thought...
Everyone thought we should marry.
But he was ambitious
and I found out he was going to America,
to his uncle.
And he didn't intend to take me.
He didn't think he was doing anything wrong.
I don't think he ever thought of us marrying.
But in a little place like that...
..and I had shown I loved him.
I had to get away first.
And that's why you entered the order?
And, being you, you wouldn't go back?
It was a strange way of bringing me in.
But God works in strange ways.
I had work to do
and I had the life.
No-one outside
can possibly know what that means.
It came to be my life.
I had forgotten everything until I came here.
The first day I came
I thought of him for the first time for years.
I seem to go back to the first time I loved him
when we were children.
The Young General reminds me of him, too.
The world comes thrusting in behind him.
I've been drifting and dreaming and...
(Voice breaks) Now I seem to be living through
the struggle and the bitterness again.
Here.
It's quite clean. I washed my hair this morning.
Don't take on so, there's a good girl.
It'll all blow over. There's nothing really wrong.
Sister Philippa is leaving.
And this morning I had a letter
from Reverend Mother.
Sister Ruth is giving up the Order.
She has not renewed her vows.
I'm sorry.
And you.
Ever since we came here,
over all our troubles, it's been,
"Ask Mr Dean, ask Mr Dean."
There was just no-one else you could ask.
Well, I had to take the Young General.
I couldn't turn out the Holy Man.
I couldn't stop the wind from blowing
and the air from being as clear as crystal.
I couldn't hide the mountain.
Look, you must get away from here,
all of you, at once.
- Run away?
- Yes, if you've got any sense.
What, leave all this work, like the brothers?
Yes.
I told you it was no place to put a nunnery.
There's something in the atmosphere
that makes everything seem exaggerated.
Don't you understand? You must all get away
before something happens!
(Rhythmic drums)
(Wind howls)
SISTER PHILIPPA: ..all snares near me.
May thy hoIy angeIs dwell here
and keep us in peace...
(Sister Honey sobs)
(Sister Briony snores)
Sister, are you there?
(Door rattles)
Sister! Do you want me to wake the others?
You can't order me about.
You have nothing to do with me any more.
I know what you've done.
I know that you've left the Order.
I only want to stop you
from doing something you'll be sorry for.
Sister PhiIippa is going back in a few days' time.
I want to send you with her.
That's what you would like to do.
Send me back and shut me up!
That's what you wouId all Iike to do!
You know that isn't true. Why should we want
to keep you here against your will?
Because you're all jealous of me.
Especially you.
At least wait till the morning.
Wait till the morning and I'll wait with you.
(Manic laughter)
- Ayah, wake up!
SISTER HONEY: What is it?
- What's happened?
- It's Sister Ruth!
Stop her! She's gone mad!
Oh, it's my fault. It's all my fault!
Sssh!
Can't stop mad people.
You should leave them alone.
- She may kill herself.
- If she's really mad, that won't matter.
All of you, search the house! We must stop her!
NUNS: Sister Ruth! Sister Ruth!
We must get lanterns!
Sister Ruth!
(Mimics nuns) Sister Ruth! Sister Ruth!
(Overlapping voices) Sister Ruth!
SISTER BRIONY: Sister Ruth!
- Sister Ruth!
SISTER CLODAGH:
Joseph! Ask him if he's seen her.
Oh, no, Lemini, we couldn't do that.
But, Joseph, anything may have happened
to the Lemini. She may be hurt.
That would be a very little thing to him, Lemini.
He wouldn't notice it.
(Drums beat)
(Growling)
(Monkeys chatter)
(Screeching)
(Whistling, hissing)
(Whistles)
Good evening.
Sister Ruth?
I can't stand it any longer.
I left the Order. I gave up my vows.
I'm finished with them up there.
I see.
Well, I can arrange for you to stay
at the rest house. I'll send my boy over now.
In the morning, I'll get ponies and porters
to take you to Darjeeling.
I love you.
You...
Well, if you do, you can forget about it.
I'm sorry, Sister Ruth, very sorry, but...
Look, let me take you back to the palace.
lt isn't too late.
Sister CIodagh is your friend.
She wants to heIp you.
She hates me. They all hate me.
You're the only one that's ever been kind to me.
- I? I've hardly spoken a word to you.
- You have.
When I stopped the woman
from bleeding to death.
- You said you were grateful.
- Did I?
Then when you stopped me in the hall,
you said...
Whatever I said, it didn't mean a thing.
Ever since you came here,
you've all gone crazy.
Drive one another crazy, but leave me out of it!
Are you going to Darjeeling or not?
- No!
- Then you must go back to the palace.
- No.
- You'll go back if I have to carry you back.
Go and talk to Sister Clodagh. She brought you
here, she can get you back again.
Sister Clodagh, Sister Clodagh!
- You know what she says about you?
- Whatever it is, it's true.
- You say that because you love her!
- I don't love anyone!
CIodagh.
CIodagh, CIodagh.
CIodagh! CIodagh! CIodagh!
(Crash)
Feel better now?
All right.
I'll go.
That's a good girl.
Try and get some sleep.
In the morning, you'II wake up
and be sorry you made such a fool of yourself.
Come on. I'll come with you.
I'll go alone.
You'll do nothing of the sort.
I'll go alone or not at all.
Suit yourself.
(Gasps)
It's morning, Lemini.
Oh, yes, Joseph, it's morning.
What time is it?
5:45 by Auntie's watch.
Fine day, Lemini.
The people call it the...
"the flying of the snows".
Joseph, if Sister Briony asks for me,
I'll be in the chapel.
(Door opens and shuts)
(Silence)
(Wind howls)
(Bell rings out)
(Weakly) Hail Mary, full of grace,
blessed is the fruit of thy womb...
(Screams)
Argh!
(Drums beat)
(Drums stop)
(Chatter and shouting)
What do you want, General?
Sister,
you know I have not been here, lately,
and I'm deeply sorry about Sister Ruth.
Thank you.
Is there anything else?
You're cross with me.
Please do not be cross with me.
I've done a very wrong thing,
but I didn't mean to do it.
Isn't it rather late to tell me about that?
Yes.
Yes, it is, rather.
I don't mean to do anything wrong again.
I'm going to give up being clever and famous.
I'm going to be exactly like my ancestors.
They were warriors and princes.
They were modest and brave and polite
and they never did anything cheating.
That is why I came to you as soon as I thought
of it, to teII you what I have done.
Must you tell me now?
- Please, Sister?
- Well, what have you done?
Sister Clodagh, I didn't know how to tell you,
so I asked Mr Dean.
And he said to tell
it was the story of The Prince...
..And The Beggar Maid.
(Dismisses servant)
You said you'd give us till the rains break.
They haven't broken yet.
What will they do with you down there?
I shall be sent to another convent
with less responsibility.
I shall be superseded as Sister-in-charge.
Will you be able to stomach that?
A stiff-necked, obstinate creature like you?
It's what I need.
I expect I shall have to remind myself of it
a hundred times a day.
I can't change in a minute,
like the Young General.
But I shall have my ghosts to remind me.
You're leaving me with more than one.
Will you do one last thing for me?
I know you'd rather not do it.
Of course I'll do it.
Will you look after the grave?
All right.
 