Boat People
Don't look at the camera...
Greet our Japanese friend Mr. Akutagawa.
Thank you.
Mr. Akutagawa is a world-famous
photo-journalist.
He took our good news
to the world three years ago.
Today he has come back to our country...
to photograph
the children of the Socialist Republic
of Vietnam...
and to show our friend
on other countries...
the new face of ourjov and happiness.
Let's show Mr. Akutagawa
our highest respect.
Now we've seen
how well Mr. Akutagawa works...
and how muck he loves us.
We were singing to welcome him...
but he did't forget his job.
I hope we can all follow his example...
and show the same devotion
to our own work.
Go on!
That's Right...
Last night I dreamed of Chairman Ho.
He has a long, long beard
and silvery hair.
I long to hold him,
to snower kisses on him.
May Chairman Ho live 10000 years!
Now let's ask Mr. Akutagawa
to sing us a song!
No, no...
This is a song from Japan.
Thank you!
Good health, Mr. Akutagawa.
You seem thoughtful, Mr. Akutagawa.
Three years ago,
during the Liberation of Danang.
I took a photo
of a crippled boy...
hobbling down an alley-way.
That image haunted me,
as if it symbolisted
the sufferings of Vietnam's children.
I never thought I'd come back and find...
so many healthy, lively children
I feel very happy.
I could stay here forever, not moving.
Oh dear! I hope I can make you
just as happy...
when we get back to Danang tomorrow.
Comrade Le, with your influence
in the Cultural Bureau...
If you can't, no one can!
Come on, old fellow, have a drink!
Thank you.
Are those boots American?
Yes, he got them
from a GI he killed.
They are GI boots.
Why doesn't he wear them?
He's waiting till he dies.
He'll wear them in his coffin.
Right, I'm saving them for the end.
We will send them to New Economic Zones
before long.
What's going on?
There's a fire!
Please stay here, Mr. Akutagawa.
You forget I'm a reporter!
Who's taking pictures?
Don't run, don't run!
Stay there!
I told you to stay there...
I'll take you with me.
I told you to stop taking pictures...
Stop, Comrade, he is a foreign friend.
I am Le Van Quyen of the Cultural Bureau.
Get up.
Call an ambulance!
Please don't take any more photos.
Stop that! He's nearly dead!
He's a reactionary elemant.
Came back to his old house...
set fire to it, and killed our Comrade.
You heard he's a reactionary.
I'm sorry the policeman did that.
Do I have to give him my negative?
No need, I'm sure you won't
misuse the pictures.
Are you alright? Not hurt?
Don't worry, I've been kicked before,
in Tokyo.
Inoue-san!
Akutagawa-san!
How are you?
Well, and you?
They told me you were back.
I just came from the office.
Are you alrigth? You don't look well.
Seeing you makes me long
to eat sushi in Ginza.
I really miss my wife and kids.
Your wife asked me
to bring you these cakes.
Thanks.
How did you find the New Economic Zones?
I only saw one Zone.
The kids there
had been wandering the streets.
I was impressed.
The kids are well looked after.
They all live together
in one big group...
much happier than kids
I've seen on the streets.
Then I wonder why the government...
cannot persuade, or even force...
city people to move
to the Zones.
Why not?
Maybe I heard wrong.
You're the one who's been there.
This is Officer Nguyen, and Comrade Vu.
You are our good friend,
I'm glad to meet you.
You're very kind...
How do you do.
Please sit down!
Beer!
It's French beer.
I wanted to offer you French wine...
but I've checked their stocks...
and they don't even have Chinese Moutai!
Don't worry, I'm happy with beer.
Fine.
Comrade Le tells me
you had a brush with the police.
I was in the wrong myself.
Not at all, we are the ones to apologise.
I got on to the unit responsible
as soon as I heard.
You have done a lot of us
in the world's press.
Now you're our honoured guest.
You'll have no more trouble.
Photograph whatever you like.
If you find anything wrong, please tell us.
We will do our best to improve!
That is true friendship!
Thank you!
Cheers, here's to success of your project.
- Thanks. - Cheers.
Cheers.
Comrade Le, Mr. Akutagawa,
I'm afraid we're short of staff.
Come on inside,
please!
Let's clap our hands
to welcome our griend from Japan.
Uncle, hold me.
Uncle, hold me too.
And me!
Little friends, sit down
and let Uncle take your photo.
Don't be naughty. Sit down again.
It's alright, let them.
Let go, back to your seats.
What's going on?
Go back to your seat. Don't be naughty.
How come?
I don't know.
Maybe they all like Mr. Akutagawa.
Come with me!
Hold me... hold me...
Be good child, I'll hold you later.
I just wanted them to sit quietly
and behave themselves...
so he can see how well our orphans
are cared for.
I didn't want anything like this.
I didn't arrange it.
The children like being held.
They don't often get the chance.
Where are you staff? Washing underwear?
We're below strength.
We need three more staff.
Alright. You can stop worrying.
We'll send someone to replace you.
Hold me, Uncle.
Mr. Akutagawa!
I was born not far from here.
This used to be the best place
for an evening stroll.
There were hawkers selling seafood
from boats.
Now they've all fled to Hong Kong
or Malaysia.
You must have heard about
the Vietnamese who've left?
I've read something. Nothing very explicit.
There are always some who can't adjust.
Mr. Nguyen, you studied in France?
I entered the Sorbonne at 18,
and came home at 22.
That was 30 years ago.
Were you always a Communist?
I spent 10 years in jail.
Ngo Dinh Viem almost got me.
Look, they did this with a bicycle chain.
Women like to touch the scar.
Do you mind if I photograph it?
Not now.
Take one when I die. I won't mind then.
Alright!
Why did you want to talk to me?
I want to take photos of the city alone.
You mean... you don't want
Comrade Le with you?
Right!
Why not?
I want to take natural photographs.
I don't want things arranged for me.
Alright, I'll have a word with Comrade Le.
Thanks.
They're too young.
Comrade Le and Comrade Vu.
They're too eager. They lose proportion.
When I see how determined they are...
I think I must have been weak
when I was young.
It makes me feel old.
You aren't old.
Recently I've been thinking
a lot about my youth...
here, Paris,
drinking French wine, eating French food...
even longing for a French woman.
I must be old!
The Revolution claimed half my life.
And now I'm old.
My mind still lives
in the colonial past.
Vietnam has won her Revolution.
But I've lost mine
I know where
to get the best French food in Danang.
I'll take you there sometime.
Get on!
Okay!
What's going on?
Be quiet and eat up. We have to go.
I'm still hungry, I want another bowl.
I don't have any more money.
Order it!
I want some...
You such a bad boy.
I'll punish you when we get home.
Take the pay.
What are you doing? My noodles!
Where are you going? Who's paying?
Forget it...
Such bad luck...
what do you kids think you're doing?
Put it down. That's mine.
- Forget it. - What's the hell!
- It's dirty. Let them eat.
- Little beggars!
You are too kind. That's mine.
Tastes good!
None for you, I want it all.
Greedy! If you drop it.
There won't be any.
Don't be afraid. I'm a foreign friend.
Your Cultural Bureau
lets me take photos.
Little boy, eat up!
Go on eating!
Can I take one of you holding him?
Just ignore me...
is that your father?
Uncle, take a picture of my mother.
Get up and take a picture, mommy.
Who is it?
Come and be in a picture, mommy.
What's the matter?
Go back to sleep, mother. It's right.
Go away and let mother sleep.
Mommy.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
I'm a reporter from Japan.
I'm here to see how you live.
You're a foreigner?
Mister, the government doesn't let us
mix with foreigners.
You'll get us into trouble
if you take photos here.
Don't worry. I have
the Cultural Bureau's permission.
You may have, but we don't.
What's all this? Who are you?
Nikon, you Japanese?
I can sell it for you
if you want.
Ah Nhac, go away!
Please go, Mister.
You really can't do this.
I'd really like to photograph them.
I'll go to talk with the Cultural Bureau.
No, don't! You'll get us all executed!
Don't make things worse!
...I can handle it.
What'd you actually want, Mister?
I just want to photograp you.
I don't understand why tour mother
is so alarmed.
There's no way
the government would let us
be photographed.
You may be okay, but we ain't.
You can stroll away and get on
with yourjob...
But we'll get jumped on.
I had on idea...
Look, I'll tell you what.
You don't have to snap us here.
Go out on the street.
Pretend I'm just a guy on the street.
Okay?
Okay!
Yeah, but what do we get out of it?
I can pay you!
D'you hear that?
I don't mind if there's no risk.
Give whatever your like.
They are still children.
That's settled, then.
Tomorrow morning at 8.
We'll meet you on the main street.
On the corner of the alley.
Fine!
- It's a deal! - Okay!
I must go.
My name is Akutagawa.
What's yours?
I'm second brother.
He's Van Lang, I'm Van Nhac
and she's Cam Nuong.
...I must go
I'm sorry to have worried you today.
I played that right.
The Japs are good tippers.
Better than the Yanks.
We'll score a packet.
Where did this come from?
It's mine... it's mine...
It's just sait water. What good is that?
I want some noodles.
When I'm earning regularly,
I'll buy you fish.
I like fish eyes!
Oh, you're all here.
Mrs. Pham!
Have you thought about
our little talk yesterday?
Hey, we're in business again.
I'm sick.
But who's to know that?
Wouldn't you like to earn
5 US dollars a time?
This is no way for you to live.
Let me take you there tonight.
A few years ago, whan I was dasperate,
I went with a Korean soldier,
and had Second Brother.
Cam Nuong isn't young any more.
What if she finds out?
Hurry up!
I'm sorry about this morning.
It's alright, I telephoned Officer Nguyen...
and he told me you preferred
to work alone.
That's right.
I arranged for you to visit a school today.
I had no office work,
so I've been waiting for you.
You've been here all day?
Did you get any good pictures?
Very good!
Mr. Akutagawa, even though I'm not
accompanying you...
you're still my responsibility
as long as you're here.
If you need my help with anything,
please contact me.
I will.
Then I won't keep you any longer.
Goodbye.
Sister, mommy isn't back yet.
I'm hungry. I want some noodles.
Be patient.
Look, Sister, mommy's cooked
some rice and vegetables!
Strange... Where did she the money?
Borrowed it!
I'll get some bowls.
Don't forget Daddy.
Come on, put me down.
Remember Daddy.
Daddy!
How did you know I'd be here?
Ah Nhac brought me here.
What are those people doing?
They're Chinese. The government
wants them to register.
Hey, what are you doing? No photos!
Who are you?
A reporter from Japan.
Show me your pass.
In order? Believe me now?
Got any ciggies? Give me one.
That's okay.
Hey, you haven't paid me yet...
you haven't paid!
Damn it!
Park the bike without paying money.
My mother ran a stall
until she fell ill.
I want to run one myself,
when I've saved enough.
But it's tough.
Gotta get up at 5 to buy
the vegetables wholesale.
What's wrong with your mother?
I don't know.
I think she misses Dad too much.
They loved each other very much.
When did your father die?
In the war, just a month
before Liberation.
He was in the army.
Mom had just Second Brother.
Sir, buy some monkey brain.
It's fresh, and the price is reasonable.
Quick. The suger-cane stall
will be closed!
How much?
60 cents for a bundle.
It was cheaper yesterday.
It's not expensive. He's charging
more over there!
Go and ask him if you don't believe.
I have the sweetest cane.
If you're not buying, I'll close.
It'll be 80 cents tomorrow.
No, bargain with him!
Bargain? We've bargained already.
I'll sell these on the main road later.
Wanna come?
Yes, I'll keep an eye on you.
Out of sight, quick.
They're taking strong men.
Damn, I dropped my basket.
If you want photos, go upstairs.
Come with me.
Come on up!
Why don't you photograph
the sea and clouds?
Why photograph people?
They're so ugly.
Who's ugly?
People don't look good.
Sometimes they do. That's why
I photograph them.
I need to piss. Don't watch.
It feels real good to piss in the sea.
Take you... you're quite good-looking.
Is your mother rich?
I have no mother.
How about your father?
The Americans killed my whole family
in the war.
I was only one year old.
I was raised in an orphanage.
So you were very poor.
How come you're so well off now?
I left the orphanage at 15
I studied and got a part-time job
at the newspaper.
It's a good job. Lots of travel.
But I'm not rich.
I hope I'll grow up like you.
Not taking pictures, but traveling all over.
No reason why not.
Be sure to look up when you come to Tokyo.
Ah Nhac, Ah Nhac!
They'll send you to the Economic Zones.
You saw, the door was sealed up.
No-one lives there.
Come on!
What you got there?
Waiter!
What do you want?
Two bowls of noodles, one to go.
Ok, just a few minutes.
Take one back for Second Brother.
See you tomorrow!
Bye!
Are you coming to the chicken farm?
What chicken farm?
Come with me!
This is still okay. The used-clothes place
would take it.
They search the bodies
before they shoot them.
Even the gold teeth are gone.
Dad, you should check his arse
for gold bars.
To Minh! You're back!
How did you get out?
I hurt my leg. They let me out
to get it treated.
This is To Minh.
He's been in a New Economic Zones.
Hi.
Who's he?
A Japanese reporter.
He's photographing my sister.
Look, a Nikon,
I could get 1,000 US for that.
I could get 1,500 for it.
You're my teacher!
I thought you wanted photos.
Why not take some?
Get clicking!
This is Akutagawa.
Do sit down.
Please!
What will you have?
A beer!
No, no beer today.
She has all kinds of spirits,
hidden away.
Today we'll have whiskey.
Fine!
Guess how old she is?
Thirty?
Past forty. You'd never guess.
She's Chinese. Her mother was
in the same line.
When the Japanese took Saigon,
she lived with a general.
When she was only 14 herself...
she was living with a French general.
When the French pulled out,
she moved on to Americans.
Can you imagine?
She still has figure of a 14-year-old.
It's as if all those French
and Americans...
never left a trace on her.
But she did learn
how to cook French good.
Her mother taught her Japanese cooking...
and how to make American hamburgers.
Steak tonight. Is that alright.
She gets steaks from the French Embassy.
How do you like it done?
Same as usual for you?
Tell me, who did you give
your virginity to?
A Chinese!
She gave the Chinese her best.
She can only do black-market business.
She has many connections,
but how long can she survive?
Maybe someone more powerful than me...
will share my taste for
her French cooking.
Sorry, I am serving these all at once.
Good vintage, 1968.
- Please help yourselves.
- Thank you!
Nice wine. Come on.
Serve yourself.
Enjoy the food.
Excuse me, where's the toilet?
Through the back.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
Today I watched two kids
help an old man carry corpses.
They had just been executed.
What do you want me to do?
Nevermind.
Don't waste it. I can still
sell it tomorrow.
I should pay you for
the photo I'm taking, Cam Nuong.
I'll give you enough to start
your market stall...
but don't go to
the chicken farm any more.
The old man at the chicken farm
is good to us.
You should't hang around
a place like that.
We're later. Only a few small fish left.
This one isn't bad!
It's very expensive.
How much?
Two dollars per catty.
So expensive!
My Dad used to like fish.
Me too. Weigh it!
Won't let you pay.
Alright.
One catty, ten ounces. Call it 3 dollars.
Two and a half... Leave it.
Wait... I'm going to close, it's a deal.
Ah Nhac will be pleased to see this.
Ah Nhac! Ah Nhac!
Sister!
Ah Nhac, we got a fish!
I'll be right there.
Ah Nhac...
Ah Nhac!
Cam Nuong!
Sister.
What do you mean, I'm too young.
I'm past 30.
I've been a revolutionary for 20 years.
Nothing to say?
Still hung up on Nguyen? Bitch!
I take this.
There's 2,000 dollars.
Enough for me, but not for Ah Thanh too.
I have more money coming,
if you can wait...
If I don't go back tomorrow...
they'll give me land-mine duty
as punishment.
It wouldn't count for anything then.
What, then?
Raise what you can,
I'll manage the rest somehow.
Comrade Vu will wonder
where this same from.
I want sausage and noodles.
Want the lot?
Three bowls of noodles,
one dish of chicken, one of sausage.
Right!
Cam Nuong, have you thought about
your market-stall?
When do you want to start it?
Maybe you'd have to work too hard.
Did you think of moving to
a New Economic Zone?
That's not for us.
Why not?
We're not bad elements.
We can earn a living here.
But things are tough for you here.
And I've seen how happy
the kids are in the N.E.Z.
You might be better off there.
And the change would be good
for your mother.
Don't drag my mother into it!
If the N.E.Z. Is so great,
why do bad guys get sent there?
Where are you going?
To the chicken farm.
More executions today.
You're taking Second Brother there?
Leave us alone, will you?
He's been there many times before.
Go away.
Don't you want to take him
handling the bodies?
You bring us bad luck!
That's why Ah Nhac died!
Go away, I don't want to see you again.
You're from a New Economic Zone?
How is it?
Not bad. Plenty of fresh air.
I've been there. It's better than that.
Which N.E.Z. Did you visit?
No. 16!
What's so funny?
That's the model one.
What do you mean?
It's the one that
foreign friends get to see.
They've trained the children there.
They all liked happy and healthy, right?
How do you know?
I was in No.15,
just over the mountain.
I thought that was an army camp.
You thought wrong.
What kind of work did you do there?
The lucky ones get farm work,
the rest dig for land-mines.
Why did they send you there?
I was a translator for the US Army.
Can you get this back to the bar for me?
Tell her I won't need it
on land-mine duty.
Anyway, it's not enough!
What was it for?
Easy-exit money.
You want to leave Vietnam?
Yes!
Now I see why
you wanted my camera so much.
You wanted it even more.
You fought for it...
as if it was your life itself!
If you can't get it back to her,
keep it yourself.
It'll cover your medical bill.
Akutagawa Shiomi, Japanese.
Yes!
I'm so sorry this has happened.
The police only just informed us.
How were you treated?
Fine, like a VIP.
They sat your head is hurt.
- Do you need a doctor?
- Yes.
No, it's just a scratch.
Actually, It's my responsibility.
If I had been with you...
it would never have happened.
It wasn't his fault. I know him.
He was broke.
I hope he won't be punished too severelt.
There'll be an open trial tomorrow.
Your camera seems to have survived.
Japanese products can take knocks.
You must be hungry.
Come, there's a good dinner waiting.
Driver, stop the car.
I'm sorry about the dinner,
but I must see a friend.
As you wish!
Uncle, Sister says you like noodles.
Her name is Cam Nuong. She's 14.
Akutagawa has been with her
a lot this week.
Three days ago, her brother
blew himself up...
He was foraging for scrap metal.
The photos he's been taking
could be damaging to us.
Any sexual relationship between them?
No, but the girl's mother
is a prostitute.
Sit down!
I've come from To Minh's trial.
He got ten years hard labour.
I know!
He asked me to bring this to you.
It was his fate.
You think he should stay in Vietnam.
I believe in fate.
I didn't know how much he needed it.
Don't feel quilty, it was for his friend.
He had enough for himself.
I want to see the N.E.Z.
Where they've sent him.
Can you help me get a pass?
Why not ask Officer Nguyen?
I've trouble him a lot already.
I can arrange it.
You help me by taking the money back
to To Minh.
Together with more for his friend.
Good. So you think he can change his fate!
He brought me a lot of trade.
He used to bring all the Gls
in town here.
All the bra-girls here liked him.
He dreams of opening his own bar
in New Orleans!
He wants me to run it.
He says I can work till I'm 70.
Mr. Akutagawa!
Comrade Vu!
Sorry to interrupt you.
We've finished our talk. I have to go.
There should be more places
like this in Danang.
Goodbye, Mr. Akutagawa.
Clever man, that Japanese.
How did he find way here?
Did Nguyen bring him?
Why was he here?
He wants a pass
to visit the N.E.Z.
Hasn't he been once?
He'll have to ask Nguyen.
He needs someone more powerful.
What does he expect to see in the N.E. Z?
This Japanese fancies himself
as a revolutionary.
I think he's trying to stir shit.
You can't take the camera.
I have special permission.
I don't care if you do.
Look after it for me.
Will you come back?
Of course. We're going to
open a stall together.
I'm sorry!
None of your business.
Get on... right, off you go!
Leave me alone!
Hey, he has a fever.
1001, 1006,
1009, 1010
1012, 1016...
Is there a doctor here?
Yes!
Where's the doctor?
Report first.
Right now!
To Minh, what is it?
What happened?
He needs a doctor!
What are you doing?
Let him go.
Who's that guy?
A Japanese reporter. The Cultural Bureau
gave him a pass.
You're kidding!
What's To Minh been doing?
His leg is still bad.
I gave him special convalescence leave.
How come he's worse than before?
It's all over for us, Ah Thanh.
Don't be dumb!
Doctor...
You're flooding the place.
He's in agony!
I'll do what I can. Where's the pain?
His wound is inflamed.
Hold him still.
No anaesthetic?
You go to town to buy it.
He's alright now.
Easy-exit money?
What do you think your life is worth?
Why did I let you go for treatment?
Back outside!
I don't care who you are,
Japanese reporter.
The Cultural Bureau has
nojurisdiction here.
Leave now.
I've seen all I want.
Shit, I can have you charged
as an accomlice.
She asked me to give this back to you.
She says she has go to Miami,
to run your bar...
until she's 70.
She got the money for Ah thanh too.
You must find a way to escape.
It's New Orleans.
Right!
Mr. Akutagawa,
you should have warned me.
Welcome.
I'm just passing.
On my way back from visiting No.15.
Good, I'll go wake the children.
The old man passed on.
They're such good boots.
Too good to be buried with him,
don't you agree?
You're back.
Didn't expect to see you again.
Mr. Akutagawa, why not
sit down and have a coffee?
You went to my home?
Did Mom tell you I was here?
Is Second Brother asleep yet?
He messed with your camera all day.
So I put it on
Dad's memorial tablet.
Mrs. Pham has just opened
this coffee stall.
I'm selling sugar-cane by day,
and helping here at night.
I'm saving,
so that Mom can see a doctor.
Don't worry yourself about
us and more.
You don't want to send us to
the N.E.Z. any more?
No.
Where are we going?
I'm taking you home.
I want to come to your hotel.
Why?
I've never been to one.
Pretty good here.
So this is what hotels are like.
Cam Nuong. I promised to help you
start a stall.
Should be enough here for that,
and for the doctor.
But promise you won't go back
to the coffee-stall.
Promise me. Not to the
chicken farm eother.
I can earn a lot more at the coffee-stall.
Alright, I know, I won't go there again.
Is it true that Japanese men
beat their wives?
Who told you that?
Everyone says so.
Not true!
I want to use the toilet.
Low water-pressure. Must flush twice.
Okay!
Why are there beer-cans in the tank?
The waiter hid them there.
There're black market.
Do you want one now?
What are you doing?
I must wash my feet.
Why?
I'll get bed-clothes dirty.
Are you crazy?
I've married since 18.
At your dad's age.
I'm taking you home.
What is it?
Oh, it's you. The Commander took
your gold leaf.
What do you want?
If that shits, I'll make you eat it!
This is for you, plus this.
To cover me and Ah Thanh.
The usual deal, half in advance.
Heard any bangs recently?
No refund if Ah Thanh
blows himself up.
Don't you worry, we'll make it.
When's the next boat?
You're lucky. Three days from now.
1001, 1006,
1009, 1010...
1012, 1216,
1021, 1024...
1026, 1029
Two dead, one seriously injured, sir.
You six, move the bodies.
You! You!
Why me?
You're later, that's why!
You!
Just three more days, Ah Thanh.
Hey, Cam Nuong!
I made two dollars more today.
You're a good businesswoman!
You smoke?
Ah Nhac taught me to.
Mr. Akutagawa!
I was just looking for you!
What is it?
Only five days left on your visa.
Shall I get it extended for you?
No need,
I've got what I want already.
Thank you!
Right, well, I won't keep you.
Well?
He's going to leave.
What about his photos?
You're leaving?
Ah Thanh... Ah Thanh...
You alright?
You guys seen enough?
Back to work.
On to the truck.
Nothing to see, back to work.
Ah Thanh!
What the hell is all this noise?
The cash?
And Ah Thanh's share?
I reserved him a place.
It's all here!
Tell the boat's captain I sent you.
He'll let you on.
Wait for me! I'm from No.15!
Wait!
Wait! Wait for me...
Over here!
Hold me.
I want to have salted egg.
Mr. Akutagawa has invited
for western food.
I don't like western food.
Don't be silly, you've
never tried it.
Over here!
Are we late?
No, I just got here.
Sit down!
I want salted egg.
Don't play with your knife. Be good.
I've already ordered
roast chicken, fried fish
soup, and ice cream.
How's that? Alright?
Waiter, can we have the
three lunches now, please.
Right away.
Got enough money left
to pay for all that?
You've given me most of
what you had.
Don't worry, I have some savings!
Good day!
You startled me.
I forgot there was a compatriot around!
- Let have breakfast together.
- Can I?
Please take a seat.
These are your little
Vietnamese friends?
Sister and bother. She's Cam Nuong,
he's Van Lang.
This is my Japanese friend, Inoue-san.
Do sit down
I'm very happy to meet you.
Want a beer?
No, I have work to do.
You went to another N.E.Z.?
How was it?
I was tricked.
How about your photo-project?
They're the reality.
I envy you, going home.
Goodbye, little friends.
- Is he from Tokyo too?
- Yes.
Is that what you do in Tokyo?
Yes, we do that in Tokyo all the time.
The Japanese like bowing.
But I can't
describe Tokyo to you.
You'll have to come to see for yourselves.
Uncle, where is the roast chicken?
Come home with us.
Leave me alone.
You're old enough to walk by yourself.
Don't worry, I don't mind.
He says he like it.
Clear away!
What's happening?
Why are you taking my Mom?
Ask your mother to tell you!
Mom!
Speak up, admit what you are.
Confess to your daughter
and your neighbours.
You were shameless to be a hooker.
And broke our law and order.
Why not just admit it openly?
Mommy!
Mom!
Say goodbye to Mommy.
Mommy, goodbye!
Although your mother did act crime.
But the country will
offer her a chance to reform.
She shouldn't avoid
her responsibilities.
You don't have to worry about your future.
The country will put your brother
in an orphanage.
And we will send you to N.E.Z. very quickly.
It's alright, it's Officer Nguyen.
He's drunk too much.
Tonight is his last dinner here.
Tomorrow he transfers to the N.E.Z.
At Mao Nam.
To do what?
Depends on Hanoi.
If he's lucky, he'll be a Commander.
How is Cam Nuong?
They need to get out of Vietnam.
Can you help them?
There's a boat every day.
I know one captain.
But it'll be expensive.
Take my camera and lens.
Must be worth a few thousand.
But it must be by the day after tomorrow.
I'm leaving then.
I hope I can see them off before I go.
I'll do my best.
I'll need some cash too.
I have some. Come by tomorrow.
You are not leaving yet?
Three days later.
Thank you for all your hospitality.
You're an artist.
All artists are my friends.
I have to leave myself.
Remember that time you wanted
to take my photo?
You can do it now.
I don't have my camera.
You wanted a photo of my scar.
I'm sure my photo
would make your collection more popular.
Comrade Nguyen, congratulations.
You've been appointed.
Commander of the N.E.Z. At Mao Nam.
The car is waiting. Let's go.
Let me get dressed.
Why bother, you look fine as you are.
There are scents as fresh as innocent children.
Mixed with rich, triumphant, corrupted scents.
We are true comrades, you and me.
Mr. Akutagawa, to be
a true revolutionary...
you must reject
petty-bourgeois emotions!
You have three more days here.
Right, I came here to say Goodbye.
Goodbye!
Goodbye, Akutagawa-san.
If you see To Minh,
tell him not to forget the bar
in New Orleans.
I'll be working till I'm 70.
I will.
I'm frightened, Sister. Hold me!
What's that, Uncle?
Diesel oil. Can you lift it?
I'm not strong enough.
You'll have to eat more then, won't you?
You'll need these papers for the boat.
And you'll need this US money.
Keep it safe.
The boat you're on is very reliable.
They asked you to bring
one can of diesel.
I'll take it for you.
Second Brother, do you like the way
your sister sings?
Yes!
Ask her to sing again.
Sing it again, Sister.
Stop! Who's there?
- Stop... - Don't go...
Run to the boat. Now!
Over there.
Who are you?
I'm Japanese.
What are you doing here? Your ID?
What are you doing out this late?
I couldn't sleep.
Comrade.
I've been here a month
but I can't find a woman?
Mr. Akutagawa, this is not
a safe district.
It's very late. You'd better
go back to your hotel.
Papers, Okay, where's your diesel oil?
It's coming, right behind us.
You can't go without it.
Don't block the way.
Papers!
Stop running!
Sail!
Get aboard!
Cast off!