(Woman screams)
(Woman 1 ) I am there.
- (Woman 2) Is she in contact?
- (Man) Shh.
(Woman 1 )Yes, I am there.
(Laboured breathing)
I see.
(Object fluttering)
There's the contact.
She's just entered... into contact.
She's entered... into contact.
- Into contact.
- (Woman 1 breathing heavily)
(Screams)
(Spirits moaning)
The dead! I see the dead!
The city of the dead!
(Gasping)
But...
No! Hold the link.
Don't break it.
Hold it. It's critical for Mary.
Don't break the link. Don't break it.
(Screams)
Mary! Mary!
(Gasping)
(Spirits moaning, muttering)
(Screaming)
(Muttering continues)
(Spirits moaning)
(Rope creaking on branch)
I'm afraid Mary's dead.
No! (Sobbing)
No! No!
(Sobbing) Mary! Mary!
(Siren wailing)
All right.
Maybe I've got no imagination,
but your story
is a little tough to swallow.
James McLuhan.
Busted twice
for peddling and possession.
That's right. So?
And you expect me to believe
that Mary Woodhouse
died out of sheer fright
while you were having a séance?
Mm-hmm.
OK, fellas, you help us,
we'll help you.
What were you on?
Coke? Grass?
- Where's the stash? Down the toilet?
- (Woman) You don't deserve any help!
You're a comic-book version sergeant.
Well, look better
in your mug shot, you know?
The Great Theresa,
the master medium.
Yeah, for you,
it's all in the book of, uh...
Your book of... what's it again?
- Enoch.
- Yeah. Enoch.
According to you,
this poor girl is dead because of a book
that was written 4,000 years ago, correct?
That's right.
I would find such an unusual paradox
of tremendous appeal terribly stimulating
- if I were a sleuth.
- Hmm.
The explanation
in every detail of a crime
before it's been committed.
Lady, you're either on grass
or you're pulling my leg.
(Chuckles)
No. The problem is in your mind.
It can't accept the truth.
But I'll help you just the same.
- In the Book of Enoch, the killer is...
- Jesus! Sergeant, come here and look!
(Spirit moaning)
(Meaning)
(Sergeant) Who's playing games here?
Come out of the floor,
out of nowhere.
Who lives downstairs?
It's vacant.
Has been for 26 years.
- But how the heck did...
- Don't you start acting up, too.
It's only a prank,
and I'll find out what's behind it
even if I have to tear
the whole building apart.
Keep refusing the truth.
At this very precise moment,
in some other distant town,
horrendously awful things
are happening,
things that would shatter
your imagination.
(Bird squawking)
(Squawking continues)
(Wind howling)
(Muttering)
(Door creaks)
(Chuckling)
(Squishing)
(Whimpering)
Hi, Officer. I'm, uh,
looking for Sergeant Clay.
-And who are you?
- Oh, I'm Peter Bell.
- You see, I'm with the New York...
- Don't tell me.
You're a newspaper reporter, right?
I can smell you guys a mile away.
You're right. I'm a journalist.
Look, there's this rumour
down at the station house that, uh,
well, someone kind of died mysteriously,
and I wanna talk to Sergeant Bell about it.
It's not gonna be any mystery
how the next guy dies
if I let any unauthorised people
in that house.
Look, uh... isn't there a way that, uh,
maybe you and I could come
to a gentlemen's agreement?
You're talking into my deaf ear, pal.
Now, take my advice and beat it
before the sergeant comes out.
(Sighs) OK.
I'll take your advice.
(Wind howling)
It's like we're in the wrong season suddenly.
Damn dust.
All these high winds.
Pretty unusual.
By the way, I hear Cindy Horan
never went home last night.
80? Ha, it sure wouldn't
be the first time.
- I remember once she was sitting in...
- (Rattling)
(Shatters loudly)
You know something?
Ever since Father Thomas
hanged himself,
Dunwich ain't been the same.
It's kind of scary.
Uh, a few beers, and you fellas start seeing
ghouls and devils all over the place.
Well, you saw what happened,
didn't you?
Sure, but that doesn't mean
there isn't any explanation.
Could've been a truck passing by,
a vibration.
Anyway, I've lost my mirror.
You forget who our ancestors were.
(Chuckles) No. I've forgot
how many beers you've drunk.
- So let's have another. House buys.
- (Rumbling)
- I got to go.
- But wait. What about the be...
- See you.
- Me too. Wait up, Mike.
- I'll see you around. So long.
- Now, wait. Mike! Ross!
Brand-new building,
new construction.
Tell you.
(Chuckles)
Build garbage like this.
I'm gonna lose all of my customers.
The language is risqué, I admit it,
but the overall message
couldn't have been more puritanical.
And, uh, why did you choose
the topic of incest?
When I was eight years old,
I wanted to marry my father.
I guess all girls that age
want to marry their fathers.
Anyway,
I got over it pretty quickly.
He was a drunk.
One day, he just picked up
and left my mother and me.
Did this leave any particular
emotional feeling in you at the time?
Emptiness.
That and pity for my mother.
- I began to hate all men, and I...
- (Door opens)
Excuse me, Gerry.
Oh, hi, Sandra.
- How are you?
- Hello, Emily.
Well, how come so early?
I mean, I thought
we'd made it for 8:00.
- That's the trouble. I can't make it tonight.
- Huh?
- I have to see Bob.
- Oh, Bob.
- You're not upset, are you?
- No, I'm not upset.
I may be a little worried perhaps.
I mean, you have been seeing
an awful lot of him, haven't you, lately?
Aw. (Chuckles)
- Poor Bob.
- Hmm?
He's a sick and lonely kid.
I don't see why people hate him so.
His mother was what you'd call
a woman of easy virtue.
No husband, no morals.
Here in Dunwich, anybody like that
is also branded a witch.
(Sighs) Look, Sandra,
I don't believe those idiots
who tell me that our ancestors
were Salem witch burners, all right?
OK, OK.
- Gerry, I am sorry.
- Don't worry.
- I'll see you tomorrow, around 9:00?
- Sure thing.
- Bye.
- So long, Sandra.
- Bye-bye. And take it easy.
(Laughs) Check. Bye.
Bye.
(Door closes)
(Sighs) OK, Sandra,
where were we?
On the same old problem - men.
Why do they have
to make life so difficult?
(Screams)
- (Shrieks)
- (Gerry) Sandra!
Sandra.
Did he hurt you?
Did he claw you?
Oh, he was just frightened.
Strange. It's the first time
he ever acted up like that.
(Gerry) He loves to have you pet him.
He always comes to you when you're here.
Something must have frightened him.
(Horn blaring)
(Man) Honey, you give me
the dirtiest thoughts.
I'm telling you, you're gonna end up
a dirty old man,
a pervert, peeping Tom.
Talk about box lunches. Man!
I saw a porno flick once
where this guy got so carried away,
he humped himself to death.
- Too much of a good thing.
- Yeah, but what a way to go.
Ah!
What's the matter?
Never see a body unearthed before?
- Any law against looking?
- Yeah.
OK. I'm leaving.
Stupid.
What time you got?
- Let's flip to see who goes in the hole.
- All right.
Call it.
- Heads.
- Tails. In the hole, sucker.
Oh, shit.
(: Whistling)
(I Whistling continues)
What are you still doing here, pal?
- Ah, come on, fellas.
- What do you want from us?
Nothing. I'm just curious
about this girl here, that's all.
Look, why don't you guys
go ahead with your work,
and, uh, pretend I'm not around.
Well, move,
cos we're almost finished.
(Grunts)
(Whirring)
(Casket hits ground)
(Grunting)
It's five o'clock.
We've bust our balls enough.
Let's go.
Amen.
Hey, hey.
You're not gonna... You're not gonna
leave her like that, are you?
Uh, union hours.
Anyways, what does she care?
She's not in any hurry.
Is she?
(Sighs)
(Gasping)
(Whimpering)
(Faint scream)
(Banging on casket, faint)
(Screams)
(Airplane passing overhead)
(Whimpering)
(Grunting)
(Gasping)
(Gasping slows)
(Gasping stops)
(Screams)
Oh, my God!
(Screaming, gasping)
(Gasps)
(Gasping continues)
(Screams)
(Whimpering)
(Whimpering continues)
(Screaming)
(Theresa) But for you,
Mary would have suffered a terrible death.
I was just lucky.
No. It was written.
Are you acquainted
with the Book of Enoch?
A text which dates back
to more than 4,000 years ago.
It contains man's first
recorded description of his...
his boundless mortal fear
in the face of malice itself.
A demanding, implacable enemy
whose search for blood is never satiated.
Mary, tell your experience -
everything you witnessed
during our last séance.
The city of the dead.
The living dead.
A cursed city
where the gates of hell
have been opened.
(Bell clears throat)
Where, uh...
Where exactly is this city?
I don't know where it is.
All I know is that it's called... Dunwich.
Well, I've never heard of it, uh...
How do you know?
I mean, how can you be so sure?
I read the name.
On a tombstone.
Mr Bell, if those gates are left open,
it may be the end of humanity.
We've got to try to get them shut again.
At midnight on Monday,
we go into All Saints' Day.
The Night of the Dead begins then.
And if the portals of hell
don't get shut before,
no dead body will ever be able
to rest in peace again.
And so the dead will rise up
and take over the Earth, and...
You must.
You've got to get to Dunwich.
You must re-close those gates.
(Faint squeaking)
Bob?
Bob, are you here?
(Gasps)
Bob?
Oh!
- (Bob whimpering)
- Bob?
(Whimpering, sobbing)
Bob! (Gasps)
Bob!
What's happened?
Did you hurt yourself?
(Loud meowing)
Oh!
(Yowling)
- Bob!
- (Yowling continues)
Bob! (Screams)
Bob!
Bob, don't leave me alone!
I'm afraid.
(Growling)
(Whimpering)
(Screaming)
(Muffled screaming)
(Phone rings)
Hello?
Ah, it's you, Mr Robbins.
No, Emily's not here, I'm afraid.
- What's that?
- She's usually home this hour of the night.
I hope nothing's happened to her.
There's been a lot of strange talk circulating.
Oh, come now, Mr Robbins.
Ignore it.
People here in this town thrive on that stuff.
You should know that by now.
She'll be home in another couple of minutes.
Ah, if you need me for any reason though,
feel free to call.
I should be at the studio
for at least another hour or so, OK?
(Laughs)
Goodbye, Mr Robbins. Goodbye.
(Wind howling)
(Breathing heavily)
No, no.
Come on, Tommy, please.
- No. Please, Tommy.
- Hey.
What the devil's the matter, honey?
You treat me like I was a stranger.
What have I done? Tell me.
How come you picked out here to park?
This place gives me the willies.
Oh, Rose, go on.
You're not a little child now.
You don't really believe in that
stupid Salem witch stuff, do you?
No, of course not.
(Low growling)
(Rose moaning, gasps)
- Now what's wrong?
- Sorry, Tommy, but...
I keep thinking that, like,
somebody's out there spying on us.
Come on.
There isn't anyone out there.
Watch.
I'll turn on the headlights.
(Gasping, whimpering)
(Engine rattling)
(Rattling)
(Rattling continues)
(Screams)
(Gagging)
(Door rattling)
(Retching)
(Growling, bone crunching)
(Screaming)
You know this Dunwich?
It's not even on the map.
So, you don't believe me, do you?
That's not the point.
Just gonna be harder to find, that's all.
We don't even know
where to start, do we?
You know, I get my inner visions, too,
you know?
Just let me meditate
over a bottle of scotch and, uh...
And?
I'll take you anywhere.
(Clanks)
(Indistinct police radio chatter)
(Man sobbing)
(Man) Well,
she certainly wasn't strangled.
Doesn't seem to have been
any kind of physical abuse.
- What was the cause of her death then?
- Some kind of cardiac arrest.
Only, that expression on her face
looks like pure fear,
- like something scared her to death.
- Scared her to...
Excuse me, Mr Robbins.
Do you know if your daughter
had a heart condition?
- No.
- No?
- No, no. She was...
- (Gerry) Mr Robbins.
- Oh, God. God! My little girl!
- Well, what's our procedure?
Sit tight. Everything depends
on the autopsy.
I'll sit tight.
You'll get your orders after that
from the D.A.
OK, but let me hear from you, Joe.
- What's your opinion, Gerry?
- (Sighs)
What's there to say?
I'm at a total loss.
It was... It was Bob.
That pervert.
You can bet on it.
They should've put him away for life after
what he tried to do with poor little Ann Ross.
Listen, I'll call out all cars
after that boy.
And I wouldn't be surprised if he could tell us
what happened to Rosie Kelvin
and Frank's kid, too.
(Officer) Sheriff Russell!
Sheriff, what the dickens is this?
(Squishing)
Good Lord.
That kid's gonna fry.
Mark my word.
(Horns blaring)
So, your, uh, newspaper editor
wouldn't believe you, huh?
Listen, when Adrian De Niro
told me about two years ago
that I'd meet a girl who'd been buried alive,
I didn't believe him either.
I mean, I laughed right in his face.
De Niro was aware of many things.
He knew all about the city of the dead.
OK. OK.
Say I believe you...
Did you see...
When you were in this trance,
did you see anything
besides that tombstone?
Oh, yes.
I saw a priest...
who, by hanging himself,
opened the gates of hell.
He must be destroyed.
(Woman) ...our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom
and the power and the glory.
(Sobs) Amen.
- The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want.
- This way, please.
He maketh me lie down
in green pastures.
Yea, though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of death...
Where is she?
- Where is my Emily?
- They're still preparing her, Mrs Robbins.
(Sobbing)
Mrs Holden.
- Mrs Holden?
- Yes.
Mrs Holden died last night
and according to Dr Thompson
was frightened to death.
Frightened to death?
- That's what he said. Fear.
- Of what?
Damned if I know, Doc.
It's the strangest thing I ever heard of.
Fear.
There's been talk that Rose Kelvin
and Tommy Fisher disappeared, too.
They went to the movies last night,
and nobody's seen them since.
That makes five people who've disappeared
in the last 48 hours.
I think it's Bob.
I don't believe in this
superstitious nonsense.
- Yeah. Maybe you're right.
- Sure.
Remember two years ago
when Bob took my little Ann into the woods?
It was a miracle we found them in time.
Yeah, well, I say it's him.
He's the one causing
all the trouble around here.
God only knows
what he did to poor Emily.
All I know is the air in Dunwich
is getting awful thick.
Soon as I can find somebody to buy
my shop and my house, I'm vamoosing.
You can bet your ass.
- (Mrs Robbins sobbing)
- Calm down, dear.
Take it easy. Calm down.
My baby.
My poor baby.
You'd... You'd...
You'd better take John-John out.
Yes, of course.
John-John, come on, let's go outside.
We'll take a walk.
You have to be strong now.
You have to find the courage
to face life, John-John.
You have to be a man now.
You know what I mean? Hmm?
(Gasping)
(Door squeaking)
- (Rumbling)
- (Gasps)
(Sobbing)
(Whimpering)
I'm hungry.
Good. There's a lollipop
in the glove box.
Look, I'm not joking.
I'm starved.
Look, you're the one that got me out here
in the armpit of the world, chasing your...
galloping cadavers.
Come on. Let's go have
a snack some place, huh?
OK.
You, uh, wanna give up?
Look, why don't you get in the car
and we'll go and check out the local cuisine.
(Sighs) Don't be upset.
Upset? Who's upset?
According to your theory,
we have less than 48 hours
before this, uh, All Saints' Day.
Oh, please, not now.
Do you mind?
Come on.
Let's go check out
the, uh, local cuisine, huh?
(Sighs)
(Growling)
- (Screaming)
- (Squashing)
(Screaming continues)
(Wind howling)
(Animal cackling)
(Squeaking)
(Low growling)
(Meaning)
(Meaning continues)
(Breathing heavily)
(John-John whimpering)
(Meaning)
(Owl hoots in distance)
(Whimpering)
Mommy!
Daddy! Mommy! Daddy!
Mommy! Mommy!
What's the matter, honey?
Emily's back.
I saw her looking in the window.
She wanted to catch me. (Sobbing)
Emily went away forever, John-John.
She's in heaven.
I saw her, I swear.
I saw her. I really did.
We'd better call the doctor.
I'm all right.
I don't need a doctor.
I don't want a doctor!
I saw her!
You've had a big day.
You're upset.
Hmm. We all are.
Off you go now. Go to bed.
I don't wanna go, Mommy.
I'm scared.
- Emily's gonna catch me. I know it.
- Oh!
(Clattering)
(Clattering continues)
(Phone rings)
(Sighs)
- Hello?
- It's me, Sandra.
You have to come right away.
No, there's no time to explain.
You wouldn't believe me anyway.
Just come, please.
I'm having a nervous breakdown.
Yes, UK, Sandra. Just calm down
and control yourself. What is it?
- (Moaning)
- There are only two possibilities.
Either I'm going out of my mind,
or something very,
very strange is happening.
Look, take it easy.
I'll be there in ten minutes, honey.
Bye.
(Breathing heavily)
(Owl hoots in distance)
(Sighs)
(Groans)
(Doorbell rings)
- Gerry, is that you?
- Yeah, it's me.
Come in.
What do you need that for?
I don't know.
Maybe a crucifix would be better.
A crucifix? What the hell
are you talking about?
(Sighs)
Tell me the truth.
- Do you consider me a basket case?
- No. Not at all. Why?
You're nurturing a pet neurosis.
That's all.
Like about 70%% of the female population
of this country.
80, according to you,
I'm not stark raving mad?
At least not yet.
Don't be silly, of course not.
Sometimes you may drink
a little more than you should,
but that's no reason to be taken away
and put into a loony house.
No. No, I'd rather not right now,
and you really shouldn't either.
All right.
You'd better see for yourself.
It's in the kitchen.
- The kitchen?
- Uh-huh.
(Exhales)
(Gasps) Oh, Christ.
Was I just imagining things?
No, it can't be. It's not...
Uh-huh. It's her.
Mrs Holden.
This morning she was inside
a coffin at the funeral home,
and now she's here in my kitchen.
How? How did she get here?
I don't know. I heard a noise. I came to look,
and there she was on my floor.
I called you right after.
I thought I was losing my mind.
OK. Let's use our heads
and not panic. Calm down.
We've got to find out
how she got here, all right?
I couldn't give a damn how she got here!
I just want her gone!
Look, let's get out of here.
I can't take the sight of her.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
(Sighs) At this point, a good, stiff drink
is the only medicine.
What are you gonna do?
Well, I don't believe
in the Twilight Zone,
so I guess I'll call the sheriff
on this matter.
-And what will you tell him?
- Well, exactly what you told me.
That you heard this noise,
that you came running and saw her there.
- And the rest is up to them.
- (Moaning)
(Gasps)
(Creaking)
(Gerry) What was that?
- (Low growling)
- (Breathing sharply)
(Door creaking)
(Gerry) It's half-closed.
We left it wide open.
What the...
Huh. Someone took her away.
Or maybe she just left.
Don't be ridiculous. Bodies don't get up
and walk away by themselves.
- (Clattering)
- (Gasps)
She's still here!
She's still in the house!
- (Screams) She's in here!
- Sandra.
- I know she's in the house.
- Sandra, get a hold of yourself.
- I don't want to see her anymore!
- Sandra, this is no way to...
- Gerry, get her out! Please!
- For God's sakes, calm down!
- Tell her to go!
- Yes. Yes.
She's in here! Do you hear her?
Gerry, she's in here!
- I can't take it anymore!
- OK, Sandra.
- (Clattering stops)
- Sandra, calm down.
- Calm down. Come on.
- You hear?
Calm down. Don't let your imagination
run away with you.
I don't know what the hell
is going on in here either, Sandra.
So we're gonna take it step by step
and search every room in the house,
all right?
And we'll find the reason. All right, Sandra?
Now you're gonna follow me.
Follow me now.
Come on now. That's it.
-All right?
-All right.
- OK.
- I'll do whatever you say.
(Light switch clicks)
- (Door opens)
- (Light switch clicks)
(Sighs)
I don't think I'll manage
to sleep here tonight.
Well, if you want to stay at my studio
or the house, you're always welcome.
- (Gasps)
- (Roaring)
- (Growling)
- (Sandra screams)
(Breathing sharply)
(Sandra) Wh...
(Exclaims)
(Gasping)
(Sandra moaning)
Good God, it's blood!
Blood! Oh!
Oh!
(Wind howling)
- (Priest) Dunwich?
- (Bell) Yeah.
-Yes, yes, I know it.
- (Church bells ringing)
- Odd that you're looking for Dunwich.
- Yeah, as a matter of fact, uh...
Yes, that's the town
where Father Thomas...
Terrible. Oh, terrible!
You know that Dunwich was built
on the ruins of the original Salem,
the village of witches
and heresy... and evil.
Yes, but, uh, can you tell us
how to get there?
It's not easy. You'll have to go back,
towards the highway.
And as you approach it,
there's a road going left.
- Mm-hmm.
- Blocked by a landslide.
- That will take you to Dunwich.
- Thanks a lot.
Uh, just out of curiosity...
(Chuckles nervously)
Why are you folks going down there?
- (Mary) Erm...
- Well, we're just looking up a friend.
Oh, I see.
Thanks again.
(Sighs)
The Lord help us.
(Groans)
(Groans, sighs)
Hey, Bob.
Hi,Ann.
What are you doing
in the back seat of my dad's car?
I didn't know where to sleep.
- You won't tell on me, will you?
- No, of course not.
Only, you get some awful weird ideas.
Come on. Smoke a little joint with me.
Only then you'd better split, OK?
- (Ross) Ann!
- (Gasps) It's him!
- Go on! Get out of here!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing, Dad. We were just...
- Get in the house! Get...!
- I... I can explain everything, Mr Ross!
- Shut up, you bastard!
(Whirring)
(Screams)
What were you trying to do
to my daughter? Huh?
Please let me explain, Mr Ross.
I was only looking for a place to sleep.
I swear!
- Pervert! Murderer!
- No! No.
No.
Oh!
(Grunting)
(Grunting continues)
No! No!
(Grunting)
(Panting)
(Screaming)
(Doorbell rings)
I guess there's nobody in.
That's strange.
What do you plan on doing?
I have a feeling
this is where the answer is.
We've got to find the undertaker
or someone from the funeral parlour.
Maybe they've gone to the cemetery.
You go.
I'll wait in your office.
I don't think I could take
a cemetery right now.
Fair enough.
(Bell) "Dweller of the twilight void."
That's heavy. Well?
Yes. That's it.
That's the very same tombstone
that I saw in my trance.
Great.
Welcome to the city of the dead.
Now what do we do?
We must find the priest's grave
and uncover him.
There isn't much time left.
All Saints' Day begins at midnight.
Well, where do we start?
OK. Well, it's gotta be
one of these.
You know, it's a good thing
he didn't hang himself in Arlington.
- (Bell) Hey!
- Yes?
Excuse me. Uh, I wonder
if you could give us some information.
Sure.
Well, we're, uh...
we're looking for a tombstone of a...
of a... of a priest
who hanged himself.
Father Thomas?
We don't know his name.
Well, why are you looking
for his burial site?
It's, uh...
It's a long story,
one you might not want to believe.
Try me. I'm just about ready
to believe anything at this point.
And that's the whole story.
My God in heaven.
The living dead.
And that's why you're here
in Dunwich?
(Gerry) What do you want to do?
What are you hoping to accomplish?
The death of Father Thomas
gave birth to some... some evil...
(Wood creaking)
(Sandra gasps)
(Wind howling)
- (Sandra) They're worms! Worms!
- (All grunting)
(Screaming)
(Screaming continues)
- (Howling stops)
- (Panting)
- (Maggots squishing)
- (All groaning, panting)
(Grunting continues)
(Grunting)
(Gasping, screaming)
(Phone rings)
Yeah? Who's speaking?
All right, John-John.
Now listen to me.
You take it easy, and you stay right there,
and don't move.
And I'll be right over.
What happened?
That was Emily's little brother,
John-John.
He just told me that Emily
killed her parents.
Emily died two days ago.
(Faint whimpering)
(Wind howling)
Gerry! Gerry!
- I'm scared, Gerry! I'm scared!
- (Gerry) Easy now.
It's all over.
Everything's going to be all right.
- Would you girls take care of him, please?
- (Sandra) Sure. Come on.
- My car?
- Yeah.
OK.
In you get.
God. God almighty.
Totally butchered.
Literally ripped to shreds,
those two.
You're sure it was Emily?
Yeah, but she was all different.
Emily was like...
She was like... She was dead.
And she was eating
Mommy and Daddy.
Poor kid.
You poor darling.
Gerry. Gerry, listen.
We got to go to the funeral parlour.
And then we got to look for that...
that grave of the priest.
-All right.
-Well?
- The kid all right?
- Scared to death.
John-John, it's all right.
- It's gonna be all right.
- (Engine starts)
It's all over now.
Now listen, Sandra.
Go to the studio with John-John, stay there,
and don't let him out of your sight.
- Yeah, sure.
- Not for any reason.
Listen, Gerry,
we'd better get a move on.
We only have a couple hours
before All Saints' Day.
- God knows what else could happen.
- (Engine starts)
(Animal cackling)
(Animal howls)
(Howling)
(Cackling)
- (Screaming)
- (Growling)
(Bone crunching)
(Squishing)
(Bellowing)
(Screaming)
(Grunting)
(Panting)
(Breathing heavily)
(Meaning)
Emily!
No!
No! No!
- (Bellowing moan)
- Go away! No!
Go away!
No! Emily!
. No!
(-Panting)
- Oh, John-John, thank God you're safe, boy.
- (Meaning stops)
Listen, there's a police car around
the corner. Mary's there, too.
- You go straight to it. Go!
- (Gasps)
(Bellowing moaning)
(Meaning continues)
- (Moaning stops)
- (Wind howling)
Yeah, I'm in car two with Sheriff Russell.
We're on Main Street.
(Bell) We got to go look
for Father Thomas's grave.
You want some of my men?
No, I think it'd be better
if you, uh, took care of the kid.
- All right. I'll take care of the kid.
- Do what the sheriff tells you, OK?
- Mary?
- Coming.
- (Officer) ...so you stay in touch, huh?
- (Man on radio) "You bet, buddy."
- Did he call?
- Yeah.
Let's get going.
(Gate creaks)
(Radio) "We interrupt this programme
to bring you a special broadcast.
"Dunwich police authorities
have declared a state of emergency,
"effective immediately
within Dunwich County.
"All citizens are requested to return
to their homes as quickly as possible.
"In case of necessity,
contact this station -
"radio WD-WC.
"The telephone number
is 825-9881.
"All citizens are urged to remain calm
and to follow all instructions to the letter.
- "We repeat..."
- Mind telling me what's going on?
The dead are leaving their tombs.
- Ah, that's a load of crap.
- Crap or not, I'm taking my money.
I'm closing my doors
till tomorrow morning,
- and I'm not opening for anybody.
- (Door clatters)
- (Meaning)
- (Scraping)
(Radio) "Effective immediately
within Dunwich County.
"All citizens are requested to return
to their homes as quickly as possible."
- (Creaking, scraping)
- (Man on radio continues)
(Meaning)
(Loud rustling)
- (Rustling continues)
- (Creatures howling)
- (Creature shrieks)
- (Animal cackling)
- (Rustling continues)
- (Animal sounds continue)
(Animal cackling)
(Sighs)
(Loud rustling)
I believe Father Thomas is buried
in his family tomb over there.
(Cackling continues)
(Rustling)
Guess what.
It's All Saints' Day.
- (Rustling continues)
- (Animals howling, cackling)
(Meaning)
(Gasping)
(Bellowing moan)
(Gasping continues)
(Whimpers)
Oh, no!
- (Gasping)
- (Meaning)
(Gasping continues)
(Meaning continues)
(Gasps)
Argh!
Well...
(Sighs) The Thomas family tomb.
Now what?
- I wish I had a cigar.
- Shall we open it?
Lady had a vision.
You're sure? Mary?
Ready?
Oh, boy. Here we go.
- (All Grunting)
- (Scraping)
That's it.
(Animal cackling)
Be careful.
Here you go.
Thanks.
(Distant dripping)
Oh! Oh.
(Gasps)
(Grunts)
(Grunting)
- (Screaming)
- (Rat squeaking)
- Oh!
- (Gasping)
(Squeaking continues)
Hold on to this
and let me try to give Bell a hand.
(Mary) For God's sake, hurry.
It's past midnight.
(Grunting)
My God. Someone must have
broken in from the other side.
- Or broken out.
- (Exhales)
Well, now what do we do?
- I want to go take a look. Give me a hand.
- (Crowbars clatter on ground)
(Grunting)
(Radio) "Having received no further bulletins
on police emergency operations,
"which are still in progress,
"we can only confirm
our previous special broadcast.
"Citizens are requested
to remain in their homes.
"Under no circumstances should anyone try
to reach the state turnpike.
"We repeat - do not panic.
Remain in your homes.
"Stay tuned to WD-WC
for further bulletins.
"For those who have just tuned in,
we repeat our previous bulletin.
"Dunwich police authorities
have declared a state of emergency,
"effective immediately
in Dunwich County.
"All citizens..."
(Breathing heavily)
- (Gasps, screams)
- (Squeaking)
(Gasps) No!
(Screaming)
(Sobbing)
Sandra.
- (Screaming)
- (Bone crunching)
(Rats squeaking)
Argh!
- (Panting)
- No.
No.
(Mary panting)
(Bellowing roar)
(Gurgling)
(Mary sobbing)
(Rustling)
(Low growling)
(Howling)
(Gasps)
(Bellowing)
(Corpses moaning)
(Wailing)
(Gasping wailing)
(Screams)
(Wailing continues)
(Wails)
(Birds chirping)
(Panting)
(Gasps) Mary!
- Gerry! Gerry!
- (Laughing)
(Both laughing)
- (Wind howling)
- (Gasps)
(Mary) No! No!
No!
(Screams)
(Thunderclap)