Ústřední Půjčovna Filmů
V Praze Presents
DAISIES
SCREENPLAY
STARRING
ALSO STARRING
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR
COSTUME DESIGN MAKE-UP
FILM EDITOR SOUND
SET DESIGN
PERFORMED BY UNDER
THE DIRECTION OF
PRODUCTION MANAGER
DIRECTOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY
DIRECTED BY
PRODUCED BY
- I can't even do this.
- So what can we do?
We can't do anything.
What are you doing?
Being a virgin. I look
like a virgin, don't I?
- I am a virgin!
- I see.
Can you understand that?
Nobody understands anything.
Nobody understands us!
Everything's going
bad in this world.
- What do you mean, everything?
- Well, everything...
In this world...
You know what?
- If everything's going bad...
- so...
we're going...
bad... as...
- well...
- Right!
Does it matter?
It doesn't matter.
What's that you've got?
What are you chewing? Show me!
What are you doing?
Is anything out there?
Come on.
Where to?
Someplace where
something's going on.
What next?
You should've been here yesterday.
It was such fun.
We can't manage everything.
We're always so busy.
What do you think of that?
Not bad. But not like that now.
Let's have a look.
Yeah...
OK, I'm going.
- At least have some wine.
- I don't know.
- Go on. What's on the wine list?
- Something special for you?
- A bottle of wine?
- No, just a glass.
That's our Jarmila!
Don't look!
So you're here?
It's nice here, isn't it?
So it's you?
My sister told me lots about you.
Won't you introduce me?
- I am the sister.
- Jarmila!
- Will the young lady be dining?
- And wining as well.
Another glass, please.
- Have you got snails?
- We don't.
- Nor rabbit?
- They've got venison.
No, that's too much. I
only want something small.
I'll have the chicken, then.
Is it big enough? One moment.
I'll have something
small to start with.
- Would you like some cakes?
- No, thank you. You have some.
Don't know...
Yes, we'll have that and that.
Don't be silly, have some.
She's scared she'll get fat.
Why aren't you eating?
- Are you on a diet?
- Well, you see...
- I couldn't bear that.
- I don't like sweet things.
I love food.
I love eating.
It's delicious.
- Have you got any little ones?
- I beg your pardon!
Isn't it hot here?
I'd say so. Here it is!
- How old are you?
- Why do you want to know?
Don't take it like that.
Do you smoke? Would you
offer me a cigarette?
I haven't finished yet!
You're spoiling her.
Do you have any filter-tips?
There you are, such filth...
The spoons are so heavy.
What time is your train?
In about 40 minutes!
40 minutes? Let's
hurry up, then.
The bill, please.
We'll be fine if we take a taxi.
- At least it hasn't gone yet.
- Would you get a paper for me?
I just don't understand.
- I told her you were an uncle...
- What do you mean, uncle?
- My boyfriend's uncle...
- What do you mean, boyfriend?
He lives in Jičín...
- She'll tell on me!
- What do you mean?
That I go around with old men!
- Here you are.
- Thank you and goodbye.
- Bye!
Sorry. He didn't want
to leave on his own.
Oh, my God.
Where does the train stop first?
This one?
Probably at the next stop.
I thought it was the
Orient Express!
Never mind. Bohemia's
beautiful too.
My Bohemia...
And who's going to pay for this?
Dead men tell no tales!
Only you forgot to
close the window!
You've got bandy legs.
Don't you know, this is the
essence of my personality?
Tie your legs up at the knees.
You've got to get some exercise.
Get me some water.
Rehabilitation centre.
Die! Die! Die!
Can't you smell it?
- What?
- How volatile life is!
Isn't it nice to be home?
- Why keep talking about it?
- Tell me it's nice to be home.
- So you mind!
- No, I don't mind.
80, say it's great.
I'll say what I like.
Maybe I'll even have a piano.
When I run around like you.
What?
Who's running around?
We've gone bad, haven't we?
And I've got a job, you nitwit!
You've spilt milk on yourself!
But you look smart!
Why do you want us to go bad?
- You know we're still maturing.
- How do you mean?
- When is it going?
- When is what going?
Let me fix that hanky of yours.
Marcelka told me you
were an explorer.
Hanky, hanky, big white hanky!
Our daddy would think
you're a baddy!
That's too much!
Don't take it like that. She's
had meningitis since birth.
And what about Blanka?
- How old's your old woman?
- I've had just about enough!
This is the fifth one to leave!
I'm fed up.
We have to think of
something better.
It's so extraordinary...
I wouldn't have
believed it possible.
Like a message from
another world...
But you're so earthly,
yet so heavenly!
You don't belong to this century.
Do you hear me?
Julie, please.
Don't be like this.
You should never have
come into my life!
Julie?
- Yes?
- Just a misunderstanding...
I don't know what's
happening to me today.
Don't treat me like
this when I love you.
I have no idea what you want.
Julie!
Now I know what love is!
I want this moment
to last forever!
Don't treat me like this!
Without you, my life is torture.
You've no idea what this means.
I must be in love with you.
Damn it!
- Julie!
- Have you got any food?
A bit of jam, at least...
- What have you been doing?
- How's life?
- Would you like some coffee?
- We're in a hurry today.
If only I was as young...
Oh, youth of mine, Why
run away with time
Why when I think of you, My
eyes fill with tears true
- Where are you off to?
- Out. It's no fun here today.
Don't leave me, my little girl
Be my friend...
Bye-bye.
Wait! Don't go.
Sit down. I'll make
you some coffee.
Look, an angel - and
she's not flying!
Look, she's got some money here!
She went to get us some sugar
and we've stolen from her!
What do you mean, we. I did!
So you're a thief!
Yes, I'm worse than you!
And it also means
that I'm a liar!
That's nothing.
Everyone does that.
No one can tell.
Come on.
Let's do something big, OK?
We're on fire!
- Julie, is that you?
- Yes, it's me.
Julie, I keep
thinking about you.
I must have fallen
in love with you.
You don't know what that sleepless
night with you means to me.
Julie, I keep waiting for you.
I'm afraid I might
never see you again.
Don't treat me like this
when you know I love you.
Are you there?
Are you upset with me?
Forgive me, but life
without you is torture.
You don't belong
to this century.
I love you Julie.
I wouldn't have
believed it possible!
Now I know what love is.
Another piece of meat?
- What are you doing?
- There's no meat around here.
What about this?
No, I only want fruit now.
What do you mean, fruit?
I don't understand you.
Say you'll come again.
Do you hear, Julie?
- I still fancy something.
- I can't hear you very well.
- Domestic fowl.
- I've fallen in love with you.
- A nice chicken.
- My little chicken!
- That's too big.
- A nice steak!
- Yes, a nice little steak!
- Oh, a nice piece of bread!
Yes, I've got some
nice bread at home.
Julie, I love you.
Say you won't treat me
like you did last time.
I wouldn't have
believed it possible.
It's never happened
to me before.
I think I know now what...
What are you doing?
What a shame!
What's his name?
You know, I have no idea.
I completely forgot to ask him.
But I've got his phone number.
- You going there?
- Of course!
Do this bit here.
Girls, you're all tatty.
All these frills!
What on Earth have
you been doing?
What's been keeping you?
How am I supposed to be able
to get rid of him on my own?
Watch out for bones.
Watch out for the bony bits!
Look out for phony bonies!
Fishy, fishier, fishiest!
Girlies! Girlies!
Hasn't the world gone bad?
Kiss me.
When's your train?
Look, rails!
I'm fed up.
I can't think of anything new.
We'll have to think of
a worse kind of life.
Aplt...
Augusta...
- Arsen.
- He's in jail, isn't he?
Right, now 'B':
Baggage...
That's too lyrical.
Beranek...
- What happened to Beranek?
- He got a job.
Coural...
Horrid!
I don't know that one.
I say horrid because we
haven't got anyone for 'H'.
- What are you doing?
- I can't read it.
It's Doda!
I see.
Who was it who kept saying,
"What will become of us?"
- The one who died?
- Yeah.
His signature must
be here somewhere.
Hansel's arrived.
Our Gretel's all het up...
Can you hear me? It's me, Hansel.
Open the door.
Please open the door.
I know you're there.
I must talk to you.
1 have to explain.
It was just a little
misunderstanding.
I keep thinking about you.
Open the door, Marie. He
keeps thinking about you.
Go on, open it, if he
Please.
He must be in love with you.
Don't start, if he keeps
thinking about you.
Marie.
He's got a nice
voice, this Johnny.
- Please open the door!
Johnny, Jack, John...
Do you love me, John?
Look, Hans, is there
anything to eat there?
Or perhaps you mind?
Who says I'm saying anything?
Give me his address, then.
Here's a little pen.
Legibly, OK?
I don't like you any more.
Nor I you.
But I mean it.
Really, not any more.
I don't like you at all.
Where are you off to?
- Where have you been?
- At the end.
At the end of what?
At the end of the pier.
- Come on.
- Where to?
Come on.
Ouch!
I told you to come!
- No!
- You have to smoke!
- How depraved!
- Indeed.
- Come on.
- Please.
Look, a butterfly!
That's what I don't understand.
Why do they say, "I love you"?
Do you understand?
Why don't they say,
for example, "egg"?
What a good idea!
Give me one.
I just meant it as an example.
Come on!
If it's something that matters.
So what's supposed to matter?
Do you really think it matters?
Matte rs?
Even when someone
doesn't exist any more?
You mean, when someone dies?
- Let's say you.
- Why me? What about you?
We're sitting here now.
Just imagine if it weren't us!
That would be stupid!
How do you know it's us?
- How do you know you exist?
- Because of you!
Of course!
Otherwise, it would be
difficult to prove with you.
You're not registered
here, you don't work...
There is no proof you exist.
There's nothing.
Is something there?
Let me see.
Something should be happening.
But what?
You're always rushing
off somewhere.
Roses red, roses red
How I love roses red
I want them for you, my beloved
I pick them to please you
For your blonde hair
a ring I shall weave
Roses, red, how I love thee
LADIES
Anything there?
We can try somewhere
else, can't we?
Does it matter?
It doesn't matter.
One should try everything!
"What... are... you...
staring... at?"
What is he doing?
He's going to water the garden.
Lucky guy!
What, getting up so early?
Nobody's paying any
attention to us!
What if we're lacking something?
People don't realise how
freezing it is in the morning.
What are you thinking about?
See how you look?
I wonder why that gardener
didn't notice us.
What are we doing here?
Why didn't he at
least tell us off?
He wasn't even sorry for us!
What an old fogey!
We're still young.
We're young and we've got our
whole lives ahead of us!
Know what worried me? That
we were invisible to him!
That's stupid!
I thought we'd evaporated!
So why didn't he notice us? Why
didn't the cyclists notice?
Why, I wonder?
Why is there water here? Why?
Why's there a river? Why?
Why, uncle?
Why am I cold? Why?
There you are. We do exist!
We exist, we exist...
It's nice to be home.
Die! Die! Die!
I'm on fire, you're on
fire, we're on fire.
Can you feel how
volatile life is?
Don't treat me like this if you
know I'm in love with you.
What will become of us?
There's no proof at all.
I'm lying here.
Just imagine if it weren't me...
We're not going on
any more walks, OK?
Right, no more walks!
IS this OK?
Too much!
Does it matter?
- Does it matter?
- It doesn't matter.
Let's go, there's nothing here.
Look, it says, "Nourishment"!
I'm hungry.
There might be
something up there.
- Yeah, cold!
- Let's go!
Quick, someone's coming!
Send us up!
TRANSPORTATION OF
PERSONS PROHIBITED
I've got pins and needles.
Are we here?
I'll go first.
This must be it.
- Where is it?
- What?
- That nourishment!
- Come on.
Come on.
One, two, three, four...
What are you drinking?
Wine.
What are you licking
off your finger?
Go carefully, so no one notices!
Look.
See, carefully.
This is interesting and piquant!
That is lovely!
Look at this animal,
it's got eyes!
This is a nice relish!
Why don't we use plates?
Let's lay out a banquet!
What now?
Canned button mushrooms!
Don't worry. Does it matter?
No, it doesn't matter.
- Did you try this green one?
- Which one?
We haven't got
anything to drink.
Quick, it's too heavy!
Johnnie!
Look! Little cakes!
These ones are better.
This is what I call a cake,
not that rubbish of yours.
Does it matter?
No, I don't!
A fashion show!
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
THEY COULD END UP.
Help!
IS THERE ANY WAY TO MEND
WHAT'S BEEN DESTROYED?
We're drowning!
We're shouting for help.
It's because we've gone bad!
Help!
- Help!
- Help us!
Help!
We don't want to be bad!
EVEN IF THEY HAD A CHANCE,
IT WOULD PROBABLY
LOOK LIKE THIS.
Let's clear all this up.
Quickly.
If we're good and hard-working,
we'll be happy...
We've got to tidy it up.
Let's make it all nice.
We'll be happy because
we're hard-working...
It still needs a
bit more here...
We'll be hard-working and
everything will be clean.
When we get everything done,
we'll be good and happy...
We'll be hard-working
and good...
Are you crazy?
It will be beautiful again,
all clean and tidy...
If we work hard, we'll
be happy and good!
We worked hard, didn't we?
Yes, we've put
everything to rights!
All nice again!
I'm happy!
I'm happy too!
We're both so happy!
Say that we're happy.
Is it just a game?
It isn't.
We're really happy!
But it doesn't matter!
THIS FILM IS DEDICATED
TO ALL THOSE
WHOSE SOLE SOURCE OF INDIGNATION
IS A TRAMPLED-ON TRIFLE.
THE END