Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Presented by BANDAI VISUAL
TV TOKYO and OFFICE KITANO
a TAKESHI KITANO film
We are ready.
It's time. Here goes.
"I beg you. Calm thyself.
Rashness will come to no good."
"Thou hast become enslaved
to such a miserable state of mind."
"Who hast led thee to such a state?"
"God have mercy. It is none other than I."
"I, Umekawa, is all to be blamed."
"Shall I be thankful to thee?"
"Or shall I pity thee?"
"Read thou my heart."
She beguiled him.
The tears she shed
fell on the gold coins.
And her tears shone like globeflowers
covered by dew.
It was indeed a sight,
which drew forth
pity from one's heart.
All the gold Chubei spent
was not his to possess.
Thus, glory was ephemeral.
Away they fled
to yonder and beyond
where their feet gulded them.
Producers
Masayuki MORI and Takio YOSHIDA
Starring
Miho KANNO
Hidetoshi NISHIJIMA
Tatsuya MIHASHI
Chieko MATSUBARA
Kyoko FUKADA
Tsutomu TAKESHIGE
Costumes by
Yohji YAMAMOTO
Music by
Joe HISAISHI
Directed, Written and Edited by
Takeshi KITANO
The bound beggars.
Bound beggars!
Well, hello.
Hi.
So, Matsumoto's bride isn't Sawako.
Evidently not.
When I got the invitation,
I thought they finally got hitched
but I was wrong.
He's marrying
our company president's daughter.
You're kidding.
The family seems to like him.
So, he's a Cinderella boy.
He's now a way ahead of us.
Whatever happened to Sawako?
Must have broken up nicely.
Never thought Matsumoto was such a guy.
Why not take the opportunity?
Yeah, the shortcut to success.
In 2 years, we'll have to
speak politely to him.
The president is kind enough to...
I'm already engaged.
Forget her. You're not married yet.
Think about your life.
Your father worked hard,
but with little success,
because he's not a college graduate.
Why do you think
he made you go to college?
Think it over.
It's about your life.
This is a great opportunity.
You must know that.
I can't leave her.
We'll go and apologize to her.
We'll beg her... do anything.
What?
Congratulations.
I'm happy for you.
Excuse me, sir.
You have a visitor.
She says she's Sawako's friend.
Hey.
What's up?
An old friend's here.
Forgot to invite him.
I see.
So, you chose success?
Sawako chose suicide.
She died?
No, she survived, but not completely.
She lost her sanity.
Doesn't even recognise me.
She's as good as dead.
Where is she now?
Hospital.
Which one?
She won't recognise you.
Sawako chose suicide.
It's delicious.
You can have more.
Whatever happened to him?
Heard he took off.
What about the wedding?
I guess it'll be cancelled.
Okay, collect the trash.
Put the trash in here. Okay.
Still some over there.
Why the hell did you
take off from the wedding?
The bride was in tears,
and the president was furious.
Can you lend me money?
What are you...
Whatever you have now.
What do you plan to do?
Better apologize quickly
or you'll be doomed.
Thanks a million.
I'll get in touch with you soon.
Hey, Matsumoto.
Where did you come from?
What's your name?
Sir... Your lady seems to be...
Don't leave the room by yourself.
You'll cause the hotel trouble.
I'll take care of everything.
Hello.
Yes... I understand...
Sorry, sorry.
Give them to me.
Yeah...
I know...
...But Sawako
isn't feeling so great.
I heard.
They say she's lost her mind.
Is it true?
Hello?... Hello?
Hello?
Hey, Matsumoto.
Are you from around here?
Where do you live?
Is anything the matter?
You know her?
Yes.
Can you pay for them?
Let me...
Come on...
Let me see them.
Do you want to try that out?
Go ahead.
Open it and try it.
Wait... Let me.
Like this.
Let me.
You blow it... Like this.
It's cold. Let's go in.
You'll catch cold.
Here.
Watch out, you morons.
What's wrong with you?
I'll buy you a new one.
Forgive me.
Boss, it's done.
We've finished loading.
Thank you very much.
We appreciate it.
We'll be off then.
It was his choice.
Boss.
He'll be guarding you.
I'm Ikeuchi, sir.
I'm starting today.
Is your mother well?
Yeah.
I see.
Yeah... Hey.
Thank you.
- Say hello to her.
- Sure.
That's my (yakuza) brother's son.
What's with those guys?
Some weirdos.
Excuse me.
Where did you say you came from?
The Takigawa Family, sir.
Oh, yeah... In Hiroshima, right?
How long have you been with us?
2 years, sir.
Is that right?
Not easy, is it?
Why did you become a yakuza?
When I was a kid,
I used to fight all the time.
Became a yakuza,
because I was bad.
Being strong in fights
doesn't mean anything nowadays.
Better use your head.
Being tough did mean something
...in the good ol' days.
After you ice him,
stay away from my place.
You have to kill even
your (yakuza) brother at times.
Go ahead.
Brother, you're killing me, too?
Sorry about it.
Do it.
Too bad... We were really close.
The doctor's here.
Oh, okay.
Damn quack. I can't tell
whether I'm getting better or worse.
He never says anything straight.
Maybe I haven't got
much time ahead of me.
Are you single?
No woman?
Not now.
How come?
Because women get in our way.
So you're an old fashioned chap, huh?
Am I?
I used to be like you.
- It's me.
- You surprised me.
Here. I made lunch for you, too.
Wow. This is terrific.
Will you eat it?
I will.
- Here.
- Thank you.
It certainly looks good.
- How is it?
- It's delicious.
I'm glad.
- I'm going out...
- Yes, sir.
- Take me to Saitama.
- Sir?
Today's Saturday, right?
Yes.
Brought them from the shop.
Won't they be angry?
No, these were left over.
Next Saturday, I'll make the lunches.
I might not be able to come next week.
Are you busy?
Yes... Well, no...
I'm thinking of quitting work.
Not much work at the factory
and it may go bankrupt.
I think I'll do the owner
a favour by quitting early.
He's a great guy,
and can't tell me to quit.
I see.
I'll find a more worthwhile job.
The way I am now,
I can't make you happy.
Being half-assed isn't good,
so it might be better...
to be alone for a while.
So, don't care about me, Ryoko,
and go your own way.
I'll come see you when I'm ready.
When I come I'll be dressed well, too.
You'll be surprised that
I've made something of myself.
Well, I'll be going.
See you.
Hiro!
I'll wait for you.
I'll make lunch,
and be here every Saturday.
I'll make lunch and wait for you.
I'll make lunch,
and be here every Saturday.
I'll make lunch and wait for you.
Wait here.
Yes, sir.
What is this place?
Don't ask me such things.
Sorry.
The woman in question.
Who?
She comes here every Saturday
at noon with 2 box-lunches
and waits for her beau.
Excuse me. May we sit here?
I'm sorry. I promised to eat lunch
with my boyfriend here.
Can you keep it vacant?
Thank you.
Hey, there hasn't been any bites.
Sorry, sir.
How come there's no bites here?
- Sorry, sir.
- Forget the sorry, sir
Hey, did you put bait on my line?
Yes, tangerine.
- Tangerine?
- Yes, sir.
Tangerine as bait?
Yes, sir.
- For fish?
- Yes, sir.
How can you catch fish
with tangerine, you moron?
This is ridiculous. Let's go.
Hey. It flew away.
Got you.
Fans often come here.
A Mr.Aoki came
to see her the other day.
She refused.
She doesn't want to show her face.
No offense. You're blind
so she won't mind you.
You'd be satisfied
hearing her voice, wouldn't you?
"They say girls become pretty,
when they're in love
Is it really so?
I hope it's true
You can be shy
You can be bashful
But when you're in love
Your eyes sparkle
Eyes meet and ignite the fire
That's when love begins
Glancing each other
That's when the beam flashes
Ma-me-mi-mu-me-mo
Magical beam
Eyes meet and ignite the fire
That's when love begins
Glancing each other
That's when the beam flashes
Ma-me-mi-mu-me-mo
Magical beam
Magical beam"
The one who was running...
Was that Nukui?
He's the oldest groupie, right?
For how long?
About 4 years...
So is the kid in red.
Kid in red? They're grown ups.
Well, we should be grateful to them.
But be careful. They can be dangerous.
The Tokyo Stock Market
witnessed continual falls in...
The Garden Hotel's liabilities
prove to be...
Hey, are you watching the traffic?
Don't put this crap on your uniform.
Watch carefully, you jerk.
"They say girls become pretty
When they're in love
Is it really so?
I hope it's true
You can be shy
You can be bashful
But when you're in love
Your eyes sparkle
Eyes meet and ignite the fire
That's when love begins"
If you don't mind,
this box-lunch was left over,
so please eat it.
Thanks as always.
I'd be happy to.
Here...
Thank you very much.
My pleasure.
- Here.
- Thanks. This is for you.
Thank you.
I wish you luck.
Haruna Yamaguchi
In-Store Promotion
- Here.
- For you.
Thank you.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Can you address it to me?
Sure. Mr.Aoki, right?
- Yes!
- Thanks for your support.
- Here.
- This is for you.
Can you address it to me?
Sure. Mr.Aoki, right?
- Yes!
- Thanks for your support.
3 Girls Drowned... 2 Dead
Pop Idol Haruna Yamaguchi
involved in a car accident...
Accident
Pop Idol Haruna Yamaguchi
involved in a car accident...
Will she live?
I just got here.
- What's the cause?
- You've seen her?
- No, not yet.
- No visitors allowed?
- Pardon?
I don't know.
I'll tell you all I know at present.
At about 11:20 last night,
on the way from Odaiba
avoiding another car
her car crashed into a power terminal.
Who was driving the car?
Will she return to work?
- When is it?
- Don't know.
A press conference?
There are other patients here, too.
When's the P.C.?
This is a hospital.
Message to her fans.
Please leave. This is a hospital.
As I told you earlier, I don't know.
Please leave for now.
I'll tell you when I know.
You haven't...?
My daughter's not home.
She's retired.
I don't think she'll see anyone.
Can't I write her a note?
Well... I guess so... Wait a minute.
Here.
Thank you.
- Can you address it to me?
- Sure. Mr.Aoki, right?
- Yes.
- Thanks for your support.
Wait here.
She's right there.
Yes, ma'am.
Haruna.
Your fan from Tokyo
has come to visit you.
I told you I'm not seeing any fans.
I don't want fans to see this face.
But this person is blind.
What?
Okay?
She's in front of you.
You're Mr. Nukui, right?
Yes.
What happened to your eyes?
I thought it would be better
if I hadn't been able to see.
I think my boyfriend will soon be here.
When he comes, please leave.
I will.
Sorry for the trouble.
Smells good.
Roses are in full bloom.
Ah... I see.
Your boyfriend...
He still hasn't come.
He's not coming.
So he isn't.
But it doesn't matter anymore
because recently...
you come here instead.
Maybe I'll stop waiting for him.
Would you join me?
Thank you.
"They say girls become pretty
When they're in love
Is it really so?
I hope it's true
You can be shy
You can be bashful
But when you're..."
I roasted some cod roe today.
Dislike it?
No, it's my favorite.
Glad to hear that.
Come to think of it
cod roe was his favorite, too.
Boss. Boss...
Hey, you try.
- Boss.
- Darn. Shout louder.
Boss.
- Again.
- Boss.
Boss... Boss.
He must be out. Let's go.
Give me a break.
Take a pose... like models.
What the hell is that?
Shut up. Hurry up and shoot.
Getting married, right?
Gonna tell everyone.
Hey, don't tell anyone.
You'd better not tell anyone.
All right. Stop it.
Stop it. It's dangerous.
Hey, stop it.
Stop it.
It's really dangerous.
Watch out. It's dangerous.
Everyone, listen up.
I have big news.
Matsumoto and Sawako
are getting married.
- Getting married!
- No kidding? Really?
- Had a crush on her?
- I didn't.
- What a surprise!
- Congratulations.
Thank you.
You should buy her a ring.
I couldn't afford it.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
What're you doing here?
You could start a fire.
Come on, beat it.
I said, beat it.
Miho KANNO
as Sawako
Hidetoshi NISHIJIMA
as Matsumoto
Tatsuya MIHASHI
as the Yakuza Boss
Chieko MATSUBARA
as Ryoko, the Woman in the Park
Kyoko FUKADA
as Pop Idol Haruna Yamaguchi
Tsutomu TAKESHIGE
as the Groupie Nukui
Cinematography by
Katsumi YANAGIJIMA
Lighting Design by
Hitoshi TAKAYA
Production Design by
Norihiro ISODA
Sound Design by
Senji HORIUCHI
Written, Directed and Edited by
Takeshi KITANO
Subtitles by Jeanette Amano