An Agent 21 / Director's Company
production
A Takahashi Group film
Starring:
Keiko Takahashi
Daijirô Tsutsumi
Executive Producer: Fumio Takahashi
Planning Producer: Atsushi Watanabe
Producer: Kôsuke Kuri
Script: Ataru Oikawa / Banmei Takahashi
Cinematography: Yasushi Sasakibara
Lighting: Yutaka Iwasaki
Art Direction: Terumi Hosoishi
Music: Gôji Tsuno
Sound: Shin Fukuda
Effects: Yukio Fukushima
Editing: Junichi Kikuchi
Costume: Takako Oda
Recording: Yukiko Eguchi
Special Effects Makeup: Tomoo Haraguchi
Special Effects Styling: Yuichi Matsui
Special Effects Camera:
Yukimitsu Kanno / Shinichi Mizuno
Assistant Director: Hideyuki Hirayama
Production Managers: Takahiro Kobayashi
Kenichi Kamada
Directed by Banmei Takahashi
Honda Residence
Takuto, it's time.
Okay!
Thanks for the meal.
Wait!
You need to tuck in properly.
Because it's cold.
- Dad will be coming home today.
- Yeah!
Trash Collection Days
Monday-Wednesday-Friday
Only throw it away on those days.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Hello.
Mrs. Honda?
Congratulations.
You've been selected to
participate in our Overseas Tour,
as our computer system
identified you as...
Excuse me,
What is it that you want?
Well, it's a special tour designed
for intelligent housewives...
Hello?
Of course, I imagine
you're very busy,
but we will work
around your schedule.
Hey, you.
Don't you think you're going too far?
What do you mean?
Calling me out of the blue
and barraging me with these things.
Isn't it too much?
Could you tell me
the name of your company?
What's your name?
Ouch!
Hubby and his tools!
Coming.
Who may I ask is this?
Hello, this is Murano Life.
Are you and your family covered
by the right insurance policy?
Sorry, but we're already covered.
Oh really?
From which company?
Could you tell me please?
Ours is much better than any other.
If you'd just hear me out
I think you'll also agree.
It's already been two years.
We'll take that into
consideration as well.
I don't really think
that's necessary.
And I'm a bit busy. Sorry.
Oh, really?
Then, sorry for interrupting you.
We have various other
forms of insurance too.
So I'll come and present those
at another time.
Thank you for your time today.
Thanks.
Coming.
Just a second.
Overly cautious, aren't you?
Open up
Darling.
You scared me.
Scared me half to death.
Welcome home.
I was ringing for ages.
Sorry, I was on the balcony.
It stinks. Throw the trash out.
Stop, darling.
I threw it out this morning
but found it on the doorstep
when I returned.
Today's not the trash day I guess.
It's OK here.
Even so, isn't that a bit much?
Must really be a clean freak.
Almost a disease.
But...
How did they know it was our trash?
A bit creepy, isn't it?
Maybe they saw you?
Next time put it out
on the right day.
Yes.
Talking about creepy, so is this.
How do they know people's
names and addresses?
They're wasting their time
making this crap.
Exactly.
They even knew our son's name.
What's that?
- Insurance.
- Really.
Maybe the "ID Number System"
has started.
What's all these, too?
This isn't a bachelor's place.
Why not leave those?
Idiot.
Hungry?
Tired?
I'll take a nap.
I had no break today.
- A morning shift tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Also, Aoki took time off, so I'll
be away for 3 days.
Oh, really.
Daddy, wake up!
I told you not to wake him!
He's been awake all this time.
He'll be up for dinner, so play
by yourself til then.
Okay!
Takuto!
Sir, do you happen to have
any itchy places?
- None!
- OK.
Dad is washing you, how nice.
Maybe I'll join too.
Please do.
Slowly shampoo then.
- Mom, it's cold!
- Sorry.
Darling.
Come on.
Hey.
Hey!
Mommy.
Don't wake up daddy.
Go to...
sleep!
Daddy will take you today, how nice!
Yes!
Hey...
Not cute!
Take the trash out, please.
OK.
See you later.
- You too
- See you later.
See you, oh your hat.
See you soon!
Sarcastic.
Have a good one.
Takuto, your hat.
Mommy!
Mommy, open the door!
What is it?
I forgot to take my picture.
My dear.
Silly boy.
Where's dad?
Waiting downstairs.
See you.
Hello?
Oh, Miyuki, it's been ages.
I hadn't heard from you,
so I'd been thinking of calling.
I see.
Even something you can't see
can be your asset.
And that's culture.
We consider culture
as a living thing.
Something which will
always be with you.
Specifically tailored to you,
I've prepared a unique curriculum to
help you become an international person.
English conversation isn't just
simply changing Japanese into English.
Our method will help you to
express your emotions
and deeply converse
with the other.
Well,
to be able to speak English, which isn't
your first language, fluently
is not easy thing to achieve.
So we have concocted a system which
allows you to carry on learning smoothly
and I want to share
it with everyone.
Thinking of your children's future,
thinking internationally is
absolutely necessary.
Somebody's at the door.
Speak soon, okay?
Coming.
Who may I ask is there?
Hello, Mrs. Honda?
Sorry to trouble you at this time,
But I brought you something
exciting today.
If this is sales talk, no thank you.
Yes, but if you'd just spare
me 5 minutes of your time?
I'm quite busy right now.
Then, please allow me to just
give you a pamphlet.
Please put it in the letter box.
Stop, please!
Just this.
How mean!
So cruel.
My hand is all swollen.
This is assault, isn't it?
Though, no need to worry.
I'll let it slide.
But...
We have a quota to fill.
So, won't you just give
me a few minutes of your time?
I beg of you.
With my hand like this,
I won't be able to work.
Go to the police if you want.
Besides,
you guys only need
your smooth-talk to work!
So mean.
Sorry.
You've reached JCS.
Is Mr. Honda in?
It's his wife.
Oh, hello.
He's...
busy in the machine room.
If it's important, shall I call him?
Oh, in that case it's OK.
Sorry for bothering you.
Jesus!
"I am..."
"sexually frustrated,"
"Can someone please..."
"do it with me"
Mrs. Honda.
Package for you.
What was written on the door?
Something indecent.
A general idea?
I can't say.
Tell me about
the "strange thing" then.
A tissue.
A tissue?
Um, a tissue paper?
With sperm.
I see.
That's a bit perverse, isn't it?
- Just a bit?
- No, I mean...
that's very, very
perverse, I think.
And, that salesman you mentioned,
what was he selling?
I don't know.
Do you remember his face?
No, I couldn't see it.
So you don't know what
company he was from,
and don't know his face.
You don't even know who was
kicking your door for sure.
Well, I'll let the patrol unit know
to be on the lookout for
anything suspicious.
Thank you very much.
Mrs. Honda.
I've your cleaning here.
Oh, thank you.
This, right?
- Yes.
- Please sign here.
Thank you very much.
Sorry.
It's me.
Are you free today?
There have been lots of strange
things happening since yesterday
and my husband is away for 2 days.
So I thought that if you're free,
why not come and stay the night here?
I see. Well that can't be helped.
It's okay. Speak later.
Takuto, can you get the
paper please?
- Takuto?
- Yes?
Takuto!
When it's finished.
It's finished.
Mommy, I can't pull it.
Of course you can.
I really can't.
Maybe it got stuck.
Somebody.
Somebody, help me!
Somebody help me!
It's nothing.
Nothing at all.
Mommy is OK.
Everything is OK.
Let's count to 50 today.
OK!
1...2...3...
4...5...6...
7...8...9...
10...11...12...
13...14...15...
Hello?
Wrapped up in a towel?
Or possibly...
Who is this?
Sorry for disturbing you,
go back to your bath.
Hello?
Sorry about earlier.
- It's me
- Stop messing around!
After freshening up after a bath,
a cold beer is nice, right?
You...
like a drink, right?
Who?
Who are you?
Your husband...
is not home yet?
Or maybe, he's not
coming home tonight?
Stop it!
No, I won't.
I'll go to the police.
Go ahead.
But...
you don't know who or where I am.
It's you.
You wrote that on my door.
Did I?
Did something happen?
What's "that"?
Pervert.
Those sort of people are around.
Why?
Because I hurt your hand
or I didn't listen to you?
What are you talking about?
Stop it!
Why do you need to call me?
Why?
Because...
you're beautiful.
Hello?
Prank calls?
Don't bother with it.
Just hang up.
It's not just that.
So many strange things
happened today.
Strange things?
Things I can't say on the phone.
I want to explain in person.
Can't you come home?
It's just 30 minutes by car.
It's impossible.
It's chaos here as the
machine ran into a bug.
Stop purposely using
such technical terms.
The program has stalled.
Yeah, yeah,
You just don't care
what happens to us!
Yes?
Who were you speaking to?
Your husband?
Or maybe... the police?
Why not stop these foolish things.
If you want something, say it.
I don't...
want anything really.
I just want to talk with you.
Because you're beautiful.
It's not fair.
What's so fun about this?
I...
think you're...
a piece of shit!
Hey, it's me.
Darling.
Sorry about yesterday.
You better now?
Yes, sorry.
I got a bit worked up.
Things are fine here.
Don't worry.
I see.
I'm gonna take a nap,
but call if you need me.
Thanks for calling.
Be back for dinner tomorrow.
Okay.
Later.
Good luck.
Takuto, that's dangerous.
Stop it.
Takuto!
Mommy, you're beautiful.
Silly.
You're...
beautiful.
Mrs. Honda, right?
Sorry to keep you, it's me.
It's boring being alone, isn't it?
Can I head over?
I really want to see you.
Hello, you've reached
the Honda residence.
We're away now, so please leave
your name and number...
No need to pretend you're out.
It's totally fine, though.
As I know you're
listening to my voice.
I've become...
even more in love with you.
You look great in a swimsuit.
Even though you had a kid,
your body is in perfect shape.
Dazzlingly so.
Thank you.
I'd love to speak more.
Oh yeah.
I'll sing a song.
Please listen.
Bubbles, oh bubbles,
you floated up in the air
Reaching the roof so high,
Only to pop and die.
Bubbles, oh bubbles,
You vanished before you could fly,
Before seeing the sky so high,
Only to pop and die.
Wind, wind, don't you blow,
Bubbles, bubbles, again I blow.
It's a sad song, isn't it?
Still won't you pick up?
I see.
Then, I'll talk a little more.
Your husband drives a Gemini, right?
It's not in the parking lot,
so I guess he didn't return last night?
His work is quite tough, isn't it?
Irregular hours, long nights too.
How do you know?
- You picked up.
- How?
You know nothing about me,
but I know everything about you.
Takuto
goes to Sumire Kindergarten, right?
Is he OK?
I wonder, is he doing well?
Mommy!
Sumire Kindergarten
Back there, Fumio said he
was waiting for you. What was that?
Fumio and I are going
roller skating later.
You can't go today.
Why?
No!
- Come on.
- No!
I promised!
I said you can't.
But I promised him I'd go!
How many times do I need to say so?
Go inside!
Takuto, just for today,
please listen to what I say.
Your juice.
Takuto!
Just be like that then!
Takuto, get up and answer the phone!
Takuto?
Takuto!
Takuto...
you idiot!
Damn.
Hello, Mrs. Kato?
This is Mrs. Honda.
Is my Takuto over there now?
Oh, I see.
When he leaves please call me.
Sorry for the trouble.
We finally could meet.
You shouldn't leave
without locking up.
It's dangerous.
Please look at me.
Please.
Let's head back in.
Sorry.
I'm sorry it came to this.
But if I don't do it like this,
you won't listen to
what I have to say.
Don't really use them?
Even though you're so beautiful.
Stop it.
Please.
Please calm down.
- Please.
- Get off!
Hello?
I'm doing something
so pleasurable now.
I'm so hard and ready to go.
Suck it.
You make me so horny.
Go deep.
Use your tongue.
You're wet too, right?
I'm gonna cum.
Open your mouth.
Shame on you.
Who are you?
You lonely soul.
Asshole.
Asshole?
Don't look at me like that.
Shall we continue?
Please stop fighting back.
Mommy! Open the door!
- Mommy!
- Takuto, run!
Shouldn't you let him in?
If he runs I'll get him.
What do you want?
I wonder.
Mommy, mommy, quickly!
Don't hurt my kid.
Please!
Mommy!
Coming. Wait a second.
Promise me, please.
Understood.
Really?
Yes.
Mommy, open it.
OK. I'm coming!
Pretend to be a guest.
Let's do it.
Welcome home.
A guest.
- Say hello.
- Hello!
Nice to meet you.
You're back early.
Fumio and Takashi,
everyone went home.
Because you didn't come.
Takuto!
I'm hungry!
Be right up.
Shall we play together?
- Let's play pool!
- Great!
Nice!
Aim for the red next.
Close!
Let me try.
I'm gonna...
use the toilet.
Go ahead.
Actually...
my husband may be coming home.
Well, if that happens...
that's fine with me.
Huh?
I don't care what happens...
to me.
Takuto!
What?
Dinner's nearly ready.
OK!
When do you normally go to sleep?
Around 8 pm, right?
Yeah, around then.
That's early.
Your dad's missing dinner.
Dad's not coming home tonight.
Isn't he?
Can I have another beer?
Yes.
Of course.
Takuto, you need to eat a lot
to become a big boy.
Takuto!
Takuto.
Mommy!
Takuto, run!
No! No!
Hey.
Are you OK?
I guess you're out.
Oh well, never mind then.
Takuto, be a good boy.
Takuto?
Takuto!
Mommy!
It's okay.
It'll be OK.
Takuto, pull yourself together!
You're a man, right?
Help me.
You want to die?
We need to fight back.
Takuto.
- Mommy!
- I'm OK!
Takuto.
It's all over.
You did so well.
Do you know
in America,
there's a rapist who
cuts out his victim's tongue.
Do you know why?
So she can't say...
who raped her.
Don't you think he's an idiot?
I really can't see
his point, you know?
If you do it...
you must crush her eyes too.
If it was me...
that's how I'd do it.
Bubbles, oh bubbles,
You floated up in the air,
Reaching the roof
so high
Only to pop
and die
Bubbles, oh bubbles,
You vanished
before you could fly,
Before seeing the sky so high,
Only to pop and die.
Wind, wind, don't you blow,
Bubbles, bubbles, again I blow.
Mommy.
Mommy!
You bastard!
It's bedtime.
Mrs. Honda?
I'm from the House of God.
Could you spare
a few minutes to talk?
Starring:
Keiko Takahashi
Daijirô Tsutsumi
Shirô Shimomoto
Takuto Yonezu
Masao Ishida
Koichi Takayanagi
Hiroshi Noguchi
Yoshihiro Shimada
Executive Producer: Fumio Takahashi
Planning Producer: Atsushi Watanabe
Producer: Kôsuke Kuri
Script: Ataru Oikawa / Banmei Takahashi
Cinematography: Yasushi Sasakibara
Directed by Banmei Takahashi