Alpha Omega.
Ely Elohe Eloheim.
Sabaoth Elion Sady.
Help me!
Help!
Alpha Omega.
Ely Elohe Eloheim.
Help me!
Elohe Elo Obosos.
Orion Elkhie Adnaia.
Detragramaton Saday.
Ely Elohe Eloheim.
Elohe Elo Obosos.
Orion Elkhie Adnaia.
Detragramaton Saday.
The pentagram is complete.
On the night of the full moon,
we offerthirteen sacrifices.
Use their blood to
cleanse our sanctuary.
For Lucifer!
To revive Satan, the lord Lucifer!
Lucifer.
Ashtaroth.
ln the name of Asmodeus.
You will lead the ceremony.
Rise!
That woman may come.
Which woman?
The woman with great powers.
The woman we don't want as an enemy.
Good morning.
Let me check you.
Okay, you may go.
Good morning Kazumi.
How's your hair?
Your breasts?
The length of your skirt...
Okay.
Everything's fine.
You can go.
l've never seen you before!
What's your name?
Misa Kuroi.
Eko Eko Azarak
Look.
Last night's accident took place here.
And the ones before that were here...
...and here, and here and here.
lf you connect all the sites of
those strange accidents with straight lines...
...you get a pentagram.
And in the middle is our school.
No way!
Why?
Good morning.
What is that?
lt's a very important magic symbol.
lt can be used as an invocation or as
protection, depending on how it's drawn.
But this pentagram was drawn with
human blood, so it's an invocation.
lt's to call forth the devil.
Magicians have their rank and order.
The highertheir rank, the
greater evils they can call forth.
There are lots of powerful
devils like Belzebub and Asmodeus...
...but it's every magician's dream
to call the Great Lord Satan...
...and to make his powers their own.
Lucifer used to be an angel,
he looks beautiful, doesn't he?
But his powers are incredible.
lt is said that if you call
Lucifer, you can rule the world.
Are you on something?
This would be dangerous
if it was for real.
You should be careful.
Are you making fun of magic?
Looking for a fight?
All rise.
Get back to your seats.
Bow.
Good morning.
Be seated.
l'd like to introduce
our new transfer student.
Miss Kuroi.
She's hot!
Misa Kuroi will be part of
our class from today on.
My name is Misa Kuroi.
Misa, let me know if you have any
questions, l'm the class representative.
Thank you.
lt must be a lot of work.
lt is, l got forced into it.
But if l do it now, l don't
have to do it when l'm a senior.
What's this room?
This room is sealed off.
lt used to be the art room.
Ever since one of the teachers
went crazy and committed suicide.
They say that at night
you can hear her voice.
See?
lt's true, the security
guards have heard it.
Really?
Really!
This is the biology lab.
This is the physics lab.
This school has had a lot of additions,
so it might be confusing at first.
l really like that.
Should we go buy one today?
Sure, l have lots of time.
Did Mr. Numata feel you up this morning?
No.
Really, he's a pervert so be careful.
And our homeroom teacher, Miss Shirai...
She likes girls.
What do you mean?
She and Kazumi Tanaka
are having a thing...
What's wrong?
What's wrong, Mizuki?
Adonai Hareitz.
Wait here.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yeah.
lt's so weird...
lt just went away.
lt's so strange.
lt took you so long to come
back, l thought you ditched me.
l'm sorry, l got lost.
Of course.
You seem like you're very
loyal to your friends.
l do?
Yes, you do.
You must have been really frazzled.
Your beautiful hair is all messed up.
ls there anyone in this school
who knows about magic and spells?
Mizuno, l guess.
Why?
What were you saying
earlier in the locker room?
Oh, what was l saying?
Oh yeah, that Miss Shirai
and Kazumi are having a thing.
Kazumi?
Let's go.
l wonder if she heard us.
Mizuki...
What?
What just happened before....
...l think it was a curse.
A curse?
l found this here.
This was stuck in its chest.
Can you think of who
might have done this?
No.
What about Kazumi?
l don't think she likes me much.
But l don't think she hates me.
Misa, are you serious about this curse?
Or is this some kind of joke?
l wish it was.
lf you hear any strange
rumors, let me know right away.
lt doesn't matter what it is.
lt could be about ghosts, or
that someone is using magic.
Okay.
You can keep this if you'd like.
Thank you.
But why?
lt's a charm.
lt will protect you.
Thank you, l will take good care of it.
Someone is after Mizuki
Kurahashi, and put a curse on her...
Who here uses magic?
Miss Kuroi.
We have a practice
match against West High...
...will you come?
l have a feeling that if you
come to cheer us on, we'll win.
Don't be fooled.
Shindo has a feeling that they'll
win if any girls cheerthem on.
Only cute girls.
No way, Misa's all mine.
Let's go.
Remember you told me to tell
you if l heard anything strange?
Some people are about to
perform a ritual to cast a spell.
A ritual?
Numata touched my chest again today!
Can you believe it?
l bet that's the real
reason he teaches here.
He deserves to die.
l don't think we should do this.
What are you saying
Kana, it was your idea.
l went all the way to
Harajuku to buy this.
But...
What are you doing?
Hey Mizuki, wanna join us?
We're going to make Numata suffer.
Where's his picture?
Let's not do this.
We shouldn't do this.
Come on, Mizuno.
You always do this.
You always wimp out.
l hate half-assed flakes.
lf you don't like it,
why don't you leave.
That's enough, Kazumi.
But she's always like this.
l hate half-assed flakes.
You're the ones who
are being half-assed.
You need a doll like this to
put a curse on someone, Kazumi.
Misa?
Are you saying you know how to do it?
You seem to know, let's
see you do it then.
Fine.
Give me the photo.
This is not my breath, but the
breath of our enemy, Hideki Numata.
Eko Eko Azarak, Eko Eko Zamelak.
Eko Eko Kernonos, Eko Eko Aradia.
Put this in Mr. Numata's desk drawer.
lt will take effect right away.
Are you sure this is going to work?
l don't think so.
Don't tell anyone about the doll,
it will decrease its powers.
Why did you do it?
l wanted to see if anyone
knew about the doll.
Besides, you wanted to see
how a curse works, didn't you?
Did you figure out who it was?
No.
But l will.
Mr. Numata has fallen
ill and is not here.
You will have study
hall instead of biology.
Yes!
Wow, Misa!
Yeah!
How did you do that?
Can you show us?
Misa Kuroi uses black magic.
Really?
No way.
lt's true.
Hey Mizuno, that means she
is the real thing, unlike you.
Shut up!
Ooh, l'm so scared.
Damn it!
The new transfer student, Misa Kuroi...
She's very pretty.
l heard something strange
from a friend of mine...
...who teaches at her old school.
He said that many
people around her died.
No way.
She's not directly involved but...
At her last school,
and the one before too...
People die when she transfers in.
Do you like the new student?
What's wrong?
What are you worried about?
You seem strange today, Kazumi.
She's so pretty.
You have your eye on her, don't you?
You're being silly.
lt's not like that.
You think Misa made Mr. Numata sick?
l heard that Misa...
Who's there?
Pig!
Miss Shirai?
lt's okay.
You don't have anything to worry about.
But Mr. Numata has a big mouth.
What if everyone finds out about us?
No matter how big a mouth he
has, he won't be able to talk.
She may be pretty, but who
knows what she's really thinking.
Good morning.
Stop it you guys!
Mr. Numata was in a
traffic accident last night.
He's in critical condition.
Mr. Numata?
Why?
lt's because you put a curse on him.
No way.
lt wasn't that kind of curse.
This was in Numata's drawer.
Besides, l know.
People died in your
old school too, right?
l heard that people around you die.
You're the one making the
blood pentagram, aren't you?
What are you up to?
Murderer!
They went after Mr. Numata and not me.
Why?
Eight people knew about the doll.
Don't let that get you down.
Everyone is just a little freaked out.
Mizuno's crazy to begin with anyway.
Besides, there's no reason
for you to do that to Numata.
All this talk of curses and black magic...
What's wrong with everyone?
So you came to cheer me up.
Sort of.
Will you go out with me?
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
What Mizuno said is true.
People around me die.
You should stay away from me.
That's a really crappy
way to reject someone.
But it's the truth.
l don't care.
Shindo!
What are you doing?
Hurry up!
l'm coming.
Think about it.
And this is the answer.
Any questions?
Okay, that's it fortoday.
After school, there will be a retake
of the test you took the other day.
This is a list of those
who need to do the retake.
Check to see if you're on it.
And Misa...
Yes.
l'd like you to take it, too.
l don't want to be there
if Misa's going to be there.
That's enough, Mizuno.
Good luck, everyone.
There's my name.
My name's on it, too!
Miss Shirai.
l want to see you after school today...
Yes.
You have 60 minutes.
This goes without
saying, but no cheating!
Even if you are finished, do
not leave until l come back.
Understand?
Begin.
Wanna go out tonight?
Where's Shirai?
l bet she forgot about us.
l want to go home.
Misa, what's the matter?
Did you hearthat?
What?
lt's so quiet all of a sudden.
What is that?
That wasn't there before.
lt's the number of evil.
Whatever.
l'm leaving.
Mizuki, you deal with this.
Me, too.
l'm leaving too.
Didn't you hear her say we
had to stay until she came back?
l didn't hearthat.
Neither, did l.
Misa, let's go.
l'm going to wait for Miss Shirai.
Come on, Shindo!
See you.
l'm leaving, too.
You're going to get in trouble!
Chie, are you leaving too?
l gotta pee.
lt won't open.
That's strange.
Maybe it's broken.
l think Beroma's going
to the second round.
Berdie's not dead yet though.
Oh no, the game's going to start!
Didn't we just go outside?
We did.
Huh?
Why won't it open?
l can't get the door open!
Hello?
Please, is anyone there?
Help me!
Please open the door!
Someone!
Someone help me!
Help!
Mizuki, l need to get going.
Me, too.
My dad's going to be hungry.
Where's Chie?
She's still in the bathroom?
What's taking her so long?
l'm going to go check on her.
l thought you left.
We can't get out.
Are the doors locked?
No!
You go out, but you're in again.
We went out but
ended up back inside.
No, the inside is outside.
What are you talking about?
We're just about to leave.
We're not lying!
The windows won't open either!
We can't get out!
Chie, everyone's leaving.
Chie?
Are you in there, Chie?
That's impossible.
lt's true.
lt's not a lie.
lt's a curse.
Maki!
Misa wait!
l'll go get Miss Shirai!
l'll go, too.
Me, too.
Why?
Miss Shirai!
Please help...
We have to call an ambulance.
Hello?
The number you have called...
What's wrong?
Hurry up.
Come on.
What's wrong?
What about the police?
There's no dial tone!
Who are you calling?
Home.
The line's disconnected.
Let me call my dad.
Hello?
Someone!
Damn it!
Hello?
Mizuno!
We're locked in.
Misa Kuroi, you did this, didn't you?
This is a magic boundary.
You are the only one who can do this.
Just like with Numata...
You put a curse on us, didn't you?
Everyone, get out!
Open it!
Hurry up and open it!
lt won't open!
Give me a hand!
Furfur, commander of the infernal
world, reveal to me your secrets!
Everyone, move away!
Open it!
No!
What should we do with the bodies?
We can't leave them like that.
lkeno, Abe, Takada, Yuka, Reiko...
Someone might still be alive.
You saw them!
You saw how torn up they are!
There's no way they're alive!
But!
Then you go and bring back
the ones who are alive.
l can't do that.
l wonder who won the match...
Why did this have to happen?
lt's you.
lt's you, Misa Kuroi.
lt's her fault.
She erected the magic boundary.
She killed them!
Cut it out, Mizuno!
Mizuno's right, we are trapped
in a web of black magic.
Misa!
But it's not me.
l couldn't break the spell.
You failed on purpose.
You pretended that you couldn't,
after all it's your own spell!
Mizuno!
What's wrong with you?
There's no such thing as magic.
Then what was that?
People are dead!
But there's no one around!
We can't make any calls or get out!
What should we do with the bodies?
l want to go home.
Me, too.
Hey...
Did anyone touch the blackboard?
lt used to say 13, didn't it?
ls that number...
ls it...
lt's us!
Cut it out!
lt means there are 7 of us left.
lt's the seven of us.
We're going to die!
We're all going to die!
Damn it, give me a break.
Don't!
Don't erase it!
lf you erase it, we'll die!
Crying won't help.
We have to find a way
to get out of here.
She's right.
We need to get out!
Get out?
Don't you get it, we can't get out!
We'll find a way!
There has to be a way.
l won't go with Misa.
lt's best not to split up.
We can protect each other
if we stick together.
Protect each other?
You were useless earlier.
Don't be fooled by her.
She's a murderer.
l'm going with Misa.
Me, too.
What about you guys?
l'm going with you, Mizuno.
l'm going with Mizuno, too.
Me, too.
You're going to die.
lt's no use.
lt's sealed.
Come on!
Wait!
What are you going to do with that rope?
We're going to the roof.
But the roof?
l know how to rappel.
My dad was into outdoor
sports, and he taught me how.
He was cheesy, but he's got balls.
l felt embarrassed because you
were the one keeping your cool, Misa.
No good?
Nader Letroll satanarse.
Yes!
We can't...
We can't get out!
No, there's got to be a way out.
l bet my dad is so worried.
He must be hungry, too.
l'm sure your mom is taking care of him.
No, they got divorced when l was three.
l'm the only one he's got.
Wait, l think this one might open.
We can get down from here!
Wait!
Don't leave me behind!
Please don't leave me alone.
No!
Kana!
Where are the others?
Maki's...
Where are Kimura and Mizuno?
l don't know.
Let's go back to the classroom.
What are you doing, Mizuno?
lt's a pentagram.
So long as you're inside of it,
you're protected from any magic.
What could this chalk
drawing possibly do?
Don't step on it!
lf you want to live, come in.
But...
...you can't come in, Misa.
Mizuki?
l don't want to die.
l'm not moving, l'm staying here.
You're going to trust Mizuno?
Get out of here.
Shindo...
Misa's going to kill you.
Misa, wait.
Don't follow me.
ls it because of what Mizuno said?
What he's saying is true.
What are you saying?
l'm a witch, a useless witch.
Stop it.
lf l had realized earlier, none
of this would have happened.
Something's wrong, l
can't use my powers.
What are you saying?
lt's my fault they all died.
And this isn't the first time, either.
This happens to everyone
who gets close to me.
Everyone dies!
Stop it!
Sorry.
But at least l want you
to pull yourself together.
We're going to get out of here.
We have to get out of here.
What l said is true.
But don't get me wrong.
l came to this school to
try to help protect you all...
...from those who are using
magic for evil purposes.
Everyone who loves me...
...dies trying to protect me.
That's how it always is.
lf you get too close to
me, bad things will happen.
Not this time.
Shindo...
The vent!
We can get out through it.
Two people are going to die.
lt won't be us.
We're inside the pentagram.
But then does that mean
Misa's going to die?
Then that means that one
of us is the murderer.
lt's open.
Give it to me.
lt's okay.
No!
No, no...
Shindo.
Don't give up.
l'll go get some tools.
Wait, l'll go with you.
Misa, is your heart racing?
l heard that our hearts don't
race because we're in love...
...but that we think we're in
love with the person we're with...
...when our hearts are pounding.
Wait here for me,
with your heart racing.
Wait.
lt will protect you.
Thank you.
l'll be right back.
Misa...
Shindo!
Oh, thank god!
Misa.
What are you doing here,
l told you to wait for me.
l'm so glad.
Shindo?
Serves him right.
Shindo always made fun of me.
Kazumi...
You're the last sacrifice...
Misa Kuroi, the witch.
You pitiful thing!
l was going to kill you
in the teacher's room, but...
lt was clever of you to realize.
l commend you.
But it's all over now.
Oh, Lucifer!
l shall be with you now.
Mizuki, it's over.
Misa!
l was so scared!
lt's okay...
lt's okay now.
l really liked you.
Mizuki...
You...
So, it wasn't Miss Shirai.
She was just following my orders.
What are you trying to do?
You should know that, Misa Kuroi.
A pentagram drawn in blood...
...and 13 young sacrifices.
Lucifer's resurrection!
Lucifer and l shall be one!
Lucifer's great powers will be mine!
lt will be mine!
You killed everyone forthat?
And l thought you of all
people would understand.
l will be the master of the world.
Everyone will kneel before me!
l don't understand you...
l don't even want to!
There's no way you
can resurrect Lucifer.
l am much betterthan you.
l can do it.
For such a stupid reason...
You killed everyone forthat?
You must die too.
You are the last sacrifice.
You will be the ultimate sacrifice.
l made this with your hair.
Cute, isn't it?
You must have been so frazzled.
Your pretty hair is such a mess.
You used my hairto block my powers.
Good bye.
What a shame, Misa Kuroi.
l wanted to introduce you to Lucifer.
Oh Lucifer.
l invoke you in the name of
the god of life and truth.
l invoke you in the
name of the most powerful god.
Alpha Omega Eloei
Eloheim, Ya-a Sedii Rukus...
Mugiens, Lexadonai, Emanuel Meshias.
Oh Lucifer, come back to life...
...and give me your power.
Your name hidden in
the letters V, C and X...
lehoba, Sor, Akura,
Rifarinse, Oriston...
Orfitone, Faton,
lnpretu, Ogia, Soperaton...
lmagon, Amru, Penaton, Soterui,
Tetoragramaton, Eloi, Premoton...
Simoton, Perigaton,
lrataton, Plegaton...
On, Pelkiram, Tiros,
Rubifaton, Sumiraton...
Pelpi, Kramarim, Tremendam, Merai...
Oh, great Lucifer, l devote
myself to you, body and soul.
Reside in my body and give me power!
This is the power of Lucifer!
l told you it wouldn't work, Mizuki.
l couldn't protect any
of the people l loved.
Maybe l'm the one who
overestimated my powers.
Eko Eko Azarak.
Eko Eko Zamelak.
Eko Eko Cernunnos.
Eko Eko Aradia.
Eko Eko Azarak.
Eko Eko Zamelak.
Eko Eko Cernunnos.
Eko Eko Aradia...