Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Are we still partners?
We've been business partners
for 1 55 weeks now.
We're sitting next to each other
for the first time today.
We seldom see each other.
I know too well that man
can hardly control his passion.
Partners should never get
emotionally involved with each other.
FALLEN ANGELS
A message for 3662.
I'm meeting his friends tomorrow.
Ask him to let me know where.
Most people work from 9:00 to 5:00.
I'mjust the opposite.
Myjob is simple.
I visit some "friends"
once in a while.
I don't know any ofthem.
And i'm not interested
in them either.
Because they'll soon be gone forever.
Going out?
Yes.
One's profession is very often
determined by one's personality.
The best thing about my profession
is there's no need
to make any decisions.
Who's to die, when, where-
it's all been planned by others.
I'm a lazy person.
I like people to arrange things for me.
That's why i need a partner.
Ming?
Ming!
You're Ming, aren't you?
Remember me?
My name's Hoi.
Don't you remember me?
I was always number one in grade school.
- Remember?
- Yeah.
What a coincidence!
If my Mercedes hadn't broken down,
I wouldn't have run into you here.
Every person has his own past.
Even ifyou're a killer,
you still have classmates
from grade school around.
Every time i run into them,
they ask me the same questions.
What kind ofwork do you do?
Give me your card
so we can keep in touch.
Maybe we could work together.
That would be great.
Always lookin' to make a buck.
Your own business?
That's worth breaking your back for!
You married?
Don't tell me you can't find a girl!
What? A son!
Looks exactly like you!
What's this-yourwife's black?
I mean... smart move!
Black grows on you.
Your skin color's different,
but you make a nice couple.
Hey, are you insured?
Maybe you can help me out.
I've been in the business
over ten years.
You might not know,
but I'm rated the top insurance broker
in all Southeast Asia.
i'm being interviewed
by the newspaper in a few days.
For old time's sake,
I'll work out the best plan foryou.
You never can tell.
God forbid, but what if
something should happen?
It's notjust foryou.
I see you travel a lot for work.
If not foryourself,
think about your wife and little boy.
I often wonder ifany insurance company
would insure a professional killer.
I'd really like to help him out,
but i wouldn't know
whom to name as beneficiary.
Remember that girl with the big boobs?
The one we were both afteryears ago?
We're getting married next week.
Here's an invitation.
Sorry—just write your own name on it.
Come a little early.
I'll write up the policy foryou.
And bring your wife.
Bye-bye.
A fewyears back, i paid a black woman
$30 to have her picture taken with me,
so that ifpeople asked,
I could say she was my wife.
And the kid in the picture—
I just bought him an ice-cream cone.
I've always wanted to go
to a wedding,
but i know very well
it's not my kind ofscene.
Going through a person's trash
can tell you a lot about them.
He comes to this bar a lot.
Maybe 'cause it's quiet.
Sometimes i sit in his usual seat.
Lets me feel close to him.
Some people you really don't want
to get too close to.
Find out too much about a person
and you lose interest.
I'm the practical kind.
I know how to make myself happy.
No, he hasn't come backyet.
You telling the truth?
Why should I lie?
- You live here?
- Something wrong with that?
Have you seen this person around?
No.
Don't come out yet.
The cops are still here.
You know where he is. Tell us.
You rub elbows
with a lot of people every day.
Some strangers might become
your friends or even confidants.
But I know very well these cops
will never be my confidants.
My name is Ho Chi Moo.
I was prisoner number 223.
I haven't seen him in days.
I'll let you know when he comes back.
I saw him come in.
You'd better tell the truth.
Stop making faces!
Stand still!
I'm a happy man.
I was very talkative when i was small.
But at age five, i ate
a can of pineapple that had expired,
and i stopped talking.
For that reason,
I have very few friends.
I found it very hard
to find work too.
I finally decided to be my own boss.
Having no capital,
the only thing i can do
is sneak into
other people's shops after hours
and run my own business.
I'm not a freeloader.
i just think it makes sense,
since the rent's already been paid,
to run the business around the clock.
Who says nobody
buys pork at 3:00 a.m.?
I came yesterday
to buy some, didn't i?
Ifyou want to do business,
you have to take
each customer's needs into account.
Buddha said,
"If I don't descend into hell, who will?"
When you're the boss,
you have to be kind,
caring and tolerant.
You can'tjust look to your own gain.
I know very well
there's no such thing as a free lunch,
so i always work very hard
until the wee hours.
I don't make a lot of money,
but I'm happy.
Are you nuts? Why should i let you
wash my clothes?
I'm a beggar.
I don't need laundry done!
I don't need it!
Leave me alone!
Are you nuts?
Keep your hands off my clothes!
Give me back my clothes!
Hands off!
I'll beat you up!
Okay, I'll pay!
I'll payyou,
if it's moneyyou want.
You're a lunatic!
Don't push me!
I don't want any eggplant!
You can't make me buy it!
I'm single.
What would people think?
Not even ifthey're free!
I'll take some melon.
Here!
This is huge!
Are you out ofyour mind?
Stop that!
I washed my hairyesterday.
Ouch! Easy!
My head doesn't itch—
stop scratching it!
I just came down for a late snack.
I don't need a shampoo.
I give up.
Do whateveryou want.
No!
I don't want a shave!
Hands off!
Listen, i'm no regular guy.
I have underworld connections.
I really don't want a shave.
How about—
I'll payyou, okay?
A double cone, please.
Oh, no, it's you!
Sorry.
Stop pulling my hair.
I'll climb in myself.
Sorry!
I'm coming in.
Hello? It's me.
What are you doing?
Go to bed. Don't wait for me.
I'm having some ice cream.
Uh, no, it's more than a scoop or two.
I don't know how much more
i'll have to eat.
No, it's not an eating contest.
Ofcourse I'll have to pay!
Yeah, but this guy won't let me...
I don't know how to explain,
but it's the truth.
Come see foryourself
ifyou don't believe me.
Hello?
No, i can't eat that!
What if my mustache catches on fire?
This isn't funny anymore.
Why are you doing this?
I said to come byyourself.
I didn't tell you
to bring the whole family.
Dad's too old for all this ice cream.
What ifsomething happens?
The kids have to go to school tomorrow.
Think about that.
Has anyone in Hong Kong ever died
from too much ice cream?
I don't want to be the first.
I'll payyou, okay?
Name a price.
I'll buy it all. Please.
My ice cream may be
a bit more expensive,
but i think this family
is having a great time.
i love ice cream.
When i was little, an ice cream truck
would stop by my house every day.
I was always happy to see it.
Once i asked my dad
why he didn't drive an ice cream truck.
He didn't answer.
I later found out
my mother had been run over
by an ice cream truck.
i was born in Taiwan.
i came to Hong Kong
with my dad when i was five.
He worked as an assistant
at the Chungking Mansions Hotel.
He's rarely talked
since my mother died.
No more ice cream, ofcourse.
Maybe the fact
we're both so quiet
explains why we've always been close.
Why are you being so nice to me?
You even bought me ice cream.
You should know
I don't like ice cream.
It's too cold!
It's bad for my health.
Gives me the runs.
Are you nuts?
Hey, open up!
What game are you playing now?
Open this door!
What are you doing?
I'll kill you!
Open this door!
Stop playing around!
9090.
I'd like to leave a message.
I'm meeting his friends tomorrow.
He should let me know where.
I get it. It's clear.
I just wanna make sure
the address was correct.
It was a fast-food store,
not a barber shop.
You may think
we must be making a lot of money.
But how much is a human life worth?
Demand comes and goes.
it's not unusual to have
no business for months.
So, once in a while
I moonlight in the financial field.
Like debt collection.
Thanks.
Hold on.
I'll get you the money.
Here.
I don't know why,
but I've been injured a lot lately.
I hate digging bullets
out ofmy own body.
It's exhausting.
I turned in early that night,
knowing when i woke up the next day,
i'd have to make a decision.
Lady, we're closed.
Two weeks after I was injured,
I asked to see her.
I wanted to tell her my decision.
But i didn't show up.
I'm sure she'll look for me here
in the next couple days.
i know that because
we've been partners for so long.
As her partner, it's not enough
for me to understand her.
I have to let her understand me too.
So sometimes i leave clues
so she can trace
my actions and whereabouts.
She's become part ofmy life
these past years.
But things always change.
I desperately want to tell her
that i want to quit,
but I don't know how to start.
So i've devised another way.
A woman may come asking for me
in the next few days.
Please give her this coin.
Tell her 1 81 8 is my lucky number.
1 81 8.
The number ofone
ofthe songs in thisjukebox.
When she hears the song,
she'll understand my message.
Forget him
And it's like forgetting everything
It's like losing all direction
Losing oneself
Forget him
And it's like forgetting
thejoy of life
It's like a knife in the heart
Bleeding in pain
May i sit here?
It's raining!
Let's have some fun!
It feels great!
Cover me too!
Come on!
What?
I'm all nervous.
Why?
Come on up.
No?
Okay.
Sure you don't wanna come up?
Positive?
Forget it.
Come and get it.
It won't dry out tonight.
You'll have to stay.
I'll take it to the cleaners
foryou tomorrow.
Okay?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Why are you ignoring me?
Open the door!
Looks nice.
Still fits you well.
Whose is this?
Why all the questions?
Are we that close?
Better be careful!
What are you doing?
Help!
Hey!
What do you want from me?
What are you doing?
I'm so happy!
Don't let me stop you.
Guess why i dyed my hair blond.
I don't know.
To make myself unforgettable.
It's pretty special.
You're making fun of me.
I mean it.
You're very special.
- Someone told me that once before.
- Who?
You!
We were together for some time.
I had long hair then.
You called me "baby."
Really?
Yes.
But let's let bygones be bygones.
Ifyou like me now, it's fine.
I didn't say that.
I just wanted some company.
Fine.
Just for the night.
Maybe you'll like me better tomorrow.
No!
Get out!
Get the hell out of here!
Get out or I'll clobberyou!
Hello?
What did you want to tell me?
You want to have kids?
Why are you telling me this?
You wanna get married?
Sure! I'll marryyou.
Give me time
to send out invitations.
You already did?
How come I'm the last to know?
You're a sly one!
You sent me an invitation?
Why?
i see.
Congratulations!
Who's the lucky girl?
Blondie?
What a perfect couple!
She wants me to be her bridesmaid?
What should i wear?
Chinese style?
A lady-in-waiting?
How interesting!
Sure! That's great!
Where's Blondie now?
I want to call and congratulate her.
Okay, thanks. Bye-bye.
Give me a dime.
You got a dime?
Hello? Blondie?
i know you're there.
Stop pretending you're the machine.
You know what?
Ifyou don't talk to me,
you'll regret it
the rest ofyour life!
You're marrying him?
I shouldn't have asked you
to pay his electricity bill.
Now you're getting married?
You filthy bitch!
He doesn't love you.
Hejust wants a son born
in the Year ofthe Pig— this year!
But it's already April!
There's not enough time!
it'll be premature.
I've got it!
You got pregnant by another guy
and told him it's his child.
I'm warning you: Next time i see you,
I'm gonna push you down the stairs!
You got that?
Hello? Hello?
I'm not finished yet!
Hello?
Gimme another dime!
That bitch!
She took the phone offthe hook!
I don't want any!
Let me cry on your shoulder.
The night's full ofweirdos.
This girl seems to turn up
wherever i go.
I'm fine now.
I'll payyou back next time.
But every time we meet,
it's the same story.
I wish I could tell her some problems
can't be solved over the phone.
You meet the guy face to face
and talk it out,
or, ifthat fails,
you punch him in the nose.
Too bad i couldn't put it into words.
But she seemed to somehow
understand anyway.
I thinkyou're right.
Let's go.
Blondie, I know you're in there!
Come out ifyou've got the guts!
I'm gonna burn this place down
on the count ofthree!
One... two... three!
I think we got the wrong floor.
Blondie, come on out!
I know you're in there!
I'm gonna burn this place down
ifyou don't!
One... two... three!
Let's try the next floor.
Are those gray hairs real?
At my age? Ofcourse they are!
Looks like a faded blond dyejob to me!
How are you related to Blondie?
I don't know any Blondie.
Her real name's Situ Hui Ling.
Ring a bell?
Never heard of her.
Is she your chick?
Leave me alone, you loony!
I'm sure they've got a thing together.
Follow him!
Do you have a daughter
named Blondie?
Or Situ Hui Ling? You look a lot alike.
Have you forgotten?
- Think hard.
- I don't know her.
We searched high and low all night.
After a while, i started to wonder
ifshe even knew where Blondie lived.
I'm tired ofthis game.
Why is everyone covering foryou?
Where the hell are you?
I'm a nice person.
Why doesn't anyone help me?
You're a slut,
and everyone helps you!
It's not fair.
What kind ofworld is this?
I don't wanna play this game anymore.
You must be sleeping with everyone.
You must have slept with her too.
i bet you have,
but you won't admit it. Right?
What a crazy world.
How am I gonna find you?
Bitch! You've got
the whole world on your side.
Blondie!
You slut! How dare you showyour face!
You're finished!
Bitch! Slut! Tramp!
I'll mop you to death!
Bitch!
How can you be so cruel!
Hey, get your face out ofthe food
and watch the door!
Blondie could walk in any minute.
She used to come here
for dim sum with her pop.
How do you spell "inadequate"?
Never mind.
I'll just spell it like this.
Listen to this.
"I, Situ Hui Ling, aka Blondie,
am ugly and inadequate.
i hereby return Mr.Johnny Kwong
to his rightful girlfriend, Charlie Young.
I will have no more relationship with him.
This will serve as proof.
Our signatures are binding unto death."
This is great, right?
I'll make Blondie sign this today.
I gotta get her fingerprints
and iD number.
Her old man can serve as witness.
I'll get a picture ofthem together.
Blondie!
- Your name is Blondie too?
- Shut up!
I'll fucking chop you to pieces!
This is Blondie!
Your name is Blondie too?
What if it is?
Is your name really Blondie?
What of it?
They say women are made ofwater.
So are some men.
Most people fall in love
for the first time as teenagers.
I guess i'm a late bloomer.
Maybe i'm too picky.
On May 30, 1 995,
I finally fell in love
for the first time.
It was raining that night.
When I looked at her,
I suddenly felt like i was a store.
And she was me.
Without any warning,
she suddenly enters the store.
I don't know how long she'll stay.
The longer the better, ofcourse.
You never wash
your feet or socks or hair.
You stink all over.
When did you dye your hair blond?
They say love can change a man.
I started to find myself
more handsome and charming.
And suddenly i discovered
i was turning blond.
Maybe because my mom was Russian.
A lot ofpeople don't understand
when my father speaks Taiwanese.
And rightly so.
it's actually Taiwanese
with the infamous Russian accent.
Hello?
Chungking Mansions Hotel.
Who's this?
Blondie!
On June 22, 1 995,
the italian team Sampdoria
came to play in Hong Kong.
I went to the game with Charlie.
She wanted to see Ruud Gullit.
She was ecstatic that night.
She insisted on staying after the game.
This is no fun!
What's the point in playing them?
They're all blond and superior.
Our players are no match.
Did they really expect a miracle?
Fools!
You know why I came?
I was the one hoping for a miracle.
Johnny is a huge fan ofGullit.
I thought I might see him here.
But how could he come?
He's getting married tomorrow.
You know why I was yelling
and waving like crazy earlier?
I was hoping he'd see me on TV.
He promised me he'd come!
So why didn't he?
I realized that she still missedJohnny.
It made me feel bad.
But i'm an optimist.
i've heard people say
everything has its expiration date.
I wasn't sure this would apply
to her andJohnny,
but I thought it might soon.
I guess I might have been
a little too optimistic.
A few days later,
I asked her to go to a second match.
She didn't show up.
i thought what she had
withJohnny would expire soon.
But as it turned out,
my expiration date came up first.
i got there early
and stayed till everyone was gone.
As the lights ofthe stadium went dark,
I realized she wasn't gonna show.
I was heartbroken.
This couldn't be.
People say breaking up hurts.
That wasn't true for me.
But something strange did happen.
After that day, my blond hair
suddenly disappeared.
Just like my first love.
I also began to realize my past behavior
had been very irresponsible.
I shouldn't have taken over
other people's shops,
coming and going as i pleased.
Every shop has its own feelings.
This realization
had a profound effect on me.
It prompted me to change my ways.
Welcome.
One person.
Look for our new menu next time.
Am i making you stay overtime?
Get a glass foryourself.
Be my guest.
How's business?
What's it cost
to open a place like this?
Good evening.
You have money?
i wasjust wondering
what it costs to open a place like this.
Do you have a million?
i had never thought
about going into business before.
When you live in a suitcase,
you don't need a place ofyour own.
But things had changed.
I had to start planning
for the future.
That night,
I had a nice chat with the manager.
He even offered a helping hand
should i ever open my own shop.
- Another beer?
- Sure, one more.
How much money do you have?
I stayed away from that bar
for some time,
partly because I didn't want
to hear song number 1 81 8.
But there are some things
you can't escape.
i've never returned
to that restaurant since that night.
Wishing you good fortune
and long life to reach the heavens
Wishing you a happy birthday
May this day bejoyous
foryou everyyear
Best wishes to you
How are you, my boy?
Your dad's fine.
Don't worry about me.
Soon it'll be your birthday.
I'm sorry i can't come home.
Is your mother feeling better?
Is your sister behaving herself?
Sato-san is a real family man.
He was a film director
before he opened this place.
So he always communicates
with his family by making a videotape.
I'm sure his son must be very happy
to receive his videotapes.
Sometimes i want
to try the same thing.
But I don't know
who i'd send my tapes to.
i don't want to end up
sending them to myself.
You whom i hold in my heart
Why did you leave my side
Because ofyou
I'm sad all the time
I miss you with all my heart
My beloved
Come back to me
Hurry back to my side
Though i'm not like Sato-san,
I can feel the same happiness as his son
on receiving his father's tape.
Get out of here!
I've got nothing to say.
i want to go to sleep.
Are you crazy?
Get out of here!
Go away!
Later that night, I discovered Dad
secretly watching the tape.
He really enjoyed it.
I'm usually very bad at details,
but i remembervery well
that it was his 60th birthday.
He kept laughing as he watched it.
Who knows what he found so funny.
But I know he was happy.
Stupid kid!
When you've worked
with someone for a long time,
he can have a certain effect on you.
I knew that fragrance very well.
i just wasn't used
to smelling it on anotherwoman.
This suit fits me well.
But I think it's shrunk a little.
I never liked this fragrance
all that much.
This afternoon
I smelled it on anotherwoman.
She wants to see you very much.
I set up a meeting foryou with her.
You're not gonna go, right?
You should go.
That wayyou could clear things up.
Then again,
it's even better ifyou don't go.
I know you'll go.
You can have this back.
I want...
a bag ofchips.
The yellow ones, not the red.
They sat there together
for a long time that day.
I wonderwhat they said
to each other.
it rained the whole time.
i started to think,
"it's raining so hard.
How will i get home by myself?"
Just when i really needed a raincoat,
he returned to my side.
It would be so great
if it could rain forever.
I'm not coming up.
Then why'd you walk me home?
You should have let me
come back alone!
I was thinking ofcoming back
by myselfanyway.
Why did you do that?
Think it'd be easier on me this way?
You're crazy!
Fuck off!
I never want to see you again!
I thought we had agreed on this.
Not me!
I never agreed to anything!
I asked you not to see her, but you did.
Now what do you want from me?
You think i'm a fool?
Get lost!
Liar!
Give me your arm.
Why'd you do that?
Can't I leave you a memento?
You might forget my face,
but not my bite.
But my face is easy to remember.
I have a mole.
Ifa woman with a mole on her face
comes up to you on the street,
it could be me.
You won't remember me.
Yes, i will.
Do I remember her?
Actually, it's not that important.
For her,
i'm just a stopover
on thejourney of her life.
i hope she reaches
her destination soon
and finds a man who really loves her.
We all need a partner.
When will i find mine?
Are we still partners?
I didn't know
how to answer that question.
I had come to look at partners
from a new angle.
As a business partner,
she was perfect.
But she wasn't the kind of partner
you could spend your life with.
I'd like to terminate
our business relationship.
Do me one last favor, will you?
I don't know why i agreed.
Maybe because
it was the last time.
I want to place
an advertisement for my friend.
On the front page.
The best thing about my profession
is there's no need
to make any decisions.
Who's to die, when, where-
it's all been planned by others.
I'm a lazy person.
I like people to arrange things for me.
It's been a bit different lately.
I want to change this habit.
i don't know
if it's a good decision or not,
but at least it's mine.
Old people say taking someone's picture
shortens that person's life.
i'm not sure it's true.
One evening, Dad wasn't feeling well.
I took him to the hospital.
He passed away a while later.
All these years, i've always felt
like a little boy because of him.
He was someone i could always turn to,
someone to solve all my problems.
Packing up his stuffthat evening,
I felt like a grown-up
for the first time.
But i don't wanna be a grown-up.
I sure wish Dad
could always be with me!
When i left the hotel,
the videotape was all i took with me.
i watched it over and over
before i left.
Watching Dad cook in the kitchen,
i feel very happy.
Though i know
I'll never taste his steaks again,
I'll never forget how they tasted.
You again?
i'll be damned!
Stop pulling my hair!
You promised!
You should know not to touch it.
I'd love to be your customer.
Did I ever say no?
Did I?
Look at me! How do I look?
Don't touch me!
My wife has gone to China.
I have some business to take care of.
Give me three hours.
I promise i'll be back on time.
Three hours, okay?
Three hours.
Two hours?
It's a deal.
Two hours and I'll be back.
Come on, trust me.
We're old friends now, aren't we?
It's a small world. We keep running
into each other. Two hours.
Trust me, please!
You have my word.
We're brothers, right?
You want it written in blood?
You gotta be kidding!
That's my bone!
Just one, okay?
ifyou cut them all off,
I won't be able to go out in public!
Could I have some change, please?
Thanks.
I'm downstairs already.
Hurry and come down.
Bye-bye.
It must havejust been bad luck.
Soon after Dad died,
Sato-san returned toJapan.
Since i didn't have much in savings,
I could only do what i'm best at:
being my own boss.
But i was very cautious this time.
I tried to pick the stronger shops.
Ones that wouldn't get hurt easily.
Like this one.
Its equipment was mostly steel.
It saves a lot oftrouble.
At times i'd run into acquaintances.
Some hadn't changed much.
Others I hardly recognized.
I was always glad when i saw them,
even though
they might not remember me.
Ofcourse, there were exceptions.
On August 29, 1 995,
I ran into my first love again.
But she seemed to have forgotten me.
I guess i'd gotten too handsome.
- How come you're so late?
- I was busy.
What's he doing?
Who knows?
It was cold that evening.
I hadn't expected winter
to come so soon.
i'm less and less used
to this kind ofweather.
Winter seems so long this year.
Though I eat a lot every day,
I still feel cold.
I've gotten used to life
without a partner.
Though i work with others at times,
I don't usually have fixed partners.
i've grown more cautious.
I won't make their beds anymore,
for example.
I don't inspect their trash,
'cause i believe
even more strongly now
that the best partners
don't get emotionally involved.
You rub elbows
with a lot of people every day.
Some strangers might become
your friends or even confidants.
So i never turn my back
on a chance to rub elbows.
Sometimes i rub till i bleed.
No big deal,
as long as I'm happy.
That night,
I ran into that woman again.
I knew very well we'd never be
friends or confidants.
We'd had too many chances
to rub elbows in the past.
We had rubbed elbows
till our clothes tore, but still no sparks.
Maybe it was the weather,
but that evening i felt a spark.
As i was leaving,
I asked if he'd give me a ride home.
i hadn't ridden
on a motorcycle in a long time.
Actually, i hadn't been
that close to a man for a while.
The road wasn't that long,
and i knew i'd be getting offsoon.
But at that moment
i felt such warmth.
Translation and Subtitles by
Captions, inc., Los Angeles.