Miss Alisha, Father wants you
to eat breakfast with him.
In a minute.
Father says he can't stay long.
Come on.
I want to look for a job.
You need more money? How much?
I just want to be kept busy.
I feel bored to death
when I'm just in the house
waiting for you to come.
Why don't you let me go
out of the country with you?
I'm going to work.
I could stay in a hotel
or go for a walk on my own.
Unless that other woman
has already asked to come along.
I was just joking. No need to get upset.
BASTARD
Where is this job interview?
This is the address.
MULTIZONAMEDIA COMPANY
Who have you worked for?
I've never had a job. I've just graduated.
Do you have something else?
Something with a more
serious style, perhaps?
That's all I have, sir.
But this is my style.
Twenty years old.
So young.
Hello?
Okay, I'll take it outside.
Yes?
Oh. Hello, sir.
Oh yes.
What can I do for you?
Is that so?
All right, sir.
No problem. Good day, sir.
When can you start work?
I got the job?
-Yes.
-Why?
What do you mean?
A moment ago,
you were not sure about my ability.
I never said that.
Who was on the phone?
I need a designer as soon as possible.
And I like your portfolio.
So I'll try to ignore
your impolite attitude,
asking me who I was
talking to on the phone.
So, what do you think, Alisha?
Yes, sir. Okay.
Give me your phone.
MISTER HARYO
Multizonamedia. How may I help you?
We're going home. Now.
You look really pretty, Alisha.
No one believes me.
But I know your father's plan.
Look, Alisha.
This is what he is going to use
to kill me.
We were confused
about what name to give you.
Ajeng,
Kirana,
or Alisha.
Then…
your father gave in
and agreed to my choice.
But since your father met that woman,
he's become her dog.
She tells your father to kill me
after your little brother is born.
But Mommy won't let that happen.
Your brother will never be born.
You two will…
never be hers.
There's only one way,
Alisha, my lovely daughter.
You,
your little brother,
and Mommy,
we will be together again in Heaven.
Mommy can't do it, Alisha.
Mommy really can't do it!
You have to do it yourself.
After me.
Everything happens for a reason, Alisha.
Who's the guy cleaning the pool?
He's replacing Mr. Pono
while he's on holiday.
Where is he from?
He said that he sometimes
works for Mrs. Pono.
She owns a food stall in Block S.
Block S?
There are lots of roadside stalls there.
They sell dumplings, satay, fried rice.
They're all in Block S.
Miss Tuti! I'm going home!
Wait a minute!
-What time will you come tomorrow?
-In the morning.
Thanks, Miss Tuti.
Miss Tuti!
I'm going home!
Hold on!
Thanks.
Miss Tuti, where's the pool cleaner?
He doesn't work here anymore.
Mr. Pono will be back tomorrow.
Why do you ask?
No reason.
Mr. Bambang, I'm going out.
Mr. Bambang, do you know
a place to eat called Block S?
You want to go there?
Okay, good afternoon.
You're with us again.
This is for the guests under the tent.
We will entertain you
with some of our songs.
One orange juice, please.
Yes?
Are you going to be long?
Yes, I am. No need to wait for me.
You can go home.
I'll just wait.
-Hey, Bar!
-What's up?
-Where have you been?
-Hey, ma'am.
I've been working.
-No wonder you brought an envelope. Cool!
-Tacky.
-Come on. Buy us some drinks.
-Thanks, ma'am.
See you, guys.
Block S to the left.
Let's go.
You're still studying?
I'll be done in a moment.
Let's eat.
What did you get?
This.
Gado-gado again?
Don't worry. When I'm rich,
I'll take you to expensive restaurants
every night.
I'm just kidding, dear.
As long as I'm with you,
I don't care if I eat at all.
Yeah, right. You're so cheesy.
FOR RENT
Miss Alisha, I was scared to death.
Where have you been?
I just wanted to be alone.
Don't do that.
I'll get in trouble with your father.
If he gets mad, just say it's my fault.
Wherever and whenever you
want to go out, I can take you.
You just need to ask.
I'm bored going out with you.
Bored or not, that's my job.
What are you getting mad for?
Have you forgotten who's the boss here?
Now, you listen.
Your father is my boss, not you.
My job is to look after you!
Okay, that's enough.
Miss, it's fine if you don't
want to go out with Bambang.
Next time, let me accompany you.
You want to go with her?
She'll go off by herself in a minute.
You can't even look after a girl.
Weren't you a private detective before?
These are for you.
I'm sorry about last night.
But these are expensive.
That's okay for once in a while.
You still want to take me around, right?
I promise I won't go off by myself again.
How long are you going to be
in the music studio?
Only until the afternoon.
Why don't you come inside
and watch me practice?
Please carry these.
My friends are waiting.
Later, come back to take my cello.
Please come in.
Thank you.
Pecel!
Who did you tell your parents
you lived with?
With no one.
I'm not crazy.
They think samenleven
means premarital cohabitation.
When it only means to live together.
It's not just couples
who live together before marriage.
Different races living in the same country
are also samenleven.
And your point is?
My point is
Indonesians have many ways of giving
negative connotations to many things.
Example?
Well, we live together
because we love each other.
Who's in love?
Why are you such a pain today?
What's up?
Right. My friend's studying.
She has an exam tomorrow.
So I came over.
I'm scared she'll get pissed.
If she gets pissed, ouch.
So?
Oh, right. Sorry.
What are you doing?
I can't drain water out of the sink.
Can I take a look?
Try and open the faucet.
You need to tighten it.
Hitting it won't do any good.
The water here is quite dirty.
But I have a spare filter.
Do you want it?
I'll go and get it.
Can I come with you?
I'd like to see
what the other rooms look like.
Renta, we've got a new neighbor.
Hi. I'm Renta.
Mia.
I haven't introduced myself.
I'm Bari.
Bari told me you're studying for an exam.
I'd better go.
I don't want to disturb you.
No, not at all.
If Bari sees someone reading,
he automatically thinks they're studying.
What are you reading?
It's just a coursebook.
Renta is a budding psychologist.
You never read the psychology book
I bought you.
That's just pop psychology, Bari.
It doesn't have anything to do
with what I study.
What book?
You know, self-help.
How would I know?
It came from the psychology shelf.
Read it, then.
I can't be bothered.
-A writer who doesn't like reading.
-I read.
You never finish.
Every good book I read makes me jealous
and makes me want to write.
You're a writer?
Just like reading, he never finishes it!
One day, my book will be released,
and it'll have "New York Times Bestseller"
written on the cover.
You just wait,
Miss Shrink.
Are you at university?
No.
Who likes rabbits?
I do.
Oh, hold on.
Where did you steal this from?
From a rich person's house.
They can just buy another one.
It's cute.
Psychologists shouldn't like
childish stuff like that.
It's so cute.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
Are you friends or family?
Oh shit! I am late!
Relax. The traffic's not bad at this hour.
By the way, our money
has nearly all gone, Bar.
All right!
Off you go!
Wow. That sounded great.
-Cello?
-Yes.
Are you a musician?
No. It's just a hobby.
Is it difficult to play?
Have a go.
Sorry.
Place your hand like this.
It sounds bad now.
You used a cassette, didn't you?
Why did you move here?
My parents died a long time ago.
I lived with my aunt.
I felt it was time for me to move out.
Where do you work?
I am still looking working for work. You?
I'll do any work.
Paint walls or be a driver.
Why did you choose to live here?
I had a mate
who told me
that if I wanted to be a writer
and find inspiration,
I should live in a block of flats.
He was right.
This block of flats is like a circus.
You get all types
and loads of weirdos here.
Have you got any material for your book?
Oh, I've got lots.
But I don't know.
It seems that I can't find a good ending
for any story I write.
Maybe because I use real people
from these flats for my characters.
They continue to live their lives.
If you think about it,
that's the difference
between fiction and reality.
Fiction has an ending,
but in the real world, life goes on.
Have you explored all the stories?
Not yet.
What have you seen, then?
What's to see?
So, you haven't been out
since moving here?
-Come on.
-Where to?
I'll give you a free tour.
The first floor is the business district.
You can find anything you want here.
Food, telephone service, Xerox machines,
hairdresser, bathroom supplies.
They are all here.
The second floor is mostly
regular families.
Hello, ma'am.
It's the noisiest as there are many kids.
The third floor is interesting.
There are lots of lady-boys. Transsexuals.
Monday to Thursday, they're men.
On the weekend, they become women.
They all stay in the same room.
They work at park entrances
and a few other places.
The fourth floor is mostly occupied
by whores.
Pardon my language,
but that's what they are.
They're pretty high class,
so they don't look like prostitutes.
They stay in this cheap block of flats
so they can save money
and send it to their family
in the countryside.
Lots of them still have families
The fifth floor is a nest of drug dealers.
You can get anything up here.
If you need some weed,
you just have to go down one floor.
Or you can just knock on my door.
On our floor, most of the residents
are office workers and students.
So, it's cleaner and quieter
than the others.
The seventh floor,
believe it or not,
is mostly occupied by gays.
On Friday nights,
there's usually a party up there.
They're fun and very friendly.
The eighth and final floor
is mostly filled with mistresses.
They stay at the top
so others don't cross them.
I thought this block had nine floors?
The ninth floor is empty.
It's haunted.
Really?
People say that the ninth floor
is haunted by the ghosts of people
whose houses caught fire.
Or more precisely,
when their houses were burned down.
This building is built over the remains.
So, where are we going now?
I want to show you my stories.
That man has never gone into his flat
since this place was built five years ago.
Why?
In my story,
he feels that if he goes in,
he loses, and they win.
Who are "they"?
The people who burned the houses
so they could build this block of flats.
As compensation,
his family was given a flat.
He's never entered? Not even once?
The flat on the corner is never opened.
A woman lives there.
Sixty-five years old.
Her name is Mrs. Dirah.
She has lived there
since this block of flats opened.
She used to live in a house on this land.
Why does she never open the door?
There are loads of cats inside.
People say that she's still a virgin.
She never speaks to anyone.
She loves her cats so much.
At first, she only had one cat. Then two.
The cats got together and had kittens.
If you ask me,
I think she's crazy.
She only goes out
to throw out the rubbish.
Let's go.
What's interesting in a story
about an old woman who loves her cats?
In my story,
she used to have a fiancé.
She loved him very much,
but he was murdered.
Next to his corpse was a cat.
She's sure that the soul
of her fiancé is in the cat.
And the kittens are their children.
It sounds cheap.
But in my writing, it doesn't.
It will resemble fairy tales.
The guy outside is called Rudi.
The one inside is called Dani.
They're a gay couple.
What's interesting is
I suspect they're father and son.
So, they're not gay.
Gay, but father and son as well.
How do you know?
I used to hang out with Dani.
I was in their room one night,
and Rudi hadn't been back for three days.
Dani was in a panic, drunk and crying.
I just listened to his incoherent babble.
He said that Rudi was his father?
Not directly.
But he got a call from his mother.
She wanted to know where he was.
He wouldn't tell her.
How do you know
they're a gay couple, then?
Everyone here knows that.
But I don't know.
Maybe I'm sick.
Am I sick?
Have you written all these stories?
Yes.
But I haven't got the endings.
Why don't you just make them up?
I haven't come up with a good one.
All my stories
are what really happened here.
So they have to be real.
There is some artistic license,
but the plot has to happen.
Can I read the stories
that you've written?
No way. It's embarrassing.
Oh, come on.
Okay.
For your eyes only.
Who am I gonna show them to?
Maybe you'll show them
to the people I'm writing about.
I'd freak out.
FICTION. #2 BY BARI
Alisha.
Everything happens for a reason, Alisha.
Are you new?
I've been here for a week.
I'm on the sixth floor.
I can't open the rubbish shoot.
Why did you come, not down?
I go down a lot.
I wanted to see what upstairs was like.
Well, it's like this. Just the same.
Are you in college?
Yes.
What's your major?
Product design.
You don't have class today?
Later today.
I'm still working on a presentation.
I'm super busy.
I'd invite you in,
but I should finish my work.
I'm sorry.
Can I have a look at your work?
I'm curious to see product design.
Okay. But just for a minute.
Come in.
I'm doing a logo design for a new product.
I have the concept in my head.
The problem is how to present it on paper.
Why don't you do this?
I'm impressed.
I have studied design.
Can I help you or not?
I always work on my own.
But it's quite urgent,
so I can use your help.
Done.
Let me see.
That's awesome!
If I have another assignment,
can I ask for your help?
I won't be able to do it this good.
Anytime.
Let's print it out.
MOM
By the way, what do you
want for your help? Tea?
I'll make one for you.
PHONE BOOTH X NO. 27
SELLING PHONE CREDIT
-Hello?
-May I speak to Dani's mother?
This is she.
Are you really Dani's mother?
Yes, I am.
Who's speaking?
Is your husband's name Rudi?
Yes.
Who's this?
I know where they are.
-Hey!
-Papa Bear!
Kiddy Bear!
Mia!
Come in.
Meet my friend Mia.
She helped me with my presentation.
Have a drink, Mia!
By the way, don't you feel out of place?
I'm a friend of Dani.
Dani's friend?
Are you a lezzy?
-What?
-Are you a lesbian?
Oh no.
Are you gay?
Gay?
No way.
You're still a virgin, right?
Yeah, definitely.
You should try it with a woman.
You should try both ways
before you decide which one you like.
There's a gun!
-Hey!
-What's happening here?
Mia!
I was right!
Rudi and Dani are father and son.
Well, stepfather, actually.
Dani's mother was just here
and shot him dead.
It was nuts!
What's wrong with you?
I was there when it happened.
Mia!
Mia?
-Where were you?
-Downstairs.
Yeah, I heard about what happened.
It's crazy. So tragic.
I'm still shocked.
Hi, neighbor. I never see you around.
I brought you this.
Such a hassle, Mi.
It's just an old collection.
Hi, Bar.
Hi, Mi.
Are you writing a story?
He's sick.
A terrible tragedy happens,
and it inspires him.
See? He is autistic when he writes.
I better go home.
Why so fast?
I just came by to give that to you.
Bye, Bari.
Bye.
Bari, wake up!
Did you see the book
that I was reading last night?
Which one?
The one with the white cover.
No.
This is it.
Come on. Wake up.
You wanted me to wake you up, right?
Don't you have a painting job today?
Yes, Mia?
That's so expensive. No, thanks.
I'm sure. No.
Thanks anyway.
What did Mia want?
She's in a store.
She saw a bunny statue
and offered to pick it up for me.
But it's too expensive.
Hurry up. Take a shower!
Where were you, Mia?
At a friend's, then I went shopping.
What's wrong?
How long have you been out?
All day.
Didn't I phone Renta this morning?
What's going on?
Someone died.
What? Who?
Her name is Mrs. Dirah.
You may have never met her.
The lady with all the cats?
Bari told me. How did she die?
She jumped from the seventh floor.
Her cats were gone.
A few of them were found dead
inside the first floor's garbage bin.
Someone must have thrown them there.
Who would do such a thing?
There are a lot
of sick people around here.
Hey.
Where were you?
I told you. I was at a friend's,
then I went shopping.
Why are you interrogating me?
If you think it was me
who threw the cats into the garbage bin,
you're out of your mind!
You're eaten up by your own fiction.
Well, no.
It's weird.
It seems this is all a coincidence.
Yesterday, Rudi died.
Now, Mrs. Dirah.
And everything happened
after I showed you my stories.
I brought you this. I found another one.
But I am not going to
collect them anymore.
-Why?
-For detachment.
What do you mean?
It's not good getting
too attached to something.
There has got to be a separation
so you don't depend on it too much.
Anyway, they're just statues
and bunny dolls.
Hi, Bar.
Hi, Mi.
Okay then, I'd better be going.
I just wanted to give you this.
What's going on?
What's going on between you and Mia?
What do you mean?
I'm not that stupid, Bari.
I know there's something going on here.
You swear?
I just don't like the girl.
Why?
Don't you think she is a bit weird?
Why does she give you those dolls?
It's like she's looking for your sympathy.
You're being oversensitive.
Maybe writer's block?
I don't know.
It feels so cruel to write
about these sorts of events.
In a minute.
Who is it, Bar?
No one. Just kids playing around.
Just twist their ears if you catch them.
All right.
Renta, I'm going out for cigarettes!
Bari, can I talk to you for a second?
Renta, you better go in.
What do you want to talk about?
I want to apologize for yesterday.
I don't know what I was thinking.
-What do you want from me?
-I love you.
I don't want anything from you.
I'm not asking for anything.
I just wanted to let you know.
Bari, wait.
Please accompany me for a while.
I can't, Mi. I better go inside.
I want to tell Renta.
About what?
-I want to tell her the truth.
-She doesn't need to know.
-Of course she needs to know!
-But why?
Why? Because I love her!
And I wish for a miracle
that she will forgive me.
You should be more concerned
about your stories, not her.
I hate those stories.
The endings are so cliché.
And what's more cliché is my own story.
A guy who already has a girlfriend
getting involved with…
A what?
A psychopath?
I am not a psychopath.
From now on, I won't bother you anymore.
You don't need to tell Renta anything.
Everything will go back
to how it used to be.
Renta!
Can you leave me alone, please?
Ta.
I will do anything for you.
Anything.
If it means that you'll forgive me.
I don't know about that.
But please leave me alone for now.
Please.
I AM SORRY, BAR.
I HAVE TO GO. I JUST WISH FOR ONE THING.
FINISH YOUR STORIES. RENTA.
The number you are calling
is not available right now.
I'm sitting on this mat.
The same mat
I've been sitting on for five years.
Here, opposite my room.
No, not my room.
If I say this is my room,
It means that I lose and they won.
They burned my house five years ago.
They took our land to build this flat.
They didn't give us money.
Just this room on the seventh floor
that will never replace my old house.
Not because it was a big house,
but I built it with my own hands.
My masterpiece.
The only masterpiece I ever had.
My marriage is clearly not a masterpiece.
My wife is dumb.
I am dumb.
We don't even know how to communicate.
We didn't go to school.
Maybe that's why
my three kids are not masterpieces either.
My eldest son is missing now.
He stabbed someone to death
when he was 14 years old.
I don't know if he's already free
or still in jail.
My second son always stays in the house.
He never leaves the house,
never hangs out,
or does anything.
He doesn't work, doesn't go to school.
None of my kids go to school.
Maybe that's why.
My third kid is a daughter.
Maybe she's the only one
that's close to a masterpiece.
Her smile is charming. Her skin is fair.
Even though she's never had a facial.
A facial!
Our family has to struggle just for food.
She'll be home soon.
She has found her soulmate.
A biker who also owns a cart
to sell fried snacks.
She will be somebody.
Her life will be better.
Today, her boyfriend and his family
are coming to propose to my daughter.
Since morning, my wife has tried
to get me to enter the room.
Why don't you come in for a while?
It's for your daughter's sake!
When their family has gone,
you can sit there again!
Or go somewhere else
until they've all gone,
then you can come back.
They'll never understand.
No one can.
Except for my daughter.
She's the only one who understands me.
I'm sure she won't force me
to come inside.
I am sure she won't be ashamed.
The time is getting near.
She'll be home very soon.
I can't wait to see her!
She just had her first visit
to the hairdresser.
There she is.
Wow. She looks so pretty.
She's prettier than usual.
She's my masterpiece, after all.
She understands me like no other.
I'm sure she won't mind
if I stay on my mat.
Father, you're still out here?
Are you trying to embarrass me?
Do you want my future in-laws to run away?
Can you force that old man to come inside?
I am sure she is acting like that
because today is her big day.
I can't be selfish.
I have to do something.
But what?
If I go in, it means I lost,
and they won.
What should I do?
What?
My body feels so weak.
I can't walk too far.
If I'm still here, they would see me
and my daughter will be ashamed.
What should I do?
What?
This railing is not too high.
Maybe I could climb on it.
My body is very light anyway.
Hop.
I am on top of it now.
One.
Two.
Three.
Everything is in slow motion.
I am flying.
Maybe because my body is very light.
Did I lose?
Or did I win?
All that I know is no one will miss me.
PERPENSI BND COOPERATIVE STORE
Where were you?
You know something happened?
Tell me you've got nothing to do with it.
I've been out all afternoon, Bari.
I want to talk to you.
-There is nothing to talk about.
-Yes, there is.
Okay, let's talk.
We can't talk here.
There is something important
that I need to show you.
Come with me, please.
Then you will understand why.
Come with me for a moment.
Trust me. I promise you,
everything is going to be okay.
Everything is going to go back to normal.
Trust me, Renta.
I AM SORRY, BAR. I HAVE TO GO.
I JUST WISH FOR ONE THING.
FINISH YOUR STORIES.
MIA, THE GIRL NEXT DOOR, LISTENS TO,
NOT ONLY MY GUITAR OR MY STORIES
BUT ALSO TO RENTA'S AND MY DESIRES
AND THOUGHTS. MIA IS TRULY A WOMAN.
How did you get in here?
Your description of me
is really interesting, Bar.
This is Renta's key!
Where did you get it?
What have you done to her?
Where is Renta?
Where is she?
It turns out that the most interesting
story of all is your own story, Bar.
What have you done to her?
Please, Mia, where is she?
I thought this block had nine floors?
The ninth floor is empty.
-It's haunted.
-Really?
People say that the ninth floor
is haunted by the ghosts of people
whose houses caught fire.
The building is built over the remains.
Renta!
Help!
Sir, please help.
And how is this story going to end?
Everything happens for a reason.
CIKINI BOOKSTORE
FICTION.
BY BARI ANDHARA