Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
…Under the whip of pleasure,
this merciless torturer
Where are we?
I don't know… nowhere.
And who are you?
I don't know. No one yet.
No one?
I shall be…
Who?
"O", perhaps.
We are here. I'll remove your blindfold.
In the late 1920s, China is restless.
Rebellions are breaking out in Hong Kong and Shanghai.
Yet Sir Stephen chose
to bring "O" here,
to test their insane pact…
…and the strength of their love.
Are you sure you won't regret it?
I won't regret it.
Are you sure?
You know that through other men,
I will be yours only.
Fruits of Passion
Mama…
Hurry up!
What are you staring at?
A new one.
A white prostitute…
Looks like it.
She won't last.
Fabulous
You really want us
to take her in charge?
Such a lovely girl?
Definitely, you'll teach her.
But…
It's a challenge. We have an agreement.
It is a detour to reach the deepest form of love.
There's no need to understand,
keep the money anyway.
You have heard of me, I suppose?
Oh, yes, they say that in Shangai…
I am the owner of a casino there.
Ah, she really is willing?
Say it yourself.
Yes, I am willing.
She'll never stand it.
She looks so fresh
and innocent.
Suika!
Show her the rules of the House.
To work here,
you need to follow these rules…
Refuse a customer, and you shall receive 101 lashes.
Refuse a customer's request,
no matter how difficult it may be…
and you shall not be fed for 101 days.
You're no more than a plaything.
Pray to God
or commit a religious act,
and you shall be forced to…
…copulate with the Untouchables, such as drug addicts.
No, never. I'll never manage.
You see…
I am no longer myself.
You are my worst passion.
I want whatever you want.
Do I please you? Am I beautiful?
I'm all yours, Stephen.
Devil… You devil!
This'll be your room.
My name is O.
And mine's Byakuran.
We'll be friends.
The poor district along the river…
…here are the alleys, the slums.
Here they eat… drink… smoke.
And at daybreak they conspire as well.
If you keep drinking like that, you'll die.
Leave him alone. If he wants to kill himself…
…drinking's as good a way as any.
Yeah, and the cemetery costs a lot less than the alcohol.
Hey, it's your turn!
Papa! Get up, get up!
Get up!
My room…
no, my prison.
But love is my prison.
Wasn't I forever looking for a prison?
Now, there are real walls.
In a lower-class restaurant behind the house of pleasure…
…which the Chinese called "house of flowers"…
a young boy…
Come on, play!
I'm feeling lucky tonight.
Good move.
You know, he might be dead.
If he is, he's lucky.
No more debts, right?
Kato, come on. It's your turn.
Okay.
He was alright… He was really nice.
I really wouldn't worry.
He dies ten times a day.
Here you are.
I never leave you.
The light came on.
Hey! You horny kid, watching the brothel again.
The noodle's getting overcooked!
Without a mirror…
…my image
and my self elude me.
Haven't you gone to bed yet?
Beautiful …
Anything you need,
you have only to tell us, okay?
Goodnight.
Please, Madame,
when shall I begin?
That's for Sir Stephen to decide.
I just take care of my pretty French doll.
You didn't get a steel pot today?
Father, I am not a thief.
Spoiled brat!
Tomorrow you get a steel pot…
…or I'll kick you out! Got it?!
Place your bets.
You won again.
You win, that's right.
Bet's down, please. We'll begin the next one.
Twenty dollars to start. Bets down, please.
The open struggle will soon begin.
Men come out of the shadows.
They want foreign businessmen to contribute to their struggle.
What you want in fact is financial help?
The coolies union has voted that every coolie must
contribute five cents to the strike fund.
Which is not enough.
I don't see why you should ask an Englishman
to help you kick out the English!
The Soviet Union is sending material
to the army in Canton.
Race doesn't matter anymore.
Now what's the sense in it?
We want freedom for China.
The Chinese will be happier if they
remain under the control of foreigners.
You're wrong!
The history of China shows that
China has always got the better of its foreign rulers.
Let's go.
Why did we even bother.
Don't be in such a hurry.
I don't see eye to eye with you politically,
but I might help you all the same.
It's a kind of gamble.
How much would you want?
Stephen, Stephen, darling.
Let's go back to France.
My parents will leave.
Let's forget the business, everything.
The international concessions can't protect us anymore.
Let's go back.
We'll live together. Over there.
I don't want to leave China.
I'm happy here.
You know, Stephen, I understand.
Understand what?
Why you want to stay in China.
Because of "O", of course.
You can laugh if you like.
I pity you.
She chose to be a whore, that's all.
You think she loves you.
She doesn't choose. She accepts.
Because it's her desire.
It's ugly.
It's appalling.
She'll end up falling in love with someone else.
You'll see. She'll forget you.
It'll serve you right. You deserve it.
You don't understand a thing.
You got flowers… dirty flowers.
Who sent them?
Don't talk to me.
I speak no English.
Sad flowers.
And they're not from him.
Then who?
Why?
The little fortune teller hands out pieces of luck.
Time is in her box.
Oka-san does her books.
Oka-san means Madam.
Mama…
…didn't the studio send me a script?
What script?
The next movie to go into production.
Is there a new movie?
Mama, I'm still the lead.
Yesterday I got a letter
saying they were sending me a script.
You still got a big payment on your debt.
Take care of it or it's a problem!
Later, later, later, all the time!
What's going on?
She's told me the same story for ten years now!
That girl is crazy, crazy in the head!
Poor Aisen…
…spent 10 years dreaming she's still an actress…
A big star.
And poor Obana, endlessly coughing.
Obana…
…you should have a doctor examine you properly.
Sakuya listens to the piano at the bottom of the river.
It only plays for her… and for us.
When I was a kid, nobody bothered to play with me.
So I often lied to get attention.
A red bird nobody ever saw.
A piece of a star that fell from the sky.
A grand piano that sank in the river.
But my lies eventually became truth.
I can hear the piano in the river.
Come on in, come on in.
Here I am in a house of flowers.
We are the flowers.
A customer enters through the door.
Which one of us does he want?
Welcome, Sir Kudo Fu, are you in love?
I got a rare taxidermy piece.
I want to give it to her.
Thank you all the time.
Byakuran, sweetie! Byakuran!
Yes?
You sure you did it?
Yes, I did it all, everything.
Then I shall give you lashes!
Not yet, not yet.
Not yet?
Your line is wrong.
Why can't you remember?
In fact, I opened the letter,
I left the bee box open, it was all me.
Go on. Go on.
You opened the letter, you left the bee box open…
…you stole Mom's underwear,
it was all you, is that it?
Forgive me, Mom.
You shall be punished.
Show me your ass!
Don't hit me, Mom.
Don't… Do it harder!
Don't hit me, Mom, don't…
Don't hit me, Mom…
Mom, don't hit me, Mom…
Don't hit me, Mom, don't hit me.
My pretty Byakuran.
Which part is she playing?
I don't have a part yet.
I'm only an image.
It doesn't matter.
I hold you, I keep you.
Even if you're away… far…
or with another woman…
…you're with me.
Still no news from him?
That's the way he wanted it.
That way he is always with me…
I like it better that way.
What do you mean?
Letters show distance.
What distance?
Oh, don't you realize
he is here, in Hong Kong?…with Nathaiie?
His new woman?
She still doesn't understand.
Oh, what a curious ring!
May I try it on?
It's for me only.
Pleasure can be shared.
Pain is only for Stephen and me.
Papa!
Oh, Stephen, you threw me into another world.
Who can explain it to me?
Soldiers are marching by. Why soldiers?
All the girls are scared.
I don't like the military.
My brother.
Idiot! Stay quiet!
As the fortune teller walks by Death…
…the day is breaking.
Is it really okay?
You stay naked… don't you catch cold?
This looks fun.
How do you use it?
Wow.
You look like a bird!
I imitate pigeons very well.
You laughed… Finally.
Let's pretend we are pigeons.
You see, she really enjoys it. All on her own.
But I enjoy it, too.
We both share the pleasure.
You're horrible.
And you refuse to see the truth.
Right now, she's in another world.
She's forgetting you.
You make pigeon noise, too.
Come on in.
We have lots of pretty girls.
That girl.
So…? Anyone you like?
That woman.
That's "O."
And how much do you have?
How much?
Of course. Blondes are expensive.
What's wrong with this brat?
You're not serious?!
This is no place for kids.
He is rebelling.
A new recruit for the coolie organization.
You sure you weren't followed?
Sir Stephen shoves aside a young stranger.
So they each meet their destiny…
…without knowing it.
Rich asshole.
Kid, going to Ku-Ron?
Mr. Kudo Fu?
Don't talk loud. People might hear.
If you're going to Ku-Ron…
…take this.
We might have to change our plans.
But what about the Red Guard?
We must act now.
We have orders from the political committee.
Any ideas?
With no arms? How?
Keep your voice down.
The committee needs an answer.
And we need guns, right?
That's our answer.
Yeah, that's what we'll say.
Who'll deliver the message?
What about the boy?
He could pass through unnoticed. What do you say?
Good idea.
He wants money.
Kid, don't eavesdrop. Come over.
We'll give you work.
You'll pay?
After this, you can eat all the meat pie you want.
I don't want that.
I'm buying myself a girl.
You again!
Go!
Today I'll be watching.
He's a butcher from Canton.
He reeks of blood.
No…
…don't close your eyes.
Look.
I know.
I've always known.
I redeem you.
I make you free.
Stephen,
Stephen
What is she like, this girl we're visiting?
Just tell me… do you still love her?
I don't care if you won't answer me.
Let's go.
Here we are.
"O", this is Nathalie.
Hello.
Let's go.
She's beautiful…
but I make her uncomfortable.
I am not embarrassed.
I wanted you to see her.
I can't imagine living without her anymore.
Other than that, nothing has changed.
I understand.
Is that all?
Mademoiselle… How can you submit like this?
How can you even bear to have lunch with us?
You are…
It's terrible.
You love him, don't you?
So do I.
That's why I want him to choose.
What about you, "O"?
Do you also want me to choose?
I want whatever you want, that's all.
Yes, Nathalie. Why not her?
He won't think of other women.
The poor thing has no idea.
Crazy…
Crazy?
I am crazy.
I want to be crazy.
I know he loves my silence, my chains.
Look… Look!
See how he loves me.
She says, "See how he loves me."
While he's looking into my eyes.
The piano in the river.
I beg of you… talk to me, Stephen.
Your voice erases everything.
The parrot's escaped!
There, there!　-Hey, hey…
Thanks.
Action.
Can you hear that waltz?
That music that trembled my heart
is coming from the river.
Yes, Ma'am.
Wrong…
You hold a gun like this, right?
I've paid good money for you, and not just for the film.
And you fire, and I will die, saying…
Bang!
"My last wish before I die…"
How long do you want to continue this?
Let me do it or I'm leaving!
"Please request the orchestra"
"to play that sad waltz…"
Stop it already.
I'm not here to play an extra.
Bitch!
Talk about an ex-actress
and cheap!
Just an ugly crazy woman.
Piano coming from a river?!
An orchestra playing a waltz!
What do you take me for?
Let me do it, or I'm leaving.
Please, please…
I guarantee she'll do whatever you ask of her, you'll see…
You're so bad.
What you're doing doesn't make you a dog.
Bow-wow! Bow-wow!
Be a real dog!
Show him an example.
Fetch!
Good dog.
See, Carloff…
You see how to be a good dog?
Paw!
Stay!
Father.
Dad, got a toy dog for me?
No, I drank the money.
"O", without a clue, witnesses the first meeting…
…the first signal.
Terrorism breaks out.
First target… the Union Jack.
First attack… a police precinct.
A little higher.
Raise your arm. The other side.
He's much too young for this.
O, You've got to get well.
Do you feel a little better?
I am sorry.
You are no good.
He ought to be here, with you now
Hey, how is she?
Don't worry. Just a cold.
Oh yeah?
Then, fine.
History sets so many different traps.
Sure of himself, he gambled without thinking he could lose.
And yet…
It's like… leaving to die.
Medical cost is not that much.
You Europeans always do things by halves, that's your way.
I've told you, not a penny more.
And now, get out!
Do you really mean it? Not a penny?
Running with the wolves, yes.
It's a gamble.
But contributing for slaughter
No, I'm not interested.
Asshole. You betrayed us!
Wait! We can work something out…
Take anything valuable.
We'll sell them and buy weapons!
Help! Help! Call the police, hurry!
A customer for you. No?
You're still not well?
Not really, I'm sorry.
IF you are sick, I won't force you.
But don't forget the agreement with Sir Stephen.
You've no right to choose.
It's okay for today, but…
Well…? "O" got roses again?
Mama.
Something's weird with Aisen.
She's always weird.
Action
Okay, okay. It's started.
Do you like to dance?
Yes, of course.
Your age?
I'm 42.
27.
That night of celebration…
…we sneaked out of the dancing crowd…
We listened by the river…
…that sad waltz…
But…
…the ship has sailed off.
I don't care.
Let's drink through the night.
I can't.
The cops will be here soon.
Then, please ask for me…
…ask that traveling singer…
…to play that sad song, that sad waltz.
Aisen, let's run away.
It's not too late yet.
It's no use. Too late.
Because the world ends… right here.
Aisen. You are not…
The two of us…
Yes.
The two of us will dance the sad waltz
and escape to the world's end.
Before the cops arrive.
The red moon over Monte Carlo,
a gleaming gun in the right hand…
…the end of the world is in my heart.
Let's make up our minds with one gunshot…
…no, with two!
The two of us, where nobody can catch us.
The movie died.
Double suicide…
Shot the man,
then drowned herself.
A prostitute and a john.
Heard she had a big debt.
Look, a piano floated to the surface.
How did a grand piano get in the river?
I don't know…
She played her last part.
She played it to the bitter end.
She took off her mask.
We mustn't cry over her.
The fortune teller has grown older.
Her box is void of future.
What's going on?
Don't come any closer.
I can't stand it, I'm leaving!
Don't touch me! Leave me alone!
What's wrong, Nathalie?
You're evil,
you're a fake, a cheat!
You're disgusting!
No!
Are you crazy?
Let go of me!
You were right, go back to "O"!
You two make a fine pair!
You'll be ruined!
She can support you!
Don't make a fool of me!
Come in.
Hello.
What do you want?
This is for you.
Sit down.
I would like just a little…
A little what?
A little smile.
Because you'd
look even lovelier, I know.
What is there to smile about?
For what reason?
I paid… a lot of money!
Don't kiss me!
Why not?
You belong to me now.
I bought you. You're mine forever.
Let me have this.
I'll buy you a new ring…
My arm!
It's because of you that I hurt it,
I needed money to pay for you.
She kissed him.
What an idiot.
He's just a kid.
You smiled! Smile more!
Does she still belong to Sir Stephen?
He doesn't know anymore.
He's beside himself with anger.
Fate turns against him.
No more opium.
Kato sent me.
Ogaku? Are you in there?
Yes.
Hello
No.
Why?
In China when friends meet,
they never shake hands.
They do like this.
Really? Why?
For fear of contamination.
Well, well, well…
why such a difficult topic?
Shall we dance?
No, no dance.
I have a good girl.
Byakuran, nice rental costume.
We're getting married.
Married?
He's my childhood sweetheart.
Neither of us could go to school…
…so we played hide-and-seek in slaughterhouses.
Why not a masked ball today?
Does this make me look like a charming demon?
"O"?
Do you know him?
He is…
That boy, last night…
Yes.
The boy was killed.
Sir Stephen killed him,
then tried to kill himself…
…but they stopped him in time.
Take this contract.
I give it back to you.
"O", you are free!
You are free!
You can go wherever you want.
But if you want, you can stay here.
You are free!
You can go wherever you want.
But if you want, you can stay here, "O".