Good morning.
Hiroshi, look.
He still carries his scetchbook.
He seems so normal
since he has lost his wife.
It's a month ago
now that his wife left him.
I wonder where he's going with the torch.
Wait, Hiroshi!
This is my secret place.
All my lost treasures are here.
All the beautiful things I have ever lost,
they are here.
All the time I have lost
is here.
Everything is hidden in the darkness.
When I was a child, there used to be
a river here. I played there.
Fish, friends, dragonflies...
They disappeared.
Chibi, is that you?
You were away out of a sudden!
And now you are here
in this cold place.
You poor thing.
I am a painter.
I have to paint Chibi.
You?
I met you once.
Then, when there was a river here.
It was you then?
Yes, I am the mermaid.
When the river got dried
this is where I stranded.
I can hear you. Your voice
sounds in my heart.
You have been living here in the dark...
all this time.
Ever since the day I met you here
I enjoy coming here.
I came here for years in order to paint.
Now I understand the reason.
Why?
Just to see you again
and to paint.
Everything, I have ever lost,
I can find in you.
From now on I will point you all the time.
What is if?
You get something in such places.
We go home. To my place.
We have to look after the infection.
Let's go home.
Thanks.
Let me see.
This will certainly help you.
This medicine heals all kinds
of diseases.
You better point me.
That is your mission.
Yes, my mission.
That's true.
Das ist wahr.
I am a painter.
I will point you.
From now on I will point you forever.
Hiroshi, what happened to the pointer
from upstairs?
He used to go out everyday
with his scetchbook.
How should I know about if?
-Haven't I told you
that they delivered a
bathtube last week?
Why are you so interested in this guy?
Stop it.
Then stop if.
You are so stupid!
What is if?
Are you ok?
Wait.
Thank goodness.
If stopped.
Thanks.
This medicine doesn't seem to work.
Damn it.
You should eat something.
What do you want?
It's long ago that I had fish.
Fish.
I'll get you some fresh fish.
Wait here.
Hello.
Is it true?
-Yes, it's true. I was shocked.
I see half bitten raw fish
in the trash every day.
You can judge people according to
their trash.
If is very strange.
I'm sick of if.
Yes, if is strange.
A whole fish in one bite.
Maybe he bought a little pet monster.
Hiroshi, you frighten me!
Are you sure you want if?
Yes, there are little puppps of seven
different colours in these tumors.
My body is full of little puppps
of seven colours.
I suffer so much.
Please hurry.
My body hurts!
I suffer.
Hurry UP!
Do if.
I am tired.
I need a break.
I go out to get some fish.
What?
Are you ok?
Don't die.
Don't die!
She died.
My mermaid is dead.
My precious mermaid died.
She died.
Quick, you have to point me.
You have to point me in the
moment before I die. Hurry up!
The painting.
It's finished.
Now I have to look after you.
No, it's too late.
You have to kill me now.
It's a long time ago that
I've seen the pointer from upstairs.
I wonder what has happened.
-I smell rotten fish.
It's so strange.
It makes me sick.
Do you think something is wrong?
What?
What's that?
Hiroshi...
Mr Haydashi?
It's open.
She's dead.
My mermaid is dead.
She is dead.
So...
What can I say?
The dead body must belong
to his wife.
It's a terrible story.
She was awfully injured.
You know, there was a baby in there.
When I think about if...
Are you ok?
I'm scared!
He killed his wife.
Let us pass.
His wife had been bedridden
for a long time.
He was an art teacher.
A very gentle, friendly man.
What will happen to him?
I have no idea.
Beautiful...
This is the result of the investigation.
According to the autopsy report
the painter dismembered his wife.
She was pregnant, in her eight month
and was in the last state
of stomach cancer.
The foetus died in the mother.
The pointer insisted on having killed
a mermaid.
According to the psychological test
he is schizophrenic
and got hospitalized.
This is the result of the investigation.
A scale was found in his
bathtube.
The Japanese Fishery Laboratory
couldn't find out
what kind of fish
if is from.