you didn't sleep well?
Yes,
quite badly.
If you like,
the operation can be postponed.
Do not
don't worry about me.
We can do that another day.
No,
today,
we're doing this today.
But t '
are you sure about this?
If ever it '
wasn't him.
I'm sure of myself.
Marie,
soon,
coming soon.
I'll be right back.
Join me at the
interior?
Yes.
The valet of
a universe?
Yes.
Come on,
put that away.
you're looking for something you're looking for someone
parlez français ou du speak english et sinon il ya
a janitor if you need to find yourself
Thanks for watching!
Oh,
my God.
Who are you?
What do you want from me?
C'
is my daughter,
she was killed.
Marie Bacheret,
8 years old,
found dead near the lime trees in the forest of
Sénard,
about a week after his death.
There were 16 stab wounds on the
the whole body,
fracture of the right wrist and middle finger of the hand
left prior to death,
serious injury to abdomen and head,
multiple wounds and subcutaneous hemorrhage.
The cause of death appears to be haemorrhage
widespread.
A third of the brain is gone,
80% of the organs were harvested,
the victim was disfigured.
L'
identity was determined thanks to the fingerprint
dental.
And then,
what's that got to do with me?
Thibault Laval,
you were the accountant for the Minard Foundation.
But us,
it was dissolved centuries ago.
J'
have nothing more to do with them.
My daughter has been kidnapped by someone
one of the foundation and
one,
is you.
But no!
Then it's
is who?
In the position you occupy,
you couldn't be unaware of it.
But at last,
kidnap your daughter,
why would the foundation do this?
What for?
C'
you can tell me.
But I'm telling you
is not me!
I don't know this child!
But what
what do you want?
Are you telling us the truth or do you want to be
here?
But it's
don't panic.
We've got plenty of time.
I know,
I'm sure I'm scary.
It's going to cost you.
Hey!
Help!
There's no point in shouting.
It
there's nobody here.
I've got to go.
Ah yes,
is the
time.
This is it,
I don't know how to thank you.
Thank you for everything you do for me.
It took a long time,
but it's the home stretch.
I
we hope.
頭痛とめまいですかはいそれと吐き気も特に異常ありませんね精神
的な不安が原因でしょう言葉の通じない環境に長くいると誰でもそ
ういう症状が出ることがあるんです心配はやりませんがあ、念のため
精神安定剤出しておきますねありがとうございます先生も長いんで
すか、フランスえ?
精神的な不安、先生にはないんですかありますよ、私だってそんな時
どうしてます?
日本人つかないとおしゃべりですか、それとも何か強力な薬物とか医
者ってそういうの簡単に手に入るんですよね吉村さんはい今まで薬
でアレルギー症状が出たことはありますかいえでは1週間分出して
おきますどうなんですか先生の場合困った方ですねすいません話題
変えます先生はどちらのご出身ですか生まれた場所です東京ですご
家族は東京に父は母親がいます母親は亡くなりましたそうですかす
いませんご結婚は聞いちゃまずかったですか若い頃からの憧れでパ
リに来ました気づいたらそのままずっとはぁーすごいな憧れがずっ
と続いてるんですね薬ここで一錠飲んでいきますえちょうどストッ
クがあるんですじゃあはいまさかこれ毒じゃないですよね冗談です
よ Hey!
Hey!
You '
hear?
Answer me!
J '
need
go to the toilet.
S '
it pleases you.
Huh?
You can't leave me like this,
please?
I believe that
we know each other.
We must have bumped into each other somewhere.
Don't you think?
Tell me if it's
is true,
because I can help you find what you need.
looking for.
Believe me,
I'm on your side.
I'm really sorry about your daughter.
I can
be useful,
you know.
S '
it pleases you,
but let me go to the bathroom.
J '
need.
C '
is for the big commission,
please.
Qu '
what would you do if I didn ' t
wasn't the person you were looking for,
huh?
But you
hear or what?
I'm going to regret this.
I'll wash you.
You'll get sick if you stay like this.
Oh,
my God.
Do you cook for him too?
It would be annoying if
he would die in front of it.
잠시만요 Oh!
Marie Bacheret,
8 years old,
found dead near the pipes in the Sénard forest,
about a week after his death.
We counted 16 stab wounds on the '
Whole body.
Thank you for
to have watched this video!
I'm fine,
sir?
Yes,
I'm fine,
Thank you.
I'm coming out of consultation,
I just wanted to rest a little.
C'
is the London doctor who saw you?
Yes.
Are you Mr. Bassuret?
Let me introduce myself.
I
is Sayo Konijima.
I'm a psychosomatic therapist.
Will you have five minutes for me?
grant?
Your name,
is Bachal.
That
did you say?
Albert Bacheret.
I remember seeing your name in some files.
by Minard.
So what?
You were part of the Circle,
isn't it?
What are you talking about?
C'
was written in the files.
I knew a few people from the Cercle,
that ' s all.
Qu '
what's going on?
C '
What's all this about the Circle?
I won't
hadn't said,
but I myself was part of the
Foundation a long time ago.
But it doesn
has nothing to do with it.
Tell me about it.
C '
was a humanitarian circle to help children.
It was created by a few volunteers from the
Fondation Minard.
A humanitarian circle?
A kind of
orphanage.
An orphanage?
Have you ever heard of
an orphanage?
An orphanage allegedly involved in '
children.
This,
is that
a rumor.
T '
re you sure?
Because if you don't,
ça voudrait dire c ' Guérin qui tait
the strings from behind.
N ' Importe quoi.
From what I
I've heard.
He killed the children
they
couldn't sell.
I don't know if it's
was Guérin himself.
But you
imagine someone
to do something like that without having received a
directly from him?
Do you have any proof of this?
C'
it's you who should have them.
You were spying on the Foundation and ratting out
information to the press.
C'
is how you
got in touch with Guérin.
That
what the hell were you doing with Guérin?
Why don't you
left Lina?
Albert!
C'
is Yoko,
what the hell?
C'
is you who
said that it
was he the culprit?
Who is this Guérin?
You '
never mentioned him.
J '
I don ' t want to
talk about it.
Why?
C '
is a bastard.
But he had real power.
Everyone hated him,
but no one dared contradict him.
What to manipulate without you realizing it.
C '
was it thanks to him that you joined the circle?
No,
I was just investigating.
To sell Foundation information to the press
?
No,
it wasn't for that.
I was doing a journalistic investigation.
When you have an interesting subject,
you deepen it.
J '
simply did my job as a journalist.
And that
what did you find in the end?
Nothing,
precisely.
All this traffic,
that's bullshit.
What's up?
C'
what's the problem?
The problem?
It
no problem.
So why don't you
left Mina?
T'
discovered a secret at the Foundation?
Guérin the
knew,
you managed to
escape.
But they killed your daughter to set an example.
All of it,
he's a monster!
Did this circle really exist?
Yes.
But not the
story of his
child.
This,
it's not true.
That
who is
happened with Guérin?
I swear to you
I never stopped telling him to the press.
C'
is a misunderstanding.
I'm sure that if I
explains Guérin,
I explain myself to him.
He'll understand.
He's dead.
Why were you doing that?
To avenge Marie?
I'm sorry to
in this story.
But it's
is not the same if there's nothing in it.
Now,
we're the ones in danger.
You don't
you're not telling me that you want me to
s'
stop there?
No,
it's not that.
Think carefully.
That
do you want to do?
what are you afraid of?
If you need me,
I'm here to help you.
Now,
you have to tell me clearly what you want.
do.
Do you mind if I stay by your side?
Why won't you help me?
I won't refuse it.
If you want me
go away,
you tell me.
I'm very sorry,
Sayoko.
We stay together,
d' Accord?
We'll look for it together,
Suki -Ran.
What?
Want to know where you can find Guérin?
C'
is this.
He no longer lives in Paris.
He's in the country.
C'
is a dream that
he'd had for a long time.
C'
is what,
this?
You'll soon have a companion.
Let's compare your story with Guérin's.
You will
bring here?
But you
are you crazy?
You
you Guérin. Do you remember what kind
type c'
was You think
he'll throw the whole
Monsieur Guérin?
Mr Guérin,
anyone home?
We caught a lot of rabbit,
no?
Oh,
ben,
this way,
game,
I leave some.
Here,
you'd say it was good.
Ah,
this,
it's boring,
there.
Good,
I hope you enjoyed it,
for that matter.
Well, yes,
it was great.
J'
loved it.
Would you like me to teach you to shoot?
Oh,
no.
C'
is too violent for me.
Come on,
take one.
Ah,
thank you,
Michel.
Good,
ben,
come on,
to the next one.
C'
is good.
Oh,
very well.
Come on,
you too.
Who are you?
That
what are you doing at my place?
Albert Bacheret.
I worked at the Foundation.
Albert Bacheret?
Ah yes,
Albert!
But it makes peace,
he says.
That
what are you doing here?
J'
should have warned you,
M.
Guérin,
but I had no choice.
The choice of what?
I don't get it.
We'd like you to come with us.
And for what?
On n '
doesn't have time to explain.
And you are?
C '
is my partner.
Pierre Guérin.
Former head of the Minard Foundation.
Your reputation is well known.
You knew that
one day,
we would have come to get you and make you pay
everything you've done.
Ah,
I see,
you're happy.
Sent by one of my former collaborators who
wants to get back at me,
is that it?
She has no connection with Minard.
And from
where she gets all her stories,
then?
This,
it's because ...
M.
Guérin?
J '
heard voices,
there,
How are you?
...
Qu '
is what you're doing here,
you?
Oh,
Albert,
How are you?
J'
understood.
Fix your thing,
there,
I'm fine.
What,
I slip into it,
is that it?
Ah,
fuck.
If I
expected to experience something so absurd at my age.
Come on.
This is it,
we got it.
Pepe,
is you.
Downstream,
good morning.
If I
expected to see you again in such a situation.
Ah fuck,
again!
C'
is my daughter you killed.
What's up?
C'
is he who
said that?
No,
no,
I didn't say that.
J'
simply said that
he had to leave the Foundation because
he was afraid of you.
Afraid of me?
No,
but you're kidding.
But how could you be afraid of someone
one like me?
You can
threatened because
he tried to divulge the Foundation's secret
to the press,
no?
What the hell are you talking about?
The secret of the circle.
What?
What circle?
What secret?
Albert,
explain.
Me,
I don't know.
C '
he invented it.
But you were conducting an investigation at Minard's?
No,
no,
it's not that.
I was doing some journalistic research.
And the result?
Nothing.
Ah,
here it is.
Good,
listening,
Albert.
Me,
I've always considered you a friend.
And I '
hope it '
is the same for you.
Yes.
Do you think it's
is how
treating a friend?
I'm completely lost,
M.
Guérin.
I don't know where the truth lies anymore.
Trust me.
We trust an old friend.
I'll tell you the truth.
The circle sold children to the
and killed those he couldn't live with.
get rid of them.
Here it is,
the truth.
Laval,
are you out of your mind?
He tried to leak the story to the press.
and he had to leave the foundation because
he was afraid of you and you,
you kidnapped his daughter and killed her for
make an example.
Albert,
you're the one who breathed nonsense into him
the same?
No,
it's not me.
Good,
Laval,
your story is completely absurd.
That
who is
has passed?
If you've made a mistake,
don't be afraid to talk to me about it.
But I
haven't done anything!
They '
Looks like we're here,
there,
without explaining anything.
They call us pfff!
I swear.
Good,
mademoiselle,
you see.
Mademoiselle?
Mademoiselle,
I don't know what your goal is,
but as you can see
is about
a misunderstanding.
Then free me!
It looks like
a snake.
Perhaps
we can stop here for today
today.
C'
is who,
this one?
A Japanese woman,
I think.
J'
was a little disturbed,
but I swear,
I'm not lying to you.
No matter what
he recounts,
our goal remains the same.
You're from
agreement?
Uh-oh!
J'
need
go to the toilet.
Albert,
can you hear me?
You have to let me go to the bathroom now.
There's no point.
I beg your pardon?
I'm telling you, it's no use.
Enough is enough,
Albert.
You'll end up here.
You don't care if you think you can go on
like this.
You'll have to see another one when you can.
I don't
still couldn't sleep last night.
No.
You,
you like me,
Anna.
You're always so calm.
It's not
is not true.
Really?
No.
This is it,
do you think we'll make it?
Of course you can.
Otherwise,
what's the point of all this?
J'
have no idea what's going to happen.
アルバーすみません、時間の問題だ。
戦争を操らないといけないほぼ終わりだ。
応援する必要がある。
正解だ、マリー・バシュレイ8歳死亡の場所はセナーの森の近く死亡
したのは1週間後全体に16本の刃を刺しています。
右腕と左腕のマジョンの破裂、死亡前腹部と頭の痛み多くの痛み、腹
部の痛み全然効きませんでしたあの薬、そうですかそうですか僕はも
うダメかもしれません。
フランス人は誰も詐欺師に見えるし通訳は嘘ばっかりつきますみん
なで酔ってたがって僕をダメにしようとしてるんですもう少し強い
薬を出しておきましょうか僕は先生みたいに憧れの人がいる憧れて
この国に来たわけじゃないからなあと2年ですよ任期が終わるまで
どうしたらいいんですか一度帰国された方がいいかもしれませんね
これで日本に帰ったら僕はもういよいよ終わりです終わり？
何が終わるんです？
終わって困るものがあるんですか？
本当に苦しいのは終わらないことでしょ？
もう分かってるはずですよ吉村さん、あなたならできますはいそうで
すねénéと一つの......ご視聴ありがとうございましたさやこさやこ聞
こえてる？
パソコンの前にいないの？
えーこっちは夜そっちは夕方特別な話はないんだけど聞こえてる？
さやこ姿見せてよ J'
have something to offer you.
He and I,
we've known each other for a while.
But I'm getting tired of it.
How would you like to put an end to
this game?
That
do you mean?
It's up to you
invent a little,
commissioner.
But why would we do that?
You don't want
shall we set you free?
C'
what's your goal?
No matter who it is
act.
Designate a new enemy and he won't
won't care about you anymore.
You don't
didn't you have an idea of someone
one who could replace you?
Chris.
It could be Christian,
no?
You mean Christian Samy,
the security type?
C'
is a bad guy,
he's a real bastard,
him.
Yes,
That's right.
And in the way he conducts himself with women,
he's a monster.
He has the ideal profile.
OK,
you decide.
Pay particular attention to the '
story you're going to tell.
Thank you.
Christian Samy,
WHO IS THAT?
C '
was in charge of security at the Foundation.
it's possible that you don't
ever come across,
but he's a real pervert.
Absolutely,
Yes.
J '
have always been reluctant to
idea of keeping him at Mina's.
J '
had a feeling that
one day this guy would end up making a huge
bullshit.
And here's the result.
I'm so sorry about your daughter.
I feel responsible for my own life.
have done anything.
And to tell you the truth,
I would never have imagined that
he'd go that far.
You're a kid.
He may have discovered your daughter when he saw her
name in a folder.
C '
is a horrible story.
Christian Samy,
I agree.
OK,
here we are at last.
We'll go and get it.
On the other hand,
it will be necessary to go towards a place to take it.
here.
C '
is a shame.
I'll let you decide for yourself who's going to
stay and the one who's leaving.
Hey!
Oh!
C '
is not what you promised!
Qu '
is it c '
is all this bullshit?
We'll find Christian.
We'll compare your story with his.
N '
anything.
Sayoko,
what should i do now?
Mr. Hira,
we'll be taken to Christian's.
There is a warehouse used as a
archive for the foundation.
Oh,
you may not believe me.
You have
other options?
C'
is good,
we're happy to go,
you're here we've been trying for a year
change the owner,
rents are always ready, but okay,
at a given moment if there is no sign of
life owner at the end of
one year,
we're obliged to help with everything.
Go ahead,
we make a sign.
You've finished Look at the
man on the right,
it's him,
Christian Guérin,
WHAT IT IS
is this?
I don't know,
it must surely be a medical collection of the
Foundation.
So it's
wasn't just a rumor,
the history of
children,
is that it?
So they did kill the children,
but they couldn't get rid of it?
Albert,
listen carefully,
this woman is manipulating you,
I have nothing to do with the
your daughter's story,
nor Laval,
or Christian for that matter,
it's all lies that
she tells you,
do you understand?
Explain to me what
I'll be damned!
But it's
is just a medical collection,
it's nothing!
At the
winter we'll be heard,
tu as raison j'ai tué Guérin J'
returned the keys.
The guard
didn't realize anything.
Christian?
Do I know him?
No.
Take a good look.
This gym,
I think I know it.
T'
who are you?
Who it
is this where you fall?
Oh,
my God.
We need
we
go now.
Thanks.
He's dead.
In any case,
he deserved it.
It
is not dead.
Christian,
Samy,
wake up.
T'
in charge of security for the
Fondation Minard.
C'
is that right?
You
hear?
We'll
brought you here to serve your sentence.
T'
are completely screwed,
there.
That
can
what do we do?
Where are we?
That
what's going on?
I'm fine.
Does anything hurt?
No.
That
who is
has passed?
Nothing.
It is not
nothing has happened yet.
He must be killed,
we have no choice.
Sevgi Ramon'
a kızı mı?
Eski Sevgi Ramon '
la paralarak geliyor,
çıtadındı.
C'
is a real nightmare
is just a nightmare,
it seems easy enough to put up with.
Me,
I'm going to go further and I hope you'll be
with me.
ST' subtitles
501 It
went by so fast that I
couldn't
stop.
C'
was last night.
D'
a single stroke,
he took out a knife and slit his own throat
saying that
he put an end to everything.
He left in the
other world where
feels more pain.
My mother used to say
was a place filled with soft lights and that
everyone would appreciate anything
he did.
C'
is a kind of
eternity that has a real reality out there.
So much so that
you can even touch it.
Ah,
that's it,
Oco,
are you done yet?
Why are you here?
I wanted to change
idea.
I'm going crazy staying cooped up there too long
a long time.
And Christian,
What's it like?
The same.
He looks like a wild beast.
Otherwise,
there's this.
But what
can
we'll make
them?
Can't we keep them at our place?
We can't take them for a walk all the time, can we?
more.
We don't
has not finished with the problems.
J'
never believed that
we could go as far as
to there.
All of it,
it's all thanks to you.
No,
this is not true.
Yes,
it's all thanks to you.
When you're here,
I feel soothed.
C'
is as if my mind were suddenly clear.
blow.
You,
there's something magical about you,
this is the shot.
Do you remember the first time
we
is met in the center?
Yes.
J'
was at the end of its rope at the
era,
but you,
you've given me new hope.
Maybe it's part of your therapy,
which continues to this day.
But this too,
it'll soon be over,
isn't it?
Yes.
That
what are you going to do once everything is
finished?
No idea.
I never thought about it.
Me,
I'd love to go to Japan.
But maybe
is a little too long.
I was in a supermarket over there this is your
car yes no parking here I didn'
t know that something to the charge a okay driver
license please Thank you.
そっちは?
変わりない?
変わりないよそう?
病院は?
まだ続けてるの?
ええそれが最後の夢だったしな俺もそっちの暮らしもうちょっと続
くと思ったけど甘かったなでも楽だぞこっちは寝る前みたいでいろ
いろ忘れることができるまあそれが一番だ君ビザが切れたら戻って
くるの?
どうかな戻ってこいよ別に一緒に住まなくてもいい夫婦はどんな形
でも続けられるいろいろ方法あるだろ I'm going to ask you some
questions.
Every time you refuse to
learn from it,
I'll get a finger.
When t '
more,
I'll switch to the arm.
Christian Samy,
t ' es l '
former head of security at the Foundation
Minard.
I'll take the '
air,
I'll be right back. I swear I will.
do when I come back Why are you angry with me?
so much?
I thought you'd gotten better.
We lost three days because of you.
I'll make you a deal.
I know the little girl.
What do you mean?
I
I saw in a video when I
was at Mina's.
A video?
What type of video?
I think I'll give you info like
this.
With nothing in return.
C'
is as you wish,
but I know it won't do you any good if I
die right away.
He's never going to let you go without
answered his questions,
which will certainly cost you all your rights.
But if you decided to help us now,
you could be saved.
Why should I believe you?
D'
agreement.
So here's what you do.
You don't
es not Christian.
{
Ok?,
No matter what he asks of you,
you never admit you're Christian.
What are you going to do?
Put that away.
We don't
doesn't need it.
He must be killed.
He says
he has things to tell us.
I'm not Christian.
What?
M'
calls François.
François Barthez.
You've got the wrong person.
Why don't you
waited so long to tell me?
You were like wild animals.
You would never have listened to what I was telling you
seriously.
I know where Christian is,
Samy.
That
what do you want to know about him?
We want to know what's going on in the circle.
C'
is this,
Albert?
Yes.
In this case,
I don't think he'll be able to answer.
to your questions.
You should check with the person who
has the most power in the circle.
That
do you mean?
You must go and see Déborah.
No.
C'
is who?
Déborah.
Déborah Minard.
The one who created the Minard Foundation.
Is she still alive?
Of course you can.
But when the Foundation was dissolved,
it was no problem for them to manipulate
the press to make people believe that Déborah was dead?
Déborah Minard.
We've finally found the person
we were looking for.
C'
is an echo.
is not as simple as you think.
It will be impossible to get Déborah to talk.
She lives in another world.
I don't know how to
explain,
but with her,
truth and lies are always intertwined.
You can never sort it out.
His aim has always been perfectly consistent.
Même si ça a l '
twisted look.
Shut up,
I don't want to know!
Me,
if.
I don't want to hear it.
Go ahead,
we're listening.
Déborah s '
was in charge of sorting the children.
Some were adopted by wealthy families,
and others,
for the circle,
l ' importance n '
was not the children themselves,
but their organs.
Kidneys,
livers,
pancreas,
eyes,
hair.
The younger they were,
and the more it sold for.
Deborah is a former surgeon.
C'
is how
she created her own traffic.
People were saying that Deborah's dexterity was
that the cruelty was almost beautiful.
Damn,
what is it?
C'
is the devil's business.
Can you meet her?
I could take you as far as
to her,
if you like.
You'll discover.
You'll discover the truth for yourself.
Where is it?
At the
where your daughter breathed her last.
C'
is where you'll find it.
And Christian will be there too.
N'
anything.
C'
is a trap,
this,
Yuko.
We can't believe his story.
But it's
is the only lead
for the
instant.
Me,
was it because of Deborah?
Maybe Lola will be with her.
Lola?
C'
is my wife.
She occupied an important place.
In the circle.
From arms to
enjoy.
They were all together.
My wife became the
one of her followers,
without realizing it.
But she
would never have let him take Marie.
And if I
had known,
I would have prevented it too.
But why?
It doesn't
is not very good at
era,
with my wife.
And Marie often found herself alone because of
us.
J'
should have been more present for her.
C'
is really the
ideal location for
children.
They should be there,
Déborah and Christian.
Probably with several armed guys.
You are
wait here?
I'm going to
first to talk to them alone, and then I'll make you
sign as soon as
is good.
You think you can take us that easily?
You may not believe me,
but do you have a choice?
We'll give you five minutes,
Papyrus.
After that,
we set fire to the building and shoot everyone in sight
those who leave.
One after the other.
D'
agreement.
Christian,
five minutes,
Papyrus.
Yes.
What,
Christian?
C'
was you?
No.
C'
Did you kill Marie?
No,
I didn't kill anyone.
I don't
all I did was film.
Filming?
Filming what?
Stop.
You know very well what it's about
act.
The children,
is that it?
While
they harvested their organs,
they filmed them.
And they sold these images to perverts.
C'
is also how your daughter was killed.
I know because
is me who
filmed.
I still remember his face.
Completely disfigured.
Stop bullshitting me.
Damn.
It doesn't
air exceeding.
That asshole.
Now,
WHAT IS
what are we going to do in this godforsaken hole?
This is it,
course.
Plus,
he took us for a ride with his video story.
C'
was to make us walk,
this.
He
well deserved.
Shall we?
But where?
You
said that your wife
was waiting for.
Taiko,
taiko,
taiko.
Marie.
The cause of your decision may be a hemorrhage
and global dysfunction.
Hello?
No,
you haven't been there.
T '
don't worry,
I won't let it go any further.
Jake,
do you hear me?
Jake?
Do you
hear?
Jake?
All in all,
c ' est du coup de couteau sur l '
the whole body.
...
I don't know.
Your daughter was also killed here.
My daughter,
she was killed here.
Your daughter,
My daughter,
she was killed here.
All that remained was the
foreigner than grilled in the great hall
capitular.
The breeze began to blow.
Grilled.
Lola?
Don't come any closer.
Why don't you
come here?
Where is Déborah?
She's dead.
And a long time ago,
she committed suicide.
I'm fine.
Where's Jake?
Jake?
The strong one?
Yeah.
He's dead.
C'
are you Theora's successor?
You wouldn't understand.
And it's
is also you who started here.
You know,
I think you didn't really like him.
and
elsewhere,
she didn't really like them either.
In any case,
how could i have done otherwise?
You,
you thought she was innocent and pure.
But with me,
she was very different.
She was always staring at me with her icy, cold gaze.
reproving.
C'
is your idea of
to see Déborah?
You know,
I don't know exactly what happened to Marie,
but in the background,
I think this is what you wanted.
You,
me,
I just let you do it.
How I
could have done more?
The children,
we're going to do something.
C'
is that
we'll go,
uh,
we'll go to the back,
there.
Just in the side room.
And Yves,
go ahead,
there.
And you play the game
we know,
OK?
Do this.
It's going to be fine.
You know,
with Jake,
we did what we could for a year.
But it's
is not possible to replace Déborah.
She was so horrible and charismatic.
Me,
I don't want to become like her.
Maybe it's
is the end,
now,
no?
That
do you
think about it?
Is this
is true,
all this?
But if it
is the end,
it's also the end for you.
Albert,
I'm not afraid of anything anymore,
now.
C'
is finite,
Sayoko,
I had no choice.
But it's
is perhaps best.
We will.
C'
was Lola.
she's the one who brought our daughter here.
She was chosen by Deborah and Guérin l'
killed.
And maybe your daughter too.
Are you satisfied?
I don't know how to thank you,
Sayoko.
You're the only one left now.
Your last meal.
C'
is not a very funny joke,
it's a hit.
You're all the same.
J'
just served once as
intermediary between the circle and
videos.
C'
was an order.
You were their coordinator,
isn't it?
Of course not,
I didn't even know which video it was.
acted.
You sold your daughter yourself.
You don't
are not serious,
Yoko.
I'm a victim like you.
Stop,
don't do that.
C'
is why you
helped.
We're in this together.
The video of your daughter being cut up while
she's still alive.
J'
imagine you want to see it.
No,
stop,
don't do that.
Stop,
Yoko!
Albert,
me,
I saw the video.
Why me?
Why are you doing this?
I hate you more than anyone.
Wait!
No,
IT'S NOT TRUE!
Stop,
please,
don't leave me alone!
やっぱりこうやって距離を取るとお互い冷静になれるもんだなちょ
っと懐かしいよ、パリでの暮らしが俺たちきっと相性良かったんだ
よ、二人は二人だけなら案外うまくやれたのかもしれないまあでも昔
のことは忘れようこうして時々画面越しに君の穏やかな顔を見られ
るだけで俺はちょっとほっとするんだちょっとキラポンじゃてぃぼ
かうんうんなんて言った?