Production:
WOWOW Japan Satellite
Broadcasting
Bandai Visual
Tadanobu Asano
Ken Mitsuishi
Kaori Tsuji
Yoichiro Saito
Hiroko Isayama
Taro Suwa
Toshiya Nagasawa
Producers:
Takenori Sento
Koji Kobayashi
Photography::
Masaki Tamura
Screenplay, Music, and Director:
Shinji Aoyama
Big brother!
Give me.
It's mine...
It's mine now.
Yasuo!
You look fine.
Let's go:
Start the engine.
Go now!
Go!
Hungry?
Let's eat.
OK. Let's go.
Kenji.
Yasuo?
Yeah.
How are you?
Finally got out. Look.
It's nice.
Not nice. Our boss died
and our gang's gone.
Yasuo.
Only four years in prison.
It's nothing for them.
I got no time.
Ain't seen him so long, bro.
I shouldn't call you bro, Sir.
I'm leaving.
Where to?
Shopping.
Girl?
Still live there?
Yeah.
Call you later.
See you.
Three coffees.
My treat
Nice guy.
Really good at fishing.
He can fish one after another.
I got none.
Yasuo, let's leave.
Now? Take it easy.
Hey.
Yasuo.
Keep it. I don't want to see.
Regard it's from boss, not me.
Where is he?
Don't fool around.
Where?
In the cemetery.
Stop joking please.
No joke.
Where is he?
I want to see him.
Is he fine? How is he?
Don't...
call me too often.
Nice to be normal.
Let's take the car.
It's lonesome.
How is your job?
Offer from Dainichi Steel.
Dripping.
Blast Furnance...
You know nothing.
Go home?
Strait jacket.
You don't know...
Long sleeves.
They tie them in back
Empty your hands.
They take away everything.
No...
You'll forsake me also.
Like your mom.
Like a rolling stone.
Yes.
What?
I can only trust you.
You're my friend.
I see. It's good.
Here you are.
Remember? Yuri, my sister.
I knew I couldn't trust him.
Had a small gun...
good for women.
Did you kill him?
No. He died by himself.
He used me so much.
I'm out...no gang...no boss.
Lies no one believes in.
Boss lost face.
So he hides himself.
Boss never dies.
I'll kill him.
Bury him and leave.
Kenji. I've got something
I want you to keep.
Don't ask what?
No need.
You're brave.
I'm shaking.
Be my lost hand.
A hassle to have one hand.
Take care. See you tonight.
Listen to him and behave.
Or I'll scold you.
Thanks a lot. Call you later.
Yasuo.
What's up?
Kill my boss.
Prisoner again.
Can't help.
See and ask why he left...
Never mind.
Call you later.
What's the song?
I don't know.
Don't touch. Muffler's hot.
Shall we go?
Nobody answers as always.
Damn.
I'm Shiraishi. My father please.
Yes.
I see.
Liar. They don't even
check on him.
Angry?
Don't be upset
Where are you going?
Boss came here?
He died.
They told you to say it.
Where is he?
So, he passed away.
Stop. I'm serious.
Went to the hospital and funeral.
It's strange.
You're only a punk. Why?
I did go to the funeral.
You have speed. Give me some.
Where is he?
Hurts...
Tell me.
He died.
Where is he?
Boss?
What the hell...
All liars.
What?
I don't like here.
Why?
Brother gone before.
You came before.
He won't disappear.
Let's wait for him inside.
Can I trust you?
Your orders?
Coke.
You?
Menu?
Here it is.
I need pictures.
What do you like?
Puffy one.
With brown sauce and fruit.
Chocolate parfait.
Right.
Chocolate parfait and coke.
She's been with you?
Ms.Q.
She's Q.
Excuse me. Phone?
It's broken.
Your store's...
No.
It's near the tunnel.
Do I have to go there...
Can you wait for me?
Where to?
To the tunnel. Phone.
To my brother?
My dad.
Your dad.
You tell him?
No.
Told nothin' to the teacher.
He'll be angry.
My brother said
I won't go back there.
Wonder if he'll disappear again...
He promised to be together:
Don't worry.
He'll pick you up later.
I'll be back soon.
He didn't lie before...
Kenji!
You!
I'll beat you!
You were scared.
Now what?
None of your business.
How about you?
I'm hiking.
By yourself? You're weird.
You too.
Don't talk to me like that.
Go!
Why so angry?
Shut up: Just go!
I see. See you later!
I'll forgive you.
Forgive me?
Yes.
Wait a moment.
You're working hard.
I'm wanted.
Yasuo Matsumura?
Yeah.
Tell him to bring the car keys.
Hey, keys.
For cars.
Throw them away.
Throw them away!
What?
Hurry! Do it!
Turn around.
Turn back
Hands on the ceiling.
Follow me.
Don't come!
Give up! No escape.
Do you know where my boss is?
You don't know he died?
You want me to give it up.
They forgot a punk like you.
Poor thing.
Who's a punk!
Kenji's motorbike.
I'm his friend.
It's melting. Eat.
Why not?
Too nice.
Don't be wasteful...
It's pretty.
They are also nice.
I just took them.
What is it?
Mountains here.
Inside the tunnel.
You've never checked the wall.
I forgot it.
What?
Time for TV.
Ice coffee. She's an idiot.
Scary.
No.
No sound.
That's it.
You like it with no sound?
Better with sound?
You like pictures only.
It's the same for idiots.
What are you doing?
We?
I know the boss, Sakanashi.
A gang member's sister.
They were here before.
What're you up to?
I don't know anything.
Tell me what!
I don't know.
I'll check.
What?
Hurts. Don't underestimate me!
What the hell!
Pay for it.
Good timing.
Without you, he'd have killed me.
It took time. How come?
Are you with me?
Hey.
Shut up.
What is it?
Who is this idiot?
Is this social work?
Gross.
Did you watch "Prisoner 6"?
No. 6 escaped to London.
No.2 called... went to HQ.
Title with rear view of Lotus.
Parachuted from the plane.
He couldn't leave
the village: Scary.
I saw it.
Really? You did?
I saw them all.
Damn.
Leave now.
Never mind. It's OK.
What's inside?
Never mind.
Hey, I'll beat you!
Hurts. Easy.
Stop insisting!
You didn't hurt me.
You wanted to?
Just pretending.
I know.
You just wanted to tease me.
That was awful.
You country bumpkins.
Stop! What's wrong!
Your mind is screwed up.
No wonder they didn't
like you. Still...
I see.
Ouch.
Why smile!
Go outside to fight!
What are you up to?
Nothing to do with you.
Not really. I was almost
killed 'cause of it.
What?
He tried to see it.
I resisted.
Why did he...
Who cares. She's yakuza's sister.
Why not say it earlier!
It's my place!
What!
Making your face!
Call police!
You punk. Crazy!
Damn. Don't snub me.
My dad...
Stop!
Akihiko.
Bring a rope.
Stop!
Ouch...
You said you'd forgive me.
No meaning.
You mean...
Bother you? You're chicken.
What!
Interesting.
What?
Revenge.
What do you mean?
Class reunion.
I'll poison the juice.
Beer sounds better.
I mean it.
He doesn't ask you to join.
I decide.
I won't ask you.
Why not?
Forgiveness.
Why?
Helped find my shorts.
Not to see your ass.
It's OK.
I must join.
No.
I must go.
You watch TV at home.
See, hurts?
You can't forgive me. Right?
Look at your eyes.
Coward.
You mother fucker!
Shut up!
Fuck you!
You're weak!
What!
Don't fight. Make him quiet.
He drives me crazy.
I'm no wimp!
You're weaker than a woman.
Hurts! Stop!
Stop kicking me.
Stop it!
You...
You!
Dead?
You killed them.
Take a memorial picture.
Smile.
Memorial picture.
Should've taken dad too.
Take the picture
at the reunion also.
After poisoning them.
No good.
Here they come.
Hurry up!
What the...
Killed'em... ridiculed me.
Let's go.
And him?
Never mind.
It's yours.
How come?
Take it.
Let's go together.
To where?
Q...Q...
What's wrong!
You kill her.
Selfish bastard!
So selfish. You can't
push only your way.
She's poor by herself.
It's your own cause. Bastard!
Q...
No, Q!
Shoot if you can.
Everything you need's
on the shelf.
Please get rid of my things...
I won't give you any trouble.
Lonely, but it must
be better outside.
Goodbye.
To the restroom.
"HELP ME"
Did you find Q?
Ride on it.
My ass hurts.
Let's go together.
How about that?
Leave it.
That's right.