I was really shocked
the first time I saw Ugetsu.
I'd thought of movies like photographs,
a recording of reality.
But watching Ugetsu,
I forgot about all that.
I knew literature could be fantastical,
and I had read fantasy literature,
but I thought movies were supposed
to be faithful reflections of reality.
But with Ugetsu,
I felt as if the world of fairy tales
and fantasy novels
I'd read as a child
had been perfectly
recreated in images,
and this was a huge surprise.
We see this thing called “reality”
with our eyes,
but since there are
many human beings,
there are many realities.
Choosing which
of those many realities
to accept as one's own
has always been
a great problem.
A ghost of the lake!
No...
I'm not a ghost.
I'm a boatman from Kaizu.
There are so many realities
that they turn into a kind of fantasy.
So we can say
Mizoguchi was a supreme realist
while also being
a supreme fantasist.
He appears before us
as an extremely ambivalent figure.
When we speak of temporal realism,
we generally need three things:
events, narration,
and dramatic progression,
and it's a basic principle of realism
that these have to be integrated.
Mizoguchi broke
all those rules with Ugetsu.
First you think it's realistic narrative,
and then just memory,
but it turns out to be
a terrifying world of fantasy.
But just when you think that
that fantasy world is real,
you're suddenly thrown
back into reality.
So you have real time
and fantasy time,
real space and fantasy space,
completely mixed together.
What Ugetsu shows us is that
they're all part of a single world.
Of all the films that attempt
to pass back and forth
between these different types
of time and space,
Ugetsu is, in my opinion,
the most successful.
The best illustration of this
is when the protagonist, Genjuro,
finally returns home
after all his adventures.
This scene reminds me a lot
of Japanese e-maki picture scrolls.
As you unroll the scroll,
you start off with a subject
and then follow
the progression through time.
Here he enters his house.
There’s a sunken hearth
in the living room.
When he enters the house,
no fire is burning in the hearth,
but then he walks
around the place,
and suddenly
a fire is burning.
We see the scene of a happy family
surrounding the hearth.
His wife,
who should be dead, is alive.
That is to say,
she's alive within him.
It's precisely as if
he were speaking with a ghost.
And this is all one long take.
A performance moving through space
like this was totally unprecedented.
But I think it's helpful to think
of Mizoguchi in contrast with Ozu.
Ozu doesn't move the camera.
And he shoots from a low angle.
For example...
at this moment you and I
are speaking at eye level.
Our view of the ordinary world
is determined largely by our eye level.
This is how we come
to discover things.
But shooting from a low angle,
it's as if you're a Peeping Tom.
If a woman wearing a miniskirt
were to stand up
in sight of Ozu's low-angle camera,
he'd be arrested for indecency.
At any rate, women back then
were seated throughout his films,
so even with the low angle,
he wasn't doing anything risque'.
But it was still very unusual,
an extremely out-of-the-ordinary
shooting position.
I like to call Ozu
“the reclining god.”
This reclining god
intently watches humanity
while lying on his side.
Ozu shoots from a low angle
from beginning to end,
without panning
or moving the camera.
In this sense he's an auteur
of “absolute cinema.”
But Mizoguchi's camera
almost never stops
but just keeps moving.
This movement clearly shows
human lives moving,
as quietly as glaciers.
That type of human time
is then skewered by historical time
within the frame of the camera.
You can think of it
as historical time
and the time of human drama
moving together simultaneously.
Fumio Hayasaka
was very accomplished...
as a composer
of pure concert music,
but more importantly,
he completely revolutionized
Japanese film music,
which, until then,
had been very old-fashioned.
He almost completely swept away
the old practices.
He had a tremendous influence.
We see this, of course,
in Kurosawa's Hashomon
and Seven Samurai with which
I assume everyone is familiar.
Collaborating with Mizoguchi,
Hayasaka created music for Ugetsu...
that may in some respects seem
like traditional Japanese music.
When a ghost appears
in traditional stories,
it's usually accompanied
by the distinctive sound of the koto,
but in Ugetsu, Machiko Kyo's character
appears to the strumming of a harp,
which I think suits
a ghost perfectly.
The Japanese flute was replaced
by the conventional Western flute.
But for percussion he used
the tsuzumi of Noh theater,
as well as
Noh's rhythmic chanting.
One thing I had noticed
was that Japanese composers
who'd watched lots of foreign movies
and listened to a lot of foreign music
made an effort
to insert beautiful melodies
into their film scores
with violins and so on.
But Mizoguchi and Hayasaka
never succumbed
to that temptation for an instant.
The most fundamental aspect
of Japanese music
is the hyoshi, or beat.
This may be translated as “rhythm”
in Western languages,
but what's important to remember
is that the sound differs
depending on what the hands strike.
If you try to transfer this kind of rhythm
with variable timbres to Western music,
you wind up using
different percussion instruments.
But with this kind of rhythm going on,
it's difficult for melodic instruments
to work their way in.
They just follow the progress
of the rhythmic sounds.
This music allows Ugetsu to approach
a depiction of the world of unreality
without merely settling
into the conventions of realism.
I believe this is mainly due
to Hayasaka's mastery
of tone color.
While still making use
of tradition,
he was able to create
a new, dramatic,
indeed, avant-garde sound
in this film.
From the very beginning...
Mizoguchi understood that a portrayal
of women shouldn't be limited
to topics such as class
and gender discrimination.
He was extremely
ahead of his time in Japan
when it came to the issue of gender.
He had great respect for women
precisely because he'd experienced
a lot of woman troubles.
Whenever any of his protégés
had such troubles,
he'd tell them to get in trouble
with more women,
because the more you experience,
the more you learn about life.
So relationships with women
were worth any expense.
This is a man whose own back
had been slashed by a woman.
He had the scars on his back,
not on his hands.
I think Mizoguchi
had a great curiosity
about sexual desire.
I don't think he was that consumed
by sexual desire himself.
I think he thought
men were no match
for women's boundless
thirst for existence.
BY portraying women,
he felt the mystery of the world
would be revealed.
When it came to desire
between men and women,
he believed in sexual license.
He didn't think people should
question others in that regard.
This has nothing to do
with any kind of
women's liberation movement,
but rather with the relationships
between men and women,
and indeed,
the violence of sexuality.
The idea that this violence
is something beautiful
was his “protest,”
if you will, against society.
This was so in both
his prewar and postwar films,
because I think he saw clearly
that sexuality is a force
that is always
at odds with society.
I was without a doubt
influenced by this film,
but I think to make
a film like Ugetsu
is something akin to a miracle.
I think Mizoguchi himself saw it
as a kind of miracle.
Given that Japan lost the war,
the closest parallel to Ugetsu
would be Italian neorealism.
Ugetsu is similar.
You have the mother,
played by Kinuyo Tanaka,
who's attacked by bandits
who roam the land like Wolves
in a time of War.
Tanaka's character
falls into their clutches
and is killed.
It's interesting that for this sequence,
Mizoguchi trades his tracking shots,
which have such formal beauty,
for documentary-like shots
that feel like something
from a newsreel.
They're astonishingly realistic.
In this scene,
the mercenaries stab the woman
and steal her food.
She's writhing in pain
in the foreground,
while in the background,
the mercenaries
are eating the food.
These two things are happening
in the same frame.
You have this realism
set against the fantasy of a man
caught up in the world of the dead.
What's fascinating is that
the movie camera,
essentially the incarnation
of photographic realism,
has the expressive power
to juxtapose these two worlds.
No matter how often
we watch Ugetsu,
we learn something new each time
about the possibilities of cinema.