Ugetsu depicts the greed
within human beings...
our lust or carnality —
that is, our sexual desire —
and the ephemeral nature
of human life.
How fleeting it is,
like the Buddhist saying:
“All things change
and nothing is permanent.”
The film shows all these things,
while interweaving
Japanese or Eastern
sensibilities and ideas.
The original story
by Akinari Ueda was written...
in the Edo period.
But to better depict
the abnormal state
of a mind consumed
by greed and desire,
the setting for the film
was moved back
to the period of the civil wars.
Mizoguchi wanted to depict
the innate ugly qualities
that are a part of human beings,
as well as
the human heart's yearning
to realize the desires
left unfulfilled while one was alive,
even when one has passed on
to the next world.
I think he wanted to depict
that kind of human karma.
Screenwriter Yoshikata Yoda
and Mizoguchi were
longtime collaborators.
But they weren't really friends.
That was because Mizoguchi
tormented Yoda relentlessly.
He wouldn't let up
until he'd wrung out of Yoda
everything Yoda could give.
With Ugetsu, Yoda had
to rewrite the script five times.
But even then...
Mizoguchi made
further changes to the script
and issued what we used to call
“a special edition.”
So as you can see in this script,
while we were shooting,
he changed lines constantly.
The assistant director
or script supervisor
would frantically note these changes.
It was hard to keep up.
He'd sometimes cross out lines,
like these you see here.
He deleted all this here
while shooting.
That was how he worked.
And just like With Yoda,
he was relentless with his actors.
He wouldn't stop
until he'd wrung everything he could
out of the actor.
So sometimes even an incompetent,
second-rate actor would give
an amazing performance
that would surprise us.
Say you're a director
and you're directing
a close-up, for instance.
You have to make sure
how much of a close-up
you're getting on film,
so you'd take a look
through the camera.
But he never did.
He'd just remain seated
next to the camera.
Then he'd make the actors
do test shots over and over...
retake after retake.
And the way he did it was -
Normally, a director
would say something like...
“Put this kind of emotion into it
when you say this line,”
or “This is an important shot.
Give me this kind of expression.”
You'd give those kinds
of specific instructions.
But he wouldn't say anything specific.
He'd say...
“It's no good.
You're not into it.”
Or something vague like that.
He often gave this instruction:
“Grasp the situation and reflect it.”
These were his famous words.
“Reflect” is usually used
as in “reflect light.”
So the actor who was told
to “reflect” was puzzled.
Actors go! all nervous.
Even seasoned actors
would get so unnerved
hearing Mizoguchi shout,
“Ready! Action!”
That they'd choke on their lines.
He was that intimidating.
The actress Kinuyo Tanaka
was a regular in Mizoguchi's films.
He wasn't demanding
with her at all.
Even when her acting didn't seem
up to her usual level,
he gave her an okay.
She was a very good actress,
one of the best in Japanese cinema.
During the shooting of Ugetsu,
Mizoguchi, myself,
and another assistant director
named Kazuo lkehiro
happened to be standing together,
and Mizoguchi started
a discussion on actors and acting.
He said many things like,
“That acting was no good,”
about some actors.
Eventually, it turned into
a discourse on Kinuyo Tanaka,
and he said, “Kinuyo Tanaka
is the best actress in Japan.”
Ikehiro and I exchanged glances
and grinned at each other.
Whether or not she was,
as Mizoguchi declared,
the best actress in Japan,
he looked really adorable
when he said that.
His face had this sweet expression.
Seeing that made lkehiro and me
break into a grin.
I suppose you must have heard this,
but he was in love with Tanaka.
At the time, he was about 50 —
I guess he was about 55
when he made Ugetsu.
So it was love in old age.
As I said earlier,
Mizoguchi was
a really inscrutable director.
He never looked through the camera.
As for the music,
you look at the script,
and you had to decide
which sections needed music.
Normally,
the director works that out
in consultation with the composer —
in this case, Hayasaka.
Mizoguchi did none of that.
So Mizoguchi did nothing,
and Hayasaka himself
was in bad health...
so he couldn't commute
between Tokyo and Kyoto.
This was before
the bullet train, mind you.
This was around 1954.
So he couldn't go back and forth.
Mizoguchi intended
to leave the music...
completely up to Hayasaka.
He washed his hands
of the whole thing.
Well, this created a problem.
Hayasaka had an assistant
named Masaru Sara.
He was a fantastic composer.
I was first assistant director,
so Sato and I
and the sound technician,
lwao Otani;
had to think
through the music together.
Otani was the sound technician,
but since I was assistant director,
I had a better grasp
of the film's theme and overall aim.
So the three of us had to decide
where to put the music:
which scenes needed it
and which didn't.
We had to make a rough sketch,
and boy did we grumble about it:
“This isn't our job!”
“The Old Man's going
to complain about this later.”
Anyway, we had some ideas
about where the music should go...
but when it came to questions like,
“Should we use a drum here,
or a flute there,
or orchestral strings here?”
That kind of thing, of course,
had to be decided by Hayasaka.
So Hayasaka would listen
to our ideas, read the script,
and occasionally watch
the daily rushes,
and then decide himself what to do.
That's how it was.
So Miyagawa
was in charge of the camera,
and Hayasaka
was in charge of the music.
Old Man Mizoguchi
didn't touch those things at all.
Then we had to dub the music in,
still complaining all the while.
But it shows how much trust
he had in Hayasaka.
What I remember most clearly
is the very first day of shooting
on Ugetsu.
We were on the set
of the Kutsuki manor.
There was a garden,
and a passageway
running all around it.
Masayuki Mori; Machiko Kyo
and Kikue Mori
were to walk along
that passageway.
That was to be the whole take.
So Mizoguchi comes on the set,
sits down next to the camera,
and stays there a long time.
He says nothing, deep in thought,
making a long face.
After a while he calls me over.
“Tanaka,
do you honestly think...
this set is how
Kutsuki Manor should feel?”
That's what he said to me.
I thought it was a good set,
large enough in scale,
and so on.
The designer, Kisaku Ito,
was experienced
in theatrical set design.
In fact, he was the foremost
theatrical set designer in all Japan.
Perhaps he was a tiny bit lacking
in terms of understanding
what a proper film set required.
That's why Mizoguchi
thought so long and hard
and asked things like,
“ls this the right atmosphere?”
“Will this pass for Kutsuki Manor?”
He was very blunt about it.
How was I to know?
Ito just made it
according to his own taste.
But the Old Man didn't like it.
We modeled that set
after the Katsura Imperial Villa
and the Shugakuin Imperial Villa.
We researched these sorts
of national treasures of Japan
to make that set.
Even the sliding screen doors
were made
after researching their equivalents
in those buildings.
The historical background
of the film's setting
was thoroughly researched
by a group
that consisted
of assistant directors
and members of the art
and prop departments.
We went to libraries
for information,
and when we couldn’t find it,
we sought help from professors
at Kyoto University,
as well as people
knowledgeable in those areas.
So right down to a vase
or anything else,
these ornaments
that were used as props
had to be researched
for historical accuracy.
Nevertheless, though many props
were just re-creations,
you had to check thoroughly.
He wouldn't accept
sloppy or haphazard research.
He repeatedly made that
clear to us.
There are a lot of memorable things
in every scene.
One scene I personally find
very memorable
is the scene on the lake.
I think Miyagawa's camera work
in that scene was wonderful.
We constructed a pool
in the studio
and filled it with water.
It was quite a large set.
Then we fanned out
a lot of smoke,
which created light and shadow
as the boat cut through the “fog.”
Unfortunately,
the smoke wasn't very cooperative.
Miyagawa would say things like,
“Make it thicker over there.”
“It needs to be thinner
over there on the left.”
But it wasn't that easy
to control the fog.
Kazuo Ikehiro and I
had to take care of it.
Generally, the prop managers
had to deal with the smoke,
but Ikehiro and I did it.
This was in February,
the dead of winter.
It was extremely cold.
So we were in the water,
trying to fan the smoke.
Finally, at the very end —
There was this boat,
and it had a hole in the rear
to keep it from moving freely.
Even if the actors tried to paddle,
it wouldn't move.
So the two of us
were hiding behind the boat,
pushing it along,
and a wire stretched from in front
was pulled by other crew members.
In those days we didn't have
special wetsuits or anything,
the way they do today.
We only had thigh-high boots.
The word “cold”
doesn't do it justice.
So we were pushing along.
One take might have been okay.
But we'd hear, “Once more.
The smoke wasn't in the right place.”
So we had to do this
for around two hours.
And the funny thing is,
once we'd finished,
finally getting an okay
and getting out of the water,
nobody said a word
of sympathy or thanks.
It was taken for granted that assistant
directors would do those things.
Let's see, a Mizoguchi anecdote.
There certainly are plenty.
We went location scouting
for this film.
We were on the far side
of Lake Biwa,
too far away to return to the studio,
so we stayed at an inn.
There were five or six of us:
the cameraman,
production designer, assistant director —
the main production staff.
So five or six of us
were eating and drinking
in a room about this size.
I have to tell you, the Old Man
didn't hold his liquor well.
We were talking about this and that.
When Mizoguchi was young,
there was this woman who was —
Well, I don't know
if you know about this...
but she was a prostitute.
And the two of them were in love.
This is when he was young,
mind you.
They'd had a lovers' quarrel...
and she had literally sliced
his back with a razor.
There were all sorts of legends
about him like that.
So that day we were talking
about the past
when that story came up,
and Mizoguchi grinned.
By the way,
he still had the scar on his back.
He showed it to us.
It was about this long.
“Look here,” he said to me.
“You can't make movies about women
if you don't have one of these.”
Now, that was amusing.
Here he was, a great director,
but he wasn't
a solemn stuffed shirt.
He had a free and easy
manner in person.
He'd been born
in Tokyo's Asakusa district.
If he got worked up on the set,
he'd turn into a fast-talking
Tokyo rascal.
That's what I really
liked about him —
that lovable, childlike quality.
Mizoguchi the human being
was really a unique person.