Mizoguchi showed me once —
not when I shot Ugetsu,
but when I first worked with him
on a film called Miss Oyu.
I visited him at home one day.
He had a variety of
e-maki picture scrolls,
And he showed them to me
And said,
“Movies are like picture scrolls.”
That's what he told me.
Movies shouldn't be viewed like books,
by turning pages.
Pictures in movies should roll out
one after another
yet still have a focal point
for the viewer.
He said something to that effect.
E-maki are mostly images
in the distance, with no close-ups,
but he said some points that draw
the viewer's eye are like close-ups.
And because of these points,
you understand the story shown
in an e-maki as it unrolls.
I completely agreed with what he said,
And from then on
I became very interested in seeing
old pictures shown in e-maki scrolls.
Masayuki Mori's character comes home,
opens the door and looks inside,
but he finds no one.
So he circles around the house
looking for his family
And comes back in through the door.
This time, Kinuyo Tanaka's character
is there inside.
That scene was such a challenge
for the lighting crew.
And it was only possible in film.
All the tricks would've been visible
if it were on stage.
But on film you can shoot
only the parts you need.
You can make Tanaka materialize
while the camera follows Mori.
This is something...
that applies
to Mizoguchi's films in general:
He uses lots of crane shots.
Especially in the case of Ugetsu.
I like crane shots,
And so did Mizoguchi.
But in the case of Ugetsu,
about 70% of it is crane shots.
The crane was moving...
for sweeping shots
and when there was a great deal
of movement, naturally.
But it was also moving in still scenes
in the Kutsuki manor.
The camera was never still
in the scenes in the manor,
though its movement
wasn't meant to be noticeable.
Images shot this way gave
a slightly unstable impression.
We shot that way
after I'd made a test shot,
and Mizoguchi agreed to give it a try.
I think that...
because the images give the viewer
an unstable impression...
that helped give the feeling
that people in the mansion
were images of ghosts.
Some people said they didn't see
the camera's movement.
So I said, “Lay one frame
over another and you'll see it.”
I talked about this once
at a film school.
One frame of a scene in the mansion
was placed over another,
and you could see
there was a deviation.
Actors knew that
a certain director worked one way
And another director worked
in a different way.
Sometimes they had difficulty playing
their characters, like Masayuki Mori —
When was that?
Wait. When did that happen?
We were having a meal.
It was a lunch break,
and we were in a cafeteria.
And an actor as skilled
as Mori was saying...
“How does he want me to do it?”
I said, “You have
a chest of drawers inside you
from which to pull out what you need,
so start from the top drawer.”
He said, “I've already rummaged
through all the drawers.”
Then after that lunch break,
he finally got an okay from Mizoguchi.
It was around 2:00 or 3:00.
He got the okay right after lunch.
I was happy for him, so I said,
“You got through it.”
And what did he say?
We had a good laugh.
He said,
“lt was in the top drawer after all.”
Isn't that a good story?
That stayed in my mind
like a really good joke.
I was sick for three years.
I don't like to be inactive,
But for three years
I couldn't go to the movies.
All I could do was watch television.
So I watched TV dramas...
and commercials.
I guess I got to study
TV commercials.
I realized a lot of money is spent
making TV commercials.
The fact that they looked great
meant quite a bit of money
was spent making them.
The money is spent
on a lot of effort and energy
in technical processing
and postproduction.
If you run the figures,
the money spent
making a short commercial
must be proportionally greater
than that spent on a feature film.
I thought, “| wish they'd use
that money to make a feature.”
I've seen some terrible TV shows.
In contrast, TV movies —
Or rather, TV dramas —
I'd gradually lost my hearing
due to my illness.
I couldn't hear at all.
So I was watching TV
with no sound...
and I was just feeling
empty and sad.
Then, as I watched TV,
I realized the images in commercials
were better than in TV dramas,
and also that more money
was spent making them.
In contrast...
TV dramas made by directors
using regular actors were boring.
If you can't hear,
you don't understand stories
in Japanese TV dramas at all.
That means there's
no exposition through images.
TV dramas,
and films too, naturally,
should tell their story through images.
Look back at silent films.
If you watch them now,
you'll be surprised
at the effort expended trying
to make viewers understand.
You'll see repeated efforts
at making the viewer
understand the story.
I really sensed
That effort at expression
in those old films.
I felt the same way
when I saw silent films recently.
But today's TV dramas
won't make any sense to you
unless you can hear.
TV dramas seem no different
to me than radio dramas.
In contrast, I wonder —
I saw a film in a theater
for the first time after a long while.
It was a sad
and depressing experience
after being bedridden
for three years.
In those three years
there'd been great advances
in technology and hardware.
The changes over
those three or four years
showed amazing development
in the images on-screen.
In that sense...
more and more feature films
have to keep up,
And by taking advantage
of these advances,
they should be able to make
interesting images of their own.
Anyway- --
Overall, though, it seems to me...
That making images by utilizing
advanced technology is still unrefined.
It might be a good idea
to go back to silent films.
If people studied them all over again,
I think movies might become
different and more interesting.