A LITTLE DOLL
Go, faster, strive.
Your children have
passed the preselection.
They all have been taken in.
Come here!
They think that they choose genius!
They don't need us.
It's we don't need them.
Don't cry I said.
Let's go.
Tell me please
how old were you when
you started to do gymnastics?
Seven.
Was your group large?
Normal. I'm sure there were
15 persons at the beginning.
How many of them left?
Some of them were
weeded out in a year.
And then... there were six
persons in the group I trained in.
There were six of us.
And all of them became sportsmen?
No.
It was only me who got into
USSR team from this group. Only one.
The coach worked with
you individually, didn't he?
When they called for meetings
he would take only me.
Other girls stayed
here with another coach.
Do these meetings occur often?
It depends on how they call us.
Well, how many times
per year approximately?
I think five or six times per year.
And what is the
duration of one meeting?
One month.
Tell me please how do you
spend the day on the meeting.
Well you wake up at 8 o'clock
and then you do morning exercises.
Then goes breakfast at 8:30.
You have some rest after the breakfast
and then go training. Four apparatuses.
Then goes dinner, one
hour and half for learning,
naptime and second training.
After evening's training you have
supper and then again... cross race.
Then...
we have free two-three
hours before going to sleep.
How long each work-out lasts?
The first work-out is
four hours long I think.
The second one is three hours long.
Tell me please... people who are
not in sports often ask
why gymnasts have so little height?
This is often being discussed.
I don't know what's being
said about gymnasts' height
but first of all they
are not all small.
There're very small gymnasts,
but there're medium height gymnasts.
But the small gymnasts
are the specific selection
that is being held by the gymnasium.
Modern gymnastics is so complex
and the requirements for
complex exercises are so high
that we choose girls
by knowing in advance about their
potential chances in the future.
Put your hands a little higher...
and the belly too... Yes.
Well done!
Good girl.
- What's your name dolly?
- Katya.
Katya...
Oops-a-daisy!
How old are you?
- Uh?
- Six.
Six...
Do you have time to read books?
Yes, we can read
before going to sleep.
Do you really have time
for it or just "can" read?
I have time.
Tell me how do you eat?
It's normal. The breakfast consists of
half a cup of coffee and sandwich.
For the dinner we
have meat without garnish
and something to drink
like fruit compote.
And the supper usually consists of bread
and butter with tea or just a curds.
It all depends on the weight.
Is it easy to keep the weight?
It's different from person to person.
For example it's easy for me.
- How old are you?
- Now?
- Yes.
- Sixteen.
Tell me please...
it's an awkward question...
If you don't want to answer, don't
The relationships are
being started at this age
the interest in friendship
with the boys is growing...
I don't know.
I feel nothing.
Maybe I don't have time for it.
And what about your friends?
I don't know.
Maybe somebody hides it but
for the most part I don't think
that sombody takes interest in boys.
How long have you
been in the museum?
Well, last year I went to Armouries.
In general we don't have time
for the museums or cinema.
Do you like cinema?
I think normal about cinema.
I will go to watch it if I invited.
How long have you been to the cinema?
Yes, it was long ago.
Which film remained in your memory?
From the last ones...
One flew over the cuckoo's nest.
I liked it very much.
And any Russian movie?
I don't know... maybe 'The diamond
Arm' and 'A cruel romance'.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
THE DOLLY
Two series
Harder. You need to work harder.
Go.
What happened?
The twinge in my back...
Go have some rest.
USSR
Vadim Nikolaevich!
I feel pain in my back.
- So what?
- It hurts me to jump.
Your proposal?
I won't be able to perform.
So, my dear... It'a a
commercial competition.
Our country's being
paid in currency for it
that is spent to buy clothes,
jogging shoes and apparatus
for your training.
So you have to endure it.
- I won't!
- You will!
Nobody asks you to win
but your name is on poster.
So be so kind...
Tanya! Please stop it!
I can't sleep.
If I don't sleep enough
I won't be able to work tomorrow.
Tatyana Serebryakova
Don't move.
Her spine is in bad condition.
Any physical loads
are completely forbidden.
Listen, it's the fourth case
in your practice.
Among other things.
Aren't you afraid?
In our country
'Success is never blamed'.
Listen, is there any way
to win in a different way?
Do you want some tea?
In a different way?!
There's a way but it needs
the real science which doesn't exists.
And the theory that
also doesn't exist.
It needs money and apparatus.
It needs the food and not
the one sold in the shops.
Come on, you are all clever
in other people's business.
I understood that you don't want tea.
Listen you, doctor! When you prescribe
a recipe what do you write out?
Something that patient really needs or
something that's available in pharmacy?
- Me?
- Yes.
I don't prescribe anything at all.
- I make X-ray photos.
- Exactly.
You know, Elena Kulakova
has separated her husband.
- Oh, come on.
- Really and trully!
- How many years they were together?
- Probably 16 years.
No, much more. Wait... They
got married in 1969...
What did doctor say?
What did the doctor say?
Ah, nothing special.
He said that you need a break.
- What break?
- A little one.
Why?
Well you can have some
rest and visit your mom.
You'll get enough sleep at last.
You will study at school...
Why are you so nervous?
It's not for the whole life.
- You will go back in a year.
- In a year?
In a year or in a six months.
We'll see.
I will lose my physical form.
Well...
The physical form is the
thing that'll come with time.
And what about Cup of USSR?
This time Vinokurova will
go for the Cup of USSR.
- Who?
- Vinokurova.
Vinokurova? Well, thanks.
- So I'm no longer needed?
- Wait...
Come here now!
Come here!
Come here I said.
Idiot.
It's a present.
Bye-bye!
My dear! Take off your clothes.
Oh god, how I missed you!
It's great that you came back!
Oh god, your bags are so heavy.
Forgive me for not meeting you but I
hardly obtained leave from my boss.
No problem I got a cab.
Where did you get this mirror?
- What?
- Where's this mirror from?
Well it's a present from a work.
Why are you standing still Tanya?
Oh god I'm so glad of your arrival!
I missed you so much!
Let's go.
I arranged a special place for you.
I've got a folding screen.
Look! It's beautiful.
You can put it here
and screen off from me.
It's your private space.
- Will I sleep here?
- Yes. On grandmother's bed.
Hey I dragged aunt Zina's table.
Do you remember her? Her son Kolya
went to the army. It was his table.
She said that she no longer
needed it. And I took it.
Here's all your music.
I haven't touched anything.
Uncle Slava wanted to open it
and listen to it but I didn't allow.
Was I right?
And here's the TV set.
Who is 'uncle' Slava?
He's... from... my job.
So Sergey Ivanovich never came?
Did he run away?
How are you?
Nothing in particular.
Do you still work at
the cashier's office?
No, I now work at the bakery.
There are 4 offices, coffee room
where you can drink a cup of coffee.
And no smell of the fish.
You see?
Do you often drink?
Gosh! It was gathered
during the winter.
And I have no time to deliver them.
Don't you like it?
Here...
Some patties.
I baked them myself.
They are grandma's favourites.
Eat.
I'm not allowed.
- Why?
- I will put on the weight.
- So that's good.
- I need to keep my shape.
Why?
Why now?
So that the heart does not burst.
Tanya. What's wrong with you?
What's wrong with you, Tanya?
Don't think...
Don't...
Don't care for...
Anything can happen in this life...
You know... the life is long...
long...
What a beauty!
England.
Comrades!
Many people say that I
read the plates,
the plates.
the plates,
So what? I read correctly.
Hey, you!
How about catching it hot?
- What form is it?
- Ninth.
- A or B?
- B.
Go away or your teeth will fall out.
Hey, sweethart, set free
the reserved seat.
It's my seat.
- Is it all yours.
- All is mine.
Isn't that much for you?
D'you wanna jam on it?
- Hey who is she?
- I don't know.
- Freebie!
- What?
Come here.
- Well...
- Get out this silly from here!
- Why?
- She stuck her ass and don't come off.
Hey you! Scram!
- Did the sheep stick in yo'r ear?
- Get your hooks off me!
What?!
Let me go.
It hurts so much.
OK, you live until break.
I won't do it anymore.
I'm sorry!
Sit down.
I'm here for a minute.
Dear friends!
I have good news for you.
Ah! There you are!
Let me present to you
Tatiana Serebryakova.
Your new comrade,
Master of Sport, International Class,
ex-champion of the world in
rhythmic gymnastics.
Quiet! Quiet!
On behalf of the teacher's council,
the directorate and myself
I do hope that even in everyday life
you won't discredit you high rank.
And I think that you, my dears,
will make friends with Tanya
and will help her to become
a worthy part of your group.
We shall.
- That's good.
- I'm sorry...
- Is Panov allowed to be late?
- He's allowed to do anything.
- You can enter quietly.
- I'm sorry.
That's all.
Elena Mikhailovna, you can begin.
I consider that the
official event is over.
Good morning to all of you.
Good morning.
Did you hear? She's the world's champion.
And you told to throw her out of here.
Come on, world's champion.
She's a lump!
- Who's on duty?
- Me.
Who's ill or absent?
None.
Who doesn't want to
go to the black board?
Me.
Pyatnov! It's a 4th
time you don't want it.
You surely will be next.
- It's not 4th but 3rd.
- Don't lie. I noted it down.
So who want to go
to the blackboard.
- Freebie?
- What?
- Yes, yes.
Come on.
Why me? You don't have right.
Have no right.
For what?
The definition of derivative.
The rule of calculation
of the derivation.
Again me, yes?
Lutikova? What do you have for a suit?
- What? It's usual suit.
- Really?
- Was it specially made for you?
- Why?
It was bought in the
shop's 5th section.
- It's an expremintal model.
- What? What model?
Experimental.
Well, sit down.
My name is Elena Mikhailovna.
I'm your form-master.
Our group is good and friendly.
Get into the way and
get acquainted with it.
I'm telling you a secret:
our girls don't wear jeans at school.
And what do your
girls wear at school?
Our girls wear uniform suits,
try to be more feminine
and tidy.
Feminine?
In this militia's uniform?
We I think we
understood each other.
Elena Mikhailovna, maybe
I'd better repair a locker?
Hey, wait.
Do you know where the next lesson is?
Let me accompany you.
My name is Lida.
Listen, are you really a champion?
Why don't you answer?
- What should I tell you about?
- You think you're so menacing?
Here.
- What a thirst for knowledge!
- Have a rest for 5 minutes.
Lida!
two ...three
- Come here!
- I won't.
I said come here or it'll get worse.
It's for the mother.
This is for the father
and this is from me.
Wanna mess with me, billy-goat?
Hey, Mr. Tall Guy! Is all your
strength went into your height?
Or the blood can't reach the brain?
Watch out, sportsgirl!
You can once get it...
Didn't you understand?
Piss off...
while I'm in good mood.
Get your hands
off me, little midge!
Did anybody ask you?
- This is Alex 'FiveFloors'.
- So what?
He won't let us out
off school for this..
- Can you run fast?
- Yeah.
If you run to the right
they won't be able to get you.
- Who are they?
- You see 'FiveFloors' with his buddies?
They are from TVET.
Damn, I wish I could
call Panov for help.
- Why didn't you call him?
- He's forbidden to fight.
- Why?
- He & his pals were stealing passers' caps
and the got caught on stealing of tobacco.
And Helen helped him
to get off the hook.
How is it 'get off the hook'?
She put up bail for him.
OK. Let's go.
- I won't...
- Don't cry!
Are you gonna spend the night here?
If anybody of you ever touch him again
I will go to my sport-school
and bring my guys here.
They'll drub you so hard... you alone!
Understand?
Oh, come on!
My deed is to warn you
and then think youself.
Well how's your health Freebie?
Wow!
- Is it made of gold?
- Yes.
- Pure gold?
- No, a gilted silver.
Can I look closely?
Try.
Cool!
- Where did you get it from?
- From there... from there...
- And this one too?
- Yes, this one too.
Have you been to the USA?
No, but I was in Canada, Japan,
Romania and the UK.
Do you have ordinary name by the way?
Yes, Fedya.
Sit on the sofa,
there's not need to crawl there.
- Can I look at it?
- Help yourself.
Did the nickname 'Freebie' was
given to you by FiveFloors?
No, by Cherpakov.
- The most clever one?
- Yeah, the local nerd.
- Do you have any cassettes?
- Yes.
- Could you let me listen to them?
- Next time.
- Maria has one like this too.
- Where did she get it from?
Her father brought it from abroad.
Have you seen it?
No, she invites only
several girls to her place.
Hey Fedya, let me cut your hair?
What?
Let's make you look more solid.
Well, no.
Don't be afraid, I know how to do it.
You'll look like this.
You were great when
you knocked him out.
How did you do it?
Our masseur showed me one point.
Poke the finger there
and that's all.
- Let me show you?
- No, no need for it.
- So, let's go.
- Maybe it's better not?
You ought to, Fedya, you ought too.
(citing Operatsiya 'Y' movie)
OK, but don't put your hands on me.
and she cut his head down to heels.
Calm down, client.
That's all. My mother will kill me.
- She won't.
- Then I will be expelled from school.
We'll see. Maybe they won't do it.
Hey, don't touch me. Carefully!
Why are you gripping my haircut?
Did you wash your hands?
Stay away!
What do you want?
What?
Hi...
It's OK. It's OK.
Where are you crawling your hand?
- Hello!
- Hello!!!
Sit down.
Who's on duty?
Halikov.
There're no ansent of ill persons.
There're no 'whom'?
Ill persons.
- What's on your head?
- Hair.
What is the rag for?
It's not a rag but 'ring'.
It helps to compact the knowledge.
I understand.
You've got into a mess nerd!
- Did your father saw it?
- No.
He's on a business trip.
- When does he return?
- Tomorrow.
OK.
Elena Mikhailovna! Why can't he have
the haircut he likes?
- Are you again in trousers?
- So what?
I thought that we came to
an agreement upon it yesterday?
I agreed with you upon nothing.
You didn't explain me why
I can't go to school in trousers.
She's right.
Why not?
Silence!
Silence!!!
School is not a disco or debating-society!
I don't know why it's not allowed.
But it's prohibited and that's all.
And it's not a subject for discussion.
Tanya will go home now
and change her clothes.
I won't.
I'm not ordering you but begging.
I won't go.
Why?
Because this uniform doesn't fit me.
In this case I can't start the lesson.
If my trousers hinder you
I can go away.
Good-bye.
Stop!
Stand on the spot!
Turn around!
Mark time, march!
Platoon!
Go to the left! [inaudible]
On the spot! Stop!
To the right!
Comrade Head of the
teaching department!
The ninth form is making
elementary military training.
The supervisor of training is Lubavkin.
- Continue.
- Yes, ma'am.
To the right!
March!
Hello, Tanya!
Why are you here?
Have you been late?
Hello, Valentina Nikolaevna!
I was dismissed.
- By whom?
- Elena Mikhailovna.
Why?
She says that it's forbidden
to wear trousers at school.
But that's correct.
You know, Valentina Nikolaevna,
we gymnasts have particular
vestibular apparatus.
In order not to get ill we
have to do this exercise every hour.
My god!
You'll hurt yourself badly.
You see? We have to do it
every hour during the year.
How can I do it in a skirt?
I understand.
Understand.
Elena Mikhailovna!
Just a second, sorry.
Tanya go to your place.
I know about it and
we have agreed on everything.
So allow her...
Wait! I warned her yesterday
so today it's out of question.
I'm aware of it and
we have agreed on everything.
Go to your place.
Good-bye.
Sit down and continue your studies.
By the way Elena, I wait
you in my office on a big break.
Well...
Let's continue.
Next time...
Alexey do you know
what's the next lesson?
I don't know.
Would you like to listen to the music?
I have a player.
I don't care about your player.
- Good-bye.
[inaudible]
I don't know what to do... [maybe]
- What do you want Serebryakova?
- Nothing.
Oh! Oh!
Your Serebryakova will soon
get out off her skin in order to show off.
Oh come on Maria!
She's a normal girl.
Shitikova you just envy her and that's all.
Me? What?
A champion! A title-holder!
She's showing her off
because she's a big zero now.
She was expelled from the
gymnastics and what's left?
She's no feast for the eyes.
With such face she should
always carry a gasmask
in order not to scare people.
Give me some fire.
It's harmful to smoke by the way!
You are also a boor!
What do you want?
What? Who's bearding here?
They are provoking you Alexey!
You mustn't!
Go away! Go away guys!
Go away!
Calm down Alex!
It's my business.
I will deal with it myself.
Have a rest.
Serebryakova!
What's happening here?
Tanya don't get offended
but the jeans and the player...
No, I have nothing against,
live as you like...
but for you it's like
a cause for standing out...
Why?
To my mind you has already
been stood out by life itself.
Aren't you ashamed
for the eavesdropping?
- No. Why?
- Piss of from here!
Who are you?!
Who are you to teach me?!
Why are you addressing
on a first name basis?
Why are you doing the same?
Well... I'm elder...
And it's my direct duty to teach you.
So teach me.
I want you to become humans.
So I'm not a human yet?
Who's a 'human'?
Shitikova?
Shlepakov? Halikov?
Or maybe Alex FiveFloors?
For that matter I'm in my 16
did such things,
received such things from life...
which you Elena Mikhailovna
won't see until retirement!
You'll sit in a secondary school
for average-minded.
You think I don't understand
why are you so angry?
I impede to rule the herd!
Because I'm not average-minded!
Not from the herd!
Of course it's easy with the herd!
Everybody is in militia's uniform.
Everybody is equal.
Anyone like everybody.
But I've never been like
everybody and won't ever be.
So that is.
So Serebryakova, I see that
it's useless to speak with you.
I... wanted to help you.
I really pitied for you
from the bottom of my heart!
But...
Are you gonna to drag me
to the head-mistress?
Or invite my mother to school?
No.
You know...
you'll regret yourself soon.
- Good-bye.
- Let's go off here. [behind the door]
Look you could regret yourself!
Are you threatening me?
I'm not threatening.
You wanted to make
humans from them
but there're no humans in the herd.
Don't you understand?
Strict discipline!
It's the acid on the desks!
Maximum attention!
Stop talking!
Panov! I'll dismiss you!
It's not a joke!
It's the A-C-I-D!
Take measuring glass with
the acid in the right hand!
In the right! In the right!!!
And slowly bring it on elongated...
On elongated hand!
If you want I can pour everything
from this jar on your face.
You'll become worse than me.
I'll tell it was an accident and
you try to prove the opposite.
Serebryakova!
What are you talking about?!
Nadezhda Semenovna, I have a question.
For example there's a brainless doll,
father's daughter,
and she's very proud of her snoot.
And the snoot is a temporary thing.
And what will she do
if anything happens to her father?
Are you out of your mind?!
Put the measuring glass into place now!
What are you thinking about
with the acid in your hands?!
That's the point, it's the acid.
Oh god! When can I finally retire
and rest from these criminals?!
Tanya.
Are you in love?
Are you out of your mind?
Nicolai, sorry, I always wanted to ask you.
Why do you allow
everybody to copy from you?
So why?
Nothing. It's just the
time to stop spoiling them.
You can allow Freebie as he has not
enough oil in the head. Maybe FiveFloors...
But for the others - there's no point.
They do nothing, fool around
and then succeed at your own.
Stop working on them.
It's high time to start 'perestroika'.
They will take offense.
Don't worry! Tell them that I asked you.
All complaints - to me.
- So what do you say?
- I'll think about it.
By the way you're quick-witted.
Help me to look into this device.
Wow, it's Japanese.
Square root, logarithms...
Here's manual in English and Japanese.
I don't know any of them.
- Translate if you can.
- I'll try.
Well, let's go or we'll be late.
If you want you can keep it for youself.
I don't need it and you're clever.
Thank you.
There was little dicrepancy...
My father returned from the voyage...
Oh...
Shame on you!
Freebie, are you gonna
change your haircut every day?
Go away! Go away!
If not Elena...
you would have such
haircut much earlier than me.
Oh, a little discrepancy...
- Thank you.
- For nothing.
This girl, right?
- Halikov.
- Me!
Draw the curtains please.
- Why?
- Do it! No questions.
- It will be dark.
- You won't get lost.
Well?
Sorry, Elena Mikhailovna,
I lost my memory.
I remembered the half of the theorem
and can't do anything about the rest.
Your agony was so brief!
Since we won't see each other tomorrow
there's little information.
As usual I invite all of you
to my Birthday party.
The gathering will take
place at 7 o'clock.
It's better not to be late.
- Morning or evening?
- It's not a school we won't be late.
I guarantee the tea
and traditional pie.
I won't let in anyone with the present.
Do you invite me too?
Well... Why not?
I would like to come
but there's one discrepancy.
I have my Birthday tomorrow too.
And I wanted to invite guys to my place.
- Wow!
- I should say!
No problem, no problem!
We will carouse!
Maybe...
Maybe you will invite
guys on another day?
I would love to, Elena Mikhailovna,
but I can't.
My mother is preparing patties
in the morning. I feel sorry for her.
Well you can invite them at 5 o'clock.
And I'll be waiting for them
by half past seven.
- Is it OK for you?
- Yes.
That's good.
Alex do you think they
will all come tomorrow?
You bet!
And if not?
Maybe Panov, Nechaev
and 2-3 goats won't come.
Listen, what can we do
to make them come too?
It's like shooting fish in a barrel.
Nechaev!
Come here!
- What do you want?
- How are you talking to me?
- What time is it?
- 2:15 PM.
So...
- Show it to me.
- What are you... Alex.
- Valuable thing.
- Yes, normal.
Let me wear it?
No, if mother finds out she will howl.
I'll give it back to you tomorrow
when you come to Serebryakova.
- Why?
- You wanna argue?
We won't argue. Au revoir.
That's all.
Hello!
Did you iron your shirt?
And a trousers too? Good boy.
Don't slip on the staircase.
I guess you put on your new shoes.
Yes.
He hung up. Asshole.
- Yes.
- How are you there? Are you ready?
- Yes, mom.
- Is everything ok?
Yes.
OK. I'm free from work now.
If anything, I'll be at Lyuba's.
- I'll be late.
- OK.
Don't make much noise and
finish your party until 23:00.
OK.
By the way I forgot to ask
what's the reason for the party?
A Birthday.
- Whose Birthday?
- Our grade's.
You're inventive souls!
So long, kisses.
Bye.
Freebie-San has arrived!
Girls are dancing there!
Masha Shitikova is like...
Masha...
- How are they doing?
- They're having fun.
What time is it?
19:00? It's OK.
That's all.
It's time to go to Helena.
- No!
- Why?
Let's watch a little more
to see how it ends.
It's embarrassing!
Helena is waiting for us.
What for? Boring conversations
and apple cake? Turn it on.
- How much time is left?
- Forty minutes.
Only 40 minutes? Let's call Helena
and tell that we're late. Turn it on.
It's embarrassing to call.
It's better me and Shurik
to go and tell her. It's not far.
- Yes, you're right.
- Do it.
Hurray!
Hi!
I invite you personally.
- I won't go.
- And what if I ask you very nicely?
Alexey, I understand you. Helena has
got you off the juvenile colony.
So, are you gonna be her
gofer for the rest of your life?
You're not going there.
- Get your hoof out of my way!
- Try to punch me!
Punch me or it's too much for you?
Do it!
Get out in the street now!
I need to talk to Panov.
I have nothing to discuss with you.
- Get out now! Hurry!
- As you wish...
Let me through.
Wait...
Wait! I want to talk to you.
Let me go, you fool!
I love you.
Say it again.
So what?
You're skunk! Cad! Anyway you'll
crawl to me on your knees!
Alexey, I asked you not to bring presents.
Where did you get the money from?
- I earned it.
- Where?
- I unloaded the wagons.
- Thank you.
My pleasure.
Oh God, what a misfortune!
The lights went out and I bake
the cakes with a flashlight.
And eveything that could be
broken in this flat is broken now.
The water tap is leaking, the lock
doesn't work, the window doesn't open.
I'm tired of it all and I'd like to
marry an electrician or a plumber.
- Don't marry an electrician.
- Why?
- I can fix it.
- You really can?
What's wrong with that?
Where do you keep the tools?
One moment.
Don't touch anything without me.
Thank you.
- Where are the guys?
- I think they won't come.
Why?
The're watching movies
at Serebryakova's flat.
Really?
- Strange...
- I can't see anything.
Ah, I'm sorry.
It seemed to me that
we are nice to each other.
It's you who are nice to us.
And transfer your feelings to us.
A common mistake
of an intelligent person.
- And what about guys..?
- They don't care.
- All of them?
- All of them.
You are certain type of person,
we're absolutely different persons.
Frankly there can't be
any friendship between us.
We have a barrier
even with the parents.
But... Why did you come?
I love you.
What did you say?
Well...
Panov... how so..?
It's strange, isn't it?
- And there's no light.
- There's light.
Frankly I...
I don't know what to do.
Me too.
What's that? Did you fight again?
Get in the car, my friend!
I give you a drive.
Well... How was it?
Normally.
'Tis a pity she lives on high floor.
It's impossible to peep.
Where are her windows?
There... Two on the
left of the third floor.
Look, they switched off the light.
- Nestro and me...
- Let's go.
Oh, they switched it on again.
Is it obligatory to tell the guys
that they switched on the light?
Yes, I do.
Hi.
How are you?
Fine?
Undress yourself.
Let go check your weight.
Wow!
+500g in just one night!
Are you out of your mind?
I can't see your ears 'cause of cheeks.
OK. You're free to go.
What does it mean "I'm sorry"?
Oh well, let's do some acrobatics.
Don't even dare to train badly.
Somersault!
Good! One more time.
On the rigid legs!
Like this.
Let's do it slowly.
Throwback.
One.
Stretch your toes!
Watch your knees.
You don't do the splits.
I'll stop helping you.
Bad.
Sit down.
Well...
Pull on the sock.
That's it.
Well, forget it.
You won't have a supper today
and a breakfast tomorrow.
Only half of the cup of tea.
Did you got it?
Come tomorrow by 10:00.
Ciao.
Well...
We know each othe for 4 years.
Perhaps... you've changed
during this time.
You grew up.
Your interests have changed.
I understand.
However...
if people are invited
and they can't come...
they tell about it.
At least by phone.
At least for the sake of not being
awaited and worried about.
Did something happen to you?
You didn't do that...
And it seems to me... on purpose.
Maybe I've also changed
during these 4 years.
In any case I consider your yesterday's
absence as an act of distrust.
Well then... you're adults and
you have right to choose.
They talk a lot about democratization,
self-government and openness nowadays.
I don't want any things
went unsaid between us.
It's OK, you're adults...
Maybe you need someone else.
I'm ready to nominate my candidature for
voting if you need another form-master.
I personally have nothing against it.
Evseeva, as Komsomol leader you start.
What should I tell?
Start voting if you want
me as your form-master.
Let's do it frankly.
Who's for me to stay?
And who's against it?
Vote.
So...
Who's for Elena Mikhailovna
to stay our form-master?
Raise your hands.
Who's for?
Elena Mikhailovna.
It's unanimously for you.
Thank you.
No lessons today.
Ah yes... we planned to
visit the philharmonic society...
Here are your tickets.
Goodbye.
- Hurra!
- Go back to your seat!
- Why?
- Nothing. Go back to your seat!
We are guilty before her.
I think we have to apologize to her.
I think that Panov will do
it better on behalf of the form.
Those who agree... raise your hands.
Hello, Alexander Mikhailovich.
- Don't you recognize me?
- No... Remind me.
We stayed in the same hotel in Tokyo.
You were on tour and we
were on World's Championship
- I'm Tatyana Serebryakova.
- Yes-yes, I remember.
Where're you going now?
- In the hotel.
- Great. You're going my way.
Oh God! it's disgusting.
Don't you understand the jokes?
What do you want?
- Let go of me.
- Try to hit me!
- Can't you?
- Go away.
He's coming to me.
Let him go.
Are you crazy? Don't you know him?
He's a criminal.
- Let him go.
- Well, it's up to you.
Panov! Bednov!
Get back to your seats!
We're done, Serebryakova!
Pack your valise.
When I was as young as you...
I fell in love for the
first time in my life.
I fell in love with physics teacher.
He was very young...
talented and... handsome.
When he talked to me...
his eyes emited a warm light.
Perhaps it happens to
all of us but I thought...
that it happened only to me.
When he aproached me...
I felt happiness.
I didn't think of anything on his
lessons. I only listened to his voice.
And I felt dizzy.
He had raucous and gentle voice.
It seemed tender to me.
One day on some meeting...
he accidentally sat next to me,
shoulder to shoulder.
And I...
I felt like I'm blind.
I felt very shameful.
And I sat like numb
and was afraid to move.
I always wanted to look at him.
One day he got sick.
And we had another
teacher the whole week.
And then...
for the first time in my life...
I...
I understood that...
because of the depression...
One can die 'cause of the depression.
These are not just words...
this is really so.
Then he returned...
and I wrote to him a letter.
Well...
A desperate letter.
And in the three days I was
called to the headmaster's office.
My letter was on his table.
My parents were there.
My mother cried.
It was a long talk...
with many wise phrases but...
The smarter were the words
the more pain I felt.
Then physicist was transferred
to another class.
And we almost never met.
We rarely saw each
other in the corridors.
And he greeted me in a very polite way.
He was afraid of me for some reason.
Of course it was an
incident for the school.
But it was solved...
But I...
I...
It was like... something...
like I lived throught...
or...
something had to be...
born and...
didn't born.
Why am I telling about it?
It's because I'm 27 years old and...
I have never felt anything like this.
I can openly tell this word "NEVER".
It's like something
has broken in me and...
that's all.
How can I explain it...
In those times...
In those times there was
some kind of recklessness and...
There was happiness
in this recklessness.
But...
Then a lot of things happened...
I graduated, got married but...
I divorced very soon because...
everything that happened afterwards...
was a kind of fake.
It can happen to each of you.
And then everything...
Everything...
will depend on each of you.
On your words,
your looks, your laughs...
Be careful... because...
it's very easy to ruin
someone's destiny.
But...
Everything is tied in this life.
If you ruin someone's destiny today,
someone will ruin yours tomorrow.
Because...
you created this law yourself,
which reads that one
can ruin anyone's destiny.
Give me the player please.
What?
- Give me the player please!
- Why?
I asked you not to bring it in school.
You can have a break.
What did you do there? What are
those elections of the form master?
Do you understand what kind
of genie you are unleashing?
I understand.
Let the democracy be but
there had to be a limit.
What kind of democracy is this without
coordination with the management.
- Ordinary democracy.
- You could consult us.
I didn't have time.
I felt that I have to do something
but didn't know what specifically.
- I felt it in a very last moment.
- She felt!
And what if you feel that you have
to blow up the school tomorrow?
If I feel it I'll blow it up.
- Georgiy Matveevich!
- Oh, come on.
It's a joke. You don't need to shout.
And after all where
can she get explosives?
Elena Mikhailovna! We appreciate you
and consider as a promising teacher.
But you should consult with us.
- Let's consult.
- Is it an order?
This is not an order, but a request
that should be fulfilled.
And the last thing... You delayed your
reference on Serebryakova for three days.
Because of this we still can't
present the list of delegates
for the conference of the
Komsomol asset to city commitee.
You are disrupting an
important event. Why?
You know why.
I'm against it.
- Do you have any facts?
- No, I don't.
But I have.
This girl is doing well at school.
She took a patronage of the most
notorious hooligans on her own initiative.
And among other things
they began to study better.
In the meantime the overall
progress score of the class has dropped.
- How can you explain it?
- I can't explain it.
But I feel there's some
relationship between these facts.
That's it.
Elena Mikhailovna!
The country entrusted Serebryakova to us.
Let's justify this confidence.
We don't need any mysticism here.
Serebryakova, where's the player?
You'd better to give it back.
Why do you think that I took it?
- Don't you have it?
- Ransack me.
Who did take the player?
Once again: who did take
the player from the table?
There's one specialist.
Master of pocket thefts.
Bednov, get back to your seat!
Why? You ransacked Serebryakova.
Why don't we do the same to Panov?
Hey, you! Show your paper-case!
Try to take and look!
Go have some rest.
Stop it!
It's not there.
It happens. Don't worry, Helena
Mikhailovna, everything will be allright.
I want everybody to
check your paper-cases.
I want player on the table in 2 minutes!
Voila!
- Who's on duty?
- Me.
Come here.
- What's this?
- Where?
In the recycle bin.
Put it on the table.
Who did this?
- Freebie!
- What?
You always know everything!
Come on, speak up!
What? I know nothing,
I saw nothing.
You'll tell everything, bastard!
Alex, idiot!
Alexey!
Elena Mikhailovna, stay out of this!
I think it's time to call the militia.
Call them! Call them!
What are you thinking about?
I'm not going to be silent.
Or you think that Panov
can do everything?
Maybe he can do everything at
your place but it won't work here.
Alexey, don't do it...
You bastard, he can't fight back!
Who did this?
Who?!
Speak or I'll kill you!
Serebryakova...
Alexey! Alexey, let him go!
Alexey!
What happened?
What happened?!
Nothing happened.
And now... repeat what you said!
Oh... Serebryakova...
Freebie! Say it louder!
So everyone could hear.
- Speak up!
- Serebryakova.
Well, what are you starring at?
Stay behind the door. Hurry!
Let me go.
- It hurts.
- What?
Oh my god!
Subtitled by Alessio.
11-2019