Milano Films
L'INFERNO
(1911)
Art direction:
Francesco Bertolini, Adolfo Padovan, Giuseppe De Liguoro. Technical direction:
Emilio Roncarolo. Set design: Sandro Pr , Francesco Bartolini
Dante: Salvatore Papa
Virgilio: Arturo Pirovano
Conte Ugolino: G. Liguoro
Lucifero: A. Milla
Contributor: Emilio Beretta
Music by Ivan Dolgunov (2010)
Dante imagines himself lost in a dark and rough jungle.
"Half way through life I was in a dark forest, because I had lost the right path."
Three beasts, a panther, a lion and a wolf, prevent Dange from climbing up the hill of salvation.
Beatrice descends from heaven in limbo with Virgil and begs to help Dante.
"I, Beatrice, am the one who makes you walk;
Site come desire to return; Love moves me, and leads me to talk."
Dante, saved by Virgil, addresses his company in hell.
"I went the hard and wild way."
Hell's Gate.
For me it leads to the suffering city, for me it leads to eternal suffering, For me it is to people convicted.
Abandon, all hope, ye who enter here!
The river Acheron on which Charon transports souls to the other shore.
"Charon, demon, with eyes of fire, calls all collected, lashes with the paddle anyone who is late."
Limbo, where all are punished who were not baptized.
"... Living without hope in the desire."
Homer, Horace, Ovid and Lucan, welcome Virgil and Dante who they agree with him.
"Being the sixth among such great sages."
The noble castle, which houses the great spirits.
Minos, who judges the souls and assigns punishment.
"There Minos growled horribly."
Lustful, tormented by a whirlpool.
"The infernal storm, which never ceases, he leads to the spirits his prey, He harasses and beats them back."
Paolo and Francesca.
"What pigeons calls of desire, sweet nest with raised wing,they will want the wind to carry them. "
The story of Francesca.
"We read one day a delight,
how hurt love of Lanzarote; alone together without any suspicion."
Dante, touched by Francesca's story, sees her vanish.
"And I fell as a dead body falls."
Cerberus, cruel beast, guards gluttons, barking with three mouths, and offense afflicts them.
The wolverines, drenched by an eternal rain, howl like dogs. Ciacco predicts to Dante that bloody feuds will rend Florence.
Pluto guards prodigals and misers.
Prodigal and covetous, with a chest dragging heavy weights injuring each other.
The Styx, in which are immersed sloths and the angry, beaten in various ways.
Flegias, the famous atheist, transports Dante and Virgil to the city of Dis.
Filippo Argenti is recognized and offended.  Dante tries to hit him.
"... He held out both hands to a tree; the teacher avoided more prudent, saying, "Go with the other dogs!"
The city of Dis, where the infidels are punished. Dante, rejected and hindered by demons, threatened by the presence of three rages on the tower, is aided by the help of an angel.
Heretics, buried in tombs of fire.
Farinata degli Uberti.  Dante predicted his exile.
"... He stood with his chest and forehead as if to despise hell itself."
Cavalcanti questioned by his son, Guido.
The tomb of Pope Anastasius.
Victim of suicide, converted into gnarled trunks, where harpies nest.
(Pier della Vigna)
"... I cut a branch of a large blackthorn;
and its trunk cried, 'Why do you hurt me?'"
Pier Della Vigna, accused of treason, deprived of his sight by order of Emperor Frederick II.
After the torture, he committed suicide.
Wasteful wealth itself, persecuted and lacerated by dogs.
"The forest was filled behind them with black dogs, running and barking."
Violence against God, nature and art, tortured by a rain of fire.
Capaneo.
The poets descend into the Malebolge on the shoulders of Gerión.
"She goes swimming slowly, very slowly;
turns and descends ..."
The ten graves of Malebolge.
First circle
Ruffians, punished by demons, are whipped.
Venedico Caccianimico.
Second circle
Flatterers and loose women are immersed in manure. Alessio Interminei and Thais.
"... That dirty and disheveled slave,
that there scratches with her nails, and now she lies there.  Thais is the prostitute"
Third Circle
The greedies are buried upside down, with the soles of their feet on fire.
Pope Nicholas III.
Dante rages against the Papacy.
Fourth Circle
Soothsayers, neck and face twisted, walking backwards.
Fifth Circle
The angry, immersed in boiling pitch, are guarded by demons.
Malacoda chooses the ten demon devils to escort the poets.
Ciampolo falls into the power of the demons and, deceiving them, escapes.
Two of them are fighting.
Demons chasing the poets.
Sixth Circle.
Hypocrites, walking under heavy blankets of lead.
Caiaphas, crucified on the floor and trampled by anyone who passes.
Seventh Circle
Thieves, bitten horribly by snakes.
Vanni Fucci predicted to Dante the defeat of the Whites.
Thieves of public money, men converted into snakes and vice versa.
Eighth Circle
Fraudulent counselors, each wrapped in a flame.
"Odysseus and Diomedes are in there, tortured..."
Ninth Circle
Those who sow discord and schisms, mutilated by demons.
Muhammad with his torn chest.
Born Bertram head disembodied.
"Gripping the head hair cut short,
like a lantern carrying it in your hand."
Tenth Circle
Counterfeiters, converted to lepers, crazy and sick.
Nembrot, Efialte, Antaeus: The Giants
Anteo holds the poets in his hands.
"... Slightly in the background, ...
... He led us."
Traitors, submerged in the frozen lake of Cocytus.
The Antenora.
The traitors of the motherland.
Count Ugolino, gnawing on the skull of Archbishop Ruggeri.
"From the fierce meal he lifted his mouth."
Count Ugolino recounts the story of his death and his sons, in the Tower of Pisa.
"... And it was me, and blind, groping about for them, two days I called to them, but they were dead.  After the pain followed more fasting."
The Tolomea. Friends, traitors. Friar Alberigo prays to Dante to remove the ice from their eyes.
Judea
The traitors of their benefactors.
Lucifer.
The underground way.
The poets leave hell.
"By which we left to contemplate the stars."
THE END