THE HYPOTHESIS
OF THE STOLEN PAINTING
Human consciousness has expired.
On the cadaver he squats,
gloating, mired.
Seated in triumph, he turns to crow.
Each time
he deals the corpse a blow.
Victor Hugo
What do you see? What do you feel?
Is it pain or is it ecstasy
that keeps you afloat in space?
P.K. BAPH. VI. 141.
No sinister adjuncts
lend their banal significance.
No hint of melodrama
injects its facile role.
Simply by interpreting
in his sober, magisterial style,
the dynamism of these figures and
by capturing gesture and attitude,
the painter reveals
the ardent fanaticism of these men,
their implacable purpose.
J. Alboise in L'Artiste, 1889.
Ingenious,
somewhat studied compositions
recalling the witty groupings
employed with felicity by Gérôme.
Adding a novelist's skills
to those of the painter,
he plays cleverly
on our curiosity as spectators
who arrived too late.
M.F. Lajenevais,
Revue des Deux Mondes, 1889.
Rare is the artist so assured
of the present and the future.
He is not merely an instinctive
master of composition.
His sense of history preserves him
from the pitfalls
of dusty scholarship.
It was also said,
"Always a painter,
Monsieur Tonnerre
"is now an artist,
in the highest sense of the word."
And yet...
Alas! And yet...
How could such paintings
provoke a scandal?
And yet...
How is it
that only six paintings...
Seven.
How is it that a simple scandal,
a mere stir in fashionable Paris
became transformed
into an affair of state?
Alas.
Today we look and look again
at these paintings.
There is nothing shocking
about them,
no common link between them,
not even a unity in style.
In some,
the striking thing
is the attention to detail
but also a lack of care
in the overall composition.
In others,
the flowing strokes
and vivid colours
but also the static quality
of the compositions.
Y et others indulge
the excessive illusionism
of a theatrical décor
but also
seem contradictory
in their composition.
That these six paintings should pose
such questions is understandable.
Seven paintings.
But a scandal,
intervention by the authorities...
Alas! Thrice alas!
And yet...
And yet only seven paintings
preserve their mute testimony.
A scandal so great
that the authorities,
for once in agreement,
felt impelled to bury it.
The press was silent,
spies infiltrated the salons
and others, diversionary scandals,
seemingly by chance,
overtook the people
most concerned with these paintings
executed more or less skilfully
by an obscure disciple of Gérôme:
the painter Tonnerre.
Two comments...
Two comments
concerning the paintings.
And two further comments.
Two further comments,
but these of a more general nature.
Firstly,
the seven paintings
do have a common factor.
Although one of them was the object
of particularly virulent attacks
- we shall see why our parents
were driven
to react in this way -
and although two or three others
among the paintings
were held to be
purely and simply shocking,
the fact is
that the scandal centred
on the exhibition as a whole.
On all the paintings,
each and every one of them.
Secondly,
if we closely examine
each painting in turn,
we cannot but be struck
by a number of curious details.
This one, for example.
We see two Crusaders
in the act of playing chess.
The composition is theatrical,
you say.
Yes, but what does that mean,
"theatrical?"
The gestures?
The positioning of the figures?
No, not at all.
The effect you describe
as theatrical
derives from one simple detail:
the lighting.
From the two rays of light, one
entering by the window on the right,
the other
by the window on the left.
Which implies
a world with two suns.
This, I might add,
is only one example.
To turn now to the two comments
of a more general nature.
Let us consider
the historical context and say,
firstly,
the paintings did not show,
they alluded.
And what our fathers saw,
at the point
when the eight powers intervened,
was The Ceremony.
And, at that time in ceremony,
whose ritual is now lost,
which today we can scarcely
begin to imagine,
the ceremony
was on the verge of becoming
a matter of common knowledge.
This could not go on.
Which is why,
some months after the exhibition,
police raided the painter's house
and burst in on the ceremony.
And why the authorities
had no alternative.
They had to act quickly.
Secondly,
the painter Tonnerre
defended himself.
From Italy, he made his appeal.
Affectingly, by letter,
he declared his innocence.
Cleverly, he turned
the rules of the game upside down.
He declared
that the ceremony did not exist.
That what was known by that name,
what the police saw
with their own eyes
was merely
a re-enactment of his paintings
through medium of tableaux vivants,
no more no less.
We can imagine today
what the reaction to this defence
must have been
within the ranks
of the eight powers.
We can guess how some people
must have smiled ironically
and others laughed quite openly.
It was inevitable that our parents
should have reacted in this way.
But we have
other means of analysis today.
And I think I know
what the painter Tonnerre
really meant to say
when he protested his innocence.
Guilty as sin, he was.
What a terrible revelation.
They were the ceremony.
And yet...
The paintings do not show,
they allude.
The paintings...
re-enacted through the medium
of tableaux vivants
do not allude.
They show.
After opening the door
the collector shows us
into a drawing-room
overlooking a large garden.
He approaches the window.
With the aid of binoculars,
we can see at the foot of the garden
the reproduction of a mythological
scene in a tableau vivant.
Near a lake,
the Huntress muses with her bow.
Sheltered by the foliage,
Actaeon's eyes
waver between this vision of Diana
and a glimpse of his prey.
Is the third figure
really necessary?
Why this third person?
And why does he hold a mirror?
Well, the mirror you mention
would have been to dazzle the prey.
In this sense the role of the third
figure in the Diana and Actaeon
would assume
an unexpected importance.
It will indeed have escaped no one
that, extraneous to the scene,
this third figure invades it
purely to watch the watcher.
In another sense,
it is not impossible
that the prey
is none other than Actaeon himself,
metamorphosed as a punishment
for having dared
cast his eye on the goddess.
Y et what is there in this painting
to make us think
it is the first of a series?
What leads us from it
to the one we may consider
the next in sequence?
At the risk of upsetting
a somewhat facile train of thought,
I would like
to inject a certain doubt.
Suppose the Diana the Huntress
theme were merely a red herring.
Suppose the anomalous
elements were merely snares.
And that the trail
must be sought elsewhere.
A trail indicated
by a detail, minor but nevertheless
exposed to full view.
Let us allow that,
as an absurd piece
of hunting equipment,
the mirror offers a thematic clue
which might further our pursuit.
The collector is asking us
to ignore the narrative element,
the arrangement of objects
and even the object
of the character's scrutiny.
Look at the mirror.
The mirror reflects the sun's rays.
Let us trace their direction.
Here we see the sun's rays
reflected by the mirror
and falling onto a basement window.
A game of chess is interrupted
by the arrival of a Crusader.
One then realizes that the sun is
entering by the window on the left
while the same rays, reflected by the
mirror from the preceding painting
are cast on the scene
through the window opposite.
Thus the riddle of the two
contradictory rays is solved.
The Arrival of the Crusader.
I think that
the untenable aspect of the theme
will not have escaped anyone.
Whence comes this Crusader?
What does he interrupt?
How, coming directly
from the Crusades,
could he burst in on the scene
and surprise the players?
And these players,
what are they hiding
that they should be surprised
by the arrival
of a new character?
A new character...
The disturbing presence of the page
will, I think, have escaped no one.
The page who makes a great show
of his consternation
before the other characters
in the painting
whereas we,
and we alone,
can glimpse his secret smile.
If we accept
that this painting follows
the preceding one in the series,
which can we take to be the next,
and why?
I think you will have noticed
that the characters are Templars.
As you see, the painter has respected
the hierarchy within the Order.
Let us now consider this hierarchy.
On the lowest level,
almost marginal to the composition,
is the page.
Then the two Templars,
equal before the Grand Master.
Respecting the painter's intentions,
let us carefully observe
the Grand Master.
What is his attitude?
Let us examine
with renewed attention
each detail of his clothes,
the severity of his eye,
the clenched left hand.
Let us accept the astonishing
gesture of his right,
indicating the mirror.
A mirror reflecting what?
The window behind which,
in the first painting,
another mirror reflects the sun
shining through
this painting's window.
Crude conjecture.
Perhaps one might now venture the
hypothesis of a group of paintings
whose interconnection
is ensured by a play of mirrors.
Conjecture.
One might see the painter's oeuvre
as a reflection
on the art of reproduction.
Certainly not. That is not the way
to look at this painting.
The effect must be considered
in a totally different way.
Otherwise
we shall become entangled
in the snare set for us.
In this particular case,
the thing to be considered
is the form of the mirror.
With due care, however,
for therein lies another snare.
We must not linger over
the significance of this form
to the theme.
It is common knowledge,
more common within each day,
that the crescent moon
is a Saracen symbol.
No one can fail to be aware that
the presence of so impious a token
within the Order
is surprising, to say the least.
Today,
though they find it
difficult to accept, everyone knows
that the presence of this token
in the Order was, alas, probable.
But this is of no consequence.
None of this matters.
What matters
is the form itself,
the fact that this crescent
should be reproduced
in another painting
which I now invite you to consider.
A series of paintings
linked by minor details
sometimes skilfully inserted
extraneously to the theme:
the ray of light in the mirror,
the second mirror
in the shape of a crescent.
And now...
I would like to draw your attention
to the extreme care with which
the painter has placed the mirror.
So that
it is really impossible to err
in arranging the tableau vivant.
Is such care likely?
What else is the painter's purpose
but to draw our attention
to what is reflected in the mirror
when the tableau is arranged?
Look, it is he one sees
reflected in the mirror.
But now let us consider
the lighting effects.
The chiaroscuro, obviously,
is arbitrary.
Why should certain figures,
perhaps not the most important,
be privileged
and others remain a shadow?
But setting aside the lighting,
let us concentrate on the figures.
All becomes clear.
Let us reverse the lighting.
Let what was plunged in shadow
emerge into the light
and what was clearly visible
return to the darkness.
The mask.
There is the link
with the next painting.
We must then ask:
which is that painting
and why does the mask lead us to it?
Now the collector explains
that this painting does not exist.
That it is the stolen painting
and that all we know of it
is that there was a mask.
A certain number of problems
now present themselves.
If the previous painting
does indeed lead us to this one,
then obviously there will be
a hiatus in the series.
And with the trail lost,
how can we establish
the order of the paintings?
No one will ever know
what in this painting
was to have led us to the one I
postulate as the next in the series.
Here is the scandalous painting
rejected by the Salon in 1887.
Apparently exhibited in private,
it was, inexplicably,
acquired by the state.
What, in this painting,
could have provoked a scandal?
Was it enough simply to show
people of some social prominence
in attitudes which are in fact
quite commonplace
while claiming that they had agreed
to act as models
for the painting?
Might this painting
not be interpreted as a means
of stifling the rumours
which lay behind the scandal
and which tarnished the reputation
of a respectable family?
But in that case,
where would the scandal lie?
Maybe...
the fact of having posed
for this scene from family life,
no matter how commonplace
or innocent it be,
maybe this fact in itself
was felt to be totally unacceptable.
In fact, although the scenes
are indeed commonplace,
it is nevertheless true
that the fact
of having exhibited themselves,
the fact of having assembled
the protagonists of a scandal
might be interpreted
as ostentation,
as acknowledging and condoning
what public opinion would have
described as an "unspeakable vice".
But are these scenes
indeed so innocent?
Can we assert
that they are entirely
free from certain obscurities?
Who knows
but that these scenes
reveal aspects of the scandal
instantly recognizable
to the initiated?
There is certainly
something disturbing
about these scenes from daily life.
We may note that in each of them
someone has just committed,
or is preparing to commit,
That in both cases,
a third character
is in the act of watching
and that through his air
of frank disapproval, this character
provokes the desire
to commit the forbidden act.
A disapproval
that he displays to the spectator
but conceals from the characters.
Perhaps
in order to guard himself
against any eventual accusation
of complicity.
The grouping tells us, however,
that those who have been
discovered, as it were,
are pointedly turning their backs
on the spy.
Knowing this,
and accepting this situation,
the spy therefore
does indeed participate
as an accomplice
in the public exposition
of the moments
preceding and following
the reprehensible act.
And since the reprehensible aspect
of this act
resides in the intention,
is not the exposition
of these moments much more so?
Does this not open up
limitless possibilities
for interpretation?
Possibilities
reaching beyond the act itself,
which, as we need not now deny,
did indeed take place.
But was this not enough
to provoke a scandal?
Furthermore,
I should add that these events
and public rumours
have come down to us
by way of a little roman-à-clef.
A brief résumé of this little novel
will give us some idea
of the enormity of the events
which rumour
endeavoured to conceal.
The beginning of the novel
describes a betrothal scene.
Tha Marquise de I. has invited
her friends to a reception
to announce
the engagement of her niece O.
who is also her ward,
to the Marquis de E.,
a friend of the family.
The Marquise is presented from
the outset as a domineering woman
swayed by vaulting ambition.
The anonymous author makes no secret
of his sympathy for the Marquis,
portrayed as a man of thirty-five,
kindly by nature
and forced by the ruin of his family
into a marriage of convenience.
The Marquis is shown
as the victim of a cunning plot
devised entirely
by the Marquise de I.
At the end of the first chapter
the Marquise
suspects her niece's betrothed
of a questionable interest
in young L.,
her nephew and ward.
The latter is described
as a boy of very winning ways
not entirely unaware of the interest
he has awakened in the Marquis de E.
The author has earlier informed us
that the Marquise had planned
to marry the two cousins,
the young L. and the young O.,
thus uniting the fortunes of the
collateral branches of the family.
In securing her niece's hand,
the Marquis de E. spoiled her plan.
But her discovery of the interest
shown in the boy by the Marquis
leads her
to devise the sinister plot
which is revealed in Chapter Two.
This is
to encourage the relationship
between the Marquis and young L.
in order to provoke a scandal
which, by ruining
the reputation of the Marquis,
would make impossible the marriage
to the girl O.
At this point,
matters are complicated
by the entry of a new character,
El Señor de H.,
Knight of the Order of Malta
and Spanish envoy to the Holy See.
Since this person
is also attracted by young L.,
he provokes
the jealousy and rivalry
of the Marquis de E.
E. and H.,
being friends of long standing
in view of their affiliation
to the same secret society,
agree to settle their
quarrel through a game of chess
with the loser undertaking
to renounce all claim to the
hypothetical favours of the boy L.
The betrothed girl
happens to witness this scene.
Perceiving the disquieting
implications of the scene
without really understanding,
she tells to her aunt.
The latter, we learn in Chapter
Four, is now resolved to act.
In pursuance of her plan,
she therefore summons the Marquis.
Arriving at the appointed place,
the Marquis finds the Marquise
partially unclothed
challengingly exhibiting herself
before his eyes.
Understanding the allusion
to his lack of interest
in the fair sex,
he loses his temper
and offers to strike her.
The girl, witnessing the scene,
assumes it to be
a lovers' quarrel.
Convinced that she is betrayed,
she determines
to confront her aunt.
In Chapter Five,
realizing that she has aroused
new feelings between the betrothed,
the Marquise summons the girl O.
to a clandestine meeting.
At this meeting,
the Marquise apprises the girl
of her fiancé's unnatural tastes.
Seeing this revelation
as a mere stratagem
to part her from him,
the girl reacts violently.
Their quarrel is witnessed by H.
who decides to propose
an alliance with the Marquise
with a view to alienating the boy L.
from the Marquis.
Thus it is that,
for the fist time in the story,
young L. takes the initiative
and confesses his love
to the Marquise.
This scene is witnessed by the girl,
now doubly jealous of her aunt
but unable to choose in her heart
between young L. and the Marquis.
She confides in her fiancé.
These revelations cause the Marquis
to fall into a deep depression
intensified
when he witnesses a strange scene
between young L. and H.
In this scene,
H., a stag's head in his hand,
is attempting to persuade the boy
to pose as Diana the Huntress.
The Marquis, bursting in the scene,
provokes his friend H. to anger.
He reproaches him
with his lack of integrity
in failing to keep his promise
to renounce the boy.
Intervening
to reproach E. for having
abandoned him to a foreigner,
the boy aggravates the quarrel.
In Chapter Ten,
we come to the scene
of the duel between E. and H.
during the course of which young L.
is simultaneously arbiter, second,
sponsor and occasion of the duel.
In despair, believing herself the
cause of the duel, O. intervenes.
While the Marquise
watches from a distance,
at last savouring the scandal
she has anticipated for months.
Unfortunately,
both adversaries miss their mark
and H.'s bullet
accidentally wounds the girl O.
Police arrest the protagonists
but intervention of E.'s family
secures their prompt release.
Accused of attempted homicide
and obliged to plead insanity
to escape the law,
H. is confined to an asylum
not far from Paris.
In the penultimate chapter,
we find the girl O.
affected by her wound.
In the delirium of her fever
she sees herself as St. Theresa
and her cousin as the angel
conducting her to heaven.
The Marquis visits her,
but seeing him
as the devil himself,
she repulses him violently.
In renewed delirium,
now imagining herself
to be a Babylonian harlot,
young O. repulses
her angel of redemption
and still seeing the Marquis
as the devil, implores him
to conduct her to hell
thus obeying a command
given by St Theresa.
Following
a long and grievous convalescence,
O. forgives the Marquis de E.
We find all the characters
assembled at a family gathering.
Suddenly Señor H. reappears,
having fled the asylum with the aid
of members of the secret society,
alerted by the Marquise.
H. publicly accuses E.
of failing to keep his promise
by continuing to importune young L.
The latter intervenes
to accuse H.
of alienating him from his aunt.
The girl O., finally grasping
the situation, breaks with E.
But the story does not end
as the Marquise would have wished.
That very night, the boy L.
is carried off by H.
aided by members of the sect
and taken to their mansion
in the rue de la Pompe.
Promptly alerted by the Marquise,
the police intervene
and interrupt a strange ceremony
involving young L.
as both priest and sacrifice.
The protagonists
all find themselves in prison
and are released
on payment of a substantial bail.
Young L.
is found hanged in his cell
and the talk is either of suicide
or a crime.
Can we accept that what lies behind
these paintings is merely a novel?
We can then say
that the protagonists
simply portrayed the novel's theme
as if it were a ceremony.
We have not yet seen or said
everything.
Two paintings remain.
We have travelled a difficult road
to come this far.
Will we manage
to travel it to the end?
Will we remember all the arguments
and counter-arguments developed?
Will we have time
to expound other doubts,
to point out the innumerable
thematic clues to the intrigue?
In this painting we may perceive
certain elements
of previous paintings.
This group, for instance,
recalls the painting
Tortures of the Inquisition.
This one, The Game of Chess.
This character
evokes Diana the Huntress.
But the other characters?
The naked women?
The clowns and demons?
We shall explain them
through the hypothesis
of the stolen painting.
The collector
once again requires us
to forget the thematic clue
and to concentrate
on the composition.
In this painting,
as in the preceding ones,
characters are grouped in threes.
Each group of three recalls a scene
from an earlier painting,
although there is, so to speak,
no linking story.
Let us turn our minds
back to the previous painting.
From there,
let us follow the thematic clue.
We see that the story
moves from painting to painting
like the hands of a watch.
Let us ask where this series of
scenes from family life is taking us.
We will now examine the characters
of the scandalous painting.
Let us trace
each character's gestures,
painting by painting.
We now see that, in moving
from one painting to the next,
the characters
are slowly completing the circle,
each in his own way.
The circle is not perfect,
you will say.
But what we have here
are really curves
which form circles of unequal
diameter if completed by imagination.
And these circles may be classified
roughly in three groups,
of decreasing importance.
And the circles of each group
are combined,
their respective product is,
of course, a sphere.
Spheres which we can in turn imagine
as combined or not
but which still evoke spheres.
But any movement
effected by a human being
leaves an imaginary trace
comparable to a curve.
We shall return to this.
Curved lines which suggest circles.
Circles leading to the sphere.
The blazing sphere which dominates
the last painting in the series.
Baphomet,
an androgynous demon.
The principle of non-definition.
In defiance of time.
An immaculate body without soul
caressed by the breezes which are
wandering, bodiless souls.
Assailed through the seven orifices
by wandering souls
seeking their reincarnation.
Souls
already despairing
of the day of resurrection.
Is this not what we have seen
repeated in all the paintings?
Is it not
the very heart of the paintings,
their occult theme?
The real cause of the scandal?
Worshipped by the Templars,
religion within a religion
of a state within a state?
Still worshipped today
in secret ceremonies
masquerading as mere debauches.
So that is the real reason
for the scandal?
It is.
But if all the paintings portray
the cult of the androgyne,
what is the role of the painting
Diana the Huntress?
I shall explain through the
hypothesis of the stolen painting.
The collector, visibly exhausted,
now invites us to consider
the Tonnerres
from a fresh standpoint.
What you have seen
are merely some of the ideas
these paintings have inspired in me
over the years.
Hence, perhaps,
their fragmentary nature.
But today...
now that I have once again
recreated The Ceremony for you,
a doubt assails me.
And I ask myself
if the effort was worthwhile.
I have, I confess, many doubts.
The enigma has been solved,
certainly,
and that should satisfy us.
But we are not satisfied.
What matters to us,
we humble mortals,
that the authorities should fear
the celebration of a cult
because this cult is the expression
of something more vast?
What matters to us,
we humble creatures of this world,
if this "something more vast"
be a revival
of the cult of Mithras?
Can we summon interest in the fact
that a cult like this
is, in effect, the equivalent
of military discipline?
And that military manoeuvres,
pomp and parades
are merely
one aspect of the ceremony
these paintings complete.
Can we feel fear
at the revelation that military life
and all that these paintings
represent
are the ceremony
whose solemn expression
signifies the mutual annihilation
of the celebrants...
total war?
No, I do not think so.
I do not think so.
Any such elucidation
would take too long for us to grasp.
Furthermore,
the cunning stratagem whereby
it is divided
in three superimposed riddles
would hardly speed us
towards our goal.
And yet,
I know that something
will be retained.
I know
that at this very moment
the paintings are beginning
to fade from memory.
I know that the snare
set by the painter Tonnerre
is beginning to show results.
The gestures,
the same gestures repeated
from painting to painting
loom up,
in isolation,
to better efface
the paintings themselves
and what they represent.
So,
let us forget.
Let us allow
the paintings to fade...
to vanish...
so that all that remains
is the isolated gestures,
the gestures of The Ceremony.
So saying,
the collector
courteously shows us to the door.
Subtitling: B.B. COM - Paris