Katya, darling.
Don't, you mustn't.
It was all such a long
time ago, Georgia.
Not for me, Katya. Not for me.
It's the blood of my
daughter on that blade.
I cling to my hatred as
I cling to this dagger.
Before I die, I swear...
...I'll see this dagger
plunged into his throat.
As I saw it in Tanya's because of him.
Crying won't help now.
Go...
He's back. Kurt is back.
Georgia!
Yes, Kurt is back.
You can't stop the hand of fate.
Milord, Milord, Kurt is back!
What did you say?
Kurt is back.
Yes, Losat, I'm back.
I told you never to come back.
Who are you trying to frighten, Kurt?
No one.
I came back because
I heard of your marriage.
Good luck.
My compliments, Nevenka.
Thank you, Kurt.
Tell the truth, Kurt.
What do you want?
Brother, I came back to compliment
you on your choice of a wife.
You must be tired, Kurt.
Kurt, you're not my son.
You're a serpent.
You like to make others suffer.
You seduced Tanya, and
then abandoned her,
...causing her to kill herself.
The same old story.
Father, you promised.
He didn't come back to
seek my forgiveness.
You're so wrong, father.
I also came back for that.
No, I don't believe you.
Are you afraid of me, Christian?
That which was once mine is now yours.
Now, it is you who are
the favorite son.
I've never been afraid of you.
As far as I'm concerned,
you can stay if you want to.
All right, Kurt, you can stay.
I've never had a warmer welcome.
It's wonderful to see things being born,
...to see them born and to see them die.
Let me go.
My pretty little cousin.
You're still in love with my brother.
You wouldn't exactly
refuse him if he -
You miserable wretch.
You always wanted to marry him.
Didn't you, Katya?
And instead?
You should hate me, you know?
After all, Christian's marriage
was bitter for you too.
Poisoned?
No, that's not the way
it'll be, Kurt Menliff.
You'll die the same way
you made my daughter die.
I obtained forgiveness
from the masters.
I would not presume
to that of the servants.
Ah, here are the masters.
I see you've already
had your tea, Kurt.
Yes, I'm not in the habit of waiting.
Nobody asked you to.
You did well to remind me.
You shouldn't treat him like that.
You'll only make things worse.
You don't know him well,
...if you think he could be worse.
It is I, Father.
There was a time when
you weren't so afraid...
...when I came to say goodnight.
Remember?
You showed me the way.
I've never forgotten it.
What do you want?
I have your forgiveness,
...but I must have my
rights restored to me,
...my title and patrimony.
I shall soon be dead.
I have not enough time
to put you to the test.
Whatever was yours, you forfeited.
Forever!
You did it yourself
with your infamy.
Be careful, father.
Get out of here!
Get out, I tell you.
I think you've got
something against me.
Isn't that true?
You're wrong. I've nothing
for or against you.
Are you afraid of me?
You were fond of me once.
Yes, once.
You haven't changed, I see.
You always loved violence.
You two, search the grounds.
Where is Nevenka?
And how should I know?
And that whip?
This?
I found it on the road a few
yards outside the gate.
I've been looking at my estates.
It'll soon be night.
It'll be harder to find her.
She's right. You'd better hurry.
Let's go.
They make quite a couple.
I have the impression that...
...Katya isn't so
eager to find Nevenka.
You don't agree?
You're a foolish old woman, Georgia.
Let's light a lantern. I want
to have a look in the moats.
Kurt...
Milady, Milady!
Georgia! Georgia!
I found her.
Milady!
God be praised.
I thought she was dead.
Let's take her home.
Come, help me carry her.
She'll come around very soon now.
It must have been fear
more than anything else.
She must have been
thrown from the saddle.
Kurt!?
Where is Kurt?
- Go call him.
- Yes, sir.
Losat!
What's wrong with her?
Oh, nothing serious.
Only some welts on her back.
As though -
...as though somebody
had whipped her, Milord.
- Go, go on!
- Yes, sir.
Mister Kurt?
Kurt!
Father, don't look.
I had to stand the sight of him alive.
It - it can't be any worse now.
Look. Look. The dagger.
The dagger.
It's Tanya's.
He's died the same death she did.
Tanya. Tanya. Rest now in peace.
God.
Dear God.
Thank you.
Have mercy on me, oh, God,
according to thy great mercy.
Block out mine iniquities.
Wash me from mine iniquities
and cleanse me from my sins,
...for I acknowledge mine iniquity
and my sin is always before me.
Against Thee only have I sinned
and done evil before Thee.
For behold, I was conceived in iniquities
and in sins that my mother conceived me.
Turn away Thy face from my sins.
Cast me not away from Thy face,
...and take not Thy Holy Spirit from me.
Eternal rest,
grant unto him, oh, Lord.
Absolve the souls of the faithful
departed from every bond of sin,
...and by the help of Thy
grace, may they be enabled...
...to escape the avenging judgement.
Oh, God, by whose mercy the souls
of the faithful find rest,
...bless this grave. Release the
souls of all those buried here,
...that they may rejoice with Thy saints
forever through Christ our Lord, Amen.
Now, our son, Kurt Menliff, is
ready for the last judgment.
May one day,
who killed him,
...also be directed by God.
Let us pray for him.
In the name of the Father, and of the
Son, and of the Holy Ghost, Amen.
Who is it?
It is I, Christian.
What do you want?
I want to speak to you, father.
I'm listening, son.
I wanted to speak to you about Kurt.
I must know.
It is hard for me to ask
this, but I've got to know.
What?
Everybody was away.
There was only you in the castle.
You and Kurt.
You - you dare ask if I -
I've always obeyed you,
father, as you well know.
I have never dared to question you.
Get out!
Out of obedience, I
married the woman you had...
...once intended for my brother.
But now I must know.
What do you want to know?
If it was you who killed
him, it's an act of justice.
Get out.
Thank you, Georgia.
What's wrong? Tell me.
I saw Losat.
He said he saw a shadow moving
in the chapel and a light.
Losat is crazier than you.
It was obviously only the
reflection of the moon.
Kurt!
Nevenka!
Kurt.
Nevenka, what's the matter?
It was Kurt. He was watching me.
I saw him.
It's all over, try to rest!
It was only an hallucination.
If you want,
I can stay with you tonight.
You must not be afraid.
No, go to bed.
I want to be alone.
All right, dear.
I'll leave my door open.
Call me if you need anything.
Kurt...
No! No! No! No! No!
No! No!
No!
Nevenka. What's wrong?
Tell me. What happened?
Kurt was here, alive.
And his boots were covered in mud, as
though he had climbed out of the grave.
Calm down, please,
you've had a nightmare.
There's no one here but me.
Look!
Does this look like a nightmare?
He was the one who did this to me.
And besides, there are the footprints.
What footprints?
They were there.
Nevenka, it was only a bad dream.
There's nothing there. Look for yourself.
No, no, it wasn't a dream.
He was here, I tell you, he was here.
I saw the footprints and his hand.
Oh, my God, his hand.
It came out of the
shadows like a spider.
Oh, help me, Christian, help me.
Are you afraid?
You once liked me a lot.
You always loved violence.
You haven't changed
and you never will.
Milady, it's you!
I heard noises and I
came down to look.
- I thought...
- What did you think?
Nothing. The dead can't
move from their tombs.
Maybe they do, if they don't find peace..
Yes, we were happy then.
Now, my life is empty and meaningless.
Do you remember that lake we used to
go to, that one up in the mountains?
You used to said with me in my boat.
You were just a little girl then.
Yes, I used to follow you everywhere.
Christian, why did you do that?
Katya, listen.
We can still be happy.
No, it's too late now.
It's too late.
No, no, dear, don't say that.
It's never too late.
I've always loved you.
And you love me, don't you?
Yes, Christian, I love you
and I'll always love you,
...but you're married now.
No...
No, don't - don't touch me.
Call him. Call him and tell
him you've always been mine.
No, I don't want you.
I don't want you.
I've come back for you,
...and to get my revenge on
all those who hate me.
You'd better leave, Georgia.
Besides, there's nothing you can do now.
Just like Kurt.
The dagger has disappeared.
The count told me that -
that it was here.
It's his revenge.
He'll kill us all because
we're all to blame.
Stop talking nonsense, Nevenka.
Are you trying to drive us crazy?
Someone will pay for this,
father, be it man or ghost,
...I promise you.
Christian,
...I've been looking for you.
What for?
I don't know.
I thought perhaps if I was
near I could help you.
No, dear,
...the only thing that will help me
now is to be able to get revenge.
Leave me alone now, please.
In a while, I'll come back to you.
Ah, it's me, Losat.
I didn't mean to frighten you, miss.
I've been watching Christian.
I'm worried about him.
Listen, I've been wanting to ask
you something for some time.
What?
The night when we were searching
the moats for Nevenka.
Yes...?
Did you stay all the
time with Christian?
Yes, I think so. Why?
Are you sure that he never
left you, never for a moment?
No. But, why do you ask?
You don't think
that Christian -
Why, I don't think anything.
That's absurd.
Why the old count too? Why?
Georgia. You're the one who's
got the dagger in your hand.
You can tell me everything, Katya.
I don't pretend to condemn you.
Oh, stop it.
Where did you get that dagger?
You know very well, Katya,
don't force me to say it.
Oh, stop it, please. You had a
reason to kill Kurt, not I.
Tell me where you found that knife.
Under the mattress of your bed, Katya.
No!
Christian!
Christian, I know who
killed your father.
What?
Yes. I could have killed Kurt.
Oh, you bet I could.
But, the count, no.
I'd never kill him, you understand?
If you found that knife there,
...then you or somebody
else put it there.
It wasn't I, Katya, not I.
Throw away that cursed knife.
I don't want to ever see it again.
Throw it away.
No, Katya, no. It's not possible.
You don't believe me.
You think I'm lying. Answer me.
I don't know. I don't know.
I can't possibly imagine that
one of us is a murderer.
No, it's absurd.
But, still, somebody here killed him.
But, now we know, Christian.
No, not Katya.
You're a coward.
You're afraid to face the truth.
- Kurt in your place -
- Kurt!
Kurt...
It's always him,
...Kurt instead of me.
He's the one you've always loved.
That's not true. That's not true.
And you've always wanted to marry him.
I've always known it.
If that's why you killed him,
it was a useless crime.
I hated him. I hated him.
I've always hated him.
I hated him.
Nevenka!
I heard screaming.
I thought it came from
your father's room.
She's not here.
Let's look in her room.
The footprints lead toward the garden.
Someone carried her off.
You'd better wait here.
Christian, don't go alone.
Katya, come inside, Katya.
Please, come inside.
Losat!
What are you doing here?
Oh, it's you, Milord.
- Where have you taken Nevenka?
- Me?
There were prints from
boots just like yours.
I don't know anything!
I was making my rounds at the castle...
...when I thought that I
saw somebody in here.
- Don't lie to me, Losat.
- Oh, no!
There was no one else in here but you.
- Milord, you don't think that -
- Quiet. Come along.
The footprints lead out
of the secret passage.
Help me.
But, who could have put her in there?
Nevenka, Nevenka!
Kurt!
How is Nevenka?
Delirious.
She said it was Kurt
who carried her there.
She also said that he whipped her.
Then he carried her to the crypt
and put her in the tomb.
We've got to help, Katya, do something.
This time I even heard Kurt's laugh.
But, I still can't bring
myself to believe in ghosts.
I know it's difficult to understand,
...but what do we know about
what happens after death?
I almost believe he's alive.
Alive?
But you saw him too. You saw him
when he was placed in the casket.
With our own eyes,
we both saw him buried.
I don't really believe that
Nevenka saw him out there?
No, no, there's no other
possible explanation.
Kurt is still alive and
hiding in the castle.
I have got to find him.
I've got to find him. I'll go crazy.
For a moment, I've suspected you...
I've suspected myself.
Then, if what you say is true,
...he could have hidden
the dagger in my room.
I'm afraid, Christian.
I'm afraid!
- Katya!
- Oh, Christian, there was someone here.
Calm down, Katya,
it's all right.
I'll go and look.
There are the footprints.
They're the same.
What are you going to do?
Open the coffin.
Help me.
Carry it over there.
Nevenka.
They're opening my tomb.
This is the last time
I can be with you.
Why do you torture me?
Because you belong to me.
Only to me.
What do you want?
We've got to go away from
here forever, right now.
I can't do that!
Yes, you will. Because, you love me.
And your love for me is greater
than anything in this world.
I hate you.
I hate you. I hate you.
It's unrecognizable.
It could be anybody.
The clothes are Kurt's.
Let's put it back in the tomb,
for God's sake.
No.
What are you doing now?
I'm going to destroy it.
Where are you, Kurt?
I'm coming, Kurt.
I've never been afraid of you.
Nevenka?!
My lord. Oh, sir, what happened?
Are you hurt?
Come on. It's not important.
Hurry!
It's locked from the inside.
We'll have to go by way of the chapel.
Yes, you're right.
Why? Why did I do it, Kurt? Why?
I love you, Kurt.
Only you!
You were right.
I love you, Kurt!
Only you.
But, there's an end
to everything, Kurt.
No, no, Nevenka, no.
Nevenka!
Forgive me.
I - had to do what -
what Kurt told me.
I killed him again,
...this time for good.
He hated you. I love you. Christian.
So, she was the one. She killed
your brother and your father.
Yes. Perhaps she was possessed.
She was convinced Kurt was alive.
She killed herself thinking
she was killing him.
Let's hope she's free of him forever.