Gelsomina!
Mother says
to come home right away.
There's a man here.
He came on a big motorcycle.
He says Rosa is dead.
Gelsomina, you remember Zampanò
who took Rosa away with him?
My poor daughter.
I'll never even see
where they buried her.
She's dead, poor thing.
She was so beautiful, so good.
She could do everything.
Zampanò,
see how much my daughter
Gelsomina looks like her?
We're so poor.
I told you, she's not like Rosa.
But she's a good girl, poor thing.
She'll do what she's told.
She just came out a little strange.
But if she eats every day,
maybe she'll get better.
You want to go with Zampanò
and take Rosa's place?
He'll teach you a trade.
You'll earn some money.
And one less mouth to feed
around here wouldn't be bad.
Zampanò's a good man.
He'll treat you well.
You'll travel the world.
You'll sing and dance.
And look what he gave me:
10,000 lire.
I have it here.
We can fix the roof,
and these poor things can eat.
Why did your father
ever leave us?
You're all grown up,
but you've never worked.
It's not your fault
you're not like the other girls.
Won't you help your mother?
He'll teach you.
Isn't that right, Zampanò?
Of course.
I can even teach dogs.
Hey, kids...
go get two pounds of salami,
a pound of cheese,
and two bottles of wine.
That's just the way I am.
Thank you. Go on, kids.
Where are you going?
Come back here.
Why do you act like that?
I'm gonna work and learn a trade
and send money home.
I'm gonna be an artist too.
I'll dance and sing like Rosa.
When will you come back?
When will I come back?
Don't go, my daughter!
I said we'd be back soon.
Time to go!
Your shawl!
Jump in.
My daughter!
My poor daughter!
This chain is a quarter-inch thick,
made of solid iron
and stronger than steel.
By simply expanding my pectorals,
or chest muscles,
I'll bust the hook in two.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
To do this, I must fill my lungs
with air like a tire.
A vein might burst
and make me spit blood.
Once, in Milan,
a 260-pound man
lost his eyesight doing this.
The optic nerve
has to do all the work,
and when you've lost your eyesight,
it's all over.
Any sensitive members of the audience
may want to look away.
There may be blood.
Thank you.
You've never made soup before,
have you?
It's pig's swill.
There's enough clothes here
for 10 people.
Shoes, dresses and everything.
Come here. There should be
something here to fit you.
I want you to look elegant.
I don't want to see you in rags.
My women have always
looked smart.
Here.
Try saying, "Here he is: Zampanò."
Here he is: Zampanò.
Come here.
This is a trumpet.
Do only what I tell you to.
This is a drum.
Here he is: Zampanò!
Zampanò is here.
Try again.
Come here.
Stand right there.
Go on.
Zampanò is here.
Say it like this:
Here he is: Zampanò!
Go on.
Quiet flame, bright flame,
quiet flame, night cries.
What are you doing?
It's gonna rain day after tomorrow.
How do you know?
It's gonna rain.
Come here.
Get in.
I'll sleep out here.
Oh, yeah?
Listen...
what's your name?
Di Costanzo, Gelsomina.
Come on, Gelsomina.
Get in.
Tomorrow...
Get in!
Thank you.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for the first time in this city,
we present a farce
bound to make you laugh!
Anybody with a weak heart
better not watch.
You might die laughing.
And since we work
to fill our stomachs,
my wife will pass
the hat around afterwards.
Come on. Quick.
Good morning, Miss Gelsomina.
Excuse me for asking,
but are you afraid of my "trifle"?
I said, excuse me for asking,
No need to be scared.
Let's go "shunting" with my"trifle."
It's not "trifle."
It's rifle, dummy!
Where would these ducks be?
Well, if there aren't any ducks,
you be the duck
and I'll be the "shunter."
That's a jackass, not a duck!
Thank you.
And now my wife will pass the hat.
Thank you to those
who can give something,
and to those who can't,
thanks anyway.
Evening, everyone.
Hey, close the door.
Hi, Zampanò.
Hey, Gypsy, how's it going?
Zampanò, how are you?
This is my wife.
You mean another one
of your girlfriends.
Pleasure to meet you.
Have a seat.
No, we'll sit over here.
Waiter.
- I'll get him.
- No, you sit still.
Waiter!
Coming. I heard you.
We want to eat.
We've got lamb and veal.
What do you want?
- That one.
- Which? Lamb or veal?
Both.
Fine. Both.
I'll have the lamb with spaghetti.
And a liter of red wine.
- Okay.
Where are you from?
My hometown.
You don't talk like us.
Where were you born?
My father's house.
Waiter!
Get us more wine.
Wool? This ain't no wool!
I could stick my toes through it.
Hey, Red!
Come here.
- You talking to me?
- Yeah. Come here.
Good evening.
- What are you up to?
- Nothing.
Then sit down.
- Want something to drink?
- Yes, thank you.
- Where's that wine?
- I don't like this place at all.
Have a cigarette.
I think I've seen you before.
It's possible. I get around.
- Here's the wine.
- Have you already eaten?
Yes.
Where have I seen you?
What line of work are you in?
- I'm a traveling artist.
This is my sidekick.
I taught her everything.
When I took her on,
she couldn't even quack.
Feel that.
What a macho man!
Look here.
I earned all this
in one hour, with these.
May I?
She's a sly one.
Let's get out of here.
It smells.
Let's go see the fireworks.
Waiter, two more bottles of wine.
How much do I owe?
- 120, I think.
- Hey there.
- Good evening.
- How's business?
- So-so.
Put the wine inside.
Hey, Red, where are you going?
Get in.
- Is this piece of junk your car?
- Don't you like it?
- Are you crazy?
It's American.
Hasn't broken down once
in seven years.
My God! What are you doing?
Feel that motor?
- Shall I get in back?
- You wait here.
Where are you going?
You're still here?
Why didn't you eat your soup?
Why didn't she eat the soup?
- I don't know. She just wouldn't eat.
Shut up about your old soup.
I'll kick your old soup!
See how she is?
You try to help and...
Tell me: Does your husband
have the motorcycle with the wagon?
The one that was
in the piazza yesterday?
I'll bet you that's him.
Over by the gardens there's a man
with a motorcycle and wagon.
- Where?
- That way, beyond the houses.
A dog died in there.
You woke up?
I planted some tomatoes.
Tomatoes?
I found some seeds, the big kind,
so I planted them.
Come on. Move it.
We're leaving?
Why? Want to wait around
for your tomatoes to grow?
Push.
Were you like this with Rosa, too?
What?
With Rosa.
What the hell are you saying?
Why did you go with that woman?
Were you like this with Rosa, too?
Knock it off!
What do you want?
You're one of those men
who runs around with women.
What?
Who runs around with women.
If you want to stay with me,
you've got to learn one thing-
to keep your mouth shut!
Tomatoes.
What have you got
in your head, anyway?
Here.
Wine! Sweet honeydew,
pleasure of Don Matthew!
Long life to the bride,
fresh as a rose!
It was all because of a dance!
A kiss!
We want to see a kiss!
She's calling us.
- Why don't you come and eat?
- We'll be right there.
Come and sit.
- Teresa, come sit down.
- I don't have time.
Come.
Follow me.
- I have to eat.
- You can eat afterwards.
Where are you taking me?
To see Oswald.
This way.
Don't pull on me.
I'll slap you.
Oswald, look who's here.
Poor thing. Who is he?
My cousin Oswald. He's sick.
He stays in here.
They never let anyone see him.
Make him laugh.
- How?
- Do what you were doing before.
Little birdie.
Scoundrels! That's what you are!
You'll get a thrashing tonight!
Out of here right now!
Who let you in?
Get out of here!
You always eat standing up
like a horse?
I always eat on my feet.
Who's going to keep
the house going if not me?
I had two husbands, but both died.
For three nights I've been up
at 1:00 a.m. to cook.
Think I'm tired? If I felt like it,
I could dance all night long.
Us older women
are better than young girls.
- Why don't you remarry?
- What? Another husband?
I'm the only one
who gives orders around here.
Is that all a husband is good for?
Giving orders?
Think I'm not made
of flesh and blood?
Everybody likes sweets
after a good meal.
What are you looking at?
Get out of here!
My first husband
was big and tall like you.
I've still got all his clothes.
They don't fit anyone.
Upstairs-
I'll get you something too.
There's a little boy
with a head like this.
Here. Eat.
The wine's all gone.
Help me bring out some more.
Listen, you really don't have
any use for those clothes?
Who else is gonna wear them?
There aren't many men built like you.
Is there a hat too?
I could really use a hat.
Sure. Come on in.
See for yourself.
Do you remember
how beautiful it was, Zampanò?
Watching the rain
from the window that day?
Why don't you teach me
to play the trumpet?
I'll learn quickly.
Did you teach Rosa?
Did she do my job?
How do I look?
Women.
Can't even smoke in here.
What the hell is the matter?
Nothing.
Then why are you crying?
Because-
Climb up out of there.
Come on, get out of there.
Gonna stay there all night?
- Yes, all night!
I'm leaving.
I'm going back home.
I'm sick and tired.
It's not on account of the work,
'cause I like the work.
I like being an artist.
It's you I don't like.
What's the matter?
I'm leaving.
I'm going home!
Knock it off, you idiot.
I'm leaving the shoes and the coat!
Everything!
I do everything for him,
and what does he do for me?
Nothing!
I'm leaving!
And now the Fool will perform
his most dangerous stunt yet.
He will eat a plate of spaghetti while
suspended 125 feet above the ground.
We ask you to keep very quiet
during this feat,
for the slightest distraction
could prove fatal.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present the Fool,
the only man in the world
to perform this feat.
Is it nice up there?
Yes, but a bit cold.
To tell the truth,
it's given me quite an appetite.
Darned wind!
It blew my napkin away.
What? You're not even going
to ask us to join you?
There's plenty of room.
If anyone wants to come up,
they're welcome.
Thank you.
Let me through.
Anna, I'll see you at the restaurant.
All right.
Out of the way.
Will you let me through?
Get out of the way.
Attention!
One, two...
- She's crazy!
Leave her alone.
- I'm going now.
- Bye, Mario.
You want a drink?
No more drink for me.
Get in.
I don't want to go with you again!
I don't want to!
Never again!
I said get in!
Take this!
Come here.
Now walk!
Get in there!
And shut up!
You got something to say?
I thought so.
Good morning.
Hey, come here.
Come on. Move it.
Come on up.
Make yourself comfortable.
Say hi to the boss lady.
Mr. Giraffa.
I've taught her everything.
Cup of coffee?
Go on. Take it.
When I got her,
she didn't even have shoes.
She's not like us.
We've seen the world.
Nasty wind!
Nazareno, careful
the tent doesn't blow away.
I'm warning you,
I don't pay nobody nothing.
You work for tips like the others.
They pass the hat,
and they're happy with that, right?
That's fine.
Have we ever disagreed before?
Then you can start tonight.
You have the girl to pass
the hat around, so it's settled.
- Where are we?
- In Rome. That's St. Paul's.
So we're joining the circus?
- Seems like a good tent.
- Come on in.
How many people does it hold?
There are seats for 400,
and standing room too.
You know him?
Look who's here! It's Trifle.
You did a good thing taking him on.
A circus needs animals.
Just kidding.
You know I'm always kidding.
Want a cig?
Oh, you've got one.
I have to admit,
he's a great artist.
And what a repertoire!
You should do the number with the chain.
You haven't done that one in ages.
Let me give you some advice.
Don't speak to me.
Otherwise you'll be sorry.
I was just joking.
You heard me.
He's really good.
Go, Trifle!
Big man.
Don't worry.
It's sure to be a disaster.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
the Giraffa Circus
presents a new attraction.
Zampanò, the man
with lungs of steel.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this here chain
is a quarter-inch thick,
made of solid iron
and stronger than steel.
I will wrap the chain around my chest
and fasten it securely with this hook.
By simply expanding
my pectoral muscles-
that is, my chest-
I'll bust the hook.
If anyone thinks the hook
is already sawed in half,
you may look for yourself.
Gelsomina, please.
This piece of cloth
is not for my protection...
but to spare you the sight of blood
in case the hook tears my flesh.
I'm not saying it takes
a team of oxen.
You're not all geniuses, I'm sure,
but any reasonable person can see
that it takes three things:
good lungs,
ribs of steel,
and superhuman strength.
Get out of there.
Any sensitive members of the audience
are advised to look away.
The drum will sound three times.
Gelsomina, please begin.
Zampanò, excuse me.
Telephone call for you.
Bastard!
Quick, it's your turn!
Calm down.
I'll talk to that rascal.
Where is he? I'll kill him.
I'll kill him!
Where are you?
- Is he hiding in there?
- I haven't seem him.
Where are you, you coward?
When I'm done with you,
you won't feel like laughing.
Coward.
What has he got against you?
How should I know?
Did you do something to him?
I never did a thing to him.
He's the one who makes fun of me.
One of these days he'll pay for it.
But who is he?
The bastard son of a gypsy,
that's who he is.
- Have you known him long?
- Too long.
Did Rosa know him too?
Listen, he doesn't know a thing
about either Rosa or me.
I don't walk
to talk about it anymore.
Let's go to bed.
There she is.
Look how she walks!
What did I tell you?
The very face we need.
Take this.
Come on.
Put that thing down,
for Pete's sake.
I always did this number when
I had a girl, and it always went over.
Gelsomina, work with us.
Scram!
Here we go.
Give it a good blow.
Magnificent! Did you know
you're very talented?
Now pay attention.
I'll play the violin,
and when you hear me go like this...
you come creeping up
behind me ever so quietly
and blow the trumpet
exactly like you just did.
Got it? Let's give it a try.
- I can't.
- Why not?
- Zampanò says no.
Hear that?
And you say it's my fault!
Where is Zampanò?
Go get him and I'll talk to him.
- He went into the city.
- Fine. I'll talk to him later.
Don't be afraid.
He won't eat you.
We're all one big family
and we all work together.
The more the merrier.
Remember,
when I get to this point...
Understand?
You sure?
Okay, here goes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I will now play for you
a very sad song.
Go on, blow.
Too late, silly girl!
Very nice.
I see Zampanò's company
has made you a genius.
Don't wait for me to finish.
You have to interrupt me!
And I told you to blow it
over here, silly girl!
Let's try it again.
See? That was great!
Now, we do that three times.
Then I walk around the ring, and you
follow playing behind me. Got it?
Let me show you something.
Put one finger here
and the other over here.
Then you just blow.
Try it.
Now follow me. One, two...
What's the matter, Zampanò?
She's working. I asked her to.
She only works with me.
Sorry, but I don't understand.
I'd have asked you earlier,
but you were in the city.
What's wrong?
We all work together here.
She doesn't work with him!
You'd better knock it off!
I'm not speaking to you.
You told me not to, remember?
Gelsomina, go see my wife.
Let me talk to him.
Stay! I tell her what to do!
If I tell you not to work
with that bum,
then you don't work with him.
Because that's how I want it!
If I catch you again-
Zampanò, leave the Fool alone!
Stop them!
They'll kill each other!
Hurry up! He's a beast!
Damn these gypsy vagabonds!
He's got a knife!
Don't worry.
They'll keep them apart.
Be careful!
He's got a knife!
I'll kill the first person
who comes near me.
Open this door!
Come out here!
Get back!
What's going on here?
- Nothing.
Hey, you!
Drop that knife!
My circus has never been involved
in a scandal like this before!
The police never carried
anyone off in handcuffs before!
It's his fault.
I've never had
problems with the law!
Where will you go now?
Don't worry. When he gets out,
he'll come looking for you.
You should forget about him.
You're better off without
the likes of him.
What will you do on your own?
Where will your next meal come from?
The motorcycle...
We'll leave it with the police.
Come with us, Gelsomina.
- But where would I sleep?
- With me. Come see.
There's enough room
for two in my wagon.
Stop yakking!
We still have to take
everything down.
The truck's coming at 4:00.
You do as you like.
You want to come, come!
You want to wait for him,
then wait!
But he'll never work with us again!
Neither one of them!
Let the tent down!
Were you sleeping?
It smells like a pigsty in here.
How can you stand it?
Zampanò is still in jail.
Maybe they'll let him out tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Yeah, maybe.
It was your fault.
Zampanò never did anything to you.
So why did they let you out?
Maybe from one point of view
it was my fault,
but he had the knife.
Come on out for a bit.
Come down.
It'll do him good
to spend some time in jail.
He's got so many years ahead of him.
I'm the one who's gonna die young.
What a nice breeze tonight.
Let's sit here for a while.
What a lovely robe.
Sit down.
What a funny face you have.
Are you sure you're a woman?
You look more like an artichoke.
I don't know
if I'll stay with Zampanò.
They've asked me to go with them.
Then it's a good opportunity
to get rid of him.
Imagine his face tomorrow
when he gets out
and finds everyone gone!
You should do it!
What an animal.
I've got nothing against him,
but I can't help teasing him
whenever I see him.
I don't know why.
I swear I don't know.
An urge just comes over me.
But how did you end up with him?
He gave my mother 10,000 lire.
That much?
I have four younger sisters.
Do you like him?
- Me?
- Yes, you.
You could have gotten away.
I tried.
Nothing.
You can be really exasperating!
What do you mean, nothing?
If you don't want to stay with him,
then go with the others.
Makes no difference
whether I go with them
or stay with Zampanò.
How would going with them
change anything?
I'm of no use to anybody,
and I'm sick of living.
Can you cook?
I said, can you cook?
Then what can you do?
Dance? Sing?
A little.
Maybe...
you like to make love.
Then what do you like?
You really are an ugly one.
Why was I born?
What if I asked you
to come with me?
I'll teach you to walk the tightrope,
way up in the air,
with all the lights on you.
I have a car.
We'd be traveling all the time.
We'd have a world of fun.
Would you like that?
But no. "Nothing."
You have to stay with Zampanò
and perform his ridiculous stunts,
and let him beat you like a donkey.
Such is life.
But you know,
Zampanò wouldn't keep you
if you weren't worth something to him.
What did he do
that time you escaped?
He really slapped me around.
Why didn't he let you go?
I don't understand.
I wouldn't keep you a single day.
Maybe...
Maybe he likes you.
Zampanò... likes me?
Why not?
He's like a dog.
Ever seen those dogs
who look like they want to speak
but all they do is bark?
Poor guy.
Yeah. Poor guy.
But...
if you don't stay with him,
who will?
I'm an ignorant man,
but I've read a book or two.
You may not believe it,
but everything
in this world has a purpose.
Even this pebble.
Which one?
This one. Any one.
But even this one has a purpose.
- What's its purpose?
- Its purpose is-
How should I know?
If I knew, I'd be-
- Who?
- The Almighty, who knows everything.
When you're born.
When you die.
Who knows?
No, I don't know
what this pebble's purpose is.
but it must have one,
because if this pebble has no purpose,
then everything is pointless.
Even the stars.
At least, I think so.
And you too.
You have a purpose too,
with that artichoke head of yours.
One of these days, I'll take a match
and set fire to everything.
Mattresses, blankets-everything.
That'll show him.
I never refused to go with him.
He paid 10,000 lire.
I do my work and he hits me.
That's not right.
He doesn't think.
I tell him, and what does he do?
What good does it do?
I'll put poison in his soup too.
I'll set fire to it all!
If I don't stay with him, who will?
So they want you to join them?
Wake up.
I asked you if they want you
to join them.
Did they say anything about me?
They said they don't want
either you or Zampanò.
Big deal.
Who wants to stay anyway?
Where I'm going,
I'll make gobs of money.
They need me.
I don't need anybody.
I'm here today,
who knows where tomorrow.
The less time in one place,
the better,
because people get
on my nerves very quickly.
I take off on my own.
That's just the way I am.
No house, no roof.
Why did you say you'd die soon?
It just stands to reason.
Goes with the job.
I'll break my neck,
and no one will remember me.
What about your mama?
So what are you going to do?
Wait for him or join them?
Go on, get in.
We'll take the motorcycle
to the police station
so he'll find you there
when they let him out.
Does this old dinosaur actually work?
What a piece of junk!
Come on, get out.
There's the jail.
I'll be leaving now.
You're going?
Yes.
But seriously,
you'd really like to come with me?
Silly, I told you I've no intention
of taking along a girl.
I really don't need one.
That's just...
a souvenir.
Good-bye, Gelsomina!
Here I am.
They asked me to go with them,
but I -
You could have gone.
Which way is my home?
That way.
Once all I thought about
was going home,
but I don't care so much anymore.
Now I feel like my home is with you.
Oh, yeah?
What a discovery.
And with all that poverty
at your house to tempt you.
You're an animal!
You don't think!
There wasn't much to eat, huh?
There was plenty!
There's going to be a storm.
What's the nearest town?
Magliano, 13 miles from here.
But you have to cross the mountains.
We'd never make it.
Not enough gas.
Our convent is over there.
Wait a moment.
Mother, I found oil.
This man wants to know
if he could stay the night.
Pardon us, Mother,
but we don't have much gas.
It's getting dark,
the town is still a ways off,
and my wife doesn't feel well.
- They could sleep in the barn.
- All right. Just for tonight.
She said you can stay.
You can sleep in the barn.
Thank you very much, Mother.
I found a little more.
It's good.
Wouldn't you like a little more?
Go on. Have some more.
Does she work with you too?
She helps me out a bit.
She plays the drum and the trumpet.
Show the sister
how you play the trumpet.
Beautiful.
You play so well.
That's enough.
Now wash these dishes.
- Let me have those.
- It's not your job.
We'll do it together.
She's so good,
and she plays so well.
What's the name of that song?
- I don't know.
What are you doing there?
Let me do that.
That's no work for you, Sister.
I always do it.
Do you always sleep in there?
There's lots of room.
I've got pots and pans,
just like in a house.
Very nice.
Do you like traveling from one place
to the next all the time?
That's how his work is.
We travel around too.
We change convents every two years.
This is my second.
- Why?
So we don't get too attached
to the things of this world.
You grow fond of where you live,
even of a plant.
You risk forgetting your most
important attachment, which is to God.
So you see, we both travel.
You follow your husband,
and I follow mine.
Each her own.
Would you like to see the convent?
I'll show it to you.
It's ancient.
Over a thousand years old.
Why do you keep me?
I'm not pretty. I can't cook.
I can't do anything.
What the heck do you want?
Go to bed.
What a potato head you are.
It's raining.
It's nice here.
Would you be sorry if I died?
Why? Planning on dying?
Once I really wanted to die
"rather than stay with him,"
I told myself.
Now, I'd even be willing
to marry you,
since we're going to stay together.
If even a pebble has a purpose.
You have to think about these things,
but you never think at all.
- There's nothing to think about.
- But there is!
What should I think about?
Tell me.
Enough of this nonsense!
Go to sleep. I'm tired.
Do you like me a little?
Knock it off.
There are silver hearts on the wall,
but my hands are too big.
Come see if you can reach.
What do you mean, no?
How dare you say no to me!
- You shouldn't.
- Shut up!
Have a good trip.
Wait a minute.
What's the matter?
Would you like to stay here?
I'll tell Mother Superior.
Sisters-
Here. Put this away.
Many thanks for your goodwill
and hospitality.
Sincere thanks
from a humble artist.
Push.
Trifle, come to give me a hand?
I'll help you someday too.
Drop it!
Zampanò, stop it!
Make fun of me now!
You trying to kill me?
That was a little present from "Trifle."
Next time it'll be worse.
Worse than this?
You broke my watch!
Zampanò, run!
He's hurt!
He's dying.
Come on, get up.
Stop clowning around.
He's dying.
Knock it off!
Hey, you!
Shut up.
Shut up!
Now I'm done for.
I advise sensitive members
of the audience to look away.
The hook may pierce my flesh,
causing blood to spurt out.
The drum will sound three times.
Gelsomina, please.
The drum!
The Fool is hurt.
What's wrong with you?
What's the matter?
No one saw us,
and no one is after us.
They'll never even suspect us.
I'm hungry.
You stay here.
I'll take care of it.
Where are you going?
Where do you think you're going?
Want to go back home?
Eat something.
Enough crying! Stop it!
I can't take it anymore!
It's cold.
I'm coming in to bed.
Don't come in.
Shut up. I'll sleep out here.
It's nice here.
It's cold.
Sit down.
Get some sun.
Let's have some soup.
It's missing something.
Leave it. I'll do it.
It's about time.
You didn't move for ten days.
I didn't mean to kill him.
I just punched him a couple of times.
He wasn't hurt.
I bloodied his nose a bit.
I turn around, he drops dead.
The rest of my life in prison
for a couple of punches?
Just let me work in peace.
Don't I have a right to live?
Thank goodness,
now we can get going.
There's a big fair in this town.
Just a few miles from here.
We'll make some money.
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
The Fool is hurt.
I'll take you home.
Want me to take you home
to your mother?
Don't you want to go home
If I don't stay with you, who will?
I can't go on like this!
I have to make a living!
You're sick up here!
Go inside.
What are you doing?
It's cold. Come on.
Come on.
You killed him.
It's nice here in the sun.
I wanted to run away,
but he told me to stay with you.
We need more wood.
The fire's dying out.
Get out of here, kids.
The show's not till tonight.
Hey, where are you going?
For a walk.
Want me to come with you?
No. I'll be right back.
A small vanilla.
And a little lemon.
Hey, you!
Where did you learn that song?
- What song?
- The one you were just singing.
This one?
A girl who was here
a long time ago used to sing it.
How long ago?
A long time.
Four or five years.
She always played it on the trumpet,
and it stuck in my head.
Where is she now?
She's dead, poor thing.
You're from the circus, right?
She was one of you too.
A vagabond.
No one around here
knew her or anything about her.
She never spoke.
She seemed crazy.
My father found her
one night on the beach.
Poor thing was sick with a fever.
We took her into our home.
But she wouldn't say anything.
All she did was cry.
She wouldn't eat.
When she got a little better,
she sat out in the sun.
She would thank us
and play the trumpet.
Then, one morning,
she just didn't wake up.
The mayor got involved,
wrote letters to find out who she was.
Would you like to go see him?
Now we present Zampanò,
the man with lungs of steel.
After that,
you'll see a humorous skit
that will have you in stitches.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this here is a chain and hook
a quarter-inch thick.
Solid iron, stronger than steel.
By simply expanding
my pectoral muscles-
that is, my chest-
I'll bust the hook.
This piece of cloth
is not for my protection,
but to spare the public
the sight of blood
in case the hook pierces my flesh.
Sensitive members of the audience
should look away.
That's enough now.
It's late. Go home to bed.
Leave me alone!
Stop drinking now.
I'll take you to Amilcare's.
His wine is better.
Put that down.
Stop drinking now.
I know how to walk!
Get your hands off me!
The check.
Throw him in the sea.
He can't even hold his drink.
Leave them alone.
Are you crazy?
I'll show you.
You a big strong man?
Let me go!
Tough guy!
I'll take each one of you on!
Damn drunk!
You're pathetic!
What are you doing?
Kicking a drunk?
Leave me alone!
You want to hit me too?
Don't you recognize me?
I'll leave you to your fate, then.
I don't want no friends.
Go ahead.
Break whatever you want.
Why don't you all come out now?
Come on!
I'll crush you like bugs!
I don't need anybody!
I want to be alone!
Alone...