MARIA CANDELARIA
A love tragedy torn from an
indigenous corner of Mexico.
Xochimilco, 1909.
Do you see?
Painting a portrait is not as
difficult as people imagine.
Master, in what subjects
do you  find inspiration?
I dont paint subjects.
I paint my life.
And what I see.
Mexico.
I heard somewhere, master,
About a picture you
have never wanted to sell.
Could you tell us why?
There are many pictures that
I didn't want to sell.
No, sir.
This one is very special.
It's a nude portrait of a
very beautiful indian woman.
that you painted years ago.
Excuse me, master.
But I'm writing your biography.
I have a fantasy of
writing a great book.
However,
it would be incomplete
if you dont reveal the mystery of
this chapter of your life.
Let's talk another day.
Now I need to
be alone.
Excuse me.
Good afternoon.
See you tomorrow, sir.
With your permission.
Good aftenoon, master.
I beg your pardon, master.
Are you still here?
I already said I don't have
nothing more to add.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Yes, you bothered me,
and you keep bothering me.
Wait.
I don't know why you
journalists believe, that
you have the right to meddle
in other people's lives.
The world likes to know what
the great men did, master.
Besides that,
everyone knows
that this picture exists.
Everyone talks about it,
in Mexico and abroad.
And for my book,
it is essential that
you to talk about it.
Look, miss.
There are things, that you just touch
and they bleed.
Do you understand?
This is one of them.
Many years have passed
since I painted this picture.
I can think about it,
only with horror.
Because it was the cause
of a tragedy.
There are times when life uses us as
instruments of others' misfortune.
You know that us, painters,
we always dream of finding
the materialization of what
we carry within us.
Of course, nearly
nobody finds it.
I had the privilege
of finding it.
And it would have been better
to never have been found.
Come here.
What a beautiful woman!
Who is she?
An Indian woman of pure,
mexican race.
As you can see,
this native has the beauty
of the ancient princesses,
that the conquerors
came to oppress.
She was a daughter
of a prostitute,
who was murdered
by her own people.
Her life has always been tarnished
because of her mother,
like some kind of a curse.
Her people always
kept her isolated.
Like a wild animal.
There is something in this story
so terrible and sweet
at the same time
that I haven't been yet
able to forget.
And it still weighs on me
despite all this time.
She lived nearby.
In Xochimilco.
In a garden surrounded by flowers.
Her name was
Maria Candelária!
What do you want?
Don't thank me
for coming.
My boss sent me.
He can't wait any longer.
He wants you
pay your debt.
He said that I
could pay with flowers.
He said.
But what Mr. Damian
want is his money.
He's spiteful.
You ignored him.
How much do I owe?
Here is the bill.
Butter: 3,20 pesos.
Molasses: 2,18 pesos.
Coffee: 1,20 pesos.
Soap: 6 pesos.
Candles: 2,50 pesos. Total.
Total?
Total: 15,08 pesos.
And the boss told me
to tell you that
you have until
tomorrow to pay.
And if you don't pay,
he will take your sow.
You dont have 15,08 pesos?
With the flowers you sold,
there should be a lot more.
You know that the people of
the city don't let me sell them.
That was before.
But I think they have changed.
After what the
priest has been saying.
Damn it.
All of this because
of your mother.
Well, it's not
that I believe it,
but that's what they say.
It hurts me deeply,
Maria Candelária.
Because I'm a friend
of Lorenzo Rafael.
And I know that he loves you.
You better fight and try
to pay Mr. Damian.
No.
No. He will not take
my little pig.
First I'm going to sell flowers.
Whatever happens.
I have my flowers
to offer
It's the voice of
Maria Candelária?
It's her.
How dare she come and sell flowers?
We will make it stop.
My flowers that
opened at dawn
Maria Candelária!
Go back to
your floating garden.
I told you to go back.
Look for whom
you have left me.
Maria Candelária
will bring you bad luck.
You will be very unhappy.
Because she is not
a good woman.
Like mother, like daughter.
Just remember who
her mother was.
You will pay for it.
Why do you go out
and sell flowers?
Mr. Damian wants me to pay him.
Or he will take the sow.
You aren't angry with
me for what happened?
- Are you?
- Not angry.
But I don't want people
to insult you anymore.
You know, Maria Candelária.
It would be better to get out of here.
To Santa Anita, Iztacalco
or further on.
Where nobody knows us.
Where we can live in peace.
And what about our gardens?
And our flowers?
We were both born here.
And we always lived here.
This is our land.
See how dark it is.
And how soft it is.
How can we leave?
The townspeople don't want you here.
and Mr. Damian doesn't want me.
No, they don't like us.
But out there is worse.
What hurts me most is
that because of me ...
the people of the city
are angry with you, too.
I will never leave you,
Maria Candelária.
How much do you owe to Mr. Damian?
15,08 pesos.
We have to pay it, that
cannot go on like this.
- With the piglet?
- No, not the piglet.
It's all that
we have at the moment.
We will get married
thanks to her.
I'm going to see
Mr. Damian and ask
if we can pay with
my vegetables.
May God hear you.
My vegetables are worth
more than anything we owe him.
My little virgin!
What brings you here?
I deserve Rafael Lorenzo
more than you do.
It's not my fault
you are what you are.
Come on, hurry up.
Good morning, Mr. Damian.
Good morning to you, doctor.
Here is the quinine
for the whole week.
Do people
answer you?
Not many.
But I already told them to
come and get your quinine,
and I myself will convince them
to take it here.
These damned Indians
are like the devil.
And if I don't do it this way,
they throw the medicine away.
Was there more malaria?
Few cases, doctor.
Some kicked the bucket.
It is strange, that it is
the female mosquito who bites
and makes people sick.
Strange? Why?
Women are the
root of all evil.
Oh, doctor.
Well, see you, Mr. Damian.
Make sure all of these bums
take their quinine.
I will give it to them myself.
It's true, women are
the root of all evil.
Go ahead, go ahead.
I'll talk to him,
it may work.
Thank you very much, José Afonso.
Lorenzo Rafael is there,
loaded with vegetables.
He wants to talk to you,
he has problems.
Have a nice day, Mr. Damian.
José Afonso.
Bring some water for the Indians.
I wanted to ask you, boss ...
Ei.
Come and take your quinine.
Line up.
Come on, next.
This starving Indian
has no shame.
After robbing me of the woman I liked
the most, he comes to bother me.
Who does he think he is?
Here.
Did you see mr. Damian?
I'll have to go somewhere else,
far away
to sell my vegetables.
I'll go with you,
I do not want to stay alone.
You are better off alone.
You know, people outside
never had respect for us.
They are abusing you
because you're beautiful.
The problem is that,
only they buy our flowers.
I do not want to be alone.
If you want, I will cover
my face with mud
so that no one looks at me
and we can go together.
Let's go then.
I will get the flowers,
the most beautiful ones.
If God wills,
we'll sell them all.
Flowers of Xochimilco, mister.
How much do you want
for all of them?
All of them?
Yes, all of them.
Well...
Three reals, sir.
Listen.
Do you want some pesos?
I'm a painter and I want
paint your wife.
José Maria, follow these two
and see where they live.
Hurry, they are leaving.
Leave it here, I'll take care of it.
I can't leave
my pots here.
You are so suspicious.
Here. Follow them, go ahead.
Quickly.
This is the model
that I was looking for.
The Virgin will not allow them
to take you away from us.
I will make tortillas.
I'm not hungry.
See you tomorrow.
It's all right.
- Good afternoon, Father.
- Good afternoon, Lorenzo Rafael.
What a miracle that
you came here.
How is
Maria Candelária?
Good, father.
I came to pray to the Virgin
to help us,
so we dont lose the sow.
And so we can get married.
She will help you, Lorenzo
Rafael, she will help you.
But, why would you
lose the pig?
Because...
...we owe
to mr. Damian.
He doesn't want vegetables,
nor flowers.
He wants money.
Well, well.
So, when
will I marry you?
Well, the sow is still young.
We are hoping that she
grows up and has her piglets.
So that we can sell them.
This is a long way off.
Yes, father.
But only then can I buy
a new dress for Maria Candelária,
and have her hand.
Well, say a rosary.
And don't forget tomorrow is a day
of the blessing for the animals.
Tell Maria Candelária
to come to the church with you
and bring the pig so that
she has a big litter,
so you can buy the new dress
for the day I marry you.
The moon is beautiful.
And so big.
It looks like a white poppy.
Where did you go?
To the church.
I was very sad.
You are not anymore?
No.
Father told me
some good things .
He asked me about you.
He wants you to take the sow
tomorrow for the blessing of animals.
He said I could
go with everyone?
Yes, Maria Candelária.
And if he said that,
he must have his reasons.
I think so.
I wanted the priest
to get it out of their heads.
It would be nice to live at peace
with the inhabitants of the city.
To treat them like brothers,
and not like wild animals.
It must be beautiful
to be greeted on the street
and to have friends to talk to.
And they smile at you,
when they see you pass.
You don't want to go for a walk,
like every full moon?
It's all right.
How good there exist full-moon
nights, so we can traverse them.
What would I do without
Lorenzo Rafael?
Do you love me so much,
Yes, you love me very much.
- José Afonso.
- Yes, boss?
- Maria Candelária already paid you?
- Not yet, boss.
With what? If the poor thing
is broke.
She has to pay me,
even if it's with the pig.
Let's go get it
Let us go to bless her
with the father
So that it grows fast and
has many piglets.
and we can get married.
BLESSING OF ANIMALS
Maria Candelária came to
bring us bad luck.
What do you do here? At church.
She came to curse
our animals.
If she comes, the blessing
won't do any good.
- Our animals will die.
- Yes.
Now that the priest is not
here, let's throw her out
What is happening?
And you, get down here.
I'm coming down, father
but her mother was a bad woman.
So she is also stained.
I order you to come down.
Maria Candelária, come here.
I see that my
words are useless.
This is the House of God.
Insulting someone here,
is like spitting into
the holy water,
or stepping on the wings of angels.
You accuse this woman,
but who accuses you?
Because you, all of you,
murdered the mother of
Maria Candelária
accusing her of bringing
shame on this city
with her bad behaviour.
That poor woman did sin.
But remember that
our Lord punishes
and you all have children.
We all knew
this woman's mother.
And her story should
hurt us deeply,
because, despite her faults,
sinner and all, she has already
been judged by God.
Nobody has the right
to offend her daughter,
who has been for years
accepting humiliation in silence.
A mother is a mother.
And I want you all
to respect
Maria Candelária.
Thank you very much, father.
I did not accuse her, sir.
I did not accuse her.
One should never accuse anyone.
Now, let's bless the animals.
Is this the pig?
- Yes, father.
- How cute is this little animal!
Forgive her, Father. It is
scared among so many people.
So, you couldn't pay me.
I am collecting now.
José Afonso, take the sow.
Mr. Damian is a heretic.
He wants to take the sow
after she was blessed.
That woman owes me money,
I came to collect.
We can only pay with
flowers and vegetables,
but he doesn't want to
accept them, father.
How much do they owe?
15,08 pesos.
It should be more for the delay.
But I will leave it at that.
Don't set your foot
here again
when you're
collecting money.
Understood?
Go away.
God willing, as soon as I can,
I'll pay you your money.
So you can sleep in peace.
Don't pay, father.
Cast her out like Jesus
did with street vendors.
You must sew your mouth.
And you children
take the sow and
may God be with you.
Thank you, Father.
This shameless Indian
will pay for it.
What a luck.
You have neither the girl
or the pig, sir.
Just like that man who
wanted an Indian girl.
That in despair
sent her to the devil:
"You talk a lot
but never do anything ".
That's it.
Oh, sir Damian.
That's the secret.
You said you were so powerful,
and what happened?
When would I ever let
a dirty Indian to insult me?
To top it up, she is the
daughter of one... you know.
Let's go.
You are cursed, sir. Damian.
Everybody out!
They say that
the truth is bitter.
But let us not play the fools.
You and I are outraged.
Or not?
I'm a woman,
I will do it my way,
even if it means
killing someone.
Starting with the pig.
So they don't get married.
- What are you looking at, primitive?
- Nothing, boss.
- Give me a rifle.
- Yes, boss.
Follow me.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
My whole body hurts, as if
someone had beaten me up.
- It's nothing, let's go.
- No.
Not you.
You are not well.
I can see it in your eyes.
Get some medicine,
rub on the body.
If you are not
well until tomorrow,
I will bring a shaman
to heal you.
It is OK.
Do not worry about me.
And take care of yourself,
Lorenzo Rafael.
Jesus, Maria, José.
My piggy.
They killed her.
Now we can never get married.
It was Mr. Damian, no one but him.
But since he is the boss,
they can do it.
What happened?
It must be the fever.
I will bring the shaman.
I'm sure it's the fever.
But you know that
I can not go.
If people see me in the city
they will attack me.
Wait until nightfall,
then I will find a way.
She is very sick.
Only you can cure it.
Are you giving her quinine?
No, sir Damian
doesn't want to give us any.
But it is not his.
The government provides it
to be administered to everyone.
Go and ask him
if you don't want Maria Candelária
to die. Go ahead.
Let me see if anyone
saw you come here.
Nobody, thank God.
Go ahead, hurry up.
Bring the quinine.
One more step and
I will kill you.
I'm not here
to argue, sir.
Maria Candelária
is very sick.
This is not true.
Get out of here.
I swear by the Virgin that
I'm not lying, Mr. Damian.
The shaman said that only
quinine can save her.
Here is the pig
to pay you.
Please give me our
part of the quinine.
There's nothing here for you.
José Afonso!
Yes, boss.
Take that bastard out
of here or I'll kill him.
Take him.
Go away, Lorenzo Rafael,
he will kill you.
All right.
Take it, and tell mr. Damian that
Maria Candelária owes him nothing.
- Who is it?
- It me, José Afonso.
Why did you accept the pig?
She must be poisoned,
it did not come with good intentions.
- What should I do with it?
- Bury it.
Dogs can get sick.
Wait.
I will close the store
for a few days.
I'm going to Xochimilco.
Why this shameless Indian
will come back
and take me
by surprise.
All Indians are treacherous.
Yes, boss.
This is her hut.
I told you that Maria Candelária
does not speak to anyone.
Nobody talks to her,
you already know why.
Maria Candelária!
- What happened? Are you sick?
- What do you want?
Go away.
I did not know that
you were sick.
I came because
I want to paint you.
But let's leave that
for another time.
What do you need?
Maria Candelária!
Where are you going?
Maria Candelária, do not run.
Do not run. I did not come
to do you harm.
I just want to talk.
I won't hurt you, creature.
Don't get wet.
You can stay, I'm leaving.
Lorenzo Rafael.
Look how beautiful are
the poppies from my garden.
They look like
small moons.
See how they descend from the sky.
Why are we so poor?
The pig.
No, don't let him take her.
Ela é como se fosse
She's like our family.
Dear God.
Dear God, why?
Why there is no water?
The channels have dried up.
All animals
in the city are dying.
Just like the pig.
Lorenzo Rafael.
The gardens are burning,
and the flames are coming
here. Let's go.
Let's go.
Lorenzo Rafael.
You are everything
I have in the world.
Don't go without me,
Do not leave me alone.
Mother, dear mother.
The pig that Lorenzo Rafael
gave to me on my birthday ...
She was so...
small.
It fit in the palm of the hand.
Look what I brought you,
Maria Candelária.
A dress so I can ask for your hand.
Now you have to be well.
Holy Virgin of Guadalupe.
I offer you my life
in exchange for hers.
It's all I have.
Heal her.
And let my will be yours
I'm the doctor who came to
take care of the patient.
But we cannot afford it.
No problem.
The painter sent me.
When did the fever start?
The chills started
yesterday, doctor.
Are you giving her the quinine?
I just brought it.
She just took a pill.
I am running risking to be seen
and they already brought
another one.
Listen to me, Lorenzo Rafael.
If this man is a medical doctor
and touches Maria Candelária,
I will not be responsible
for her salvation,
and the Virgin will punish you.
Are you a doctor?
Don't insult me.
I am a healer.
With the grace of God I healed
all the sick people in the city.
Oh, yes.
An osteopath.
Do not call me that.
I said that I am a healer.
I warned. If this charlatan here
touches Maria Candelária,
I won't be responsible
if she dies.
Do not go. I beg you, don't go.
Look, miss healer
Let's do something.
This creature is very sick,
let's heal her together.
Allow me to
give her an injection,
and then I leave her
in your hands.
No way.
First I will
break your bones.
So you think I'm a mule.
With all these things that you brought.
When a mule doesn't move,
there are no spurs that will move it.
How long will it take?
A little.
Please hurry up, madam.
Wait outside.
But why, miss healer?
What why? Don't you know
that I have to rub her whole body?
Get out quick.
because I don't have time
to heat the ointment.
All right, all right.
Let's go outside.
Maria Candelária was healed.
He went to ask for her hand,
as they said.
Maria Candelária was
happy with her new dress.
Take him. He's the thief.
Just a minute.
Once again desecrating the
house of the Lord.
What is wrong?
Today when I returned to the village,
I found out that this Indian
broke into my store.
This time, he will go
to jail like
a bandit should.
Is not true,
it is not true, Father.
Lorenzo Rafael is not
capable of robbing anyone.
You know him, Father.
Oh no? And that dress
that you are wearing?
The dress.
It's your dress to get married.
And the medicines?
And the money?
Not money, father.
I took the medicine
for Maria Candelária
who was sick.
For the love of God, Don Damian,
don't take him away.
Help us, Father.
I will return the dress
and the medicine he stole.
But don't let them take him.
What are you waiting for?
Move!
Lorenzo Rafael,
Lorenzo Rafael, no!
Father!
Please take care of her.
Cry, put it out.
We should not keep despair inside.
I can't bear my cross
anymore, father
I feel like screaming,
scream until my throat is dry,
or God, our Lord hears me.
And you?
Why can't you hear me?
What did we do to be
punished like two criminals?
We loved each other,
we were poor?
You never look at us.
To everyone else, however,
you listen,
and help them and extend
your hands to support them.
With us, you are tough,
you are bad.
Maria Candelária!
Don't talk to the
Virgin like that.
You are stabbing
her heart again.
Look, see how her
eyes are crying.
No.
I do not want to
hurt the Virgin.
It was despair, father.
It was despair.
Forgive me,
Blessed Mother of Jesus.
I know that you
are very busy.
There are so many of us who
ask you things all the time.
I am so small.
I'm so behind everyone else,
that probably
it's not my turn yet,
to be heard.
Tell her to
forgive me
for everything I said.
I didn't mean to offend her.
How could I want to
offend her, Father?
Quando eu era pequena
my mother taught me how to
see the light in things.
Tell her
that I will not
complain again.
And to do with us
what she wants.
Lorenzo Rafael.
And you?
Yes, sir.
I'll give you ...
one year in prison.
I didn't steal
a penny, sir.
Only the medicine
and the dress.
For...
For Maria Candelária.
And the money that
I had in the drawer?
Shameless Indian.
One year in prison.
Arrest him.
Another one.
Bathe him.
Stay quiet.
- He looks like a thief.
- Shut up.
This is not Xochimilco.
Hey, a cigarette.
Let me see him, sir.
I can't
I brought the dress
and the medicine.
so you can let him go.
He was tried.
The crime must be punished.
Get your things, go.
It can get worse.
My God,
what should I do?
Do you want an advice?
You better
find a lawyer.
One of those who talk a lot.
Or speak to Mr Damian
to drop the charges.
No. Not him.
Come on, I said that
you can't see him.
Let's go.
For the thousandth time,
stop pestering.
Let's eat in peace.
You too, what
are you waiting for?
Don't waste you time with women.
No, man.
Didn't I tell you?
That you would bring bad luck
to Lorenzo Rafael.
Well, you already did.
You had to stay what you are.
This is a time to prove that
you are
a real woman.
Make Mr Damian forgive
Lorenzo Rafael.
Didn't you say you love him?
Buy flowers!
What do you want?
I want to see the man
who paints.
Here is the paper
that he left in my hut.
He's in Mexico City.
Will he come back?
I do not know.
He may come back tomorrow.
I'll wait outside,
with your permission.
Maria Candelária.
- Sir.
- What is it?
They put him in jail.
- Who?
- Lorenzo Rafael.
But, why?
Because he stole the medicine
that would heal me.
Only you can help us.
Well, let's go.
No, gentlemen.
I'm sorry.
The judge is on vacation.
I think he went hunting.
I was trying to do something,
but I am poor and
I can't pay the bail.
Look at the bail amount, Mr Secretary.
I will pay.
It is for Lorenzo
Rafael to leave right now.
I'm sorry, sir.
Only the judge
can set bail.
Ten days will fly by.
Maria Candelária.
Come here.
So,
at least, let
this girl see him.
Of course, she can see him.
She can even bring him
food, if she wants.
I believe that the prisoner
hasn't eaten since he arrived.
Hey, you.
Take these men and the Indian
to the prisoner in cell 30.
Almighty heaven,
I knew you were coming ...
Lorenzo Rafael.
Maria Candelária.
- Lorenzo Rafael.
- Maria Candelária.
You will be leaving in ten days.
They promised the priest.
Maria Candelária.
I was not able to sleep
since they caught you.
Just thinking about
how lonely and sad
you must be here.
Don't cry, Maria Candelária.
Or I cannot handle it.
I am not
crying, Lorenzo Rafael.
Look at me.
You see?
I'm not crying anymore.
As soon as I leave
we will see the priest
to give us his blessing.
He has just blessed us.
We're almost married.
So,
do you forgive me
for what I did?
Forgive you?
You know that I love you more
than myself.
Poor thing. You should see
how good she is.
Look, father.
It is not an exaggeration
to say that in Maria Candelária
I found everything
I was looking for.
I paint Indians,
as you know.
And since I saw her,
I felt in her what, must
have been, in the past,
that delicate race.
Emotional and wonderful.
For me, it is like
the essence of true
Mexican beauty.
I understand perfectly.
I'll try to convince
Lorenzo Rafael.
We are very good friends.
Me too, sometimes,
I paint my portraits.
I am only
a newbie, you know.
Altarpieces for believers,
that take us to church
with devotion.
And for me it's a
great happiness.
I charge for the painting.
May God forgive me.
Thank you very much, Father.
Don't thank me.
Thank this gentleman who managed
for Maria Candelária to see you.
Thank you very much, sir.
You are the one who sent
the doctor, right?
Yes, it was me.
We were thinking about thanking you
after we get married.
But it was not possible.
I didn't steal the money, Father.
Only the medicine.
And the dress for
Maria Candelária.
To get married.
I've already returned everything,
Lorenzo Rafael.
I don't disapprove of you, son.
I am hurt because of
what happened.
Do not worry.
You will have to stay for a few days,
because the judge is not there,
but we’ll get you out.
May God pay you, sir.
Why didn't you eat?
Maria Candelária will bring
your food every day.
I'm going back to
my garden
to start making
some tortillas.
It won't be long.
Take these centavos.
Pay me back
when you can.
No, sir.
Not money.
In the garden we always have
corn and beans.
Thank you very much, Father
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
May God be with you.
Shut up.
Stay quiet.
Look, Lorenzo Rafael.
He is a painter, and is
interested in you a lot.
Yesterday Maria Candelária
talked to him.
I said that she
could go see him.
I was always
interested in the Indians.
Everybody knows me
in Xochimilco.
They committed many
abuses against you.
It is natural that you
are wary of strangers.
I'm telling you this because
since I saw you
on the market,
and I asked to paint
Maria Candelária,
I noticed your distrust.
I wish you
had listened to me.
None of this would have happened.
Isn't that right, Father?
If he wants to paint
Maria Candelária,
I do not see anything
wrong with that.
It's like any other
kind of work. Honestly.
It is a distinction that he
wants to paint her.
I don't want to paint just her.
You too.
Me whenever
you please, Father.
Especially because he was
so kind to us.
But as for
Maria Candelária,
well,
I prefer not.
Maria Candelária.
Look at me.
Lupe.
I do not know
how to talk to her.
I'm afraid that
she refuses.
However, there is no other
way to finish painting.
I think I can
convince her, master.
You will see.
Come, beautiful.
I will show you
something.
It's me?
Is it not?
Yes.
But she is broken.
Well, it lacks the body.
The master has to paint it.
He's just getting started.
Come on. Let's go.
Do not worry.
You are very beautiful.
But only without clothes
you can be as beautiful as you are.
There's nothing wrong
Maria Candelária.
No.
Creature!
Hey!
Don't go!
Maria Candelária.
She's gone, master.
I was almost sure
that this was going to happen.
The natives are like that.
And that’s why her
virtue was not touched
neither by money,
nor by civilization.
But you have to finish
painting, master.
The face is already there
and you drew the rest.
My body looks
like hers, master.
If you want, I can.
All right.
Let's start, then.
The Flowers of Xochimilco
- Good morning, dear.
- Good morning.
- What news do you bring?
- None.
In Xochimilco everything
is the same, and here?.
See if you recognize this painting.
Holy Mother of Christ!
Maria Candelária.
Naked.
Here it is
I was not lying.
There is no way
to get around this.
It is Maria Candelária.
A shame for
the people of Xochimilco!
We'll throw her out of the garden.
She is just like her mother.
Yes.
We will expel her from the city
so she never returns.
The shame that she puts us through.
Right?
Yes!
Let's expel her.
Don't let her escape.
Yes, expel her.
Expel her.
Let's get the shameless one.
Everybody follow me.
Let's go.
Lorenzo Rafael.
Lorenzo Rafael!
Do not leave me alone.
Open for me, sir.
Let me out.
Let me out, sir.
Let me out, let me out, sir.
Let me out.
- Open the gate.
- Shut up.
Scandalous Indian.
Let me out, sir.
Please.
Oh my God.
They will kill her.
Lorenzo Rafael!
I didn't do anything wrong.
I know that.
Maria Candelária.
I did nothing wrong.
Slut.
She turned out to be
just like her mother.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Lorenzo Rafael.
Translated by P.Sky
It was a story
of Maria Candelária.
THE END