Pardon me.
What?
The sign says persons with
tattoos can't use the pool.
You can't go in.
Fuck you!
Piss off!
Please follow the rules.
Tattooed guests can't use the pool.
You should have told us earlier.
Before we bought our
swimming trunks.
Will you reimburse us?
I'm from the Dragon Gang.
You're embarrassing me in public.
We ain't leaving until you apologize.
You got that?
It's beautiful.
I've never seen such a wonderful
'Lion with Peonies' before.
Who are you?
Look to his 'Lion with Peonies'.
No thanks.
Go ahead. He won't bite you.
Lions are the king of beasts.
Peonies are the king of flowers.
On him the king of beasts rests
with the king of flowers.
Right?
Right.
You know a lot, madam.
Are you one of us?
Am I what?
Quit busting my balls, punks.
Don't give civilians a hard time.
Or don't you know better?
You want to swim in a sewer?
Then quit fucking with me.!
Aren't I good?
Are you some boss's moll?
A foreign VIP is here and
this place is full of cops.
See them?
They're detectives.
If you're smart...
You should go.
We will. Thanks.
Hey, you!
Watch your livers.
Tattoos are bad for them.
Thanks for the advice.
Thank you so much. You're so brave.
Are you really a boss's moll?
Do I look it?
You certainly do.
This is who I am.
Mahiru Inoue, Attorney at Law.
A lawyer...
Yes. I specialize in 'Minbo'.
What's Minbo?
It's lawyers' jargon...
For how yakuza skirt the law
to extort money.
Call me if you need help.
"MINBO OR THE GENTLE ART
OF JAPANESE EXTORTION"
Good morning, Vice Minister.
Go right in.
Hi
About the summit...
Yes?
The foreign Minister disqualified
your hotel.
I did my best, but...
But what?
We spent millions on a new
'intelligent' convention center.
$300 million.!
Why can't we host the summit?
Class.
Class?
You must host heads of state.
We can't afford mistakes.
Just look out there.
The decision was that no hotel...
which can't handle those people...
can host a summit.
We have a proud tradition! We must
get rid of the yakuza.
The chairman ordered it.
Reception Manager!
Yes, sir.
Form a team to evict the yakuza.
Whoever was in charge is fired!
We're looking for a few good men.
The requirements are high.
You must be brave...
and diplomatic...
and know the law.
Have a quick mind...
and tenacity...
and decisiveness.
So none of you qualify.
But if you do, you will have a key job.
If you are qualified, step forward.
I'm impressed.
Now, I will explain your duties.
Your job will be...
To get rid of the yakuza.
What's wrong?
Aren't you brave enough to protect
our hotel?
Security Chief.
You're the expert.
Sorry, sir.
If I were younger, I'd volunteer.
But don't to want to get
hurt at my age.
Forget it!
Assistant Managers...
It's your job anyway.
I'm sorry, but I don't think...
What?
He's a newlywed.
So what about you?
I've got this home loan...
I must talk to my wife first.
Sir.
I will volunteer.
No.! You're too important.
Prince Mutsu says you have
a million-dollar smile.
You stay put.
Excuse me.
I'd be happy to volunteer.
Oh, no.!
You know 2,000 customers by name.
And...
Their social standing, cars...
You're too valuable.
You're the best doorman in Japan.
That's not the way to recruit.
It's tough.
We can't transfer good people.
We should hire professionals.
Say, what's your name?
Wakasugi, sir.
When did you start?
Spring this year.
You're good for a new employee.
I once worked at a warehouse.
Sports?
Sorry...
I wrestled Sumo.
What were you best at?
Pushing out.
Do you want to wrestle again?
Sir?
Push people out?
What people?
The yakuza.
How much do we spend on yakuza?
It varies each year.
Usually around $300,000.
When the director had his
mistress problem...
It cost us $500,000.
Say, Mr. Suzuki.
Yes, sir... I'll be home at six, Mom.
What's for dinner?
Sushi?
With eggs?
And sea eel, too?
It sounds yummy.
Mr. Suzuki.!
Got to go, Mom.
Yes, sir.
How do we handle yakuza expenses?
What do you mean?
As entertainment expenses?
Of course not.
That needs receipts. Yakuza
don't give receipts.
So how do you enter them?
Unaccountables.
Not expenditures?
That's right.
Then we can't budget for it.
When our people are threatened,
what do they do?
About the money?
They come here and beg.
They shouldn't pay.
The more we pay the more they want.
But instead of refusing, they pay.
Because it's not their own money.
They just worry about themselves.
And we clean up their messes.
If they think like employees...
we'll always be paying.
Hey, Suzuki.
Sir?
You're it.
What?
You're promoted to Yakuza Manager.
But I'm just an accountant.
They need me here.
As a reward, you get a splendid title.
As my 'Special Aide'.
Your mother will be so proud.
You get an assistant.
Who?
Wakasugi, the bellboy.
He's a good man.
And my budget?
You said not to pay.
So, no budget.
What do I know about yakuza?
Well...
Let's ask a top yakuza.
You know one?
No.
Then just shut up.!
We could contact a politician.
We can't.
Why not?
We have no budget.
Some yakuza are causing
trouble in the lobby.
Guests are complaining. Go stop it.
Yes, sir.
Right now.
Right away, sir.
You talk to them first.
It's your job.
I'll let you do it for experience.
No, thank you.
Paper- scissors-stone?
1 - 2 - 3...
Once again.
I a ways lose.
What's wrong?
I got to pee.
Just hold it.
Stress inflames my gall stone.
You're kidding.
It's true.
Stress is the worst thing.
Come on.
You signed this fucking IOU?
So now fucking pay.
We want it today.
Now, asshole!
Shit, they're real yakuza.
What do we do?
You go first.
Please?
What?
Please. Please?
For an ice-cream soda?
With two scoops?
OK, OK.
Excuse me, sirs.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Uh... um...
Would you please talk more quietly.
What?
What did you say?
Speak up, fucker.
I, uh, I...
I only asked if you could
talk more quietly.
Get lost. It's none of your business.
Don't order guests around.
Motherfucker.
But other guests have complained.
What other guests?
Which ones?
Bring them here!
Have them complain to us.
You hear me, idiot?
I said go get them.!
Bring them here!
Now.!
I'm not sure if...
You can't?
I'm sorry, I can't.
You're sorry?
If you are, get down your knees.
And fucking apologize!
You, too.!
We had a ca I that somebody
was causing trouble.
Were you screaming?
No, I wasn't hollering.
Nonsense!
He was just now!
He's lying. He only stopped
when you arrived.
Calm down.
Tell me your story over here.
Nobody can prove I was
causing trouble.
Where's the evidence?
You have a recording or something?
What were you doing?
Educating them.
Educating?
Yeah.
They don't know how to
treat their guests.
So I was teaching them how to
treat guests correctly.
You can't file a complaint.
Were they violent?
Well, no, they weren't but...
Then our hands are tied.
The police can't interfere
in civil cases.
What?
But they threatened me.
Everybody heard them.
Isn't that right?
You heard.
Didn't you?
If you want to teach them, do it
quietly and don't bother anyone.
If you need us again
we'll be right over.
Good-by.
But, officers...
How dare you call the police?
A guest tries to help educate you
and you call the police.
Don't you respect your guests?
Don't fuck with us.!
Who called the cops?
Let's settle this fair-and-square!
Can we talk privately?
What the fuck is this?
Thanks so much.
You got some balls on you.
I like you. So we'll leave
for today - for your sake.
Call me if you ever need help.
Excuse me.
Can I ask you one thing?
Why do yakuza... I mean members
of your profession come here?
Because we have a great
information network.
Once we find a good hang-out...
Our friends learn about it quickly.
Oh...
Look at it this way. It means you
are a well-loved hotel.
A well-loved hotel!
Hello, sir.
How did you get rid of them?
I paid them 'taxi fare'.
How much?
$1,000.!
I begged the accountants.
Mr. Suzuki...
You didn't handle that very well.
Everyone in the lobby saw
what happened.
It harmed our image.
Be more tactful.
You do it, then.
What do you mean? It's your job.
It's not a job I care for.
We do it for the good of the hotel.
Hello.
Hold on, please.
It's that yakuza. He wants
to talk to you.
Hello. What can I do for you?
Two double rooms?
But I just gave you some money.
All right. But no more education.
And just this one time.
Give them an inch...
Let's have a look at that thing.
Yes, Boss.
You cooked it?
Sure. For 5 minutes in boiling water.
Take a bite of it.
Bite this?
Yeah. It will add some realism.
Yes, Boss.
Let's start this thing.
Anything wrong, sir?
I don't know much about Italian food,
so I just wanted to ask you...
about this unusual ingredient.
Is this Italian seasoning?
A cockroach.!
What, a cockroach?
I'm very sorry. I'll get a new serving.
Wait a minute.
You'll do a lot more than just
bring a new serving.
I'm the manager.
I was told you had a problem.
I want to apologize.
There was a cockroach in
her lasagna.
You must be mistaken.
The way we prepare our lasagna...
that would be quite impossible.
But there was one in my lasagna.!
There was definitely a cockroach
in her food.
And she bit into it.
So how can you say...
That you think it is 'quite impossible'.
You listening, asshole?
I'm very sorry.
Fuck you.
You think you're too good for us?
You think you can insult us?
You listening?
I want to see the big boss.
And have him apologize.!
Got that?
You start scrubbing your
kitchen right now.
Or I'll go to the Health Bureau.
Say something.
I don't want any half-ass apology.
I'm terribly sorry...
Our general manager is out.
Can we see you tomorrow after
I discuss this with my superiors?
All right. You can't make any
decision anyway, can you?
I'll be waiting.
Send somebody important by ten
in the morning.
To this address.
I'm Ibagi of the Cobra Gang.
Yes, sir.
You'd better keep your promise.
We're from the Hotel Europa.
We're here to apologize.
Please accept this humble present.
And this $ 500 as a token
of our regret.
According to our regulations,
this is the proper amount.
Give me a break!
I apologize! Please.!
One of my boys fucked up
and has to be punished.
We never do a half-ass job of
punishing our mistakes.
We are very thorough.
Wait in the car and keep the
engine running to...
rush him to a doctor.
Yes, Boss.
Say, Mr. Suzuki.
I'm Ibagi of the Cobra Gang,
not some beggar.
As a good customer of your money.
I just want you to be more careful.
I don't want your money.
So how should we show
our sincere regret?
Well...
Admit your error in full-page
newspaper ads.
Then close your restaurant for
a sanitation check.
We can't do that.
I had him cut his finger off.
Right.
Listen, Mr. Suzuki.
One of us makes a mistake,
he loses a finger.
You know how you do it?
First you buy a sharp meat cleaver.
Then you wind a string around your
little finger...
and tie it very tightly.
When your finger turns white
and numb...
You place your hand on the table,
under the knife.
Your palm can be either up or down.
Most believe it's easier with
the palm up.
Hold the knife like this, and
take a deep breath...
Please stop. Please!
I tell you what.
Since you came all this way,
just write me a simple apology.
That will satisfy me.
I'll forget the whole thing.
Yes...
That's the Health Bureau.
Damn bureaucrats.
Your bureau sucks.
Why do you let the Hotel Europa
serve cockroaches?
You're guilty of gross negligence.
Do you have proof?
Just a written apology
signed by the...
General Manager's Special Aide.
He admits their food is infested
with roaches.
What will you do?
We'll, we...
If food poisoning develops...
You'll be liable.
You got that?
Say something.
I'm not leaving until this is settled.
Get some food.
I'm staying all right.
Come on!
Say something!
Don't underestimate us.
I can get a bureaucrat fired
anytime I want.
Say something!
I am terribly sorry, sir.
What's wrong with your hotel?
Can't you solve your own problems?
Make sure they don't come back
to my office.
Absolutely, sir.
I'll personally insure they don't
bother you again, so could...
Yes, yes...
Yes...
Good-by, sir.
You idiot!
The Bureau is furious.
We must do something.
Then pay them their blackmail.
We can't involve the Bureau.
They hushed up a real food
poisoning case once.
So no more mistakes.
But...
It's all your fault.
You wrote that stupid
letter of apology.
But...
Do something!
That's what you're paid for.!
Hey, Mr. Suzuki.!
Thanks for the rooms.
Hello.
You don't look good. What's wrong?
Nothing.
I hear you got problems.
The Cobra Gang has...
some posters saying bad things
about your hotel.
I'm worried about you.
What will they do?
Paste them up all over.
Send them to the media.
Can we stop them?
Let's see...
If you like I could talk to them.
Would you really?
Seeing you so miserable makes
me want to help.
But I need $ 20,000 for expenses.
Of course.
I'll get it right away.
Bring me Suzuki!
The goddamn Special Aide.
Right now!
I'll go find him.
The accountants said you'd be here.
It's nice and quiet.
They say it's your hideout.
Ibagi is here.
He's demanding to see you.
I'm not going.
Why do I have to do this?
I'm not trained to deal with yakuza.
Come on, Mr. Suzuki. Somebody
has to deal with them.
But why me?
I'm sorry.
I'm from a good family.
An only child.
My parents never yelled at me.
So why should the yakuza?
Sorry. I shouldn't take it out on you.
I'd better find out how
'well-loved' I am.
You hired a yakuza?
Fucking fool!
Some punk threatened me
to drop this matter.
Asshole!
You trying to set us against
each other?
That could cause a war. Will you
take responsibility for a war?
You fucking idiot!
But I just asked him...
Shut up!
I can't stand it.
I'm proud and you insulted me.
You owe me.!
You listening?
But...
I'm going to file a damage suit
against your hotel!
And tell the press.
The Tourist Bureau will
revoke your license!
You want that?
Should I do that?
Fucking answer him!
I apologize for my mistake.
So don't call the Bureau.
All right.
But then you got to show me your
hotel is sincerely sorry.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong?
Look.!
Bloody piss.
It's the stress.
The General Manager wants
a word with you.
Sir, look.
Yours?
It's Mr. Suzuki's.
What have you been up to?
Hours after I appointed you,
we had to pay $1,000.
$ 500 for a roach and then $ 20,000...
And now $ 50,000 to Ibagi.
What is wrong with you?
But you ordered me to solve
it at any cost.
I never said to pay that much.
I didn't pay because I wanted to.
I had to. To save this hotel!
Why should we two take all the shit?
They threaten you?
No.
Then you don't know how bad it is!
You dump your shit on us and then
you bitch about the fucking cost.
You fucking appointed us...
To evade your own fucking problems.
Stop, Mr. Suzuki! You're sounding
like them now.
I'm sorry.
All I think about now is yakuza.
Sir, I don't mean to tell you
what to do.
Can't we just consider this
an expensive lesson?
I'm sure they've learned a lot
in the last few days.
Let's face it, we did give
them a dirty job.
All of us at reception should
have helped.
Please give them a break.
If you say so. I'll give them
one more chance.
But I'm giving you some
professional help.
Do exactly as you are told.
Study hard and learn the tricks.
Don't pay another cent.
Why didn't he hire a pro earlier?
Instead of appointing us.
He was only giving us
a chance to develop.
The pro might be worse than yakuza.
I'll bet he's some drill-sergeant type.
Who's there?
Are you Suzuki and Wakasugi?
You look pretty bad.
I'm Mahiru Inoue, Attorney at Law.
I'm your new baby-sitter.
What's wrong?
You're a woman!
I certainly am.
Women can't handle yakuza.
I can. Minbo is my specialty.
Minbo?
What is it?
When yakuza get involved in
civil conflicts...
and use fear to extort money.
There's a long legal term.
But we call it 'Minbo' for short.
It feels good here.
I'm so tired...
from evicting yakuza from a condo.
Here's your first lesson.
What is it?
Don't fear the yakuza.
Impossible.
We have reason to be afraid.
I can see that...
because you're good-natured.
But bad-looking.
You're bad-mouthed.
But I'm good looking.
Pretend he's making a scene.
Stop him, Mr. Suzuki.
May I start?
Who the fuck are you?
What the fuck you want?
Excuse me, but you're bothering
our other guests.
Please be quiet.
What the fuck?
Don't tell guests to shut up.
I'm... I'm not saying shut up.
I'm... it's just that...
Don't hurry.
Just talk naturally.
I'm not telling you to be quiet.
For the sake of our other guests...
Please just lower your voice.
What?
Who's being bothered?
Bring him here!
Don't be intimidated.
Your behavior would bother anyone.
Keep going.
Don't insult me, asshole!
What's your name?
Get me your boss.
He is...
Can't you hear?
I want your boss.
He is in a meeting, so please
talk to me.
Just a minute.
That's one of their usual tricks.
Don't be intimidated.
If you get nervous...
They just press harder.
Fuck his meeting.
Do you know who I am?
You know what I'll do if you
don't get him?
Don't weaken.
Are you going to get him?
There's no reason to.
'Implied Violence'.
Your shouting implies violence.
You're talking big for a little guy.!
You want to get hurt?
I'll crush your skull.
All right, that's enough!
That's it.
Do you understand?
'I'll crush your skull' is
a criminal threat.
It is?
Be glad if they threaten you
or use violence.
Because then the police can act.
I see.
This is hard work.
It's none of my business but...
If your colleagues knew you were
helping us...
Wouldn't you be in trouble?
My colleagues?
Huh?
What are you thinking, you fool?
This is Police Detective Akechi.
Nice meeting you.
From now on, meet yakuza here.
This will be called the 'VIP Room'.
In here, you must act like
real executives.
Yakuza are vain. Treat them politely.
Hi
Hello.
Hide a camera there.
And one behind that tree.
Place another camera here
right in the open.
Replace that glass-topped table.
Remove this crystal ashtray.
That could even crush Suzuki's skull.
Hi
Monitors will let us watch
what's happening.
If the police come,
let them in this way, and...
Have them wait here.
From now, this is out turf.
Always meet yakuza on
your own turf.
Never go to their office again.
All right?
Yes.
Let's go.
My name is Hanaoka and I stayed
in Room 629 last night.
I'm afraid I left my bag in the room.
Can you check?
Yes, a bag?
Can you describe it, please?
Yes, green... two handles...
And a gold lock...
We have it right here.
Oh, good.
I'll be right over to pick it up.
My name is Hanaoka.
Go get it.
Yes, Boss.
Good morning.
I'm Hanaoka who forgot his bag.
A green one.
I called and asked if I could
pick it up here.
One moment, please.
Is this it?
That's it.
Mr. Hanaoka from Room 629.
Here you are.
Thanks very much.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Good morning.
I'm Hanaoka. I left my bag
in Room 629.
You're supposed to have it here.
Just a moment, please.
Mr. Hanaoka has already picked
up his bag.
What do you mean?
How could that be? I'm Mr. Hanaoka.
But he said he was.
What is this all about?
I am Mr. Hanaoka.
Then, who was he...
How should I know?
I just want my bag back.
But the other gentleman took it.
My bag?
He came right after he called.
He gave his name and room.
Did you ask for identification?
No, I'm so sorry.
Your apology don't solve nothing.
You got a big problem.
You know what you did?
That bag contained $ 500,000
in promissory notes.
What?
We shouldn't discuss this here.
Please come to the VIP Room.
This way, please.
How many?
Four of them.
Let's make it six of us.
Remember, never meet
yakuza alone.
And always outnumber them.
Excuse me, everybody.
I need to borrow three bodies.
I need mean-looking ones.
You.
And you, too.
And you.
A pretty good team.
What's that mean?
What is your name, please?
How many times do I have to
tell you? Hanaoka.
Your full name?
Hey.!
Why you need his full name?
With money involved we must be
sure of everything.
And as the hotel's representative,
I must make a full report.
My full name is Mahiru Inoue.
What is yours?
Stop this bullshit!
What you going to do about
the $ 500,000?
You know all guests must deposit
valuables in our safe.
Why didn't you?
Fuck you!
You fucked up!
Stop bullshitting, bitch.
Our promissory notes...
Serial numbers, please?
You idiot!
That's confidential information.
That's strange.
With serial numbers we can
halt payment.
Why the fuck 'strange'?
You calling him a liar?
You say we're pulling a scam?
No bitch can accuse us!
Hey, easy.
But, boss...
I said stop!
We act polite and she'll understand.
Say, Miss Inoue.
Here is my business card.
I'm in a tough spot because
you lost my bag.
You understand?
It was our fault we didn't check
his identification.
And we will apologize for that
particular error.
Right, I knew you would understand.
So what about the promissory notes
that were in my bag?
You'll be happier if you solve it
while I'm still polite.
Accept some friendly advice...
Some of my men will do anything
to see that justice is done.
Even go to jail for the sake
of justice.
They are real fine men.
You have a husband and kids, right?
I'm single.
It's not safe to be living alone.
So I suggest...
You think this over carefully.
Can I ask you a question?
Of course.
These young men who aren't
afraid of jail...
What kind of men are they?
Cut the crap.!
Don't fuck around!
If you want to say something...
I'd better get your full names, too.
Fuck you!
Stop blabbering.
Do I understand, Mr. Hanaoka...
That your young men might
assault me.
Is that what you mean?
I'm not saying that.
You'd better not be.
Because it's a criminal threat.
Shut up!
Don't try our patience.
What about the money you lost?
Under the circumstances, we can
assume a thief stole it.
Therefore, I think we should
notify the police.
In fact, I have already called
the detectives.
Mr. Akechi, please come in.
Hey, Hanaoka. What's happening?
I stayed at this hotel last night
and they lost my bag.
You stayed here?
Why here?
I had to meet somebody to
collect some debts.
So you're in the finance
business now?
Just he ping a friend.
You're good at collecting debts.
Well, I guess so.
But you're no lawyer, so you
broke the law.
Give me a break.
Take him to the station.
What happens now?
They were lying. So it's all over.
But it was our fault we didn't ask
for identification.
We will be more careful.
I can't get over it.
How did we do it?
No idea.
Surprised?
You bet I am.
You thought a woman
could never do it.
Of course not...
To be honest, I did. I'm sorry.
Please tell us.
How did you do it?
That's just the way they are.
Stand up to them, they become
cowards.
You're so darling.
You wouldn't flinch. Why?
I didn't flinch because...
I know they would never
hurt us.
Yakuza wouldn't hurt us?
You're joking.
But they didn't.
They're always violent in movies.
They only hurt each other.
Nothing to do with us.
But cutting off fingers?
That's only among themselves.
In cases like this, they
seldom use violence.
If fact, they can't.
Why not?
They can't afford to.
Violence can land them in jail.
But they're always claiming
they're not afraid of prison.
Mr. Wakasugi.
Yes.
Listen.
Prison is expensive.
Huh?
Legal fees, bail, living expenses...
Cost $ 200,000 a year.
One punch can cost a
Yakuza $ 200,000!
Right.
Their hands are tied.
Nobody spends $ 200,000
to earn $ 2,000.
Are you still frightened now?
Come to think of it, I'm not.
All you need is to know your enemy.
Let's tell the General Manager
the good news.
I can't wait to see his face.
He's out golfing.
Excuse me.
Sirs.
This gentleman is on his own and...
I wondered if he could join you.
How about you?
Fine with me.
All right.
Thanks. My name is Iriuchijima.
Welcome.
Maybe I shouldn't ask you,
since we just met.
But how about a little bet to
spice things up?
Fine with me.
How about ten for each nine?
That's not too much.
Thanks again, I had a great time.
My pleasure.
Mr. Kobayashi...
I don't have much cash
with me today.
Can I wire it to you?
Don't worry. Let's just forget it.
Not at all. I always pay my debts.
Forget it.
But I insist on paying.
A bet is a bet.
I'll wire it to your account.
Give me your card.
Well, if you insist...
Here you are.
The Yamaha Bank just called.
A Mr. Iriuchijima wired
$ 20,000 to your account.
$ 20,000?
Yes, sir.
Are you sure?
Should I check again?
Never mind.
Mr. Kobayashi.
Mr. Iriuchijima, I was
going to call you.
Your bank made some mistake.
What do you mean?
They put $ 20,000 in my account.
That's right.
Pardon?
There's no mistake.
I did send $ 20,000,
But you said ten per nine.
In my circle ten means $10,000.
That's ridiculous.
Nobody bets $10,000 on nine holes.
Hey, don't be so loud.
Betting is against the law.
What?
Gambling is a criminal act.
We're both guilty.
Come on. Let's just forget
the whole thing.
I'll refund it.
I can't let you.
I'm a man of honor. I always
pay my debts.
You planned this.
People might gossip.
I get muckrakers visiting me
all the time.
'Hotel Executive Arrested for
Gambling'...
That would be a great story.
Sir. They're here.
OK.
I have to run.
Can we talk later?
Sure. I'll be at this place tonight.
It's a nightclub.
But it's quiet. We can talk there.
What should I do?
We meet tonight.
I'm in trouble.
You really got trapped, didn't you?
To let you off the hook they
usually ask for...
Twice the amount they paid you.
He's here.
Good of you to come.
Sit down and have a drink.
I'm having champagne.
Bring a glass.
No thanks. I have to go.
I just brought this.
We'll talk business later.
Let's just toast our new friendship.
But...
Come on. This is my turf.
Don't make me lose face.
To our friendship. Cheers.!
Cheers!
Get my guest a pair of scissors.
Ask him, Akemi.
What's this?
It's her turn today.
Which one first?
You do the left one.
It's your turn.
No, I'm all right...
Go ahead!
You're very good!
Let's drink.
Well, all right.
A great cut.
Another drink...
Cheers.
I'm feeling fine...
Looks like he's coming to.
You really made a fucking mess.
What you going to do about it?
You shouldn't drink so much.
We had hell of a time stopping you.
You're strong for an old man.
As soon as we stopped you wrecking
the place, you jumped Akemi.
You got a pretty good tool.
But it did bad things to Akemi.
So we're going to fix it.
Give me the razor.
Hold him down.
This might hurt a bit.
Shit.! It broke. Get some scissors.
Get the scissors!
Wait.
Maybe this is better.
Put his dick through the loop and
yank both ends.
Hold him down.
We do it on three.
Stop! I'll do anything!
Help me.!
Let's go. One two...
Ho d it.! Ho d it.!
What the fuck are you doing?
Let him go.
Mr. Iriuchijima!
Stop bothering my friend.
You're not a kid any more. You
shouldn't behave like this.
Poor Akemi. Did you know she is
only 18 years old?
This is bad.
You could be arrested for sexually
assaulting a minor.
Did I do all this?
You sure did.
We're in big trouble.
To tell you the truth...
This place belongs to the Boss of
the Black Swamp Gang.
His mistress runs it.
If things get bad,
I may have to chop my finger off.
What can we do?
$100,000.!
Can you hush this up for $100,000?
Please, Mr. Iriuchijima!
Don't pay $100,000.
Don't pay anything!
This may sound harsh.
You were insane ever to visit
their place alone.
A stupid mistake for a smart
executive.
But everybody makes mistakes.
Just be careful not to repeat him.
And paying $100,000 would
be repeating.
But I promised.
General Manager.
Leave everything to me.
I'll handle it.
Never meet them again.
Don't take their calls.
Understand?
I am Mahiru Inoue.
I'm Mr. Kobayashi's attorney.
What?
We don't want no lawyer.
We want Kobayashi.
Get lost!
We want him!
About this...
Why isn't he here?
He's got to keep his promise.
He gave me
full power-of-attorney.
You may not deal with him.
Say, Ms. Inoue.
Kobayashi got down on his knees
and promised to pay me.
So, I guess you brought the money.
Money?
I didn't bring any.
Then go get it.
He wants to pay.
No lawyer can deny that.
Or are you going to pay us
on his behalf?
I'm a lawyer. I don't do such things.
Why are you here?
I'm his attorney.
We don't want no lawyer.
Got that, bitch?
We want him to repay his
debt directly.
Repay what debt?
He never borrowed your money.
On what do you base your claim?
He said he would pay.
It's between me and him. It's none
of your business.
He says you threatened him.
Nobody threatened him.
Can you prove it?
Can you prove he owes money
to you?
We have witnesses.
We're all witnesses.
Then go ahead and file a suit.
If you feel he is liable, go to court.
I can't do that.
Lawsuits take too much money
and time.
Be reasonable with us.
Legally speaking...
He said he'd pay.
Not keeping a promise is
ethically wrong.
I'm talking about ethics.
Do you have an IOU?
No. It was a verbal promise
between gentlemen.
Will he welch on a verbal agreement?
I will never accept that.
I don't intend to do anything illegal.
So report it to the police.
If I do that, will you pay?
Of course not.
Then, you had better let me
talk to him directly.
If anybody breaks a promise
and run away...
I teach them a very hard lesson.
What you say is bullshit.
I can teach lawyers lessons, too.
Listen, lady lawyer.!
As I said...
Just bring me Kobayashi.
He is very afraid.
Of what?
This is a safe, law-abiding country.
I'll meet him in a nice, open place.
I'm not asking to meet in a dark alley.
But he's afraid.
You come along too, then.
If you're seeing me, you don't need
to be afraid.
But when you aren't seeing me...
What do you mean?
How do I know?
I just want to be paid back.
I live a fair-and-square life.
I just want him to keep his promise.
If he's sincere, I might compromise
with him.
But if he runs, I'll never forgive him.
In fact, I'll get angry. I'm that
type of man.
And when I'm angry, I act!
Let's solve this by cooperating.
He didn't accept the $ 20,000
you sent.
I put it in escrow and filed a writ.
It's still yours.
About your claim that he damaged
Club Scarab...
and assaulted its employee Akemi...
He does not recall any of it, so
I'm afraid you must file a suit.
We'll see you in court.
But I don't want to go to court.
I want to see him.
For what reason?
To get my money back.
Do you think you lawyers...
can always protect him?
The police can.
Fuck you!
I'll get my money, police or no police.
Try to stop me!
I request that you do not see him.
I'll go to his house.
If you do, I will involve the police.
We don't care, bitch!
Go ahead.
You're in the wrong. Look at how
badly he wrecked this place.
I believe the owner is Mr. Kuronuma
of the Black Swamp Gang.
Yeah.
So if Kobayashi pays you,
the money goes to him?
So I'll call Mr. Kuronuma.
Wait a minute.
You're going to call the Boss of
the Black Swamp?
Of course.
It's his club.
Wait a minute.
Our profession has its own
proprieties.
If you call him it could cause
difficulties.
That's your problem.
Ms. Inoue.
Yes.
You've got as much guts as we do.
I'm honored.
Say, Mr. Iriuchijima.
I appreciated your compliment, but...
I still think it would be wise for
both of us to drop this matter.
If you are willing to forget
everything...
I won't involve Boss Kuronuma.
You win.
It's forgotten.
God, I was nervous.
What if they had filed a suit?
They would have had to submit
evidence.
And prove beyond a reasonable
doubt that he did those things.
And they can't.
So that's why you were claim.
Today, I told myself not to be scared.
And?
And I wasn't.
I wasn't either.
They used to terrify me.
Today, I was calm enough to admire
their art of shouting.
I learned a lot today.
I can't wait for the next
confrontation.
Can I handle it?
No. It's my turn next.
This arrived.
I got an appointment with Kobayashi.
I'm Iriuchijima.
Certainly, sir.
Is the General Manager in?
He's at the construction site?
Someone to see you.
I wanted to talk man-to-man.
You got a bad attitude.
It was a dangerous thing you did
involving that lady lawyer.
My boys do terrible things
when they get mad.
You shouldn't hang around
places like this.
A big steel beam could drop on you.
Or you could get accidentally
knocked over the edge.
You saw what I sent?
I'm stuck with a huge inventory
of the same stuff.
You want to buy it?
How much?
Ten million.
Ten million dollars!
That's ridiculous.
Not for the hotel.
Don't play stupid.
It... it's impossible.
The board would never...
Is this going to be the new wing?
Yes.
What's it costing?
$ 200 million.
You're behind schedule, I hear.
Yes.
All right. I'm leaving for now.
I'm going to make it easy for you
to get ten mil ion from the board.
How did it go?
He's scared.
One more push should do.
We got to give them a good excuse
for approving ten million.
What excuse?
Anything.
How about organizing a protest
against their construction?
Leave that to me.
I'm a local resident. I'll do that myself.
Stop this construction.
Or you' I be sorry.
You need our approval for
construction.
We can ruin you.
Do it while you still can!
As I was saying...
If you don't, we'll make you.
Say something, huh!
Let's all calm down.
Wakasugi.
You know how much you're polluting?
Got any idea?
What are you talking about?
There's the noise.
And vibration and dust.
Mud on the roads.
Toxic chemicals.
Do you have proof?
We got photographs.
And pictures don't lie.
See?
This shows dump trucks
soiling the road.
They're great pictures.
The tires are making the road
a muddy mess.
You got to stop it.
What will you do?
It looks like our vehicles
in those pictures.
We'll investigate.
That's no fucking answer.
We'll tell the government.
They will make you stop.
You want that?
Say something, asshole!
Answer me.
Speak up!
Thank you for your concern.
We appreciate learning your opinions.
What?
That's no answer.
What kind of attitude is that?
We will be more careful.
We'll contact the government
ourselves and...
Do whatever they say is necessary.
We thank you.
What the fuck is this? This ain't fair.
If you continue your construction...
We'll be watching everything for
the smallest infraction.
Got that?
You're being unfair.
You yakuza claim to help the weak.
So, stop troubling the weak.
What the fuck?
You're the ones troubling us!
Don't shift the blame.
It ain't right.
It ain't fucking right, at all.
May I remind you...
We're recording this.
What?
Hold it.
Is that a camera?
Yes.
You got microphones in here, too?
Let's go.
Sorry to bother you. We'll be in touch.
We did it!
We chased them away!
But why did they go so easily?
They have something in mind.
Something devilish.
Ladies and gentlemen staying
at the Hotel Europa.!
Did you know that you are being
spied upon?
The Hotel Europa employees are
watching your every move...
through hidden cameras and
microphones!
It may look like a first-class hotel.
But it's run by Peeping Toms.
The new wing that they are
constructing...
in an environmental nightmare.
It is polluting our drinking water and
creating lung-destroying dust.
Vibrations are causing miscarriages.
Our health is being ruined.
The Hotel Europa is a diabolical
menace to society.!
The Hotel Europa must be stopped
from polluting the city!
Stop your spying!
Stop your unethical conduct.
I'm very sorry.
We have asked the police to
stop them.
The noise gave your baby a fit?
We'll get you a doctor.
I'm very sorry, sir.
This spying things is absolutely
unfounded and...
We want the boss!
Please talk to me.
We want the General Manager!
You need an appointment.
We don't need one.
It's about your pollution.
It's his duty.
The General Manager sees no one
without an appointment.
What?
He won't talk to local residents?
Cut the crap.!
Say something!
There he is!
Hey you!
Stop.!
Stop, you scumbag!
We want to talk.
The bride and groom will now
cut their wedding cake.
Darling.! What is going on?
What...
What are you doing here?
Naoko.!
They're harassing your family too.
Look at this! What it this all about?
It was sent by courier! What's
happening?
Darling, what happened?
What have you done?
We've been getting strange
phone calls and...
Naoko was followed by a man.
This was thrown in our garden.
Meatballs with razor blade inside.
The dog didn't get it, thank god.
But it's driving me crazy.
And those awful trucks.
You've been cheating on me, too.
All this is just yakuza harassment.
Your husband is a victim.
Please trust him.
We'll stop them. Don't worry.
Come, fix your makeup.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
There's something else.
Thank you for confiding in me.
You must have suffered badly.
Will you help me fight them?
That's my job.
This is now a war and my generalship
is not good enough.
I'm asking the Chairman for orders.
Oh!
The grandpa!
He's the Chairman.
Goodness, excuse me.
You hired me?
I made the arrangements for you
to help us.
I fell in love with your courage.
I made a good choice.
Thanks to you, hosting a summit
is now possible.
We need advice about
a new problem.
I was careless and they are trying
to blackmail me.
I apologize.
Should I fight them on this?
Let me say something
before you answer.
Those photos are fake.
He met with them alone and
fell into a trap.
He is innocent of everything but
an honest mistake.
Thank you.
What should we do?
What happens if we don't fight?
We pay them $10 mil ion.
I believe in your innocence.
But we can't pay ten mil ion just
to save your reputation.
If we don't, we face a huge scandal.
Our General Manager sexually
assaulting a minor...
I'm sorry, but the public is all too
ready to believe dirt like that.
If those photos get out,
we're ruined.
We'll never host a summit.
They will never be distributed.
Why not?
Photos are like hostages.
You don't release hostages
before getting a ransom.
Don't pay anything.
Money might solve this problem.
But tomorrow the hotel would be
filled with yakuza.
And new troubles would start.
Do you want that?
We should stand up to the yakuza
from now on.
If they discover we will stand up
to them...
They will just fade away.
And we're almost there.
Let's keeping trying.
Continue to stand firm.
Don't yield.
Don't pay another cent.
As the board, you should make this
official policy.
Please!
What do you think?
I agree with Ms. Inoue.
Let us fight to the finish.
If it doesn't work, you can fire me.
Please let us fight.
I feel the same way.
Let us fight. Please.!
If we fail and the scandal
is about to surface...
Fire me and place the blame on me
to save the hotel.
I'll leave my resignation with you.
All right. Go ahead.
Thank you, sir.!
What the hell!
The yakuza taught you to be
skilled negotiators.
Ladies and gentlemen, yakuza are
attempting to extort money from us.
They think that proper citizens are
soft and easy to scare.
Well, we're not!
We will not pay a sing e cent to them.
We have no reason to.
If they want to kill somebody,
they can kill me.
This hotel is my child and I will
die to protect it.
This hotel is my life.
I intend to leave it in better shape
than it was when I started it.
I may be 82, but I want to tell you
filthy rogues...
I'm not senile and I'm not afraid.
I will never compromise this hotel or
its reputation.
When yakuza visit, we take them
to this room.
Since they only use vaguely
threatening words and gestures...
we record everything for use
in court.
This room is wired for both
sounds and pictures.
What they mean by 'spying' is...
the cameras and microphones
in this room.
What do you call this room?
The VIP Room.
Where to?
To court.
To stop the noise.
Can we do that?
I'll apply for an injunction.
What's that?
A preventive order.
In our case, preventing them from
contacting us.
And using speakers to slander us.
And threatening us.
And obstructing business.
Will they do it?
Our recording will help.
Fellow residents,
please listen to us.
Lawyer Inoue, did you know...
somebody wants to kill you?
You should be very careful.
Stop taking those fucking pictures.
Get out of here, you scumbag!
It's pretty awful.
I understand your situation.
I sympathize with you, but before
issuing an injunction...
We must summon the other party...
To hear their position.
But this is extremely urgent.
The situation is worsening.
Customers are leaving.
It's a question of survival.
The other party is a yakuza.
Call them on the phone.
Yes, sir.
We're fighting a mighty battle...
for the good of our community.
We got no time for any judge.
Our problem is with the hotel,
Not with any court.
Make a memo of that call
for the record.
Yes, sir.
I've decided.
I'll issue your injunction.
Thanks, Your Honor.
It's just a piece of paper.
They don't believe in paper.
They'll ignore it.
That's fine, too. You'll see.
I'm Ms. Inoue.
I'm the summons server.
They're yakuza, so I asked
for police help.
These are detective.
Hello.
That's it.
I'm from the court. Open up.
They think if they don't answer,
the injunction will vanish.
I know you're there!
Open up.!
If you don't, we'll break in!
Take it easy.
I hereby officially serve
this injunction.
Thanks so much.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much.
Hey, wait.
Hey, Wakasugi, I want to talk to you.
Come with me.
I'm the hotel's lawyer.
You may not speak to hotel
employees.
You must go through me.
What?
Why the fuck do that?
Hey, Wakasugi, did you hire
this fucking lawyer?
You trying to bust our balls?
Answer, punk!
You better apologize while
you still can.
Our boys are hotheaded.
Look at this one.
He doesn't mind doing time for me.
Don't!
Let me speak.
You're angry because you can't
handle a lawyer.
Well, too bad.
We already reported...
your complaints to the government.
If they fine us we'll pay them.
We'll never pay you.
If you come to our hotel...
you'll come in a herd, right?
Like the herd of steers you are.
Hold it.!
Wakasugi, you made me lose face.
We will meet again.
So that's the situation.
Now I understand.
Even through we got an injunction...
They'll ignore it and still barge in.
And then we can act.
Right?
Let us know when they
violate the injunction.
We're ready to pounce.
Thanks so much.
Now I see.
You got the in junction so
the police can act.
It should also keep them
away from us.
Is it over?
Let's hope so.
I've always wanted to ask...
Why aren't you afraid of yakuza?
Well...
Probably because I know them.
My father was a surgeon downtown.
Yakuza missing fingers or with stab
wounds often came to our clinic.
One big boss even used to
carry me piggyback.
One day he staggered in,
covered with blood.
Some family had shot him.
The shooters barged in and
demanded...
my father give his patient up.
Some carried swords or pistols.
My father refused.
He wouldn't surrender.
So, they shot him.
They took the boss to the beach.
They buried him alive in
the sand. Headfirst.
And your father?
An ambulance came.
But he was already dying.
I was bawling.
But he said:
Everybody dies sometime.
And it's better to die for your
beliefs than...
Live as a coward.
Remember that always.
After he said that, he raised
his hand...
Like this...
And died.
Few people are as strong
as he was.
Most people fear yakuza.
They're afraid to look at them,
let alone fight.
Yakuza trample people's pride.
They humiliate them.
I find that unforgivable.
They use fear...
To make people live like cowards.
Watch out!
Hang on!
I'll call an unbalance.
I'll get you next, Wakasugi!
Will she make it?
It missed the artery, but it's
still critical.
If an infection doesn't set in...
We'll know by later today
or tomorrow.
She got stabbed protecting me.
Because I tried to provoke them.
It's all my fault. It's all my fault...
Suzuki speaking.
They came back?
Yes, right away.
They're at the hotel.
Let's go!
Detective Akechi?
You can act at last.
They violated the injunction.
Right. How many?
Ibagi, Iriuchijima, and seven others.
Got it.
Let's go.
Do you want back-up?
No. Just ourselves.
I'll come too.
But, sir...
You act tough. I'll act weak.
Maybe we can trick them.
The court has forbidden you to
contact us.
It is illegal for you to enter this
building or speak to us.
We have nothing to discuss
with you.
Please leave.
We're local residents!
And we local residents aren't
satisfied.
One phone call and I'll have 2,000
men here.
And 20 trucks.
We can still stop the construction.
You got that?
So stop fucking around!
Got that?
I must remind you...
Everything you say or do
is being recorded.
What the fuck!
Who said you can record this?
Take it easy.
Our justice will prevail.
It's much nicer without that
lawyer cunt.
Is she sick?
So what's your answer?
Answer to what?
To the construction question.
Which construction question?
Our request to stop it.
You never got our approval.
You're insulting us!
Say something, huh!
Show your good faith!
Have they mentioned money?
No, not yet.
When they demand money,
we bust them.
Yes, sir.
Easy. Calm down.
Look, Mr. Suzuki.
This is a tough neighborhood.
You can't get
the residents' approval.
So leave it to us pros.
We'll settle everything for you.
Answer him! Say something!
What exactly are you saying?
Are you retarded? Or just
playing dumb?
I really don't understand.
What must we do to prove
our 'good faith' to you?
Fuck!
Figure it out yourself.
I'm sorry. I still can't figure it out.
Since the board must approve,
your requests must be specific.
Does 'good faith' mean money?
We just want you to be reasonable.
What do you mean by 'reasonable'?
By answering the complaints of
residents.
Will that involve paying the residents
money?
Should we pay you?
How much are you asking for?
I must give the board an
exact figure.
I'm talking to myself, understand?
Other companies usually pay about
zero-point-zero- five.
Does that mean five percent?
But five percent of what?
You stupid fucker!
Of your $200 million
construction cost.
There.! He mentioned an amount!
Can we bust them?
That's $10 million, isn't it?
There's no reason to pay you
anything.
The court can decide.
This is our final decision.
You may go.
Fuck the court!
We're the victims of your pollution.!
You know that?
Are you going to take your
victims to court?
Don't act innocent!
Now that's an obvious threat.
Hey, hold it!
Hold it.
Say, Mr. Kobayashi.
You're not going to be unreasonable
like them, are you?
What do you mean?
You know what happens
if you let us down.
I'm afraid so.
Then what's your answer?
If we pay you, will you promise
to give me the pictures?
Sure, I will.
And if we refuse?
I'll distribute them.
The scandal might force
your hotel to close.
You'll be fired.
If that's what you want...
You fool!
You just admitted to blackmail.!
We arrest you for extortion.!
Where's your warrant?
Show me the warrant!
We caught you red-handed.
Ibagi.!
Hey.!
One of your boys stabbed Ms. Inoue.
We caught him and he confessed
you ordered it.
You're an accomplice.
You'll get 20 years.
Welcome back.
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Don't strain yourself.
Really, I'm fine.
Goodness!
They're completely disappeared.
Even their smell is gone.
Do you miss it?
Yakuza are coming.
With their bosses.
There's at least 20 of them.
Let's get ready.
Get out of our way!
Who the fuck are you?
An employee of this hotel.
What the fuck!
Out of our way!
In accordance with our regulations...
Members of your profession
may not use our facilities.
But if you come alone and act
discreetly...
You may use them.
However, we will not allow...
you to enter accompanied so
brazenly by this many others...
who are so obviously members of
your profession.
We host important government
officials from abroad and...
have been ordered by the
government to maintain...
a certain image and atmosphere.
I mean no disrespect. I am only
asking for your understanding.
We cannot let you enter our
premises today.
Shut the fuck up.!
Don't fuck with us.
We did it!