I have a few more ques--
I can't make it stop!
I used to make things without
it all being so complicated
I was 22.
Hold!
I'm gonna come in and get wide.
You ready for wide, Ma?
Gazing upon my mom.
Go down to Barbara's feet.
One of them.
Go!
A parallax fantasy.
My mom performs
her period piece.
The mime-ic
embodiment of the ovaries.
Fallopian tubes.
Uterus.
Cervix.
Ovulation.
The creation of the egg.
Its release.
Its journey.
Its weight.
Menstruation.
Stay right where you are.
And I never showed
this film to anyone.
- I'm sorry, are you cold?
- No, I'm just--
I'll warm up in a second.
It's, it's, it's...
I promise it looks good.
You can't even
really see your feet.
Okay, are you ready?
Many years after this,
I received an email.
It was from a new website.
They wanted content
based on a theme.
Female Trouble.
They wanted to know
if I wanted to pitch an idea.
I wrote back, "Is this
a John Waters thing?"
They wrote back, "No."
She created this mime-ic...
Still I had heard that
the website had a lot of money.
And...
I thought of
my mom's period piece.
At the meeting, I was nervous.
Sweating, undulating.
Just like my mom.
The one who's a mime.
My mom is a mime.
I pitched the full performance,
this time complete
with comedic sound effects.
Everybody was laughing
and I was sweating,
and they even floated the idea
of someday making
a feature film together.
Are you married to this idea?
Or are you open to,
I don't know,
maybe something
more narrative?
At the end of it all
we shook hands
and they promised to be in touch.
I went home, I waited.
I felt dirty for dragging
my moms into that building.
A week later
I received an email.
The website liked me,
but they thought that
my idea was too...
...ass-oteric.
I didn't know
what ass-oteric meant,
so I asked my new boyfriend.
He said it was
pronounced with an "ES",
not an "ASS", and told me
to look it up.
Esoteric.
Adjective from esōterō,
meaning inner.
Intended for or likely to be
understood by
only a small number of people.
Esoteric.
E-so-te-ric.
I didn't know what was so...
esoteric about
my mom's period piece.
The website wanted
to know if I wanted
to direct a different video.
One in which
little girls talked about
what they dreamed
of being when they grew up.
But instead of
little girl dreams,
it was little boy dreams.
You know, lawyer,
fireman,
football player,
filmmaker.
I wished I was
the kind of person
who wanted to
direct that video.
I wished because...
movies about
the pain of being female
were awash with money.
But instead I wrote...
Dear So and So,
I think that probably
the most "female" thing
for me to do
would be to "realize"
your "vision"
and "direct" this "video."
That being said, as a person,
I don't think
the Idea is a good one,
and I hate not having
a choice.
A better video would be
of a female filmmaker
pitching an idea to a website,
and the website calling the idea
assoteric.
And then telling the
female filmmaker what to do.
And then I signed it.
And maybe the most female trouble
part of it all was
that I walked
into that meeting
having already made
a feature film.
But I didn't have
the words to say it.
I don't feel female.
Until somebody tells me I am.
Dude, you got this.
Just like, say action with authority.
Right, left...
- And you say...
- Action.
Action.
- Action. Action.
- Action.
- Action. Action!
- You just yell it.
- Action. Action.
- Action.
Action!
- Action!
Okay, it starts here.
12 years ago.
The day I drove past the lake.
The lake whose
shore was home
to one of the US of A's
first moving picture studios,
specializing in
'damsel in distress' films
The lake so deep
that after the studio's
flammable nitrate films
were thrown into it
they were never recovered.
I drove past the lake
and into my hometown.
A hometown with that hill
filled with failed communes.
The same communes
that my moms
and dad fled to.
In my hometown
as a young woman,
I felt the
vicious cycle of birth.
Giving birth and death.
Nevertheless I returned
home to make this film.
My first feature film
with my family and my friends.
I was 25.
So good.
Hey Vita!
How do I look?
Is that them?
Yeah. What, you haven't met them?
No.
Holy shit, you're so shy.
Hey guys, come on.
- Circle up!
I have a couple
of announcements
before we,
before we get started.
So the first announcement is
I trust you all so
inherently and implicitly,
and chemically
and emotionally
and spiritually,
conceptually,
no matter what,
and I really hope
you can trust me too.
We are all the
authors of this film.
And the second
announcement, thank you,
is that there's this old guy
who lives down the road
from my moms'.
He will offer you weed.
It is goblin weed.
Do not smoke it.
I'm telling you--
- I have to smoke goblin weed!
- Do not smoke, do not...
- If a goblin offers me weed...
- It is nasty, powerful little shit!
The crew consisted of Sam,
the assistant director.
- Not the producer?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Alexis, the cinematographer.
But we're more like sisters.
- Bobby.
- Hi! Pleasure.
Alexis's assistant.
She had given him head once.
JJ, the designer.
I had given him head twice.
And... Dustin.
- Hey baby, you're back!
- It's good to be back!
- Hi baby.
- Hey. Hey.
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
I had this like
really intense dream
that you were like with someone
else, and I like woke up
with this like weird taste
in my mouth.
- Sorry.
- No, it's fine.
- It's all just a dream.
- Yeah.
Hey, I got a...
it's like a little...
heart-shaped rock.
For luck or something.
- So nice. Thank you.
- Yeah.
Okay, I gotta get back to work.
Okay guys, let's go!
Let's go! Let's do it.
Let's make a movie. Yeah!
What about him?
Oh great, sound guy.
Wait, tell me your name again.
I'm so fucking bad
at remembering names.
Oh shit, Sam, Sam, Sam.
It's the guy.
Can you talk to him?
So I am the producer?
- Yeah?
- You gonna introduce me?
Oh, right!
Okay guys, guys, wait.
This is Dina.
- Go ahead, introduce yourself.
- Okay...
Hi, I'm Dina.
I've never been
in a film before.
I play the main character.
I don't think she has
a name yet.
But I've watched
tons of movies.
All right, let's get into it.
- Yeah!
- Okay!
Oh, phones! Okay...
It was the middle
of what could be described
as a revolutionary decade
in moving images.
The aftermath of
a world financial collapse
coupled with the rise of
the first affordable
and professional
digital moving image cameras
created an era of
micro-budget filmmaking.
I had $4525.
Action.
So we did what we had to do.
Squeeze in!
We begged,
we borrowed,
we stole.
And before we get too far,
I should tell you
it was bad.
And I was on
a lot of Adderall.
which is probably why
I can't remember
the sound guy's name.
Vita, he's almost here!
Oh, oh, okay!
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
How we doing? We good?
Okay, great!
Great, great, great.
- Forty five seconds!
- Oh shit! Oh, all right. Here we go.
Here we go! We're ready!
We're ready. Okay. Okay.
All right, guys!
Alright, JJ, get the fuck out!
Come on!
Guys! We gotta go,
we gotta go!
Buddy, get out--
We gotta go! Let's go!
Let's--
JJ! Come on, come on!
We gotta go! Okay...
- And...
- Hold on, hold on!
And action!
Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven! Six!
Five! Four! Three!
Two!
One!
I remember I paid
Airplane Andy 50 bucks.
He built the plane in his garage
and taught himself to fly.
He was willing to do
as many takes as I wanted
to make it feel real.
Cut! Whoa!
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Yeah, I mean that--
you can--
You okay?
Are you okay?
- Amazing!
- Vita!
- Okay...
- Vita, um...
We were rolling, right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Okay.
He wants to do it again
even closer,
and then pull out
at the very last second.
But I'm sure I cut
him off after three.
'cause he kept flying closer...
You want to do another?
and closer
and closer.
Hey...
Fuck me, man,
come as close as you want.
Okay. Yeah, let's go.
It was a primal experience.
Did you cum?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Where?
What do you mean?
- Shit, sorry.
- Oh fuck.
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry.
Fuck.
Alright, don't be upset.
- Oh no.
- Hey. Hey...
Hey, hey...
I love you.
I love you too.
God damn it.
Kill you...
I'd read this list online.
The most important things
for a director to be.
And the number one thing
was healthy.
And dad, maybe
it's the sound of the zoom
that makes
you turn your head.
Alright, y'all ready...
No, it's just the light.
Okay, so some questions.
One, are the eventual worms
alive or plastic?
Two, Alexis says
neither are red enough,
but we need more light, so.
And three, we need to talk
about the prosthetic belly.
Vita, what do you think?
Live, live worms.
Use whatever
fucking lights you want.
Can you get me
the morning after pill?
- What?
- The morning after pill.
Don't be dramatic.
I'm serious.
- I'm honored.
- He came in me.
He said something, like,
primal took over.
Oh my God.
Vita! Hey, yo.
- Never...
- Thanks.
Yep.
- By the way, I'm--
- Vita,
- the crowd is sort of--
- Are you guys making a movie?
- Just wanna make sure we have some light.
- I can tell them to stop.
Now?
- Later.
- ...go out and buy one.
Whoa, there it is.
- Happy day.
- Yeah!
Your bike, I just found it.
I don't know whose that--
- How you doing?
- Good.
Hey, ah, why don't you, like--?
Vita, I want to shoot the scene
so that it feels like we're
in her head and looking at her.
And where do you want me
to put the hard drives?
Vita? How are you?
Is that two shots or one shot?
Cash?
A lot of people showed up
to help me make my film.
- Hey darlin'.
- Hey!
But Cash was the only guy
in a 22.6 mile radius
that could have been
a movie star.
And yes, everyone
was in love with him.
Good, how are you?
- There you go.
- Thanks.
- Wow.
- Alright.
Okay, everybody, listen up.
Hey.
Wow, this is amazing.
I know I haven't really been
around much in the last few years,
so it's really nice to
see all your familiar faces.
I wish I could pay you.
But like maybe
you could, maybe?
Well, you know,
there's a lot of beer
and you can have as much
of it as you want,
so that's something.
And this is my producer, Sam.
He will take great care of you.
He will look after
everything you need.
All right. I'll take it
from there. So yeah!
Like she said, just fun,
pretty simple stuff.
We're going to have you all
sort of scattered...
I cast Dina as
the main character in the film
because she seemed
like the perfect muse.
We had the same friends
and boyfriends.
Both of our dads
were larger than life.
She was me,
but beautiful.
And like any great director,
it was my job
to wait patiently
and let the muse take over.
Hey, you know,
I broke up with Billy.
Holy shit.
Finally.
I know.
- That guy's a loser.
- I know.
Good for you.
Make sure your hands,
they're always...
touching something.
Your character's trying to...
ground herself
in this world that she just
feels completely alien in.
She's trying to determine
her boundaries,
the rules, just, you know.
And in the end it's just
going to be her in the trees.
Girl enters and crosses
the frame at a diagonal.
She disappears
behind a sand dune
in the foreground,
at the edge of the frame.
Camera at this point
actually stops operating.
The girl walks away
a considerable distance
and takes her place behind
another sand dune, further away.
The camera then resumes
its shooting
and immediately begins to turn
in a panoramic movement
toward the direction
of which the girl's
left the frame.
Blah, blah, blah...
Moves out of the frame--
Okay, um, instead,
she emerges much more distant.
And so the alienation of
the girl from the camera
exceeds the actual time
which proceeds what would have
presumably been necessary.
What is that from?
Maya Deren.
You emailed it to me.
This is the best part.
She goes on to say
about filmmaking,
"And so, ready or not,
willing or not,
you must come to comprehend
with full responsibility
the world in which
we've now created."
Wow.
Cool.
Well, you didn't send me any lines
or anything, so I memorized that.
Because I'm an actor now!
Everybody who will be in the bar,
let's get into places. Alright.
Watch your step. Yep.
Alright, nice and warm.
Come on.
Hey, I'm not paying you
to hang out.
Get the fuck in there.
Lovely...
- Roll sound.
- Sound speeding.
- Roll camera.
- Rolling.
301 Apple, take one.
Set.
Action!
So the film was
about a young woman.
She lives in a small town.
She's taking care
of her ailing father.
She has a boyfriend.
And a secret lover.
She gets pregnant
and decides to leave home
in search of her mother
who abandoned her at birth.
This is a true story.
This is a true story, except...
and you already know this.
I have two moms.
One of them is a mime.
I was never abandoned.
I did get pregnant, though.
A year and a half
before we shot the film.
I found out
on my 23rd birthday.
My birthday is
November 23rd, so...
Vita.
It was a once in a lifetime year.
Hey.
Go! Everybody to laugh!
Really animated!
Give me party!
On November 24th
I sat at the clinic
and cried and cried.
I asked the nurse,
"Why am I
the only person that I know
who this has happened to?"
And the nurse
looked away from me
and back at me again
and said,
"This happens to a lot of people.
It's just that
nobody talks about it."
Do not hasten to bid me adieu
Just remember that Red River Valley
And the--
Okay, can we cut for a second?
Let's hold the roll.
Dina, you have to
see him by now.
See who?
Can you guys be quiet
for just a second?
See him, your secret lover.
Hey, Gideon, will you wave?
He's an actor.
He drove up from the city.
Oh shit.
Hey, sorry.
I didn't know
you were in this scene.
I'm Dina.
Hey, Gideon.
I'm moving to LA.
Cool.
- Okay, wait, we're gonna go from the--
- Okay.
Come and sit by my side if you love me
Do not hasten to bid me adieu
Just remember that Red River Valley
- Fuck!
- No!
Fuck!
Hey.
Hi, hi.
What are you guys doing?
Can you come here
for a second?
Why?
Come, I missed you. Come here.
Why are you wet?
We got all wet together.
Hi. How are you?
How is the film going?
It's going-- It was going
well before you got here.
What are you wearing?
I like your funny vest.
It's my cameo.
It's the most important
shot of the scene.
Can I take a picture of you?
Baby...
- Sorry...
- Your lens cap is on.
You have to
go back to the bar.
Still rolling, Vita.
- What's happening?
- Okay.
- Hey you gotta go.
- We...
- I gotta get back to work.
- Can you take a break?
- No.
- Is there a lunchtime?
No!
We could go back.
Go-- I just wanted
to have sex with you.
Shut up.
That's so embarrassing.
You're so wet.
Why don't you help?
It'll go by faster.
- If you help out...
- Yeah, let's...
Listen to JJ.
I'm going to help.
Come over here,
you're gonna help.
Alright, we're gonna help.
- Go over there?
- Bobby's over there.
- Hey, Bobby.
- Bobby!
I was sent to help you.
- No, no.
- Hey!
- I'm good. Thank you though.
- Yeah. You're good.
You do your thing.
I'm just going to like...
- No, like I'm--
- Don't touch that.
Don't touch that!
- Sorry.
No. I don't--
He asked me to help with the--
Okay. I will not touch the light
- and I will help over here.
- Stop messing with the equipment.
Why are you yelling at me?
You guys were singing.
What were you singing?
Yeah.
...if you love me
Vita, I'll just be in the scene.
...bid me adieu
Adieu!
Thank you.
Vita!
You know, I don't think
we need this shot.
What about the close-up?
Why don't you--
we get the most shooting.
Are you absolutely sure
you don't need this shot?
Vita!
...Red River Valley
Yeah, I'm sure.
I always wondered if that shot
would have made the film better.
Guess I wonder about
a lot of things.
...bid me adieu
Adieu. Adieu. Adieu.
Just remember that Red River--
Dina, um...
I'm gonna need you to really
dig a little deeper on this one.
I mean, the scream's gotta come from,
like, a really...
- painful place.
- Okay.
Okay, I don't, I don't get it.
Like, where is
this all coming from?
Well, Dina, she's...
emotionally torn.
Okay.
I don't know what
that means, honestly.
Maybe we should try it
from a different angle,
like, shoot from behind,
and then you
can add a better scream.
Yeah, but we have to stay
with her. It's gotta be that.
Dina, maybe try it, like,
you just, like, stubbed your toe,
and it's, like, that one spot,
and you always do it.
No, Sam, it's not...
it's not like
stubbing your toe.
She needs a real life example.
This is after the scene where
she meets her secret lover?
Yeah, but he's not secret.
So is it about the boyfriend?
It's-- we all read the script, right?
I mean, yeah, but
40 pages of mostly prose.
- JJ... Can this please wait?
- Can I just--?
Vita, what if she's, like,
not in pain at all at this point?
- What do you mean?
- Like, what if...
Like, instead, she's...
she's, like,
coming to terms with
who she's, like,
meant to be, you know?
But it's, like,
it's the opposite of that.
I don't know,
it's not like the opposite.
It's just, like, a different--
it's a different take.
- It's, like, the same...
- It's the opposite of that,
I am telling you.
- Okay...
- She's not just cool with it.
Yeah, I'm just, I'm, like,
throwing out an idea.
It could be cool.
We're just gonna,
we're gonna keep, keep going.
Yeah, okay, let's,
let's try it again maybe.
Thank you. Let's keep going.
Why, why does
everything I do just, like,
fucking upset you, up here?
Can we just
get through this scene?
Yeah. I'm just trying to,
like, help out here.
But it's not helping.
Could we, could we, like,
go and talk for a second?
- Right now?
- Yeah.
- You need to talk right now?
- Yeah, yeah.
What are we gonna talk about?
I'd rather just not do this
in front of, like, everyone.
Can you, like, take
just, like, five minutes?
No, I can't.
How can you not see
that I'm busy?
I'm trying to
finish this scene.
Baby.
You make me,
like, feel really bad
being here.
I think I'm just gonna, like,
I'm gonna go back home.
You finish the film,
and yeah, I'll see you later.
Okay, I'm...
I'm gonna be right back.
Just keep, keep it rolling.
No, we can cut.
Cut that.
- Okay...
- Especially when the fucking--
The sexual tension is dripping.
- Bobby.
- Just the regular tension.
His regular attention.
Hey.
Just, Dustin, stop.
You wanted to talk.
Let's talk.
Just try to see
what I'm doing here.
Yeah.
Look, why, why are, why are you
taking this all so fucking seriously?
What do you mean,
why I'm taking it,
why aren't you
taking it seriously?
I'm trying to be,
I'm trying to do this
with my fucking life.
This is me.
Yeah, look, I'm trying to
be here with you, okay?
And you don't even
fucking, like, see me.
I think you should be up here for me.
Yeah, I am up here for you.
Okay, well, you're not really helping
me out on a day like today, okay?
Because you make me feel like
shit in front of, like, your crew!
Okay, well, I'm kind of
dealing with a lot.
Like, Dina's not
fucking screaming.
The crew won't fucking
listen to me
'cause they're all fucking stoned.
You came in me yesterday
and I have to find
a distinct minute
to take the fucking morning after pill
so I don't puke everywhere.
Sorry, I said I was sorry.
You just don't fucking get it.
Like, you are amazing.
Like, you're trying
so fucking hard
to, like, make this fucking art,
but you're like, you're--
You don't even understand how
fucking amazing you are.
You're-- yeah, you're so
much better than me, okay?
- What?
- Yeah, like...
you could do anything
you wanted, okay?
You're capable of...
of, like, everything.
- Like what?
- Like, like, I don't know, like--
You...
You're capable of having, like, a baby.
Like...
Like, you're awesome.
I love you.
And I want to be here for you.
I just want you to,
like, want me with you.
You know?
I don't want to have a baby.
Yeah, I didn't, that's not,
I didn't mean, like, right now.
Vita, where are you going?
Did you know that
after an egg is released
from the ovary,
it is viable for up to 24 hours?
And the morning after pill
can work for 72.
Unless the sperm
and the egg collide first.
I didn't know that then.
I was an idiot.
And convinced that
I was the only one
taking the film seriously.
So, let's do one more scream
before we roll.
When you're ready.
After the egg was released
from my ovaries,
but before I took
the morning after pill,
we filmed this scene
where the main character
screams.
It was meant to represent
the moment that
she became pregnant.
It was at this
moment inside of me
that the sperm
and the egg collided too.
So, the film was about
a young woman
who was taking care
of her ailing father.
She gets pregnant and decides
to escape her hometown in search
of her mother who
abandoned her at birth.
This is a true story.
This is a true story except
I have two moms,
and I had two abortions.
Hi, I'm Vita and
I'm the writer-director
of the feature-length film
Always, All Ways.
Here I am in
my childhood bedroom,
aka my editing suite.
I moved back home
a few weeks ago
to complete the first of three shoots
over the course of nine months.
I've been reviewing the footage
and it looks amazing.
We've decided to start
this crowdfunding campaign
with amazing rewards
for people who donate
to finance
the next two shoots,
which will cost
approximately $18,000.
I want to get as many people
involved in this vision as possible
because your mark on my film
is what I'm looking for.
Okay, cut!
Tail, slating!
Bring it.
You want me to cut this scene?
Cut it.
- Mark.
- Guess what?
- What?
The film is officially listed!
No turning back now, dude.
Look at that!
No way.
- Whoa, we did it!
- Beautiful.
Cool!
Okay and then we--
Take some time to recover
and take, you know,
just take some deep breaths and...
and you crawl over to the worm.
- Okay, crawl over...
- See it?
You pick it up, you hold it.
You know, deal with it,
feel it.
You know, take it in.
- Her nets are going to rip--
- Quiet.
What's the point
of the worm again?
I don't know.
I think it's about her
being pregnant or something.
The film was filled
with thin motifs,
like earthworms,
and a bunch of other
ass-oteric images.
I didn't give a shit
about the audience.
I liked the earthworms
'cause I had read
that they hold
both sexes inside them.
They are beholden to no one.
Wait, Bobby,
did you move the light?
I told him to do that
because it's just,
it's a really shitty bathroom.
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Raise your hand
if you like the light.
I just think it looks better.
- Um, Vita?
- Yeah?
What should we do next?
I don't know,
just fucking go with it.
Okay...
Actually, the more telling
pattern that haunted the set
was that of near death.
First there was the plane.
Then...
the deer.
The lightning.
The goblin weed.
The drama on the pier.
And then there was...
the night.
With Cash.
And the whiskey.
You can dance tonight
if you want.
Whatever you want, darlin'.
Is that the best mask
you could get for me?
It is, it is.
They didn't have much
of a selection, I guess.
With the mustache falling off
and everything?
Keep doing what you're doing.
Wait for my cue.
Get rowdy.
Action!
Darlin'.
Darlin', darlin'.
How's it going?
Did you hear the news?
Did she tell you?
You didn't tell her?
Baby, we're having a baby.
We're having a baby...
Having a baby?
This is great, Cash.
Keep going.
Can I get another?
Yeah, let's pause.
You want to get him
a beer and a shot? Sam?
Come on, brother.
Why did you give him
more to drink?
- Are you joking?
- I didn't give him anything.
They are already drunk.
- How the fuck is this on me?
- Guys, guys, guys. Hey!
What is the problem?
It's fine.
I know these guys.
We're good, we're just having fun.
It's going to be okay.
Don't-- just calm down.
The prosthetic belly is--
Whatever this decision is,
can you just make yourself?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Action!
Fuck!
Don't stop.
Goddamit.
Motherfucker.
Where was I?
Baby.
Baby?
Baby. We're having
a motherfucking baby.
We're having a fucking baby.
It's probably going to be
a little fucking girl.
We're having
a fucking baby girl!
Get in here, motherfuckers.
The prodigal son returns!
Go, go, go!
What's going on?
We're having a fucking baby.
- What?
- We're having a fucking baby girl.
- We're having a fucking baby.
- We're having a baby.
We're havin'
a fuckin' baby guys.
We're havin' a baby!
We're havin' a fuckin' baby!
We're havin' a baby?
We're havin' a baby!
We're havin' a baby...
I remember thinking
I was brilliant.
So that's everything except
those lights upstairs, right? Okay.
Alright. Yeah.
You can give him a little time.
You can come up there.
- Alright.
- Thanks man.
Hey, um, dinner's almost ready
and I got some more
beers for the guys.
- Great.
- And maybe us.
Yeah, and us.
For sure us.
Don't let them steal a bottle.
We're having a baby!
Congratulations.
But I knew
I called out to him.
Wait, where are you going?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Wait! Stop! Where are you going?
Cash!
Stop! Don't drive!
Come back!
Or maybe I didn't call out at all.
I don't remember anything
after that.
Except the beans.
And the music.
We were all so hungry.
Hello?
19.5 miles outside of town.
They found Cash's truck
wrapped around a telephone pole.
And the only person
I told was Sam.
Maybe we should
just wait for Cash.
Yeah.
But I think JJ can pass.
I mean, with the jacket
and boots, it's probably fine.
I think it's fine.
So you just let me know...
Yeah.
I mean, I'm kind of tired,
so I don't want to hold it up.
Yeah, I mean, I think
we'll do a couple.
And see.
About how high, or how low?
- Okay...
- Can you even breathe in there?
Well, the only way to do
the scene is with the mask on.
Can you put your arm
over her shoulder?
No, come on, JJ.
Like this.
Like you mean it.
Hang on her, JJ.
Cover her almost.
Man, can you fucking just--
What is going on?
Why are you--
Can we just be a
little bit professional?
This is really annoying
for me to have to
stop my conversation,
to be having this
conversation with you.
It's really annoying
when you touch the boom.
I didn't touch--
You touched me with a boom.
- You never touch the camera.
- That's so fucking weird of you, man.
- I can...
- Just be professional! It's like--
Have we forgotten
how to do our job?
You touched me with
the fucking boom.
- I didn't do shit.
- Stop, stop, stop.
- Stop yelling at people.
- I know we're fucking tired--
- Please Vita. V!
- But let's all be fucking
professional for a second.
We are all here for your movie.
It was an accident.
He didn't mean to hit you.
He's stupid, he's not an asshole.
You good?
I think I drank
too much last night.
Hey, Sam?
Sam...
What are we doing now?
Hi.
Sam told us what happened with Cash.
- Uh-huh.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- So...
besides the equipment...
and us...
you can still shoot
the rest of your movie.
I remember thinking I was brilliant.
Come get this fucker!
I wanted them to be wasted.
I wanted it to be real.
And...
I guess in this moment...
their performances
were brilliant.
Or at least realistic.
We're having a baby!
Wasted.
And even though
he didn't die...
And you're trying
to get him over here.
No amount of real
is worth someone's life.
Sam...
And then...
Yeah, look back at her.
You alright?
When I was in
the sixth grade...
my dad told me he had HIV.
He'd had it my whole life.
And I didn't tell anyone.
Maybe because saying it out loud
would have made it true.
Or because...
Every person I saw like him
was a character in a movie.
How long was I asleep?
And they all died.
Where is everyone?
I guess they're really gone.
But my dad didn't die.
And so I cast him in my film.
As the father of the main character.
We can film it on this.
What is that?
Your dad gave it to me.
I already got some
pretty cool shots on it.
No, absolutely not.
This is the...
this is the most important scene
of the entire film.
She is saying goodbye
to her dead dad
before she gets
the fuck out of town.
And if we don't get it, it's not
gonna make fucking sense.
It's not gonna be good.
When did being good
ever stop you?
Ah f--
Now come on, let's shoot this scene.
So all I did was lay
in the grave for two hours
contemplating death for nothing?
This is so fucking stupid.
Hello?
Is that a real grave?
You wanna hit?
Stop!
We share everything
on this hill.
When I was your age,
one of us just stood up
on a park bench
and spun around
and pointed north.
We had to get out of the city.
We didn't want
to be with those people.
Live with them.
We certainly didn't want to be
buried near them either, huh?
Dad, she doesn't
want to hear your story.
Did you hear something?
Are you sure
you guys are related?
I know. How could somebody
so beautiful have a father like me?
But I'm sure. I'm sure.
She didn't tell you
how her moms conceived her?
- Dad!
- No.
Don't mind her, I'll tell you.
She had a baby...
and her mom told her
she could...
Really?
Yup.
Imagine growing up your whole life,
people telling you,
"Make a movie!
You got a great fucking story!"
Shit.
That fucking great story is that
your moms are lesbians
and your dad is gonna die.
Maybe you should make a film.
Believe me, I tried.
I bought that
video camera for her birth.
I tried all that.
It was misunderstood.
So I just gave it up.
Well, that's a shame.
Nah.
It's a terrible world out there, girl.
But the strong women
said to the faggots,
"There are two important
things to remember
about the coming revolution.
The first is that we will
get our asses kicked.
The second is
that we will win."
Did you write that?
No. A friend did. He's dead.
But it always reminded me
of us up here on this hill.
So the film was about a young woman.
Who was taking care
of her dying father.
She gets pregnant
and decides to leave home
in search of her mother,
who abandoned her at birth.
This is a true story.
Except...
I have two moms.
I had two abortions.
And my dad survived.
Okay. So that's a wrap-wrap.
Wrap!
I'll probably take
a look at it and see if...
And I think I made
the main character
live this parallel life to mine
because I didn't know how
to talk about these things.
Or I didn't trust the rules of cinema
to do them justice.
- Dancing is my life.
- Good!
- That was so awkward.
- Or...
- You get to dance again tomorrow.
- I was afraid to.
Still...
I wish I could show you
something that is true.
Did you know that most
filmmakers spend their entire lives
making some version
of the same movie.
And I wonder...
every time...
are they this alone?
Okay! Let's go see Mama.
Boop!
You're so pretty.
What's your film about?
Hey...
Hey!
You're naked.
So are you!
Go get the fuck outta here!
Wait, we can't take his truck.
Just get in.
I mean, I should pee.
Yeah, me too.
Oh God!
I just decided.
I am going to go away
after we finish the film.
Yeah, there's this school.
I could take some film classes.
And it's near my dad's
so I can take care of him too.
And I need to stop smoking.
What?
I don't think we're gonna
finish the film.
Shut up.
Come on.
Come on, dance with me.
You don't need to tell me
what happened, man.
I get it.
You know I got pregnant too.
While you were gone.
But fuck that.
Making this film has been
fucking freeing.
A real resolution for me.
Come on.
Fuck, come on!
- What are we doing?
- Just come here.
Okay.
- Ready?
- Okay.
And a-one.
And a-two.
And a-three!
I mean tonight was fun but...
you know, I want more than
dudes who just want to fuck us
and have their babies.
You know, we've got to
finish making the film.
You were always next to me.
Falling in love
with making something.
No matter how treacherous,
biting,
cruel.
And so, ready or not,
willing or not,
we must come to comprehend
with full responsibility
the world in which
we've now created.
It's the best thing
you ever said to me.
That was actually
the best thing
you ever said to me.
It's going to be okay.
You okay?
We'll do that again.
Okay.
I think it's going.
Okay, start walking.
Same with your legs,
can you put your legs over there?
Give me...
just like out.
Hi.
What are you doing?
Just looking for planes.
Are you a ghost?
Boo!
Shouldn't you be going
to the hospital or something?
I read this story once
in the newspaper
about this kid who had to be
born in the hospital.
See, there was this lady.
She kept trying to have babies.
But every time she had a baby,
it would die in her stomach.
So the grandmother said,
"Oh, I've already had babies.
I can have another one."
So that's what they did.
They took the sperm and
they put it inside the egg,
and then they took the egg
and they put it
in the grandmother.
And when it was ready
to come out,
they took her to the hospital
and they cut her open
and took the baby out.
Whoa.
Yeah.
It was really cool.
Except since it was born
from its grandmother
it had, like, old lady blood.
So it was like an old person
and a young person in one.
Anyway, that probably
won't happen to you
because you're not an old person.
And what am I?
In this life, ideally, happy.
You want a hit?
Cut!
- What?
- Cut!
Why did you stop us?
We were just getting going.
Dad, she's pregnant.
You can't offer her weed.
You know, I don't even know
if the film is about
her being pregnant.
Have you ever
seen a pregnant person?
Look at that belly.
What do you mean?
It looks good.
It looks like a pillow.
No, it doesn't.
- It does.
- Totally.
Why didn't anyone tell me?
Does it even matter?
Ah, shit!
It is a pillow.
Hang on, this is not
a joke, Dad.
My whole fucking life is
riding on this movie
so I need the belly to look
like a fucking pregnancy belly.
Why didn't we
have this conversation
like nine months ago, Alexis?
I think people tried to.
I'm scared.
Has the belly looked
fake the whole time?
I like it.
It's like an allegory.
Like a metaphor.
It's like an act of creation.
Pillow is child,
soft, weird, hot air,
cumulus, myth,
way up and way down.
What does it all mean?
The belly should be realistic.
Like, she really is pregnant.
I feel like it's depends what
movie you want to make,
if the show is
based in reality, right?
What?
Where are you from?
You can't show everything!
Reality has never,
will never be safe.
Not for me, not for you.
Reality is not art.
Art is this.
Up in the clouds,
floating to the future.
Yeah, you just gotta explain
to the audience why you
chose to use a pillow.
Yeah and this one director
who used to...
And I remember this so well.
It's just for a moment
I stopped caring.
'Cause it was so beautiful.
Just to be making
something with people.
And I wish I had stayed right here.
So...
is this movie about pregnancy?
I named the main character Anne Marie
because I had read somewhere
that it means mother
and daughter in one.
And the film
had many endings.
But by the time
Anne Marie finally gives birth,
which is a scene we actually shot
before the entire crew quit.
we were supposed
to understand
that she's not giving birth to a baby.
Instead,
and please hold your laughter,
the audience has
come to understand...
Action.
that she is giving birth to herself.
And after meticulously
cutting together the montage,
in which Anne Marie
gives birth to herself
in all the places
she's already been,
I went to the post office
and I mailed the film
to as many film festivals
as I could afford to.
Maybe a hundred or...
fifty, or twenty, or...
twelve.
And...
and I went home.
And I waited.
And here's the real plot twist.
Push!
The film was not accepted
into a single festival.
After I received that
final rejection, I pissed blood.
See, despite doing everything that
they tell young filmmakers to do
despite begging
and borrowing and stealing,
alienating my friends and family,
and writing from my experience
in crowdfunding,
and almost
fucking killing someone.
If you look the film up online
right now, it is considered abandoned.
And my film was never seen
by anyone.
And last night I stayed up
watching my film again and again.
And I texted a friend.
Why am I the only person I know
who this has happened to?
And they must have looked
away from their phone.
And back again.
And said to me.
Are you still there?
So this is my first film.
I thought that writing it out
and filming it
and casting an actress
to play me was going to
make it all feel better,
but I never thought about it ending.
I've tried so many times
to tell this story,
but if I could not get here,
to you.
I would abort the project.
Because abortion is...
an understanding.
But abandoned...
unseen.
Look what you did.
I feel like
I'm doing a bad job.
How does this film end, Zia?
What do we do now?
Okay.
Hey...
Jessie.
Hi. Are you ready to move on?
- Yeah.
- Come on, let's go.
Okay.
Yeah.
It doesn't end.
But you will make
something again.
With people you care about,
and who care about you.
And it will be hard
and embarrassing.
But eventually you will
stop losing sleep.
And stop worrying.
You will make things from joy.
And not despair.
Even films that should not be films.
And every time you will
give birth to yourself.
And every time you will find
a new version of the truth.
Again and again
and again.
Vita.
Birthday please.
November 23rd.
Oh.
Happy belated.
23 on 23.
That is a once in a lifetime year.
Alright.
So how are you feeling?
Okay, I just want to remind you
that you are absolutely
within your rights to be here.
And if you've been having
any new doubts
since you signed the consent,
you are also absolutely
within your rights
to leave this room
without this procedure.
So, may I ask you,
are you having any doubts?
- No.
- Okay.
Then I'd like to tell you something.
It's something I tell everyone.
What we're about to do here
is remove a small group of cells
that could not exist
outside of your body.
I just want to be sure
we dissolve any fear
you might have
about regret, okay?
Okay.
So I'm going to talk you
through absolutely everything.
But first,
would you like a tissue?
Okay.
That's better?
Alright, so go ahead
and lean back
and put your feet into the,
into the stirrups here for me.
Great. And then just
scooch down
the table just a little.
And...
go ahead and place
your hands right here.
Perfect.
Oops.
Okay.
Cold hands coming through.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
It is so cool
to see you as an adult.
I mean, you wouldn't
remember me.
You were just that tiny baby.
I was a midwife's assistant
back then.
I was at your birth.
I helped deliver you.
I'm sorry. Would you like me to be quiet?
Some people do prefer quiet.
Did you pick this music?
It reminds me of
my Enya days.
It's a really great choice.
Speculum.
That's the thing that's
shaped like a duck bill.
You know,
the story of your conception
was really pretty extraordinary.
It's a town myth.
You're going to feel something
like a small pinch now?
Actually, would you tell it to me?
This story of your conception?
Okay.
Where should we begin?
First, your father
finds a 35mm film canister.
And then he jerks off into it.
And then he puts on the top
and puts it into
his breast pocket.
He puts on his coat
and goes out into a snowstorm.
He makes sure
to keep his hand
over his heart
to keep that canister warm.
At the top of the hill,
he knocks on a cabin door
and your moms answer.
They take that
35mm canister from him
and slam the door.
And then they load the contents
into a small plastic syringe.
The kind that's usually used
to feed baby cats.
And then one of
them uses that syringe
to inject the contents
into her cervix.
And...
nine months later
you were born.
And that's a true story.
So...
are you ready for a loud noise?
Good.
You know
all you need
is a body to create.
But what you create
that is up to you.