A FILM BY SUSUMU HANI
But isn't it expensive?
Don't worry. I have money.
Everybody does this, you know.
- And if they find out?
- Find out what?
That we are underage.
Let's do it some other time.
But we're almost there.
- Well...
- Well what?
- You know...
- What is it?
- This is my first time.
- Really?
Do you want to see nude models?
Your fate is written in your palm.
Come on in, you won't regret it.
This line shows that you
are very sensitive.
Your love life is very
demanding.
When did your skin
become so beautiful?
You don't make it
with me only.
- You think it will work?
- Don't be afraid.
Do you have big breasts?
INFERNO OF FIRST LOVE
My name is Shun, what's yours?
I'm Nanami.
Short time?
Yes.
Want a bath?
No, thank you.
Make yourself comfortable.
Won't you kiss me?
I'll get undressed.
Aren't you cold?
No, I'm used to it.
Used to it?
I'm a nude model.
But...
What?
Nothing.
What? Say it.
This is like a dream.
You can do whatever you like.
I'll close the curtains.
What is it?
It's tickling.
You may.
Where are you going?
I'm thirsty.
"Attention! Fire risk!
No smoking in bed!"
This is really your first time?
Not even with a prostitute?
Do I look like that?
You're not very sure of yourself.
You're only young once
So if you're a man
Doh-
do what the others can't do
What the others can't do?
Don't we all do the same thing?
Why do you close your eyes
when you kiss me?
I'm shy.
Don't you want to see,
if I have my eyes shut?
- No.
- But you are sure of yourself.
No, I'm not.
But you had a girlfriend,
didn't you?
No.
- When was your first love?
- First love?
- Do you want to talk for a while?
- Talk?
I want to know more about you.
About me?
My father died when I was
seven years old.
The year I first went to school.
My mother married a boxer
and left me alone.
They didn't have a real
wedding ceremony.
The night she left, she said to me:
"Forgive me!"
I forgave her.
When I was little, I was naughty.
They sent me to reform school.
People said I was "hopeless".
Then a couple named Otagaki
took me away.
These kind of people are called
benefactors.
They didn't adopt me,
but I call them father and mother.
My stepfather is a goldsmith.
I was his apprentice.
Now I'm his journeyman.
I am a good goldsmith.
But I'm very reserved.
Therefore my father sent me
to laugh lessons.
It was supposed to make me happier.
"All right now! All together!"
What do you do, usually?
Usually?
On your days off.
Go to the park and feed
the pigeons.
I am grateful to my father.
Someday I'm going to have
to pay back my debt to him.
After all, I'm kind of a criminal, and
though I'm not his own child,
he raised me.
Today, both of them went on a trip,
and therefore I have a day off.
I've got a friend, too.
A friend?
Yes, a little girl friend.
Once she asked if she could hide between my
legs while she was playing hide and seek.
She has a lot of freckles.
Since that day, we've been
friends.
She was the only friend I ever
had before you.
I was born in Shizuoka.
I came to Tokyo with a group
of employees.
First, I worked in a shoe factory.
But they didn't pay enough.
"Why's a girl's mother...
like a girl's girdle?"
"Because they both stick to her."
Since the money wasn't enough,
I found a job at a nude studio.
A friend of mine knew the owner.
Mama-sen told me
that it's pretty hard work.
And that everything depends
on my figure.
I was frightened at first.
But everybody
told me I was really good.
To be honest,
I really thought I had a nice body.
Then I acquired some steady customers.
Like Mr. Ankokuji - he has a beard.
He says I'm the best in Shinjuku.
He knows everybody.
He looks stern,
but when he smiles
his whole face lights up.
But don't worry, he means nothing
special to me.
But a nude modeling job can't be
all that nice.
People always think it's a very bad job.
But I don't care about that.
We're good girls.
See you again, Nanami.
Going? Well, come back soon.
- See how much money I've saved?
- Yes.
I think it's a lot of money.
Well, we haven't much time left.
Shun, do you want me?
Would you like to try again?
What is it?
What do you think?
Do I look funny?
Everything feels so curious to me.
I feel embarrassed.
You're holding back, aren't you?
Shall we try again some time?
Yes.
- Aren't I attractive?
- What?
Aren't I sexy?
Very sexy.
We're going now.
Sorry, wrong door.
I'm sorry. Next time I'll be better.
I was sort of mixed up today.
Do you like me?
Yes.
Then kiss me.
SURPASS YOURSELF
It's cold today, isn't it?
When I was young they never gave
us much money.
Only two yen for a whole year's bonus
they'd give us.
We used to go to Asakusa to
eat Sushi.
But one piece of Sushi cost five Rin.
A whole plate was eight sen,
but it was good.
It is expensive enough now.
I smell something burning.
Have a look,
I found this in Shun's pocket.
What is it?
It's a toy.
Isn't he a bit too old for toys?
Shun's improved a lot.
Is that so?
Momi.
Elder brother.
Kitaro, the devil in the graveyard?
No, that's Enormous-Eyes.
He was funny, he was.
Long-haired Lion.
I see - the lion, and Kitaro, the devil...
That looks like a sling.
Go! Go! Go!
My pony, go!
Let's do some riddles.
Who asks first?
Me.
When you peel a cabbage
the core comes out.
What comes outwith an onion?
When you peel an onion...
You peel an onion...
then the core comes out.
Sorry - please try again.
You're no good at it.
What comes out? Come on, tell me.
I'm getting married tomorrow.
Come on, Momi darling. Let's go.
Watch it.
See.
Be careful, there's broken
glass lying around.
Let's take this way,
it's safer.
Take care, Momi.
Hey you! Wait a minute! Stop!
Child molester!
- Stop!
- What happened?
I have seen everything,
dirty bastard!
Child molester!
Hold him!
Stop him!
Keep quiet!
You child molester, keep quiet!
Beat the shit out of him!
Come up!
Hold him!
Dirty bastard! We have to teach
him a lesson!
Hey, you!
What have you done?
You're a real scumbag!
The guy did something to a
little girl at the graveyard.
Enough now!
Don't go too far with it!
It was a child.
He must be a pervert.
It's of no use to beat him.
Calm down!
Are you Mrs. Otagaki?
Please sit down.
And you are Shun?
Sit down please.
Please look at me.
Please look this way.
I hear you are not feeling so good.
Are you still worried about yesterday?
No need to be afraid.
Today I'm going to hypnotize you.
The association-therapy will work
better that way.
Just relax and tell me
whatever you want to say.
- I'm not the police, so just relax.
- The doctor only wants to help you.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Just sit down and relax.
Sit over there please.
I'll give you an injection
to make you relax.
- Ms. Sugano.
- Yes, doctor.
Please keep still!
This won't hurt you.
Soon you'll start feeling fine.
Now concentrate on both your hands.
After I've counted to five
they'll become light and will float.
Ready? One...
See, they're lighter already.
Two...
Three...
They're getting lighter and lighter.
Four. They are floating.
Five. See, higher and higher.
They are floating.
See how easily they rise?
See? Higher and higher.
They float higher and higher.
Higher and higher.
That's good.
More, more...
they float free now.
Now, I'm going to count to three.
When I clap my hands.
Your entire body
will be completely relaxed...
And you will enter a deep hypnosis.
One, two, three, go!
Now watch this carefully.
Your eyelids are getting heavy.
Getting heavier and heavier.
So heavy that your eyes are closing.
Your eyes are closing.
Closing, little by little.
Now, they are closed.
Now you see a screen in front of you.
It's like a movie screen.
Watch it carefully.
When I count to five,
you'll see it.
One, two:
You can see something white.
Three: It is a white screen...
Four, five: Now you see it clearly.
Now when I count to five
you'll see a movie.
One... two... three... it's begun.
Four... you can see it clearly.
Five... everything is very clear now.
Tell me what you see on the screen.
Tell me what you see.
Pigeons.
Pigeons? In a park?
Yes.
I see a girl.
A girl... who?
Mo...
What's the matter?
Look at the screen!
Look carefully now.
Tell me, do you see something?
You see something?
What is on the screen?
I've seen what you've done!
Pervert!
- Child molester!
- He did it with a little girl!
What did you see?
Look carefully now.
You have to look at the screen again.
Now, you see something again.
Tell me what you see.
- She must pee.
- She must pee?
Can't you see anything else?
Somebody's peeking.
Go on.
- My face.
- Your own face?
What else?
What's the matter?
Look at the screen!
You can see everything very clearly.
A very clear image now!
Look at the screen!
You can see everything very clearly!
Everything is very clear!
No...
I can't see.
She's gone out now.
Shun-darling.
I'm afraid.
Shun-Darling...
She's gone out.
Look carefully now.
Shun-darling.
What do you see? Tell me.
The pigeon's dead.
She's gone out now.
Graveyard...
- I see it.
- Shun-darling!
It's getting smaller and smaller.
Smaller and smaller...
Smaller...
I'm a little boy.
Father...
Shun-darling!
She's gone out now.
Father's coming.
No!
Shun-darling!
She's gone out.
What are you doing?
He's touching me!
No...
Don't do that - stop it!
No, no!
I'm afraid!
Stop, Stop it!
Doctor, stop it!
Please stop! Let him!
Stop! Stop it now!
Doctor, please stop!
When you peel a cabbage,
out comes the core.
What comes out with an onion?
Why don't you come in?
Come on in!
- Come on in!
- No, I don't want to get in a raid.
- Why don't you come and look?
- Next time!
You want to join the university?
Yeah, I'd like to join Todai university.
State universities are better.
Will you pass the entrance exam
of Todai university?
I don't know.
First of all I have to be accepted
for the exam.
What will you do at the university?
I'll study, of course! Read books
and so on.
They take their mothers to
the exam? That's weird.
- Yes, it is.
- What kind of mothers are they?
It's very cold!
How long are you going
to hang around here?
You know what naked girls do to you.
I'm sorry.
Wait a moment, your dishes!
I like Tokyo University.
- What's the first thing you'll do, if you pass?
- I don't know.
Lots of things - but first
I want to relax.
I know how they feel.
I'll take my child, too, to register
at the university.
You got a boy that big?
Yes, but I'm not married.
- Nanami, you're wanted.
- Yes, coming.
This Mister again?
Maine gachameki gachakuchane.
- What?
- Repeat it.
Maine...
Maine gachameki gachakuchane.
Ain't easy!
It's Aomori dialect.
A real magic word,
if you want to improve your
articulation.
Here, 1,000 Yen.
What? Only a thousand?
Give me another thousand.
- When you undress.
- Another thousand.
- Two thousand?
- Yes.
- Here's the second bill.
- Thanks.
Don't you undress completely
for two thousand?
Wait! Not that fast!
- Lift one leg.
- Higher.
Higher!
- Like this?
- Higher!
That's obscene. I won't.
Come here.
- Get this off.
- Pull it down to here.
- Like this?
- No, a little lower.
No, I can't.
But, that's your job!
It's against the law
to show pubic hair.
- Then what did we pay for?
- It's not my fault.
Keep your hands off!
You're not allowed to touch.
- But I like to.
- No, hands off.
- Hi.
- How is it?
- What?
Ma)! I 10in you?
We didn't call you.
If you do it for free.
No. Naturally I'll get paid.
Well, show a lot.
All you want.
Is it all right with you?
No, not at all. I'll leave, then.
You leave?
It's all right isn't it?
You're no good anyway.
I'll do better.
Let's go, then.
You've got a nice body.
- Come nearer.
- Let's decide on a price.
- That's all right. Come on.
- How much will you pay?
Shut up, and let's go.
How much did you give her?
You've got to show it.
One thousand yen.
How much was it?
One thousand.
It can't be.
- Ask her, then.
- Then I can't show you.
How much then?
_ I'm going.
- Okay.
How much, then?
- Show a lot and we pay a lot.
- No, you have to decide first.
We want to see first.
- Someone's there.
- I didn't hear anything.
Who is it?
I found something.
How would this be?
Very well.
It was hard to find it.
Lay it there.
What was wrong with the tiger skin?
It looked better.
Aren't you cold?
Isn't this a nice kimono?
It looks good.
- By the way...
- What?
Otoki's manager asks for money.
- But I paid him last time.
- Yes.
Tell him I'll take care of it.
Is it true that one of them is a
lady doctor?
I don't know.
In Germany I hear they use rawhide.
They wrap up naked girls in it, then...
They leave her there.
Then they wet it, then...
It shrinks and gets tighter, so tight...
That sometimes her eyes can pop right out.
It looks good.
- You look especially good today.
- The chair should stand here.
- Who will win?
- The blonde will get the other!
I hear that Ilse Koch died.
When?
Last fall - she hanged herself
in some women's prison.
She had this magnificent whip.
It was made from a bull's penis.
In the concentration camps she cutoff
the foreskin of prisoners...
whenever she found one
with an especially big cock.
If you peel a cabbage,
the core comes out.
What comes out with an onion?
When you peel a cabbage
the core comes out.
What comes outwith an onion?
NA-NA-MI
You - come here.
Come in for a while.
What do you do - undress?
How much?
Two thousand.
TWO?
- For two?
- Sure!
It's a good offer.
Let me go.
Wanna know, what he wants.
Come in, its fun. I'll be nice to you.
- Come on in.
- It's cheap.
We show you something beautiful.
- You're a man, aren't you?
- Come on in.
They say, if you pour ink on it,
it will get harder.
A man without a hard-on
is no man.
- Let's have a drink.
- Yes, please.
Who are you?
I'm Nanami's friend.
A friend?
It's backwards!
I don't want it.
What are you laughing at?
I don't laugh.
Where are you taking Nanami?
I watched you.
You wouldn't understand.
Mr. Ankokuji often dreams about fires.
Fires?
Don't you ever dream about fires?
No. I don't.
You're still young.
You still believe in love.
Don't you?
No, I can't.
But I can believe in Nanami's
genfleness.
But you have a wife, haven't you?
She's as cold as ice.
I've often thought of setting her afire
when she's asleep.
That's cruel.
But I gave up.
Now I'm in love with the scars
on Nanami's back.
They're mine - she made them for me.
Think I'm joking?
Shut up! Don't make fun of me!
- Bastard!
- Stop it, Shun, no!
Baked sweet potatoes!
Are you cold, Miss?
How about one? They're fresh.
Shall we?
Thank you.
How much?
50 Yen for you, otherwise it's 70.
Try them - they're good.
The best way to bake potatoes
is never to burn them.
You don't look very happy, young man.
You want to try this one - it's good.
Doesn't it look good?
A little while ago I was here
and this bar girl...
I offered her some potatoes.
She said she wanted hers raw.
So I asked her...
Did she want mine?
We laughed a lot about that.
- Here.
- No, thanks, we have to go.
- You have to go?
- Yes. See you.
Thank you very much.
- Would a bowl of noodles be all right?
- Two bowl of noodles, please.
Coming.
Was that the same man
you mentioned before?
Yes.
What does he do?
He's an executive in a large company.
Don't you eat?
I'm not hungry.
Let's go to the movies next Sunday.
What's playing?
"Rustlers on the Range".
I don't like westerns.
You've got a nice handbag.
It was a present.
From that man?
Yes.
Are you still mad,
because of the other day?
Not at all.
Next Sunday -
Next Sunday I have another
photo session.
I'm sure you'd rather be home.
Could you girls smile a bit more?
Your boyfriend's probably waiting.
Hey blondie, look over here.
What do you think of her?
Got breasts like homemade bread.
Does your wife know?
Know about what?
That you're here.
Funny, and you're
just married.
I know but I can't help it.
It's like an addiction.
Nanami, there's your gentleman
friend over there.
Daddy!
I got some firewood.
Mama cook the fish.
Let's have a big smile now.
Let's go on.
What did you want please?
Do you want to talk to the teacher?
- Excuse me.
- What do you want?
It's about the basement.
Well?
Isn't there the photo club
of Mr. Ankokuji?
No, I don't know anyone
by that name.
In the basement.
It's a ballet practice room.
I'm not lying, ask them.
Has it always been ballet?
For about a week now.
But before it was Mr. Ankokuji
wasn't it?
Maybe so.
Don't you know?
Why are you asking so much?
Oh. It's you.
What is it?
You're Nanami who was in
that show last week?
Where is Mr. Ankokuji?
I'm looking for him too.
Tell me what you want -
I'm his friend.
I had an appointment
with him here.
Really?
Yes really.
I don't know where he is.
Me too. This is the only place
I know about.
Bastard! So, he's run out.
And he hasn't even paid me
for the bear skins.
The record for lonely people!
Only 100 Yen.
All possible answers recorded.
What's this one?
This one has fairytales and true stories.
And this one is for old people...
and for singles. You can answer
with "Yes" or "No".
I'm not lonely.
That sounds good.
Records for lonely people!
100 Yen apiece.
Buy them here.
- You sell them?
- Yes!
What does this one contain?
True stories.
This one is for when you're lonely.
- Then the record talks with me?
- Yes.
Do you make a lot with it?
No. Money doesn't matter.
A beautiful girl like you should
be a model or something.
No. I'm very lonely myself.
Thus I try to help other
lonely people.
- I'd like to listen to that record.
- You're welcome.
I understand.
This is very interesting.
I understand, I understand very well.
That sounds good.
You're so right. I agree completely.
MY BOSS IS AN IDIOT
That's an interesting story.
Now I feel better.
That's really great.
- Don't scatter them all over the place.
- Stop making such a fuss.
Look at that crazy man.
Hey, crazy noodleman!
- Who's that?
- The noodleman!
Now he's completely out of his mind!
Shun-darling!
She's gone out now.
NA-NA-MI
Am I sexy?
Why do you close your eyes
when you kiss?
Oh, it's you is it?
Hello there, Nanami.
What happened?
This gentleman ate and now
he won't pay for it.
It's one hundred and fifty yen.
You seem to know him -
would you do something about it?
Well I can't say that I know him.
I'll pay you back later.
We have hardly anything
ourselves, you see.
- 150?
- Yes.
Is it true that that's a wig?
That's right.
Where was it made?
Made in Japan.
It's nice - may I touch it?
Please.
Very well-made.
Isn't it?
I didn't know that it wasn't real.
I wanted to make a wig out of
my own hair.
It's nice. You could sell it for a lot.
Really? I'll look into it.
Hallo.
May I speak to Shun please?
I see, when will he be back?
I'm just a friend of his.
Stop, don't do that. He's a sexjack!
Call the police!
Sorry, my joke went too far.
You'd better watch what you're doing.
Come in, please.
Where will we sit?
Let's sit here and watch TV.
I don't like to watch.
TV is no good, is it?
Is noodles all right?
Two noodles, please.
THE VICE OF MASTURBATION
Will you join the university, Daisuke?
Machi and Professor Daige expect
a lot from you.
I'm no good.
But yes, you're brilliant.
I envy your schooling.
It's not all that great,
always studying.
Been back home recently?
No, I don't have the time, you know.
And I can't afford the fare.
How about you?
I went back briefly
during summer vacation.
See Reiko?
Well... let's not talk about it.
I understand.
Shun!
Have you been here for a long time?
I didn't see you sitting there.
I'm sorry.
It's alright.
Come on over here.
May I introduce Daisuke to you?
He were schoolmates back home.
He's the only one of us to go to
high school.
This is Shun.
How do you do?
He's taking us to the School Festival.
What am I supposed to do there?
He's showing a movie that he made.
I'm in the Film Club.
Want to show off?
You're very rude.
Why?
You weren't polite.
I can't pretend things I don't feel.
I'm sorry I invited you.
I should have come alone.
O-n-i-o-n!
Let's go over there.
Where?
Join Daisuke.
Go ahead then.
The School Festivals are all right...
But that doesn't mean you have to
run around with him all the time.
We could have come by ourselves.
I'm not going without Daisuke.
But we don't have to spend
all the time with him.
Look at that short skirt.
She's got too much makeup.
She sure is no student.
She looks pretty flashy
if you ask me.
- Over there, in that building...
- He's in the Film Club.
- Art, Literature...
- With such bandy legs,
- and Music.
...I wouldn't wear a mini.
Cigarette?
No, thanks.
Do you have a match, then?
No, I don't.
- Look at her nails.
- Red like a traffic light.
Do you have a match?
No.
Want a poem instead?
Sensibility and taste
are formed by reading.
What you are really doing
is forming your own life.
Therefore, reading is very important.
Does it have a story?
Well, it's a love story.
There it is.
Great, you've even got a poster.
I made it myself.
It is written, directed, produced, scored,
publicized, and acted in by me.
Does he play in it?
Yes, and he has a sideline job, too.
He's looking good.
When will you start?
Right now.
Now, I'm going to show my film,
"A Record of First Love".
Admiration forever...
Chizuko Kubota, Third Grade, C-Class...
We were classmates and...
I fell in love with her.
"I love you"- written five hundred times.
This book of poems,
this book of praise...
Yet my heart cannot reach her.
Alas, we must part.
The graduation ceremony...
I wanted to talk with you...
But you walked away with another boy.
My heart was broken.
My heart was freezing.
But that doesn't matter anymore.
Now I have forgiven you everything...
But we have no future together.
On our last school trip...
To Komazawa...
You gave me some candy at the gym.
If you'd been only beautiful...
I might have loved another.
But you had something that
was all your own.
The class party...
I came, full of hope.
You weren't there.
You betrayed me.
But I couldn't blame you.
Your bus-stop...
- Even now I wait there.
- From here on, the picture's very shaky.
- At the school gates.
- I followed the bus by bicycle.
- You hadn't changed at all.
- With the running camera in my hands.
- So it's a little shaky.
I pretended not to notice you.
Then I'd turn and look at you.
Then the bus came and
you were gone.
We met again - May 5th.
You were riding a bike.
Remembering how we promised to write...
How empty everything is.
Only school without you...
That is me then, now,
and in the future.
I will never change.
I will admire you, love you, adore you
for all of my life.
You were all the beauty, all the people,
all the longing of my life.
My neverending love.
I am entirely yours and can never
belong to anyone else.
But you are not here now.
If I could live over the school days again...
I should be so happy.
And when, when can I confess
my love for you?
Oh, that was beautiful!
You're a real film director.
Thank you - I only wish she were
here to see it.
I'd like to have seen her.
I wonder what happened to her.
Shall we go have some tea?
No, I'll wait for her a little while.
Thank you very much.
I hope she'll come soon.
- See you again.
What is it?
Anything wrong with you?
Nothing.
Something's wrong.
Well, what kind of film was that?
What?
Rubbish! It was childish.
You thought so?
Well... not completely childish.
Silverfoil.
What?
Shall I keep it?
Throw it away.
The film was called "First Love".
It was sentimental.
You think so?
Throw that away.
No!
Do you still meet the perverse,
bearded man?
He's normal.
Those people are disgusting.
But he was always kind to me.
Want a drink?
When you peel a cabbage
the core comes out.
What comes out when you
peel an onion?
What?
You peel a cabbage and
you get the core.
What do you get when you
peel an onion?
Oh, that one.
You know?
You really do?
It's tears.
From a cabbage you get the core.
From an onion you get tears.
I see!
I understand.
No wonder, I peeled an onion
and still couldn't get it.
But tears came out when you
did, didn't they?
Shall we try again?
This time it will be all right.
Why?
I feel it Will.
Me too...
Tomorrow night...
At the same hotel...
Six o'clock.
Same room.
This time it will be all right!
This is first love!
First love!
Shun-darling.
You dress up?
Interesting newspaper story today.
There was this married businessman.
He worked late with a man from his office.
And ever since then he doesn't want
to sleep with his wife.
What are you doing?
Ungrateful! Get out!
Stupid!
You end up in prison anyway!
A real delinquent.
That's Momi.
Momi! Hi!
Hi!
I solved the riddle.
What is it?
You get the core from the cabbage.
And you get tears from onions.
Yes! Yes!
You've been all right?
I don't see you in the park much.
Am I a bad girl?
No, but why?
Was it bad what I did?
No, you're the best little girl
in the whole wide world.
Yes, I am!
- Bye! Bye!
- Bye!
' See you!
I'm going to bring a girl next time.
Her name is Nanami.
You'll be good friends.
Can you lend me some train fare please?
I'm sorry but twenty, even ten yen will do.
Please, please.
All right, knock it off!
Well, haven't seen you for a long time.
Not since that girlie-show, remember?
Where's that girl?
What girl?
The one called Nanami.
Pretty well-built but short.
I've been wanting to talk to you.
I got a sponsor for the next show...
Make lots of money with shows like that.
Oh, I understand.
I think maybe you'd like to
help us with this?
It's a good deal and I got it all set up.
Can't go on selling corn-on-the-cob
all my life.
As a pimp you'll have a good life.
How about it?
You can't get away.
Stop! Stop!
We'll get you! Stop!
And now: Laugh.
All together.
Look! All the blood!
These kids just don't pay attention.