GIRL'S REFORM SCHOOL
[WHY DID THEY BECOME LIKE THAT]
Producer Tsuneyasu MATSUMOTO
Written by Toshihiko TAKEDA
Screenplay by Hiroshi SHIMIZU
Cinematographer Hiroshi SUZUKI
Lighting Director Iwaji HIRAOKA
Sound Mixer Tsukuru KATAOKA
Art Director Seiichi TORIIDUKA
Music Ichiro SAITO
Assistant Director Teruo ISHII Editor Hidetoshi KASAMA
Production Chief Kihachiro YAMAMOTO
Cast
Kyoko KAGAWA
Junko IKEUCHI  Konomi FUJI  Misako UJI
Utako MITSUYA  Masako NAKAMURA
Keiko OUGI  Chiyoko KUNI  Akiko MIE
Kikuko HANAOKA  Katsuko WAKASUGI
Wakako KUNITOMO
Eiko OOHARA  Masako FUJIMURA
Chisako TAHARA  Ritsuko NONOMURA  Yukiko MORO
Yasuko ASAKURA  Kyoko KATSURA  Tomiko KOIZUMI
Sizuko INAMI  Yoshiko SHIBATA
Keiko HASEGAWA  Kuniko TAMAGAWA  Sumiko MOTAI
Hideko MURANO  Mayumi TAKAHASHI  Yuuko TSUJI
Shuuko ITO  Fujiko OOTSUKA
Saburo SAWAI  Hiroshi TSUKIJI  Toru HIRANUMA
Younosuke AKIYAMA  Kan SUGI
Chieko NANIWA (TOHO)
Toyoko TAKAHASHI (SHOCHIKU)
Directed by
Hiroshi SHIMIZU
Every girl in this school
has fallen into bad habits.
These children have arisen from
the chaos at the end of the war.
One girl is a kleptomaniac,
one has the habit of lying,
another is addicted to stimulants.
One girl wants to see the world.
One can't help gambling
or is a pyromaniac.
And one sold herself to get money...
Let's not expose any more.
They are not naturally bad.
After coming here
their improvement is remarkable.
It is like a sick person
trying to get out of bed...
and who rapidly gets better.
They are good as long as they are here.
But, when they go out into the world,
many of them return here heartbroken.
As for life in this school,
in the morning they study
according to their level.
However, there are those
who do not wish to study.
And we do not force them.
In the afternoon,
they do piecework.
The girls here no longer know how to laugh
from the bottom of their hearts.
Then
we got them this job
hand painting okame masks.
Because we hope
they will laugh some day
just like an okame.
They divide up their earnings:
One third is for food.
One third for clothing
and daily necessities.
The rest they save.
Or some send money to their families.
They cook by turns.
There are always
five girls on duty.
From now on, we will try to describe
events inspired by a true story.
Hiroko HATA   Birth: 25 May 1938
Feb - May 1955:
Removal of household goods, staying out
without permission, smoking, vagrancy.
Many of the girls in this school
are from poor families.
But you come from
a wealthy, well-known family in Iyo.
Why did you run away from home?
It's true.
You have your parents.
Why do you feel need to run away?
Your father and
mother love you, right?
Then, do you have a problem
with your brothers?
Your parents love you, there's
no problem with your brothers.
Then, what is your problem?
Well, you should become
a good girl as soon as possible,
and then your family can stop worrying.
Please take her and
introduce her to the other girls.
Let's go, Hiroko.
Everyone.
From today, Hiroko Hata
will be one of us.
I hope you can be good friends.
I'm Hiroko Hata.
- Yone, she'll be with you.
- Yes.
And can someone
help her with her luggage?
Please take the Futon.
- What a nerve.
- Right.
It looks like a wedding.
- Bring it in here, please.
- Yes.
Please put her luggage here.
Yone, please help her.
Hiroko, you can ask her
for anything you need.
I'll leave everything to you.
Please.
Here.
Oh, a tip.
Long time no see.
Thank you.
Why were you sent to this school?
This [theft]?
Or this [drugs]?
Why did you come here?
I didn't "enter",
I was sent here.
Then, why were you sent here?
This?
Or this?
How dare you. I'm here longer than you.
You should show me some respect.
So, what?
- You hit me.
- Yes, I did.
Please come. It's awful.
What are you doing?
What happened?
She's so shameless. She used gestures
like "This or this" to me. Damn her.
You used gestures like "This or this"
to me first. Damn you.
You can stop quarreling. Yone, everyone,
go back to your places. OK?
I won't lose to her.
I'm a newcomer, so I held back.
Damn it, she's a bad one.
Look.
How fierce you are.
Why not smile.
You see? How pretty you are.
Why are you here?
I like you very much.
I...
Give me a hug.
I'm the daughter of mistress.
I was taken in by my foster mother
after I was born.
No one has told me
if my real mother is alive or dead.
I...
so want to see my real mother.
You should become a good girl
as soon as possible.
I'll take care of you
instead of your real mother. OK?
Now then,
you can go back to your bed.
Give me one hug more.
But, if you are found out,
you'll be in trouble.
You understand, don't you?
Let's go, alright?
You need to go quietly, right?
- Good night.
Where are we going?
Follow me.
What can I do for you?
Last night, where did you go?
Wherever.
I won't ask you again.
Just give me a cigarette.
I don't have any.
Don't lie.
Look here.
You have nicotine-stained fingers.
The girls who smoke most probably
bring in hidden cigarettes.
Come on, give.
You won't?
Then, I'll expose your secret to all.
I have them in my pyjama pocket.
Really?
You can get a cigarette
during work hours.
Let's go back.
What are you doing?
I know what you're looking for.
What was in your pyjama pocket.
You don't need them any more.
That's why you left them
for me last night, right?
Is that right?
Am I right?
Miss, I'm sorry.
The teacher took them.
I'll buy you some.
So, please don't tell anybody
about last night.
Yone, please come.
This.
It was in the closet.
You were eating it, weren't you?
I've seen this once before.
I thought I'd ask you.
Yone.
You can talk to me about anything.
Feel free to discuss anything.
Yone.
Don't take it all on yourself.
You can tell me anything. Right?
It's OK. I won't do anything bad.
If it's as I imagine,
sooner or later we'll all find out
Please tell me before it's too late.
Yone, please.
I have nothing to tell you.
Yone.
- I found it in her closet.
- Again?
I think it's just as you said.
- What did she say?
- That she'd nothing to tell us.
What do you want?
Your behaviour has really thrown me.
Teacher suspects me now.
- What? About the cigarettes?
- No, it's not that.
Don't get carried away.
And don't spoil everything.
I got it. You're angry because
teacher found your summer orange.
Shut up. Clear off.
- What happened?
- I don't understand a thing.
I think she's misunderstood something.
Yone. Yone.
Please, pick her up.
Yone, pull yourself together.
Oh my God. Are you OK?
Tomiko MIYAI
Birth: 11 Nov 1938
8 Mar 1955: Removing household goods,
9 May 1955: 3 counts of theft with vagrancy
I've heard news from Mrs. Oda
that your father isn't feeling well.
Recently you've been doing well,
so we thought we'd let you go back home.
What do you think?
Miss, can I go home?
Really?
Even if you do return, you shouldn't
defy your mother. Do you understand?
Even if she is your step-mother,
she will love you if you behave.
When you are with me,
you behave yourself.
If you obey your mother,
everything will be fine.
Do you understand?
You shouldn't revert to old habits.
Then, this is your bank book.
And...
This 500 yen is for your train fare
and to buy a present for your father.
- Don't lose this money, please.
- Thank you very much.
Everyone.
They let me go back home.
You should become good girls
and not revert to old habits.
They said so to me just now.
Miss, can I write you a letter?
Of course.
However, if you are fine,
it's better not to write to me.
But, if you have any problems,
you must write or come
to the school to consult with me.
Anyway, do the best you can.
You have nothing to lose.
- Tomiko. You've come back.
- Yes.
Really. You have to try the best you can.
Miss.
Can we go this way?
Hello.
Welcome.
What has Tomiko done this time?
She has become a good girl
and is very well behaved.
I heard her father was sick,
so, I've brought her.
Ah, I see. Thank you for
taking care of my daughter.
- Please come in.
- Thank you.
How is her father doing?
He went to hospital.
The doctor said he has a stomach ulcer,
so he's quite upset.
Anyway, he drinks too much.
Please come in.
No, thank you.
I must be leaving now.
Please, love Tomi.
Tomi.
You must listen to what your mother says.
And she will love you.
You know what I mean.
I should leave now. Please give
my best regards to her father.
I'm sorry I couldn't
have entertained you better.
- Goodbye.
Why not say goodbye?
Goodbye.
Mother...
This is a present.
What? You brought a present?
What a waste of money.
Tomiko.
How long are you sitting there for?
You're not a visitor.
It's time to prepare dinner.
Who told you your father was sick?
He sent me a letter.
Your father?
Look what he's done.
He had no need to write
to someone in such a school.
And, you.
If you had let me know in advance you were
coming back, I'd have found you a job.
Suddenly you come back, and if you
stay here, what will people think?
If you stay home,
I'll be too embarrassed to go out.
What are you doing?
We're not cooking this.
Tomiko, you came back.
You sent her a letter
to tell her you were sick.
Letter? I didn't write her to come back.
I wrote to tell her
to be a good girl.
While I was at it,
I wrote I was ill.
That's of no concern.
What are you going to do with her?
Will you keep her here
as long as she wants?
I don't know what to say.
She's your daughter,
so she can stay.
But if she goes back to her old ways,
we shan't be able to show our faces.
It'll be too embarrassing.
But, she came back as a good girl.
Who knows?
Even the teachers may be saying
that they've gotten rid of a nuisance.
Mother.
I'm a good girl,
that's why I'm back.
I'll listen to everything you say.
I won't lie,
I won't do anything bad.
So, please let me stay home.
Please, mother, please.
Please.
Mother.
Father, please ask her.
I'm back.
Just what I thought,
you've come home.
See.
Already everyone
in the neighborhood knows.
How embarrassing.
That's all you can say.
So what.
I'm getting out of here right now.
Hey, Tomiko.
What are you doing?
Did you run away from there too?
I was given permission to go home
because my father is sick.
Then, what are you doing here?
I...
What happened?
Tell me.
They made me feel uncomfortable.
So, I left home.
Why not stay with me.
We'll go round the pachinko halls.
We'll get by.
Anyway, where are you staying?
Don't worry about accommodation.
Leave it to me.
You haven't had dinner
yet either, have you?
I know a good Ramen restaurant.
Let's go.
I'm thinking of going to Osaka soon.
Why don't you come with me?
Osaka?
What'll you do in Osaka?
It'll be great if we go there.
And there is someone I can trust.
I was thinking of going far away.
- But I don't have any travel money.
- Money?
Don't worry about it.
Leave it to me.
Yes, that's right.
Tomiko Miyai.
I see.
Then, I'll go pick her up right away.
Thank you for calling.
Excuse me, I just got a call.
Thank you for coming.
Please.
What happened, Tomi?
I haven't painted in ages, my hands
are shaking, I can't draw at all.
How about this?
Will this pass inspection?
What's that?
It's only got one eye.
- It's a wink.
- It's a funny wink.
- I thought it was crying.
- What's that?
You're just a newbie.
What? Newbie?
If I'm a newbie,
you're a "re-newbie".
What? Say that again.
Go on, Aki. I'll help you.
I'll help you, too.
I agree. If we don't teach her a lesson now,
it'll become a habit.
You always flatter teachers.
Damn it.
What?
Do you want to fight?
Listen, everyone.
- Good news.
- What is it?
The owner of the paper fan shop
came to talk with the principal.
He says they're busy, so he wants
two of us to work at his place.
I'm just a dead loss anyway.
Kimi.
You are too.
Your marks are lousy.
If it's oldest first,
then that means me.
If they work well,
I'll come ask for more.
If that happens,
it will only encourage them.
Miss Oda, which girl would you chose?
Who is the most suitable
according to the results?
Tomi was just the right person,
but there's that business with her.
Aya is good
and Toshi is also.
If you work hard,
others can also work there.
Please work hard for them.
That's right. You have a responsibility,
since you are our representatives
Fortunately there are no men there.
You can be friends, but don't fight, OK?
- If you don't understand something,
you should ask politely. - Yes.
Why all of a sudden
do you want to quit today?
What don't you understand?
You know what I mean.
Anyway, we're leaving.
Impossible.
It would be a disaster.
We're chock full of orders,
so we'll be busy from now on.
No matter how busy we get,
we...
don't want to work with those girls.
They came because they
have good marks at the school.
There is nothing to worry about.
That may be true,
- but we'd be in trouble if people
thought we were the same as them.
Excuse me.
They are the best
students in the school.
They won't be any bother to you.
Please let them work with you.
I don't mind working with them,
but there are many
unmarried girls working here.
They have made an effort to be good,
and they are glad
to be working in the real world.
Please let them work here,
in order to help them.
The teacher is asking you to do this,
please try to understand.
Anyway, let me think about it.
Excuse me.
Please.
Please work with them.
Please. Can you do that?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
No, it can't be helped.
If another opportunity arises,
I'd appreciate your consideration.
We'll return to the school.
Thank you.
This is only a small present.
Thank you for your kindness.
You can take it.
I'm really sorry.
I didn't want to hurt your feelings.
I'll handle it better next time.
- Thank you very much.
- Bye.
I understand.
This is...
the reality you face.
But, stay strong.
Hana, how was it?
- They said a hair salon wanted
to hire someone.    - How nice.
But, I refused.
- Why? Don't waste the chance.
- Why won't you work there?
I don't want to be like Aya and Toshi.
I know but...
- Masa. Masa, the teacher
is calling you. - Really?
Why won't she work there?
- Please come.
- Yes.
A hair salon wants to hire someone.
Do you want to work there?
The salary is 2.000 yen, live-in.
I'd like to stay here for a while.
Why?
You said you'd work anywhere.
You've been doing well recently
and the requirements are normal.
I would still rather stay here.
Are you afraid of being
like Toshi and Aya?
Don't be like that.
How long have you been here?
It doesn't matter. If you don't want,
you needn't work there.
However, you can't just
stay here as long as you like.
Yes.
Miss Oda, this matter
is a real problem.
Masa, are you going to work there?
I refused.
Even though they said
I shouldn't plan on staying here forever.
But you can stay.
If someone's looking for a wife,
I'll go marry him anytime.
In order of results,
it's Chiyo's turn next.
Chiyo, do you want to go to work?
My mother is in poor health
and I have a lot of
younger brothers and sisters.
I want to go back home and work.
What's more, when my mother
finds a job, she'll come for me.
It's nice to have a home to go to.
If someone would be responsible for me
and protect me, I'd go home.
But, in my case,
I have no one at all.
I am contacting you urgently.
Please tell the teacher you
are my aunt and please pick me up.
Please do it immediately.
Kiyoko.
I'm Kiyoko Tanaka's aunt.
Thank you for your help.
I had no idea
she'd been here so long.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
- You are her aunt.
- Yes.
Today I went to her house.
I've just found out she is here
and I was so surprised.
I see.
Then, I talked to her family.
I wondered if
she'd be staying here for ever.
We decided that
I would supervise her.
So, I came here.
Thank you for coming.
She is now of marriageable age.
She cannot always be here, so,
we were just wondering what to do.
Oh, really. Then I came
at just the right moment.
I'll take care of her.
I'd like you to handle this matter
at your own discretion.
- Please wait a moment, I'll fetch her.
- Thank you.
Kiyo, please come.
Yes.
Let's go see.
Kiyo.
What have you been up to?
I was so surprised
when I heard about you.
Anyway, you can't stay here forever.
so I've come to pick you up.
- You should do your best.
- Yes.
- Do you understand?
Is that right?
Why didn't you write to me before?
All this time at that useless school.
But I was trying to become
a respectable woman.
Nonsense.
But, "Bad habits are hard to break".
And I can't live there forever.
- That's why I sent you the letter.
- Really.
It's all the same to me. Firstly,
you should go to a beauty salon.
I know.
- But I'd rather have Tonkatsu than that.
- Tonkatsu? OK, let's go.
Yone.
Yone is always giving us trouble.
That's strange.
I'm not sure she was at dinner.
She was but she didn't eat anything.
- Miss, I can't find her anywhere.
- Have you looked in the backyard?
- I'll go see.
- Thank you.
I'll come with you.
- Are her kimono and things in her room?
- Yes, and her shoes, too.
That's strange.
Did you look there?
I'm scared. I'm going back.
Miss.
I heard a groan from the storage shed.
Hurry.
Yone. Yone.
Please call a midwife.
Please bring the principal here.
Yone.
Keep calm, now.
- Please boil some water.
- Yes.
Hello. Hello.
Yone, hang on in.
Someone, shine a light.
Yone, you can do it.
Someone, please come here and help me.
I'll do it.
Hold her shoulders.
Yone, hold on.
Yone.
Move aside.
Come on, stay over there.
Hold on. The midwife
will be here soon.
Someone please come.
Don't move.
Yone.
The baby. Hold its head.
The midwife is coming,
do your best.
Will the midwife arrive
or will the baby be born first?
Try harder.
Yone, hold on.
I knitted these,
but they are different sizes.
Thank you.
I don't mind, thank you.
Yone.
Is it true that you are going to leave
the baby in a children's home?
Who said so?
The director has gone
to see a family court judge.
No way.
What is it?
- He's so happy today, he's smiling.
- That's good.
What a cutie.
I'll give him some milk soon.
Please take care of him.
Is it true you're going to leave
my baby in a children's home?
The director went to see
a family court judge about this.
Miss.
Please.
Please don't take away my baby.
I'll raise him no matter what.
Please let me raise my baby.
I know I've been bad.
But since he's been born,
I want to be a good mother.
Please let me raise my baby.
And please let me be a good mother.
I'm so happy
that you think this way.
Yone.
We will try our best
to meet your expectations.
So please make sure
to be a good mother.
Come on.
When I'm a good girl and go out from here,
I want to have lots of children.
- A lot?
- Well, two or three.
- One child would be enough for me.
- If I have children, I want to have lots.
- I'd prefer a boy.
- I want a girl first, and then a boy.
I have never heard a lullaby
from my real mother.
Goodbye. Good luck.
Chiyo.
This is from teacher.
Goodbye.
Please check it.
Ten thousand yen.
Twenty thousand.
Thirty thousand.
Correct?
Correct, right?
Then, please, your seal.
Here, please.
Mother.
I'll look for a job right away,
please let me live here.
I'll do any hard work,
please let me stay here.
Please.
But...
Please. Please.
Please return the money.
We'll return your money.
Alright.
Then, when you start work,
you can support your large family.
To tell the truth,
Kiyo told me about you.
I felt sorry for you and your family.
So, I came here.
I talked it over with your mother.
If you work for me, it will be a great
help. So we agreed on it.
And your mother
came looking for you.
I hoped that you could live here.
But when your brothers
and sisters are hungry,
if you do something bad again,
I'll be the one in trouble.
And you'll be back at that place.
Even if you stay here, it will be hard,
getting funny looks from the neighbors.
And your brothers and sisters
will feel humiliated.
That's why it was
so kind of her to come.
That's right.
If possible, I'll send enough money
for your family each month.
Come on, everyone.
Let's hurry.
Pay no attention, let's go.
What's wrong? Come on.
Miss.
I just saw a girl there.
I think it's Chiyo.
- Chiyo?
- She looked strange.
It looks like Chiyo was there,
I'll go check.
Chiyo.
Oh, Miss.
Mother.
Chiyo.
Don't take the mask off.
If you want to see a made-up face,
there are plenty of other girls.
I'd feel sorry for her
if you take off her mask.
If you feel sorry for her,
why make her do this?
You are angry.
Chiyo, let's go home.
Miss.
Please wait.
You can take her if you like.
But, I spent a lot of money on her.
I need to send her family
money each month.
Her family is a large one to support.
Is there any other way
of earning enough money?
Or, if you can look after
her whole family,
you can take her anywhere.
Can you serve her tea?
What should we do
with girls like these?
Without the welcoming
cooperation of society,
the number of
delinquent girls will increase.
Everyone,
I thank you
for your warm support.
THE END