Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Go over there.
It's beautiful!
Come on!
Giorgio!
Help...Help!
Help! Somebody's drowning!
Where's Romolo?
He went to City Hall.
To hell with City Hall!
It's a woman.
There she is!
Tino's not here either?
Is she trying to drown herself?
There she is.
Go in after her.
Jump! If she gets to the sewer
she won't come up again.
A woman's drowning!
You guys head her off.
I'll go in after her.
Pascello!
Run! Come over here!
What are you doing? Not like that!
Turn her upside down.
Stefano, hurry up!
Where'd you fish her out?
Careful.
Hold her under the stomach.
She was drowning!
She probably slipped.
Mario saw her.
She must have slipped
and fell in.
- Did she jump off the bridge?
- No.
- Did she go under?
- 3 times.
- At least 7 times!
- 10 times!
She must have swallowed a lot.
We'll need some help. Stefano!
- What happened?
- Hurry!
- Faster with the arms!
- She lost a shoe.
I think she's dead.
Get the water out,
before it's too late.
Look how it's rushing out.
Move it, kids!
We saved her!
Beat it!
Let's get Pompeo.
He never seen anyone drown before.
Look.
I don't wanna look.
I'm afraid.
Looks dead to me.
Corpses don't throw up water.
She opened her eyes!
Put her down.
We'll give her
artificial respiration.
She's bleeding.
It's just a scratch.
What she needs is brandy.
Brandy nothing!
What she needs is milk.
Quiet! She's coming to. You, with
the motorbike, go get some milk.
I'm outta gas.
Take it easy now.
You're all right.
You can thank the Holy Father.
You're fine.
- Where's Giorgio?
- Which Giorgio?
Where are you going?
Who's she looking for?
- Wasn't she alone?
- Yes.
Who does he think he is?
Take it easy. Come here.
I'm going home!
Where's my shoes?
Here. There's only one.
She's got 7 souls...like a cat!
See? She can hardly stand up.
Poor thing. She's in bad shape.
You were almost dead.
Leave me alone!
Let go of me!
Hey! We're the ones
who saved you!
Fine. You saved me...
Now I wanna go home, O.K.?
O.K. Suit yourself.
Go home. Goodbye.
Hi, Cabiria.
You know her?
Sure. She's Cabiria.
Where's she live?
On Via Cecilia, near the gas
station. She lives the life...
Giorgio! Open up! It's me!
It's me! Cabiria!
Wanda!
Wanda! Have you seen Giorgio?
What happened to you?
Mind your own business.
Did you see Giorgio?
- Which Giorgio?
- My Giorgio.
What happened to you?
What do you want from me?
What do you want?
I don't want nothing.
You mind your own ass!
Go inside and dry yourself off.
I don't have the keys.
Where'd you put them?
In my purse.
Where's your purse?
Giorgio's got it.
We took a walk by the river and...
...I fell in.
He got scared and ran away.
Cabiria! Open up!
Come on, open up.
I gotta sleep!
Tell me something, Cabiria.
How much did you have
in your purse? Answer me.
If you see Giorgio, I'm right here.
What are you doing?
You're right to stay home.
Go to bed
and get some sleep.
I'll see you later
when I get back.
Why didn't you take your aspirin?
Take it, it'll do you good.
You still here?
Aren't you tired of yakkin'?
Can't you see I had enough?
Get lost! Who told you
we were friends?
Get lost, will you?
And don't come borrowing
my thermometer anymore!
Who's asking you for anything?
What a nut!
You're a sweetheart!
Someone would throw you in the
river for 40,000 lire?
Drown you for 40,000 lire?
Nowadays they'll do it for 5,000.
Someone who loves you?
What love?
You met him a month ago!
You don't know his name
or where he lives.
Can't you understand?
He pushed you in!
He pushed you in the river!
And you were lucky, because me
I'd have held your head
under myself! You nut!
Tell the cops!
I'm no stool pigeon.
Take my advice!
Report him!
But why? Why'd he do it?
I gave him everything.
I gave him everything he wanted.
He didn't have to do it.
I'm such a moron.
What if I died?
That's it! The party's over!
We're through! Finished!
Silk shirts!
I'll give you silk shirts!
Find anotherjerk like me!
Look what I bought him!
Checked suit!
Camel-hair coat!
Never again! Never!
And who's gonna feed you now?
St. Peter?
Eternal love!
You dirty vitellone!
Go back to selling balloons!
I'll burn it all!
Chicken soup, veal chops...
You should drop dead!
This is the last time!
You'll never see me here again.
This is my last evening.
I shouldn't even
be seen with you!
Look how classy I am.
You look like Moby Dick to me.
How dare you!
Know where you belong?
In the nuthouse!
Use your eyes!
Take a good look at me!
Look at me. A grande dame.
She gets worse all the time.
They oughta put her away.
That's how you'll end up!
And that's the heater...
- This car's got everything.
- Even Coca- Cola.
- Gimme a ride?
- This ain't no tank!
- Get out!
- I'm not getting out.
Come on, move!
- Why should I?
- I'm taking Wanda for a ride.
You don't know how to drive.
It's my car.
I do what I want.
Get out.
I'll visit you in the hospital.
This I gotta see.
Why not the bigger model?
Another one!
What do you know about cars?
You're always in the bushes!
You're always on two wheels!
Here comes the psycho again.
- 'Bye, handsome.
- 'Bye, sweetie.
Remember to come see
your princess.
Cute! Real fancy!
Me, I'd have picked a grey one.
It's a fancier color.
But this one's cute.
You're gonna kill the battery!
Wanda, get out.
I don't want to argue tonight.
Neither do I, you fanatic.
Still, a Fiat is a Fiat.
With a car,
life's a lot different.
You sit up there, high up,
and you signal right, left...
People think you're well off...
a secretary, a daddy's girl...
The men all chase you.
It feels great!
- Listen to her!
- What?
I know how she got that car!
That cokehead!
Wait!
Stay right here!
- Let me get out!
- Stay!
Dance, Cabiria!
You're in luck!
I'm the best dancer in Rome.
Come on!
Now she found another
deadbeat to say "I love you".
One who'll send her off begging.
Get off the street, dear,
or I'll have you arrested.
Here I am, gentlemen!
Here I am!
Just as well.
Who needs you?
Where you going with the car?
To the old-age home?
Maybe if you were 20 years
younger!
Filthy flea bag!
You're justjealous!
Hear that, Cabiria?
She can't get away with that!
Look how you'll end up,
you lousy whore!
"Please...be kind...
Have a heart!"
"Please, for my Giorgio's sake!"
Do it! Poke her eyes out!
Wanda, here we go again.
Forza, Cabiria!
Never mind her!
Hit her low, in the belly!
Don't stop them!
It's too much fun!
Stop it before the cops come!
I'll kill her!
Let go of me!
Get her in the car.
Get her away!
- Leave me alone!
- Get inside!
I'll punch you a new face!
It's not over yet!
She ruined my face!
Forget about her.
You're scared of me, right?
You lousy loser!
Have a smoke.
Where you wanna go?
To Via Veneto.
Via Veneto?
Think you're the Empress Poppea?
Cabiria, you and me oughta
have a talk one of these days.
You're not doing it right.
Who's watching over you?
Look at Marisa and me.
She's safe wherever she goes.
Nobody in Rome would harm her.
You know why? Tell me.
Let me out.
What do you expect
to do here?
Girls fight for spots
on Via Veneto and Villa Borghese.
Cabiria, why not find yourself
a serious man like me?
I don't need one.
- I say you do.
- I say I don't!
Why should I slave
for filthy pigs like you?
Let's drop it.
Yeah, drop it.
Better let me out.
Yeah, it's better.
So long!
Degenerate! Go take a walk
on the Passeggiata Archeologica!
Can't I look?
Know how gorgeous you are?
Get going.
Yeah? I'm staying right here!
See?
Sorry.
Are you blind?
Jessie!
Jessie! How can this happen?
Alberto Lazzari!
Jessie, I don't want to get upset.
Jessie, cut it out!
Let go!
Don't make me lose my temper.
Come back inside.
Give me the keys.
- Go inside. Don't be stupid.
- Don't you touch me, you pig!
Move over. Let me in.
Where are you going? Where?
- Do I get the keys or not?
- No!
- You're not getting out!
- You're hurting me. Let go!
Listen, dear...
Listen one last time.
- There's no more to say.
- I'm tired. You're exhausting!
- Let go! You're ruining my fur.
- I bought it!
You louse!
- Wait a second...
- What for?
You can go.
Lousy second-rate ham!
Listen, Jessie. If you don't
come back, it's over!
Fine! It's over!
Finished!
At last! So much the better.
Thanks, thanks, Jessie.
What do you want?
Go away!
I'm talking to you!
Get in.
Who, me?
Yes, you. Hurry. Get in.
Fast!
Close the door.
Get out.
But why?
Come on, get out.
What's it gonna be, Mr. Mustache?
What's going on here?
Get out, get in, get in, get out!
Make up your mind!
Come on. Let's have some fun.
- He said to go in.
- So go in.
How are you, Sir?
How about a table?
Tonight's show is exceptional.
Your umbrella, Signora?
Right this way, Signora.
Who's that?
May I help you?
Sit over here. Come on.
Please...
Sit over there.
Alberto!
Monica...
What are you up to, Alberto?
Are you shooting?
- Yes.
- No need to introduce him!
Pleased to meet you.
Yesterday the Americans
gave me a screen test.
It turned out fantastic!
I have a 16 millimeter print at home
if you want to see it.
Ladies and gentlemen, that was
part one of our show. Before you dance
I'd like to salute and applaud
an illustrious guest who is
honoring us with his presence.
Must I applaud too, Alberto?
O.K., boys! Mambo number 26!
Do me a favor,
come to our table.
A bunch of my friends
would love to meet you.
- Come on, Alberto.
- I can't.
I'm with the lady.
Let's dance.
Mambo...the world turns
around the mambo.
What a mambo.
Oh, boy! What a mambo!
If you wanna be with your friends,
don't mind me.
What?
You can go with your friends.
That's enough. Let's go.
Good night, Commendatore.
Get in. Hurry up!
- Did you eat?
- No.
Well, a little bit at 8 p.m.
- Let's get some supper.
- What?
Let's have supper.
Good. Where are we going?
Home.
Wait! Wait a second!
Hey, Fancy Pants!
I'm talking to you!
Look at me!
Look who I'm with!
Up yours! Know who this is?
- Did anyone call?
- Nobody, Commendatore.
- What do you mean nobody?
- Nobody called.
- Were you awake or sleeping?
- Nobody called. I was here.
All right.
Supper for two in my room.
If Miss Jessie calls, I'm asleep.
If she insists, I'm asleep.
If she still insists,
I'm still asleep!
We'll eat upstairs.
What's your name?
What?
Come on, move.
What? Another dog?
Look at these!
You got fish, too?
Yes...
Now, where did I put it?
- Leave it for the maid.
- But it'll get wrinkled.
Idiot! What made me do it?
Did you ever see an idiot?
Well, you're looking at one.
Just leave it!
Come.
Your name again?
Where are you from?
What?
- Where do you come from?
- From Rome. Piazza Risorgimento.
Sit down. You're making me
nervous.
You like it?
Kind of...it's not really my thing.
It's not my taste...but, yes.
Beethoven's Fifth.
I love it.
Come in.
Leave it there.
I'll do it. Go.
And close the door.
Let's see what he brought us.
Caviar...lobster...
Help yourself. Eat.
I'm not in the mood.
Help yourself.
I don't know if you like it.
1949.
1949...
Take that off.
It's hot in here.
Guess I tore it.
- Where do you live?
- Past the gas station.
- Where?
- On the road to Ostia.
- You come to Via Veneto?
- Via Veneto? Me?
I work the Passeggiata
Archeologica. Much more convenient.
Why?
I'm on the Cilia.
Subway takes me right there.
There's another girl,
my friend Wanda.
She lives there, too.
But I don't bother with the others.
The others sleep under the arches
in Caracalla.
Mind you, I have my own house
with water, electric, bottled gas...
I got every thing.
Even a thermometer.
See this one here?
She never, ever slept under an arch.
Well, maybe once...or twice.
Of course, my house is...
nothing like this.
But I like it.
Eat. Eat something.
What's wrong?
Damn it! I know who you are!
I know!
Can I say it?
Can I?
Alberto Lazzari! I knew you
right away! I saw all your movies.
- Very nice!
- Which is your favorite?
Well... the last one
in a costume with all that stuff,
then Vittorio Gassman came...
pushed the door open and said:
"Fermi tutti!"
Then it was his daughter.
That wasn't me.
What do you mean?
You're as nice as your house.
Bring the glasses here.
- Champagne.
- Sit down.
What's wrong now?
Who's gonna believe this
when I tell 'em?
They already think I'm full of it.
I might not believe it myself
tomorrow.
You have to do me a favor.
Give me a picture
and write: "Cabiria was here
at my house. Alberto Lazzari"
"Cabiria Ceccarelli
was at my house."
Like that.
Now let's eat.
And you eat, too.
An olive.
Should I open it?
Chicken! Some chicken breast
to chase away the blues.
Here's your plate.
If you want to play more
of that music, I'd like it, too.
And what's this?
I saw it in a movie once.
- Commendatore.
- Yes, Davide.
- It's Signorina Jessie.
- Tell her I'm sleeping.
- She's here.
- What?
- She's downstairs.
- Just don't let her in.
She's already in. She's coming up.
Idiot!
Alberto, open up.
- Who is it?
- Don't be stupid! Open up!
So? Open up.
It's important.
One moment.
- The picture!
- Oh, yes. Hurry up!
Alberto, will you open up?
Go in the bathroom a minute.
Yes. I'll get rid of her...Hurry!
I'm not leaving.
I'll stay here all night!
- Quiet, don't move.
- Open up.
Alberto, please open the door.
Open up, you bastard!
What do you want?
What's on your mind?
I'm tired.
I have to be up early tomorrow.
I'm working. You know that.
I'm thirsty. Give me a drink.
- What?
- I'm thirsty.
Now what?
I can't go on this way!
Well, neither can I!
Yourjealousy
is morbid, unbearable.
I'm tired of it.
I can't take it any more.
Let's call it quits
while we're still friends.
That's too easy.
I'm not going anywhere!
Jessie, don't do this.
Get some sleep.
You're tired and
I'm falling apart.
We'll call each other tomorrow.
- I know you've stopped loving me.
- Who told you?
You've stopped loving me.
- Admit it.
- I'd never say such a thing.
Admit it, and I'll never
bother you again.
But I'd be lying.
Even if we saw each other
occasionally...
Every two or three days,
I'd be happy.
Why so seldom?
We could be together much more.
- Every day?
- Yes, every day.
But stop being so jealous. Is it my
fault that women always look at me?
But you're ugly!
How do I get outta here?
Hey, Cabiria. Alberto Lazzari's
been lookin' for you!
I'm not even talking to you!
- Don't listen to her.
- Who's listening?
Hey, Cabiria, there's Limpy.
There's a winner.
Hey, you old lecher!
Homesick forjail?
Come on, Cabiria,
let's have a good laugh.
Why'd you bring him along?
A weed never dies!
The Madonna might
have mercy on my uncle.
What mercy?
The pilgrims of the Madonna del
Divino Amore just went by.
I don't believe that stuff.
- Don't you believe in miracles?
- Not me.
Should we go there on Sunday?
We'll all have
something to ask.
Cabiria, you goin' too?
Me? I dunno.
I'll think about it. Besides,
what would I ask for?
I've got everything.
I'll even be done
with the mortgage soon.
But I might go anyway.
I haven't said no.
We'll see.
Think the Madonna would
waste a miracle on him?
Funny, huh? She knows
how you made your dough.
Selling coke
and pimping women.
I'm going to see the Madonna
and I know exactly
what I'll ask for.
Don't make fun of stuff like that.
You really want to go?
What'll you ask for?
I'm talking to you.
Hey, you! Shorty!
Wanna lift?
A shortcut...
He calls this a shortcut.
I've been walking an hour.
Who knows where I am?
You live in the caves, too?
I've never seen you before.
I've got my own house.
Gorgiano!... Gorgiano!
It's me. Come up.
How are you doing?
Not so bad, thank you, sir.
And where's Pietro?
Sleeping?
They took him to the hospital
two days ago.
Said he was in bad shape.
- What do you need?
- Whatever you want, sir.
Here's a blanket. Is that alright?
What hospital
did they take Pietro to?
To the Fratebenefratelli.
Alright, I'll visit him
if I have time.
Hey, Dark Hair...
who is that guy?
But who is he?
With some charity?
Hey, I'm talkin' to you.
Can I help you?
Going back to Rome later?
Can you give me a lift?
Yes, later.
Elsa!
Ah, caro!
I was expecting you Saturday,
but you came today!
I was just thinking yesterday,
"He comes every 9 or 10 days...
"He came Wednesday,
so he'll show up Saturday!"
Bomba! But I know this one!
But Bomba... You live here?
I wish I had everything I used to...
A place in Rome, a place in Ostia...
Showered with gifts!
Money in the bank!
Jewels! Gold!
I had five kilos of gold!
She's not lying, you know.
Now who'd believe it?
But this one in her day...
Here they don't even
make me comb my hair.
But if I wear a low-cut blouse
and the white earrings, then...ha!
Come, Elsa. Take this.
Oh! Look at the sweets you
brought!
And only for me!
None for the others!
Give it to me to hide.
The one with the chocolate!
Pignoli! Look at the pignoli!
Like rainfall!
Caro! Thank you, thank you!
When will you be back?
When?
God protect you from evil, my son.
Of course...
Lots of starving people in Rome,
eh?
You drive around at night a lot.
Not as much as needed.
How 'bout during the day?
No, in the daytime,
the poor wander about.
How would I find them?
Go figure...
Me, I'm out at night, too,
and I've never met you.
But how'd you get
the idea of doing this job?
I don't even know myself.
Like that. Little by little.
We're here... There's your tram.
Do you live far from here?
About 19 km, on the road to Ostia.
What's your name?
Maria Ceccarelli.
Are you alone?
My father and mother
died when I was little.
I came to Rome later.
Now go and get some sleep.
So I...
Arrivederci...
Go ahead, tell me.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Don Vincenzo,
the group from Rieti is here.
Get your prickly pears!
Fresh prickly pears!
Eat my Indian figs!
Gimme a hand, Maurizio.
Wanda, get a load of this crowd!
Divine Love
Grants grace at any time
There's the candle guy.
Come on, Uncle.
Viva Maria! Viva Maria!
How much for the candles?
Take your pick.
I got some for 50, 100, 150...
The biggest you got.
We'll take two each.
Wanda, the candles! Over here!
Are these all right?
I just want one.
Maybe I'll pay you later.
No, I'll pay for them all.
- What'll I do with it now?
- Stupid!
How much altogether?
Lovely Lady
Who with gladness
In their hearts
Honor you today
Make way! Sick man here!
Let us through!
Oh, the poor lad.
So young!
We're over here! Wait for us!
We're gonna get photos!
- Come, Cabiria. They're calling us.
- I'm coming.
Where's Wanda?
Wanda, come on!
Marisa!
Get lost! With that nose
you want a photo?
How much the picture?
Now what do we do?
You need to confess. Down
there, where it says "confessione".
I already confessed yesterday.
Watch out! He's a cripple!
- Long live the Madonna del Divino Amore!
- Thank you, Holy Virgin!
Ave, Ave
- Wanda...
- Yes?
I'm gonna ask for mercy from
the Madonna, too. Like you.
What am I asking for?
You don't remember?
I could ask for a villa
in Peripli.
That's not what you said!
Don't you remember?
I'll ask for whatever I feel like.
But you said you'd ask...
I changed my mind.
Why are you talking like that?
See? You made
my candle go out.
30 masses at 1 ,000 each.
That's 30,000.
I gave them thirty-five.
Yeah, you did O.K.
You never know...
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Careful not to get burnt.
I forgot
the act of contrition.
"My Lord, I repent
with all my heart..."
- And after?
- It's written in the confessional.
Wait here.
We can't go in together!
That's enough for now!
Use the other entrance!
Watch your hands!
Take it easy. Don't push!
I'm sick. I can't help it.
He's sick, too. Can't you see that?
Careful, Uncle.
- There's the altar, Uncle.
- I can't...
I can't go on. I can't move.
I'll hold you 'til
we're at the altar.
I gotta rest.
Rosie, come here.
I think he's gonna pass out.
Try again, Uncle.
We're almost there.
Everyone has a secret agony.
Everyone has a wish
for You to fulfill.
Open your heart to the suffering,
Oh, Holy Virgin!
Mercy, Madonna!
Call out with all your hearts,
"Viva Maria!"
- Viva Maria!
- Mercy, Madonna!
Mercy, Madonna!
Viva Maria!
- Heal me, Madonna!
- Make me well, Madonna!
Heal me, Madonna!
Make me well, Madonna!
Mercy, Madonna!
I beg you with all my heart!
Wanda, here!
Who with gladness
In their hearts
Stay close.
What happens next?
I dunno!
You oughta hear my heart beating.
I'm shaking.
I feel so strange, Wanda.
- Viva Maria!
- Mercy, Madonna!
Now all kneel and pray.
and beg our heavenly mother
for forgiveness.
Amleto, will the Madonna
bestow Her grace on me?
I think so.
Now approach the altar
of the Virgin.
Look into Her sweet eyes,
and in Her glance each of you
will feel the light of hope
turned on in your heart.
Madonna, help me
to change my life.
Bestow your grace on me, too.
Make me change my life.
- Uncle, now!
- I'm afraid.
Drop the crutches.
She'll have mercy on you.
I'm afraid!
I'm holding you!
Madonna, I'm a sinner,
a worm of the earth.
Have mercy on me, Madonna.
Don't leave me!
Lost your tongue?
Have a drink.
Careful, Wanda.
One glass and she's smashed.
What are you doing?
- I'm thinking.
- About what?
- What?
- She's thinking.
Too much thinking
will make your head explode.
Look at those delinquents!
Stop with the damn ball!
They're doing it on purpose!
I'll fix 'em!
Get the ball.
Blondie, the ball!
Come on, we want to play!
Give us the ball!
Next time I'll kick it
the other way!
You wanna stay here by
yourselves?
Uncle and I will leave. Just say so.
- Why should we want to?
- What's wrong with you?
- What if we wanted to?
- What's wrong?
Hey! Come over here
and get your ball!
Come over here
if you want it!
Go get her.
She can't even walk.
I'm not gonna tangle with her.
She'll manage.
This music's boring!
Let's rock!
Are you nut?
We haven't changed.
Nobody's changed!
We're all the same as before,
just like the cripple.
What do you want to change,
Cabiria?
You think this is the end?
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna sell the house.
Everything. I'm leaving.
Goodbye, you guys.
I'm through with all this!
Where'll you go?
Where? Think I'm like you?
I know where I can go. I know.
Just look at those little nuns!
Where you going with that banner?
Looking for snails?
- Why'd you make her drink?
- I made her drink?
Did the Madonna give you mercy?
Did she?
Cabiria! You wanna get us
arrested?
Amleto, look at her!
What?
Bring her back!
Leave me alone!
I wanna listen. Go on playing!
Come have fun with us!
Come dance with us!
Forget about your banner!
Forget about it.
- Why do you always butt in?
- Get lost!
Cabiria!
You're in no condition for this!
- Leave me alone.
- You're blind drunk!
Who's drunk?
What do you know?
Is the show any good?
I asked you a question!
Want me to say it stinks?
As you can see, ladies and
gentlemen, my assistant's head
has been completely
impaled by the daggers.
There's no doubt
that his head must be
soaked in blood.
You'll be amazed to see, instead,
that his head has disappeared!
In the second part
of our show, we'll feature
experiments with magnetism,
hypnotism and auto-suggestion.
Would anyone in the audience
care to volunteer? Prego, Signori!
I will!
Come right up.
Don't be afraid.
There's absolutely no danger.
We now need a representative
of the fair sex.
- How about you, Signorina?
- Me?
Yes, you! Come up. Be brave!
I don't want to.
Would you leave those young men
up there all alone?
You go, then!
Come on, chickie!
We need a laugh.
Wanna laugh?
Look at you in the mirror!
Come on, Signorina,
don't make us beg.
Should I come and get you?
I'll come and get you. Beg you.
Don't be afraid.
We're all good friends.
All tricks...
- Will you come?
- Sure! I'm coming.
Think I'm scared?
No reason to be.
There's no reason to be afraid.
You've showed how brave you are.
Come, you'll be fine.
Now, let's enjoy ourselves.
Oh, I'm so forgetful!
It's really unforgivable!
I completely forgot that
Signorina Elvira is still inside.
Oh, this heat!
You're hot too, aren't you?
How about a nice boat ride?
Does anybody here get seasick?
I was on the Isle of Elba
as a kid.
You barely got to Ostia.
Nobody here gets seasick?
That's very good.
Ah, here's our boat.
We named her "Intrepid" because
she always defies the waves.
Come on, boys.
Don't make me beg you.
Signorina, you stay here.
The boat is waiting. The sea is
calm, and the weather is fine.
I'm getting out of here!
Where are you going?
Damn, he's good!
He zapped him!
Look into my eyes!
Take the oars.
Row!
The sea is calm, transparent.
Feel the breeze.
Enjoy filling your lungs with air
saturated with salt and iodine.
Dolphins!
Boy, look at 'em jump!
One of you doesn't feel so good.
Things are looking bad, boys.
It's the open sea now.
The waves are swelling.
Hear the wind whistling.
It's a hurricane!
Help! Hold the rudder!
It's every man for himself!
Mamma mia bella!
I'm drowning!
- Scared, weren't you?
- You'd have been, too!
You were plenty scared!
Where are you going?
- You mean me?
- Yes.
It's not over?
It's not over.
You'd leave me here all alone?
What's he want now?
Signora or Signorina?
Did you have fun?
Not really.
I'd like to talk with you
a moment. Come here.
- Are you from Rome?
- I live in Rome.
In what part of town?
Colonna? Parioli? Prati?
In Prati.
Come on, be honest with me.
Where do you live?
In Borgata San Francesco.
What's so funny?
Don't pay any attention.
They're justjoking.
So, you're not married,
but you'd like to be.
Why should I get married?
Who'd marry her!
All girls want to get married.
I know a nice young man
who'd be happy to marry you.
Me?
He's rich, handsome
and drives a Ferrari.
Let's see if we can arrange it.
What type of work
do you do?
She's a countess!
Listen, I'm fine the way I am.
I got everything.
And now I'm leaving.
I don't need anything!
O.K.?
Even better.
So you're rich?
With a bank account, houses...
I own the house I live in. O.K.?
And now I'll get going.
One moment!
Don't make me look foolish.
At least let me introduce you
to the young man, Oscar.
Who the heck is Oscar?
Please step forward.
How elegant you look.
Come here. I'd like to introduce
you to the Signorina.
She wanted to meet you, too.
A pleasure.
The pleasure is all his,
believe me.
Now that you've met,
I'll leave you two alone.
This is a beautiful garden,
filled with flowers.
You can talk, confide in
each other. No one is listening.
Look, Signorina,
Oscar is offering his arm.
Come, Signorina, take his arm.
There's no harm in that.
But...we just met.
You're strolling among the flowers.
The birds are singing
but Oscar doesn't dare to speak.
He's shy, moved.
Now he says, "Signorina,
"I've been hoping to meet you
for such a long time.
"May I ask you a question?
"You're not spoken for, are you?
"There was never
a man in your life?
"Ah, I thought so.
"I often see you standing by your
window, and at Sunday Mass.
"Your eyes are always lowered.
You're always with your mother.
"That's good. Picking flowers
indicates a gentle soul.
"Signorina, may I hope
to see you again?
"Ah, thank you.
What did you say your name was?
"Thank you. I'll save this flower
like a precious object.
"Would you dance with me?"
Play, Maestro.
Oscar and Maria wish to dance.
The orchestra will play
a beautiful waltz.
"I'm wealthy
but I'm alone and unhappy.
"What good are fancy cars,
long journeys and luxury hotels?
"Smoke! Illusion!
"What I really want is a home,
children, and a wife like you."
When I was eighteen, that's when
you should have known me.
I had long black hair...
This long.
"For me, you'll always be eighteen."
Then it's true?
You love me?
Is it really true?
You're not trying to fool me?
Do you really love me?
There, there. It's all right.
What happened?
What did you make me do?
I have to close up.
I'm going!
Listen, are those creeps
still out there?
Everybody's gone.
There's nobody left.
Get going.
I gotta close up.
I'll show them a thing or two!
Pardon me, Signorina.
I'm Donofrio, accountant.
Forgive my boldness.
I don't normally
stop young ladies in the street.
I was among the audience.
Oh! You were there, watching!
Great show!
I bet you liked it!
If I ever see that slime-ball again...
Signorina!
Please don't misunderstand me.
I agree with you.
In fact, I sympathize with you.
I came to tell you
how moved I was.
We can all pretend to be
cynical and scheming.
But when we're faced with...
purity and innocence
the cynical mask drops off
and all that is best in us
awakens.
I wanted to thank you.
You did me good.
It's gotten chilly, hasn't it?
May I? Excuse me.
It's the night-time humidity.
May I buy you something?
But... I really don't know you.
Those damn creeps
are still there!
Excuse my persistence,
but these experiments with magnetism
are extremely dangerous.
They can cause imbalances
and other disturbances.
That's why I felt so strange!
Cold, hot, sweaty.
Like I had a fever.
How about that!
I would suggest a Fernet.
It'll do you good.
Come and sit down.
Just a moment.
Please sit down.
Two Fernet, please.
I swear, I've rarely suffered
as I did tonight.
When that charlatan spoke words
of love to you in Oscar's name
and you answered
with such modesty and trepidation,
it made me sick.
Something hurt me in here.
I was ill. Really ill.
Hurry up. I'm closing.
Don't be upset.
Some things cannot be touched
by human vulgarity.
Even amidst a crowd
that laughs idiotically,
there's always someone
who understands, who knows,
who appreciates.
But what did I do?
You acted out a very tender
and delicate love scene.
I'm still deeply touched.
I can't even express it.
Yes...what struck me most
is that deep inside,
you're as pure as you were at 18.
When you went to Mass
with your mother
and had long black hair,
falling down to here.
I really said that?
Closing time.
- How much?
- 150 lire.
Thank you....
Hey, you, go sleep at home!
Listen, Signorina...
What happened tonight
is extremely important to me.
Just imagine...
I'm not from around here,
I just came here by chance.
I enjoy strolling in the city
in sections that I don't know.
I went into that music hall,
without knowing why.
There's no explanation for what
happened. As if guided by fate.
Yes, that's the word: fate!
But who are you?
You sound like you're from Parioli.
What do you mean?
You talk like they them.
A refined type.
I told you my name is Donofrio.
I'm a government employee.
What do you want from me?
You might understand me better
after I tell you my first name.
Oscar.
I'm Oscar.
- Your name's Oscar?
- Yes.
So what? Your being Oscar
could be a coincidence, no?
Sure. But isn't it strange that the
hypnotist chose the name Oscar?
Signorina,
I really must see you again.
You're taking the bus?
Yeah. I'm dead tired.
I gotta get to bed.
Do we say goodbye now,
never to meet again?
Impossible.
I've got to see you again.
The city is vast and we still have
so much to say to each other.
When and where
can we meet again? Please!
I don't know...I'm busy..I work.
I'm a salesgirl... Anyway,
what'll we say to each other?
- What?
- What would we say?
There's the bus.
So long. Arrivederci.
Please don't say no.
I work, too.
Maybe we can meet after work.
Like tomorrow evening.
Signorina, wait! Tomorrow?
- The evening, no.
- Sunday afternoon?
Sunday, the Stazione Termini,
at seven.
I don't know. I feel so strange...
What're you doing?
Hurry. Let's go!
Here I am!
I was over there.
Sorry I kept you waiting.
Thank you for coming here.
You might have thought me
annoying, out of line.
It was all so strange...
As if I were dreaming.
I took the liberty,
if you'll accept.
Thanks. You didn't have to.
My pleasure.
Let's go that way.
He says he likes to talk to me.
And he talks. Boy! Does he talk!
The type who reads a lot.
Well-educated.
Last night we saw
a first-run movie.
Hey! That's your third!
I know they're good.
We went at the Metropolitan.
A costume movie.
Gladiators, Christian martyrs.
He explained to me
that it wasn't a true story.
It's just for the movies,
understand?
And then, he told me that...
he gets a kick out
of talking to me because...
because I understand him.
He's even good-looking.
Black eyes, brown skin.
A northern type.
Then we had pizza at a trattoria.
He always pays.
Even for the flowers.
- Nothing? He wants nothing?
- 'Course not.
Do me a favor, Cabi!
I'll be meeting him again
tomorrow.
What's he after?
How do I know?
And who cares?
As long as he pays!
Oh, sure!
The cops!
What you all need is jail!
Arrest them all!
I'm not running away.
If you want me, I'm here!
How are you?
How elegant you look today!
How are you feeling?
- Fine, and you?
- Thank you. Here...for you.
- Thank you. You shouldn't have.
- Don't mention it.
- It's too much.
- Take it.
Where shall we go?
Wherever you want.
Sunny day.
Let's go to the Aventino.
Your family's not from Rome?
No. I have no family left.
My mother and father
died when I was a child.
Loneliness is a heavy burden,
but I'd rather be alone
than make compromises.
We lived in Puglia,
in a small village.
The name is unimportant.
You wouldn't know it.
I grew up in an old house.
I remember the oil lamps.
My father owned a small plot
of land. His name was Giovanni.
My mother's name was Elsa,
the poor soul.
I like the name Elsa.
It's pretty.
I had no brothers or sisters.
When my father died
some ruthless relatives
robbed my mother
of what little property she had,
leaving us very poor.
I went looking for work.
What are you doing, my child?
Good day, Father.
Some alms for Sant'Antonio?
Sorry, I've no money on me.
Never mind. Some other time.
What's important is
to always be in God's grace.
You are in God's grace,
aren't you, my child?
You're not in God's grace?
Why not?
Everyone should be
in God's grace.
Whoever lives in God's grace
is happy.
I'm in God's grace
and I'm happy.
I even went to the Madonna
to ask for Her grace.
Maybe you didn't know how to
ask, or maybe you didn't need it.
Are you married?
That's bad. Girls should get
married and make children.
Matrimony is a sacred thing.
In the grace of God, my child.
Ask Sant'Antonio for help.
If you need me,
I'm Brother Giovanni.
I'm at the San Francesco
Monastery, but I'm hard to find.
I'm always running around.
Hey, Blondie!
So long!
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow I'm busy.
Then the day after tomorrow.
Same time.
I'm busy then, too.
I was gonna tell you...
I dunno if I'll keep seeing you.
But, why?
It's not that I'm
uncomfortable with you.
But what's the point?
What am I doing with you?
We're both wasting our time.
And doing what?
Anyway, what do you
want from me?
If you want...I'll marry you.
I wanted to ask you before.
But I didn't have the courage.
I've wanted to...
to ask you since
the first time I saw you.
What are you saying?
Marry me?
Marry someone you saw 10 times?
That's not how it's done!
Really!
Thank God I'm an honest woman!
That's not how it's done.
Excuse-me.
What do you know about me?
Who I am?
You ask me like that?
I'm no fool!
And you chose me!
I've asked you no question.
I don't want to know anything.
Prejudices don't touch me.
Because... what matters
is that I know your inner self.
We are...we are
two lonely creatures.
We have to stick together.
I need you.
Don't tell me that.
Don't, if it isn't true.
But it is!
What did you do?
What is it, you nut?
I'm getting married!
He asked me to marry him! We're
buying a store in Grotta Ferrata!
He's almost signed the contract.
Without me knowing, he arranged
it all: a store, a house!
I'm selling everything!
I'll sell the house...the house...
We're getting married
in two weeks!
Wanda, I'm leaving!
Does he know that you...
Of course he knows!
I told him everything.
I didn't hide anything
from him.
But he's a saint. An angel!
He didn't want to know
anything. He didn't care.
He loves me! He loves me!
Wanda! He loves me!
Who's there?
- Hello.
- May I see Brother Giovanni?
He's not back yet.
Why do you want to see him?
- To confess to him.
- Go to church for confession.
I want Father Giovanni
to hear my confession.
He can't hear your confession.
He's not an ordained priest.
I know, but...
I'll wait for Father Giovanni.
Fine. Then wait.
Why'd you pack this?
I'm not taking that!
Should I take the owl?
Nah, it brings bad luck.
But I'll take the seashell.
See if it fits.
If it fits, I'll take it.
I sold that.
Put it over there.
What a waste!
Leaving all this good stuff.
- Here are the dishes.
- Sold. Leave 'em!
Them, too?
Why not?
I got paid for them.
It would cost more
to move everything.
He sold everything back home.
So I'm selling everything, too.
All new!
Me, I'd have taken all the stuff.
Are you forgetting anything?
What could I forget?
- Did you take the money?
- Of course! I'm no idiot!
See? You forgot your fur.
Fur? What fur?
- No! I don't want that.
- Give it to my aunt?
Sure, but hurry!
They're waiting to move in!
Damn it! Those low-lives.
Close the suitcase. Tight.
Oh, la mamma!
Take one more look...
and then I'm getting married.
- What?
- I'm getting married, too.
What did I say? Nothing.
How do I look?
Real good.
It cost me 1 ,200 lire.
You got robbed.
You paid too much.
Ah, my pocketbook.
Goodbye, D'Artagnan.
Let's get going.
Time to leave.
See them? I can't stand
those starving bastards.
Let's go.
Here are the house keys.
I'm leaving. Arrivederci.
If you need anything, just tell
my friend, Signorina Wanda.
She'll write to me.
Arriverderci.
Have a good trip. Good luck!
Thank you. Likewise.
Never mind. I don't wanna
say goodbye to anybody.
It's better that way.
I'm so happy now,
and then all these people...
They'll ask questions...
I'm leaving.
I'm getting married!
- Send us some wedding candy!
- I will!
Say goodbye to Nando and
his uncle, and to everyone.
Nice, eh?
They're pretty.
You're getting married
and I never met
this fianc of yours.
I couldn't bring him
where everybody knows me.
Here's the bus.
It's here.
Ciao, Wanda....
Why are you crying?
Who's crying?
Aren't you crying?
I'll write the minute I get there
with my address.
And you'll get married, too.
Let's go.
Hurry, the suitcase.
I'll send my address right away.
Stay out of trouble.
You'll get a miracle, like me.
- Yeah, sure.
- It'll happen.
- What are you doing?
- I want to pay.
- But there's no reason...
- Please! You've always paid.
Anyway, what's mine is yours now.
It's all the same, isn't it?
Waiter!
It's getting late.
You'll see how beautiful
the sunsets are up here.
You want to get me drunk?
It's such a light wine.
The money.
Put it away.
It's my dowry.
350,000 for the house.
That's all those crooks would pay.
They knew I was in a hurry,
so they took advantage.
Then I got all my money
from the bank.
400,000.
See? I made them give me
all new bills.
Because you never asked
if I had money...
You, you're an angel,
a saint!
If you knew what I went through
to end up with this money.
I told you, I don't want to know.
Please!
Let's get away from here.
The beatings I took.
You see, some guys are
just after a girl's money.
You wouldn't believe it.
Everything for love.
But not that way.
But what about my old age?
Who worries about my old age?
I'm sorry...
Waiter, keep the change.
Let's go.
I didn't want to go on
like that forever.
I'd have quit if I could,
even tomorrow.
I'd have gone away.
To live that way forever?
I already owned the house.
Know what me
and Wanda planned?
Rent a newsstand.
Understand? You didn't exist...
Where are we going?
It's so nice here.
Let's take a little walk. O.K.?
I don't even remember
how I started.
I was a child,
that's all I remember.
And the suitcases?
We'll take them later.
You should have seen me at fifteen
with my black hair,
long, down to here.
Who understood anything?
My motherjust wanted the money.
Where are we going?
I don't know.
We're just strolling.
What's the name of that song?
Won't you kiss me?
Come...
I know a shortcut.
Oscar! Where are you?
What a bad boy you are!
Look at these flowers.
Like 'em?
They stink, but still...
I never saw flowers
like these before.
Let's go.
I'm coming.
Smell them.
What kind of flowers are they?
What's wrong? Are you sad?
Me? No. Why?
You stopped singing.
Wait a minute.
Why don't we carve
our initials on the trees?
Let's go and watch the sunset.
The sunset, eh?
Where do you wanna go?
What a strange light.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Guess there's some justice
in the world.
You suffer,
you go through hell...
but then happiness
comes along for everyone.
You've been my angel.
Your hand is freezing.
Are you cold?
Having regrets?
Beautiful, eh?
Look how deep it is!
I'd love a boat ride
right now.
Are there any boats
down there now?
- Can you swim?
- Not me!
I almost drowned once.
But they saved me.
Just imagine!
I was pushed in!
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
You don't want to kill me,
do you?
Answer me!
You want to kill me?
You want to kill me!
Don'tjust stand there.
Say something!
Speak! Don't be like that!
Speak!
Tell me.
For the money?
For the money...
Kill me!
Throw me off the cliff!
I don't wanna live anymore!
Kill me!
Throw me off!
Shut up!
I don't want to hurt you.
Can't you see that?
I don't wanna live anymore!
Kill me!
Maurizio, hurry up!
We're leaving.
We're gonna lose our way
going home!
Translation (1998)
by Giulia D'Agnolo Vallan
and
Bruce Goldstein
Subtitles (1998)
by Helen Milsted Eisenman