Tell Pong to respect
me and stop teasing me.
I know, I owe him money.
He said I was a crybaby,
that men don't cry.
He insulted me, said I
washed my wife's underwear.
He shoved me and said:
"Stop crying,
or I'll beat your wife."
In front of my children!
Uncle Luk,
I've lost my authority as a father.
Since then, my kids have been rude to me.
Sheng, you're more focused
on making babies
than earning money.
My wife asked for
a few more days.
Can't she deliver later?
Just a few more days.
Of course,
you can pay me back later,
but I won't reduce my interest rate!
If everyone were like you,
I'd starve to death.
No way!
12% every day, not a penny less.
I can smell my salted fish!
You have a good nose!
Are you sure it's yours?
Speak louder!
Here!
I told you to go easy
when there are kids around.
I said I'm your adoptive relative,
give me one more month.
He said, "If you were my dad,
I'd still beat you up."
Why did my salted herring
end up at your place?
Because it's expensive!
Should I pay for the fish you lost
and pamper a son to give to you
in case yours dies?
You good-for-nothing,
you have no manners.
He's one of us.
We're all Chinese!
Chinese bowl!
Chinese abacus!
Chinese orchid!
Chinese goose leg!
Chinese old man!
And you, are you Chinese?
Only my mother knows.
Chi got beaten up!
What? Chi got beaten up?
Where is he?
Downstairs.
It's none of your business.
Don't get involved!
Those brats!
They beat up my son.
Why did you fight?
Do you owe them money?
Chi, you need to stop!
Go tell them.
If you do,
we won't be friends anymore.
Instant Noodles...
Are you eating noodles?
That's her name,
her dad owns the Yung Café.
She's 20 years old, too old!
No, that's Pea Pudding.
Instant Noodles is 14,
and he got her pregnant.
He's here,
so whatever's on your mind,
please speak up.
Of course he's wrong
taking advantage my daughter.
Stop moaning.
Important thing is what he wants.
Marriage, as soon as possible.
The groom is responsible for the banquet
and the wedding cake.
It's then who beat me up.
Next time check how many brothers
this girl has.
Well, then?
I'll guarantee my brother will marry
your sister
but not the banquet or the wedding cake.
What are you saying?
My dad is on the verge of renouncing
my brother.
What? What are we going to do?
No banquet, no cakes?
You call it a wedding?
So you're going to leave it at that.
Of course not.
We Leongs are responsible people.
Even though my brother is only twelve.
When he says he's a man, he means man.
Dating at his age.
You claim he cheated your sister,
any evidence?
As things go. I don't see an end to end.
You cheated my sister
and you're shrill it.
I am not a man if I let my brother run.
You think we'd be sitting here
if we want to run.
You know the law as well as I do.
You get ready
to go to jail for intercourse with a minor?
Where's the minor? Who's a minor?
I am a minor.
Why didn't you say so before?
Stop squabbling with him.
Get the police, send him to jail.
Right, send him to prison.
Wrong. The publicity isn't going to do
any good.
Family matters should be kept
in the family.
Well, whatever. Hurry up and decide.
Shut up, you bitch, Really.
Why did you hit her?
If you have guts, you'd punch him only.
You want to play rough,
you maniacal?
Dear friends,
I had been in this program for 10 years.
Now, because of bad heath
I have been leave you.
I thank you for being with me
and love this program.
You know
I love Beethoven's 5th symphony.
I'll play it again for you,
the Beethoven's 5th symphony.
I say good-bye to my friends,
my husband and my son.
I hope that when they hear this music
they'll keep up their spirit and live.
Did you drop this?
I'm returning it to you.
This… This is… this…
What is he saying?
What's is this "this"?
What is he talking about?
This is a public pool.
Please observe the rule.
No misbehaviors.
Everyone with long hair,
boy or girl, should wear bathing cap.
Any boards or inflatable
objects are not allowed.
Obey instructions from the lifeguards.
Violators will be ejected.
Walk, don't run.
What's this? An insurrection?
This is a public pool.
Playing around like that is a misdemeanor
I must ask you to leave.
Pack up your balls and mattresses
and leave.
No pleadings, no fuss.
Just pack up and go.
Hey, what are you doing up there?
Get down.
You can't stay here, get down.
Why are you so hostile?
Miss, don't you know this platform
is reserved for lifeguards only.
It's for observation of the whole pool.
You can't stay here, please get down
I just climbed all the way up
my feet is tired out
I can't move.
Why don't you carry me down.
Well? Do you have to think about this?
Where are you from?
Me? I'm from here.
Are you going to carry me or not?
You're out of your mind.
Are you shy?
All right, come on.
Thank you.
You nymphomaniac.
I got it.
Hey, give it back.
Give me my pants.
Got you.
Why do you like to spy on my aunt
and your stepmother?
Let me go.
Look at you, hiding behind a mask
all day.
How are you going to survive if you're
timid?
Kathy you have something against
David Bowie?
You pick on him every time I see you
Louis.
Pretty, isn't it?
Is Kabuki still in fashion?
Good thing never go out of style.
Is your Japanese boyfriend teaching you?
I give up.
Did you try this?
Ask Auntie to buy for me next time
if she goes to Japan.
The kids there go crazy over stuff
like mad.
Want to try?
Kathy, what are you doing?
Do you still want to sniff your
Japan gasoline?
There's a 17 year old boy in Nagoya
who sniffed 83 cans of this.
His shin started to rot, most dread,
his mind deteriorated
and became vegetable.
The Japs' invasion, there's truth.
Where's the pants?
My pants.
What pants?
My lifeguard pants.
Your pants isn't here.
It is because you're pretty doesn't matter
you funny.
Hey, this place is too small.
Is this your boyfriend?
What do you think?
Hey, I'm not.
Who cares about you.
Hey... Hey...
Come watch! There's going to be a show?
What's going on?
You're real cute.
You're crazy to fool with me.
Give me my pants back.
If not, I'll strip your skirt off.
Oh no! Quick! Save her?
Louis, come save her, quick.
Worst comes to worst, you get heat to
him, go, hurry.
You are a man, be a hero
and save the damsel.
Give it back quickly.
Go on, get over there.
You're such a coward.
My pants.
This doesn't look too good.
Not at all attractive.
So, you're her boyfriend?
No.
Of course.
You don't look like it, you're more like
a pansy.
Yeah, a real pansy.
What pansy?
Is he one of your good sisters?
Of course.
What good sisters?
This is what you call good sisters.
Hold it.
Don't, don't.
Do you have to use your teeth?
It's you who's a sissy.
What do you know? This is called street
fighting.
No more.
Sister.
Get inside first.
Are you afraid?
Afraid? I'm just scared you're going to
catch cold.
Put it on quickly.
See how filthy your pants are.
Does it hurt?
Here, have a drink.
Bye!
John.
Beer.
Very well.
That person stepped on my foot.
What are going to do about it?
Hey, who you're looking for?
Tomato?
What's the matter? Why don't you just
hang up?
What do you care where I go?
I'm going to sleep in the streets,
come look for me.
Can I come over to your place tonight?
No way.
Well, where can I go then?
I have nowhere to go
I have all my clothes at your place.
You can't come and that's final.
What can I do? I want to see you
I don't care.
I have to come pick up my stuff?
Pick up what? I already said we're
splitting up.
Well, you weren't clear about how?
Thought I made my self clear the last time.
You weren't clear.
I don't understand.
Andy, what do you want me to do?
Tell me.
Whatever you say I do, I'll do it.
Somebody here? Is it Lily? Lulu?
Don't open the door, don't open the door.
Hey, What are you doing?
Get off the line. Idiot.
This is a public phone.
Look, there's someone waiting
to use this phone
I don't like to say anything more.
You're going to die? Good.
I'm still not impressed.
You think it's "Love story"? Is it cancer?
I'm going to die tonight.
Still on the line?
Yes
I'm done soon.
Andy! Andy!
You can use the phone.
Can you pay for my drink?
Pay it yourself.
Thanks.
Bill!
$9.5, thank you.
Still here, bye.
Hey, still out this late?
I have no money for cab fare.
Wait a minute.
Where do you live? I'll ask him to take
you home.
No thanks, I want to sit here for a while.
The air here is so
refreshing, tell him leave.
I'm sorry, you can go.
Bastard.
Did you afraid of running
into a nasty type?
There's nobody more nasty than me.
Bye.
Hey, I'll take you home, Tomato.
Go on up, Andy's waiting for you.
Want me to go with you?
Can I give you a kiss?
Bye.
Of course.
What's wrong?
I'm leaving.
So soon?
Why can't you spend a night here?
I don't think so.
Thank you.
What are you afraid of?
I love you so much.
Buddy, do you have a room?
What a coincidence.
Fancy meeting your servant here.
Sit down then.
I'm going to sleep.
Come talk to me.
Take off your shoes.
My shoes?
It's more comfortable.
Where did you get this book?
Ah B gave it to me.
He thinks I like him
just because I kept it.
Actually I haven't even glance at it.
Ah B.
The one that I screamed at on the phone
just now?
Then Andy is Ah A?
Is he always this brutal to you?
Yeah, it's not the first time.
It can't be helped, nobody forced me
to love him.
I'm not going back again, though.
Why don't you go home?
Where's your parents?
You' re so sweet.
Nobody's ever said that of me.
Don't you know you're a good person?
It's late, I think they're all asleep.
Yeah, that was what I said.
Clear everything.
OK, let me do it.
Rinse it if you can't wash it
I can't accept vermin.
Come and help me.
Kitty, Kitty, Miao, Miao.
You still haven't gone.
Let me wash my face, ok?
What show are we seeing anyway?
A foreign film, in English.
Even if it were good I wouldn't understand.
So many good films and you have to
pick a foreign one.
Name one thing that's good about the film.
What's good is that its long enough.
Even if it's bad you have a place
to go 3 hours.
Could you treat me to some fish porridge?
Have I even seen the girl who's coming?
Let's go.
After the show, should I phone before
I coming back?
That would be best.
Whatever you do, don't do it on my bed.
Hey, what are you up to?
Is there a power shortage?
Oh, it's you.
My, but you're thrifty.
What are you doing here?
No one invited me to the show?
Do you want to see the show?
No, it's too long.
Go see something else.
No, there's enough to see at home
Don't need to go out.
Go to instant noodle's
I won't go.
Then go to Auntie's
I'm broke.
$30, that's not enough for 2 hours.
Wow, this girl is really precious.
Go before I kick you downstairs.
OK, I'm going.
It's enough for 3 hours.
Bastard.
You're my brother, I'll give you advice.
There's a nice, quiet place
where the food is good.
Go to hell.
Bye bye.
Mother says to at least rinse it
if you can't wash it.
She hates rats and cockroaches.
Bean Cake.
You're the only one left in the store.
My brother wants nine glasses of
egg nogs.
Make it up to him and make it snappy
he is in a hurry.
Nine glasses?
9 glasses and not one less, I'm going.
Who are you looking for?
Is Mr. Leong here?
Not here.
My name's Fong, I have things to
discuses with him.
My friend ask me to come here.
He said Leong is generous in help
the needy!
Leave your phone number?
Here it is.
What's up?
Delivering the egg nogs.
Who ordered them?
OK, put them here.
Is there anything else?
No, let's go.
Collecting bottles.
No bottles to collect.
My god, look who's making a call?
I wanted to phone you from the store.
I phoned and phoned but never got line.
It's going bad before it even started.
Mother?
She went to the show.
Work it over any loose change,
small notes or big notes.
Fine.
What's up?
They want to come over to
your place, instead of mine.
That's even better.
Sixth uncle.
You come too, please sit wherever.
Help us get the game set up.
Bring out the mahjong set.
Change the set, this one brings me bad
luck.
Don't change it, there's no need to change
I'm a just man and I say there's no need.
No, I still think we should change the set.
Let me make a bet.
This set will do, don't waste time.
Game 1 1,6, game 2 1,6, game 3 1,6.
Missy, this is no laughing matter.
This is the number I want.
Let's go home.
Your auntie hasn't gone to sleep yet?
I won't know until I go home and see.
Kathy, Shinsuke is here.
When did you arrive in Hong Kong?
Just now?
What's happening?
I've left the Red Army.
I should have left a long time ago
like you told me to.
Now I'm a deserter.
Any Red Army member can kill me.
Take this opportunity.
I'll play it again for you
the Beethoven's 5th symphony
I say good-bye to my friends,
my husband and my son.
I hope that when they hear this music
they'll keep up their spirit and live.
Is that really your mother's voice?
How come it sounds so young?
She was already 45 years old.
She presented classical music on radio.
There's loads of them.
Before she died, that was the year before.
She said to me, Louis
when you think of me,
you listen to these tapes.
Do you still miss her?
Did Kathy come?
No, the master is upstairs.
Continue, don't mind me
I'm Pong, are you Tomato?
Tomato is inside.
How is it? Good sister.
Kathy is late, this is
Tomato, this is Pong.
We went rowing the other day
so much fun.
How come you're with him?
Me with him?
You mean he's with me.
When I entered
I thought the girl playing the piano
was you.
She's his step-mother.
Your step-mother? She's got class.
Where did you get this?
That Jap was such a jerk.
I'm his assistant chef
but he gets on my nerves.
Couldn't take it so I sneaked out
to play pinball.
He found out and gave me a piece of shit
he threatens to fire me.
You know I have very little patience.
So I took this back.
Believe it or not, I can cut a 1001 piece
sashimi out of this.
Didn't you say you were a taxi driver?
That was before.
What now?
I'm taking it easy, careful I don't steal
your job.
What are you doing?
Where's the kitchen?
Keep this in the fridge.
Outside.
Kathy.
Pong.
He is my friend from Japan, Takedashi.
This is Pong, have a seat first
I have to look for Louis.
See you later.
Good evening.
I like the freedom young people
in Harajuku have.
Kathy wants me to guest him.
As long as you're open minded
you can feel free anywhere.
Not in Hong Kong, it's too crowded.
Tokyo has 3 million more people than
Hong Kong.
A more dense population.
Not the same
the Japanese are being dressed.
Daddy? Is Nomad in Hong Kong?
Where is it berth?
Nothing, a friend of mine wants to stay
a few days.
Good, we'll get in touch.
What did he said?
He said it's a shame
Japan has a lot Chinese don't appreciate.
Unbelievable, what does
Japan have to offer.
Tea ceremony, flower arrangement,
karate...
Everything borrowed from China.
Chinese can't preserve what's good
in their culture.
They should thank the Japanese
are doing it well for them.
So, you speak Chinese.
My dad was stationed at Nanking during
the war.
He taught me, but I'm not good at it.
Nanking.
Ask him how many Chinese his dad
slaughtered.
Ask him if he had a taste of Chinese
Kung-fu.
A real kung-fu expert
will inhale and exhale silently.
A real Sino-Japanese battle.
What's going on?
Stop it, we're all friends.
What friend?
We may be friends but he's Japanese.
Tell him not to worry, we'll take him
to go on early tomorrow.
Don't worry, Louis will take care of you.
Do you like Oki Masao?
This was his most acclaimed piece
at Milan fashion show recently.
Oki Masao? Yes, I know
I'm a great admirer of his fashion design.
Sorry, I don't understand Japanese.
Louis.
Stella.
Kathy didn't come?
No.
Let me introduce you, this is Louis.
He is my niece Kathy's friend.
He studies fashion design, likes the
Japanese best.
Mr. Louis.
This is Miss Chiyoko.
She's Oki Masao assistant.
She came here especially from Tokyo.
She helps the preparation
for this fashion show?
Have you met Kathy's boyfriend?
I want to ask him to be our model.
You mean Pong?
No, the Japanese guy, Shinsuke.
Shinsuke?
Kathy's boyfriend, just arrived form Japan.
Kathy has quite a few boyfriends.
Are these two swords real?
He wants to know if these swords are real.
They're real but not authentic.
It's based on the old sword of Yagyu.
She said it is real.
Not bad, style quite good.
I know, it's shogun's samurai.
He knows Shogun's Samurai.
T.V.
Conspiracy of Yagyu.
But the moment I saw these swords
it reminded me of Samurais
committing suicide.
Yes, excellent progress.
He is in Hong Kong now,
but we still don't know where he's
hiding.
All concerned parties have been found.
None have the power to block our plan.
There's no danger.
All we lack now is the last assault
No problem at all.
Thanks, we'll complete our mission soon.
Let me declare again that I don't love you.
Our love and spiritual lives have nothing
in common.
What about the sex lives?
Were there sex life?
He wishes there were.
Be more serious.
Our lives have nothing in common...
and no future.
Please stop pestering me.
Just a moment.
It's finished.
If things go on like this,
I'll turn into psychopath.
We both suffer.
I never want to see you again.
Why don't you split and get lost.
This will do, it's ruthless enough.
Enough.
You have to deliver this for me in a while.
Louis.
Buy me something to drink?
What do you want to drink?
Anything will do.
I have a letter for Tomato.
I can leave it with you.
Come on in.
Would you mind pouring us some tea.
Please don't bother?
Please have a seat.
Sit.
There's no tea, will a soft drink do?
Fine.
We're out of soft drinks, how about water?
Anything will do.
Ice water.
Somebody here with a letter for me.
Let me declare again that I don't love you.
Our love and spiritual lives have nothing
in common
and no future, please stop pestering me.
If things go on like this,
I'll turn into psychopath.
We bother suffer.
I never want to see you again.
Why don't you split and get lost.
The bearer of this letter is my true love
forever.
You're good, it's just that he's better
than you much more.
See for yourself, no fight.
No fight, what do you mean "no fight".
It means no comparison.
No fight.
No fight, what do you mean "no fight".
No fight... No fight.
Auntie, I'm not...
Auntie...
OK, I'll show you a real fight.
He really fell.
You must go to shopping very often?
Yes, about three times a week.
Have any hobby?
How many times you play mahjong
in one week.
Where is Kathy?
She said she'll wait here no reason
she shouldn't.
How would I know?
Hey! Did you know I made it with Kathy
last night?
Really?
Do you know where?
At Disco Disco?
No.
City Hall?
Space Centre?
Wrong again
I can't guess.
Next time, maybe the subway.
Water proof.
You must go to shopping very often?
Yes, about three times a week.
Louis... Louis...
He didn't fell down?
What are you doing up there?
Yearly at this time he goes by the route
to Arabia.
Next month
it will be our turn to sail past there.
And then go straight to Arabia.
I've thought it over, and I still
want to go Japan first.
Otherwise, I'd die unfulfilled.
Does Kathy approve?
What you're afraid of?
No, but Arabia is too far.
Besides, next month is still a long time.
Who knows what it will be like the day.
And then I might have moved to Outer
Space.
Good morning.
Louis, where's Kathy?
Miss Chiyoko wants to find her.
Yeah, I don't know where those two guys
hide my wife.
I'm so embarrassed to disturb you.
Has Kathy gone looking for her new
boyfriend?
What has he said that's so funny?
This idiot is also looking
for his girlfriend.
You mustn't tell him.
Kathy's with her boyfriend on the Nomad.
What's Nomad? I thought it was agreed to
keep it secret.
Nobody's allowed to reveal where's Nomad.
What is Nomad?
It's Louis' father's boat,
all black and very special.
What Nomad are you taking about?
Nothing.
These kids plan to go to Arabia
on Nomad.
Isn't it ridiculous?
She said Nomad again.
What are they talking about?
Speak up, where's Kathy?
Come with us to Arabia,
the Nomad is very safe.
Where to? Brazil?
South Africa or Switzerland?
Kathy, did you remember
where I've been to this year?
Even I can't remember all the place.
But Arabia is not the same.
It's not one's native land.
I want to return to Japan.
I want to go back to Japan.
Remember how deserters are treated
by Red Army.
They'll force you to commit hara-kiri.
You can't avoid death, why run away?
Come with us, I guarantee nobody
can find you
I'd rather die in Japan.
You've changed.
Yes, I've not been able to sleep well
in past months.
Because whenever I close my eyes
I dream of being executed.
You're not that weak.
Yes I am, I've seen too much blood in fact.
I cannot be a cold-blooded "Red Army"
anymore.
We're going with Pong and Louis to Lantau
Island in a few days.
Come with us.
Do you like Pong?
Yes.
Because he's both coarse and tender?
Yeah, when I'm with him
I don't have to waste so much energy
to think.
Only the physical, purely physical.
No direct contact,
but I know he's on a yacht.
We've already found out where it's located.
We'll make our move immediately.
Good, our orders are, at whatever
sacrifice
the renegade must be executed in HK.
He must commit hara-kiri.
Yes.
Strictly confidential, top secret.
Kathy.
Hey, we already stayed here several days.
We won't come to any conclusion.
Let's go.
Good, let's go.
You miss that Jap.
I am, so what.
He must feel lonely on Nomad,
let's to visit him.
We do nothing for the society.
What society, we are the society.
Japs... That's an insult.
Why doesn't he come over?
Let's go swimming.
Faster.
Run, she's going to kill you.
Pong... Pong
Kathy, don't go out.
Pong... Pong.
Hara-kiri.
Cut off his head.