Nosferatu the vampyre
Lucy.
Calm down.
Lucy, calm down.
I see something horrible.
Calm down, Lucy.
Be calm, Lucy. All is well.
Jonathan, you know, it's not good for you -
always eating your breakfast
with such haste.
It worries me.
Good morning.
Ah, harker. Please come here.
Yes, mr renfield?
I have a task for you.
It's something I don't dare entrust
to anyone else.
You're very kind, mr renfield.
Count Dracula
has sent me a letter from transylvania.
He wants to buy a house here.
Of course, it's a long journey
to go and see him.
Where is that?
Over the carpathian mountains, isn't it?
Yes,
but be assured, there will be
a large commission.
Oh, then I could get a
nicer house for Lucy.
She deserves something better.
Yes.
Well, this won't be easy.
It may take you a long time,
and cause you a fair amount of sweat,
and also, possibly,
a little blood.
It'll be good to get out
of the city for a while,
away from these canals,
which go nowhere
apart from back on themselves.
Transylvania... there it is!
Deep in the forests.
A wonderful place.
A little gloomy, but very exciting.
The count is looking
for a beautiful old house.
I thought about the big
one near your place.
But it's almost in ruins,
it's been abandoned for years.
I'm sure he will be able to restore it.
Anyway, we'll offer it to him.
- You'll leave at once?
- At once? Today?
Certainly. I've got all the papers here.
We mustn't make him wait.
All right, if you insist, then
it shall be today. I'm ready.
Today? Right away?
Yes, to transylvania.
It's a strange place
where there are still some wolves,
and people believe in ghosts.
Jonathan, don't go!
- I have this awful feeling.
- That's ridiculous.
You'll be in danger. Don't go.
Wolves, robbers, and ghosts.
You mustn't leave like this.
I cannot permit it.
Let's at least spend some time
by the sea first -
that place we always liked so much.
Lucy...
I don't know. Sometimes I'm so blind.
Jonathan, I have to say this,
even if you think it's foolish,
coming from the feeble,
defenceless heart of your wife.
Yes?
I feel it like a force,
an inner, nameless,
deadly fear.
Lucy is the dearest thing in the
world to me. Take care of her.
Mina, treat her like a sister.
- Yes.
- Goodbye.
Innkeeper! Quick, my supper.
I must go to the castle tonight.
Must you really go there?
Yes. Why?
Do you have any idea
what that place is like?
Do you wish to bring ruin upon yourself?
Do you know that
at midnight, all kinds of evil spirits
are set loose?
- People disappear without a trace.
- Oh, come on. That's all superstition.
Oh, no.
You will not find a coach
which will take you there.
And your own horse
needs to be taken care of here
for a few days.
I'll find another horse.
Don't go there, sir.
The gypsies, some of them have been
to the other side.
They know.
He says you shouldn't go there, young man.
He says that you have to pass a great chasm
which swallows the unwary.
Then come towering crags,
then the borgo pass,
where the light suddenly divides,
and there, he says,
one land rises up towards
heaven and one falls.
No one has ever come back from there.
The gypsies here say
that no such castle exists,
except perhaps in the minds of men.
Just a ruin, they say. A ghost castle.
And whoever enters
that land of phantoms
is lost, never to return.
For me?
'Of vampires and bloodsuckers,
'of corpses which devour their own flesh,
'of incubi and succubi,
'of the living dead
who follow strangers in the night
'and jump on their backs.'
"Transylvania... nosferatu, the undead.
'The curse will weigh heavily on the people,
the curse of the vampire, nosferatu...'
Coachman, could you take me
to the borgo pass? I'll pay you well.
There is no road to the borgo pass.
But it's right there.
I need your coach.
I haven't got a coach.
Could I have at least one of your horses?
I'm willing to pay double the price.
Sorry, sir, but can't you see?
I haven't any horses.
Well, then, I'll have to walk.
Count Dracula?
I am count Dracula
and I welcome you to my castle.
I've been waiting for you,
you must be Jonathan harker.
Yes.
Come in.
The night is cold,
and you must be tired and hungry.
These are the papers.
The folded document contains
the floorplan of the house,
which I'm sure you will want to see.
Yes, yes. Please help yourself.
Go ahead.
I'm afraid you must dine alone.
It's nearly midnight,
and I partake of nothing at this hour.
Unfortunately, the servants are not
at our disposal either,
so allow me
to attend to your comfort.
Listen.
The children of the night make their music.
Ah, young man,
town-dwellers cannot feel empathy
for the soul of a hunter.
The knife might be dirty.
It could give you blood poisoning.
Please let me do it.
- It's the oldest remedy in the world.
- It's nothing. It's hardly worth mentioning.
It's only for the best, you understand.
Let's sit up a while.
It's still many hours till dawn,
and during the daytime, I'm always away.
Lucy, my love.
There is no postal service from here,
but I shall write a diary,
preserving all my thoughts
and feelings for you.
Last night, after a tiresome journey,
I finally reached my destination,
the castle of count Dracula.
I had a bad dream, but I hope it'll pass.
I still feel a little weariness.
Everything about this castle looks
so unreal. It is so strange,
that at times I wonder
if I haven't dreamed it.
I no longer attach any importance
to sunshine or the glittering fountains
that youth is so fond of.
I love the darkness and the shadows,
where I can be alone with my thoughts.
I am the descendant of an old family.
Time is an abyss,
as deep as a thousand nights.
Centuries come and go.
To be unable to grow old is terrible.
Death is not the worst thing,
there are things much more horrible.
Can you imagine enduring centuries,
each day experiencing
the same futile things?
I'm glad you found
such a large old house for me.
Very near to your own place,
I understand?
Yes, it's just around the corner.
May I have a look at the contract?
What a
lovely throat.
It's my wife, Lucy.
Your hand...
The documents, the contract for the house.
I will sign at once.
Yes, but we haven't settled a price...
It's a small matter between gentlemen.
I will accept whatever
you consider to be fair.
How long did it take you
to get here from wismar?
Four weeks.
Ah, yes...
It takes a while to travel by land.
'From the seed of belial
is the vampire born,
'he who feeds on the blood of mankind,
'who, unredeemed, taketh his refuge
in caves, tombs, coffins,
filled with the cursed soil of cemeteries
'wherein the black death
hath reaped his harvest,
'the plague.'
Jonathan!
She has a sudden fever.
And her pulse is very fast.
She needs to rest.
Call me at once if you
think it is necessary.
But I don't think it is
really that serious.
Oh, god, he must be going to wismar.
Lucy!
Lucy is in danger. I've
got to get out of here.
It's strange,
but the papers are all in order.
It reads,
'from varna to wismar.
Garden soil for botanical experiments."
Open one of them.
I want to make sure. This one.
Mother superior.
Stop the black coffins.
The patient we got
yesterday is having a fit.
- Which one?
- The one who bit the cow.
- We have him in solitary confinement.
- I'm coming.
Blood is life!
- Blood is life.
- Has he done this before?
Yes, he did the same a few hours ago. Instead
of taking food, he tries to eat flies.
- Blood is life.
- Give it to me, let go!
Help!
Now!
Quiet. I hear the rustling of sails.
Still there's no letter.
But Lucy, you mustn't worry.
The post from transylvania
is very slow.
Even the postman says as much.
Something has happened to Jonathan...
Lucy, have faith.
The lord will hear our prayers.
The lord is so far away from us
in our hour of distress.
The young gentleman is quite ill,
he mustn't travel yet.
The black coffins.
I must get to wismar
before the black coffins...
The young gentleman should wait at least
until the doctor comes tomorrow.
But Lucy is in danger. I have to go.
The black coffins... evil is on its way.
Yes.
The ship seems burdened by a curse.
Since we left the black sea,
one after another, four sailors and a mate
have taken ill and passed away.
One sailor and our cook have disappeared
without a trace.
A rumour circulated, terrifying everyone,
that there was a stranger on board.
We searched everywhere.
Only the rats are a real plague.
We are still trying to maintain
a north-westerly course.
Wind is steady, 12 knots.
Mr renfield.
You sent my husband to transylvania.
I haven't heard from him in weeks
and I am deeply worried.
I'm ready to set out for
transylvania myself.
Stay here.
The master comes.
Who is coming? Tell us more.
The master of the rats.
The army of rats is hungry
and 400,000 strong.
We had better leave now.
'Plague
"n varna...
The master is here.
Lay a plank across.
The ship must be fully checked.
Untie him.
Not a soul on board,
very little freight,
and the hold is teeming with rats.
But here is the log.
It is truly a mystery.
Perhaps, gentlemen,
the ship's log may hold the clue to it.
"Varna, sixth of June.
'Crew, apart from me, the captain:
Two mates, five sailors,
'a cook. Direction: The dardanelles.
'Course westward.
Today a third man died of fever.
'Last night, the second mate, who was on
watch, disappeared without a trace...
'20th of June.
'Course northward, high waves,
making 14 knots towards biscay.
'Fear grows daily among the men.
'Only the first mate and I remain alive.
'Something seems to be on board.
'Rats everywhere. Could it be the plague?'
go home quietly, please.
Shut the doors and windows.
Gentlemen...
Madam, we are delivering this man,
who says he lives here.
Lucy!
Jonathan!
Who is this woman?
That one...
Let's bring him in.
He must be suffering from
a severe brain fever.
The sun is hurting me.
Dr Van Helsing, do you think it is possible
that we have all gone mad
and one day we will all wake
to find ourselves in straitjackets?
Excuse my uninvited entrance.
I am count Dracula.
I know about you.
I read Jonathan's diary.
Since being with you, he is ruined.
- He will not die.
- Yes, he will.
Death is overwhelming.
We are all at his command.
The rivers continue to flow without us.
Time trickles away.
And look outside.
The stars spin and turn in confusion.
Only death is cruelly certain.
Death is cruel to the unsuspecting.
But death is not everything.
It is crueller to be unable to die.
I wish I could partake of the love
which exists between you and Jonathan.
Nothing in this world, not even god,
can touch that.
Even though, since his return,
Jonathan does not recognise me any more.
I could change everything.
If you were to come and join me,
there would be salvation for your husband
and for me.
The absence of love, you know,
is the most abject pain.
Salvation comes from ourselves alone.
And you may rest assured
that I am not afraid to
think the unthinkable.
Good night.
Stop!
Help!
'Nosferatu, the undead.
'He who drinketh the blood of his victims
'and turneth them, likewise,
into phantoms of the night.
'He 1s as a shadow and hath no reflection.
'At night he goes hunting
'and penetrates through walls and doors.
'In the shape of a bat, he wafts
into the chambers of the sleeping,
'in the shape of a black wolf,
he hunts down those who flee.
'Abandon all hope if he appears.
'And yet, though the vampire
be an unnatural being,
'he must obey some natural laws.
"The sign of the cross casts him out.
"The sunlight destroys him.
'A consecrated host can bar his retreat.
'And should a woman pure of heart
'cause him to forget the crow of the cock,
'the first light of day will destroy him."
What is your command, master?
Go north.
To Riga.
The army of rats and the black death
are with you.
Thy will be done. Amen.
Amen!
The plague! The plague!
What are you doing here?
- I must go to the town council.
- It no longer exists. It's been dissolved.
- Then I have to see the mayor.
- He is dead.
Go home as quickly as you can.
I know the reason for all this evil.
Why won't you listen to me?
I know the reason...
But, my child, these are just figments
of your imagination.
But dr Van Helsing,
you have read Jonathan's diary.
You have seen it with your own eyes.
It's getting worse out there every day.
The plague, the rats...
And this book about the vampire.
You must see it.
We live in a most enlightened era.
Superstitions such as you mentioned
have been refuted by science.
I am absolutely certain it exists.
I believe what I see with my own eyes.
Faith, faith...
Yes, faith.
Yes. Faith, dr Van Helsing.
Faith.
Faith is the amazing faculty of men
which enables us to believe things
which we know to be untrue.
You must come and help me
destroy this monster.
We must find his lair.
Coffins have arrived by boat.
Let us start searching tonight.
My child,
you need to rest and recuperate.
This business with your husband
has completely worn you out.
No, dr Van Helsing. Tonight!
This has got to be studied
first, scientifically.
No, tonight! There is no time to lose!
The good farmer knows that everything
must happen in its own time.
He doesn't dig up the wheat
to make sure it is growing.
Only children playing at being farmers
do such things.
Then I shall destroy the monster alone.
Well, then...
Mother superior, my medicine...
How did I come to make
your acquaintance, madam?
God, forgive me for what I do.
- Join us, please.
- Drink with us. Be our guest.
We've all caught the plague.
We are enjoying each day that's left.
Madame Lucy!
Madame Lucy! Open the door!
Are you all right?
Come quickly to the schraders'.
Something terrible has happened.
Lucy, compose yourself.
You can come closer,
it is certainly not the plague.
My god, what has happened?
We don't know exactly.
Except that this morning,
schrader found Mina dead.
Yes. He lost his mind.
He was raving.
The matter will be explored
with scientific thoroughness,
without superstition or prejudice.
Enough.
Enough of your science!
I know now what I have to do.
A consecrated host may bar the vampire.
And should a woman pure of heart
cause him to forget the crow of the cock,
the first light of day will destroy him.
Now I know everything.
Oh, god,
I should have listened to her before.
A stake, and a hammer, quickly.
I have to destroy this fiend forever.
Stop!
Don't do it!
No.
Help!
Van Helsing!
Seize him.
That man has murdered the count!
Have you?
With that stake? Yes.
But I can explain.
I don't need an explanation.
You are under arrest, dr Van Helsing.
Arrest this man!
Arrest? You are asking to arrest him?
- Go and get the police.
- The police are no more.
Then... then take the man to prison!
There is no one there
to guard him any more.
Then you must arrest him yourself.
How am I to do that? I need weapons.
Arrest him! You are a town employee!
Well, where will you take me, then?
I wonder myself...
Take me wherever you want,
or can.
What are you doing standing there?
Fetch a broom.
Can't you see everything
is covered in dust?
Seal the bedroom
for the official investigation.
And bring me my horse.
I have much to do
now.
 