Are you really moving tomorrow?
Yes, early tomorrow.
Don't forget to call and
let us know your number.
Sure.
You're lucky,
getting accepted at "Mater".
Many others get accepted.
But I'm not.
My daddy said my new school
was the football champ.
They're here since kindergarten,
what make you decide
to have them transferred?
We'd like them to be
in the school closer to our home.
Isn't here close enough?
We're moving to a new home.
Okay.
Here, it's all done.
Thank you, I have to say goodbye.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Let's go ONN.
OHH, bring your brother.
I've got to go.
Don't forget the number.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Let's go.
We'll stop by at the supermarket.
I'll prepare a special meal.
Let's celebrate a farewell
to our old home, okay?
Okay.
Don't forget my favourite.
Definitely, everybody's favourites.
It's from mom.
Come on dad, let me.
"Will be late tonight"...
late again.
"Remind OHH to pack
and take care of the baby"
Go dad.
Watch out.
I'm going to get you now.
Come on UMM. Let's go.
OHH, be careful!
How's it UMM, having fun?
It's no big deal.
Nothing to be afraid of.
Come here, give him to me.
If it were you, and daddy pushed it
as fast, how about it?
How about what?
Come, race with me.
Okay.
Be careful.
Watch out for the car.
Then, the prince and his horse
are going to rescue the princess
and the kids from the witch castle.
But that wicked witch came back
and flies right in front of the prince,
princess, and children.
You are very good getting
in my castle.
But no one ever lives to tell.
In a meantime, the witch said.
Hmm.. What's it call.
That one-eyed giant.
Yes, she called for the
one-eyed giant from the pit.
All of a sudden,
the witch used her power
to darken the sky,
so dark that no one could see anything.
The prince then swung
his magic sword around,
to bring back the sparkling stars
to the sky.
So they could see the trail.
Mommy's home.
Have you eaten yet?
I did.
Why's the house so dark?
Daddy's telling us a fairy tale.
Daddy, let's continue.
It's really a fun.
Aww..ONN.
Come on daddy.
Did you pack your stuff yet?
Not yet.
Haven't I told you to?
And still up so late.
It's okay, I'll help her pack.
Come on guys, let's get to bed.
But it's not ended yet.
Don't complain.
You've listened to it
so many times already.
But it's still fun.
Some other time, okay?
Hey, who do you want to be,
prince or princess?
May be the horse?
I want to be the prince.
How about being a witch?
Dad, how's our new home?
It's an apartment.
They don't have a yard
like ours then.
They should,
every large apartment usually has one.
They might even have a playground.
What? You've never been there?
No, I've never been there.
Come on, flight.
- Get it, that one-eyed giant.
- Again.
You too, better sleep now,
so you can get up early.
Strange, why haven't you been there?
Sleep.
Thanks.
Give me a hand.
Easy...Easy.
Be careful, it belonged
to my great grandfather.
Higher, be careful.
Oh, my god.
I'm sorry.
What?
- Help!
- What is it? NID.
- What?
- A turtle! Help me!
Oh, just a turtle.
What a scream.
ONN, come out here.
Bring your NINJA out too.
Didn't I tell you?
I don't allow you
to bring NINJA along.
If he's here alone,
who will take care of him?
Who will feed him?
Enough. It'll find its way to survive.
Take it back to the pond. Now.
- But he'll die.
- Now!
Are you throwing this away?
We'll keep them.
They're daddy's fairy tales.
Go, get down to your pond.
I don't want the children
to have any problem.
At least,
during the first six months,
you shouldn't make any contact.
Give them a chance to learn
about what's happening.
After that,
you may visit them sometime.
But not too often.
They're also my children.
We've already agreed on this.
Would you think it over?
It's not only giving me a chance,
but the children's too.
It's over. It's already over.
PHA.
Get in the car.
OHH
OHH...We'll be leaving now.
Get in the car.
What about dad?
Why isn't he coming with us?
He'll come.
He has some work to finish.
He'll join us later.
What about his stuff?
Why none of his thing
is coming with us?
They're all still in the room.
Get in the car now, OHH.
I said he'll come.
ONN, daddy's not going.
Mommy lies,
daddy won't live with us.
Mom and dad won't live
together anymore.
That's enough!
You lie, I'm not going,
I'll stay with daddy.
OHH.
OHH, listen to me. Please.
I don't want to go.
I want to live here.
OHH.
- Daddy please, don't get divorced.
- OHH.
- Let's stay together please.
- Wait, ONN.
Please, I beg you.
- Don't cry baby. Listen to me.
- OHH.
This separation will just be temporary.
Everybody should have some problems.
And there is one between mom and dad.
But trust me,
we shall work it out,
and we'll be together again.
I'll stay with you.
Please, let me stay with you.
No, you can't.
I've got lots of work to do.
I don't have time
to take care of you all.
Go stay with your mom, okay?
I won't.
Me too.
Come on, do as I told,
go with your mom,
and I'll come to see you.
Come, OHH, ONN.
It's time to go now.
Come on.
If you don't go,
Me and him are not going
to talk to each other ever again.
Go.
Come, ONN.
Let's get going.
When is daddy gonna come to see us?
I don't know.
Excuse me, PHA.
OHH, ONN, come here,
come see your room.
This is your room, ONN.
Do you like it?
I also bought you this new desk.
Okay, put your things in place.
I'll be back to help.
Come, OHH.
Your room, like it?
Why don't ONN and I stay
in the same room?
You're not that young anymore,
and should have a little privacy.
Okay? I have to go help ONN unpack.
It's very convenient here.
The store downstair opens 24 hrs.
Your school is only 10 mins.
Away by bus, and my office
is just a little bit further.
I can drive you to school everyday.
What about UMM?
I'll put him in the nursery downstair.
See? It's very convenient.
Okay, let's eat.
Here's yours, UMM.
Come on, sweetie. Come on.
Here, take it.
It tastes really good.
Doesn't taste good at all,
daddy can do much better.
Come on, UMM, take more.
Come on, open your mount.
Sleep, close your eyes now.
How're you doing, Ninja?
Here, eat this.
I want to go home.
Let's go back to our old home.
Please mom,
you don't have to be good to daddy.
You don't even have to talk to him.
But let's live together again.
Try to understand me,
give me some time.
It's too painful for a child
at your age to feel.
I can't stand living
with him anymore.
What's so painful?
You're a woman like I am.
When you grow up,
you will understand.
Go to sleep.
Just don't think too much,
give me a chance,
give me some time.
Oh dear.. Oh my.. NINJA. NINJA.
Help! OHH! ONN!
It's NINJA, hurry up!
What's it, mom?
NINJA! It's right there.
Take him away. Throw him out.
OHH, don't!
Haven't I told you,
not to bring him here.
There're food in the refrigerator,
warm it up yourself.
I have an appointment,
got to be hurry.
Save sandwitches for lunch,
or you may buy anything
from the store downstair,
I've left some money
in the drawer in my room.
Oh, one other thing,
it would be good
if you will stop by sometime,
to see your brother
at the nursery downstair.
Let's go.
Are you hungry?
I'll warm something for you to eat.
I'm not hungry,
I'm not gonna eat.
What we'll have
for breakfast look delicious.
I won't eat.
Come on, try a little.
NINJA.
OHH...
I love you.
What if Mr. NIRUN wouldn't go for it?
We've got to find someone else then.
But if finally this doesn't work.
Then, everyone for themselves.
Really, having to meet
with Mr.NIRUN for just few times,
I've already used nearly every bit
of my endurance,
and if it's not for a tiny chance
of success I saw,
I would have lost my patient by now.
Wait for me.
Where do you think our house is?
There, may be,
over the horizon there.
That's very far.
I wonder what's daddy doing?
He must be very lonely.
Let's get back inside.
Here's your brother.
What a baby
how annoying.
Oh baby, don't cry.
Whoa!
Your mother called,
she'll be late,
she asked me to bring
your brother up here.
Now if he's still crying like this,
we might not take him anymore.
Quiet, please, don't cry.
The prince burnt
the witch's castle down,
and all her magical power
was destroyed,
the witch became an old
and helpless woman.
The prince and the princess
then got married,
and lived happily everafter
that's the end.
Why so soon?
There're still some of witch's troops?
Just forget about them, would you?
Your story was not fun,
daddy's was better.
You're already drunk,
better go home, please,
it's very late.
I'm just drunk of you.
Don't be kidding, please go.
I'm very tired, please.
Okay, I'll go.
But you should wait
for me again tomorrow.
I'll pick you up.
But we already had two meals
together today.
Every meal everyday
with you will be fine for me.
Here you go again.
Just drive carefully.
And please don't forget,
you had promised,
you'd arrange for me a meeting
with Mr.CHATREE.
I won't forget,
be seeing you.
Why don't you go?
Gentleman's duty,
Gotta see you in,
Okay.
OHH!
Hi kid.
Good night.
My god, what's going om?
Why're you not in bed?
Sis told us daddy's fairy tale.
I told you to put your brothers
to bed early?
Is your daddy's tale more important
than my order?
Look at this, what a mess?
I've been very tired through the day,
and still I have to clean up
all this mess.
This should be finished,
there'll be no more
of this stupid fairy tale.
If you throw it away,
I will not live here.
What did you say?
I won't live here.
Now I know, you hate daddy,
you have a new boyfriend.
What?
You divorced because you want
to have an affair.
Stop it!
I hate you...I hate you.
OHH.
Listen to me, I'm sorry.
You don't understand,
you were wrong about me.
OHH. OHH.
ONN.
OHH.
There's nothing between me
and Mr.NIRUN.
UMM, quiet.
I try to be good to him,
because I want him
to help finance my magazine.
Otherwise I wouldn't make it.
OHH, open the door.
OHH.
OHH, would you come out
and talk to me?
I've got to go to work.
I'll have to finish up the magazine
for the printing house.
OHH.
Okay, if you don't want to talk now.
Just take care of your brothers.
We'll talk when I get back.
I've already warm up
some food for you.
ONN, be good,
take care of your sister.
I'll cook chicken-musmun
for our dinner.
Mom said nothing's going on.
Do you believe her?
Oh, my goodness, good morning.
Hello UMM, Hi.
It's strange,
he always cries once he's in here.
Come on, dear.
Kids are all like this,
he'll be quiet soon.
Come, come to me.
Especially him, he's very cute,
easy to take care of,
always in good mood.
Just don't worry.
He's already begun to love us here.
I must go, it's getting late.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
OHH, where're you going?
I'll go to see dad,
I'll live with him.
Let me go with you.
I'll get my stuff.
Don't bring too much.
Let's go home, NINJA.
Hurry up, ONN.
You're stealing mom's money.
We need to have some money,
otherwise, how can we go to see dad?
Come on, ONN.
OHH, Let's take dad's story with us.
Go.
Hey, wait.
Going down the elevator
with the backpack like this,
wanna get caught or what?
Then how can we get out of here?
There, the fire escape.
Come, ONN.
What about UMM?
Are we going to leave him
here with mom?
It would be a very hard time
for him before he grows up.
We'll take him with us.
Let's go.
Miss, is the English teacher
of room 702 in?
Just wait for me here,
I'll go get UMM.
Let's do it.
Could you just sleep?
Here, your brother is really
what people can't stand,
crying all the time.
Doesn't he know how to sleep?
So let me take him to my apartment.
Your mother's gonna ask
for a return then.
Here. If you want to take care of him,
it's got to be here.
Oh my.
If we knew he's such annoying,
- we wouldn't have taken him.
- Definitely, how boring.
UMM, don't cry,
I'll take you to see daddy.
There he is.
Oh shit, cops. Let's go.
Hey boy, where're you going?
Hey, stop!
What shall we do?
Take the stairs.
Don't shoot, they're kids.
Guard! Stop those kids!
Don't shoot.
Stop the kids!
Don't let them go!
Security! Stop the kids!
We're police.
Cops.
- What's going on? What?
- Stop!
Hey! Hey, What're you doing?
Stop the kids! Quick!
The stuff is with them!
Where are they?
That way, they went that way.
What happened?
There, over there.
There're police everywhere.
Where? Let's take a look.
What happened?
- The kids, they ran that way.
- Who?
Hey BAN, cops are after us.
Quick, they're comimg.
You two go with DEN,
I'll handle them.
Get out of the way! Police!
Follow me.
Out of the way please!
Stop!
Come on, hurry up.
Quick! Don't be afraid.
Damn! This is mine.
We're police, sorry.
- Be careful, it's very high.
- Hurry up!
Here's one of them.
Take him.
Excuse me.
One of you, That way! Go!
Come on.
They're still after us.
Jump!
Where's my brother?
Where're you going?
I've got to see my brother.
Let go of me!
The police's got him.
I've got to see him.
Do you want to get caught
like your brother? Idiot!
Hey, they're here!
Follow me, idiot!
Where's the stuff?
I've already had it hidden.
We'll go back and get it later.
Where are you going?
We're going home.
Let's go.
Just don't worry,
he doesn't have the stuff,
they're gonna release him.
Come on, let's get our stuff.
Damn it.
Where the hell...
It's gone.
The basket where
I hid the dope was gone.
Did you look all over?
Did you mistake it
for another basket?
Did I mistake it?
It's a ratten basket at this size.
But it's gone.
The BOSS's gonna kill us.
Children nowadays really scare me,
pushing dope is one thing.
Hey, quiet.
Did you read the paper,
the other day?
A boy at 11 raped a woman.
This day, every boy up from nine,
they're already dangerous.
Hey! Where's the boy
from 10th floor.
Hey kids! Open the door!
Daddy.
- Dad.
- Daddy.
Daddy.
Dad!
Daddy!
Where's daddy?
He probably went out.
We'll wait, he'll be home soon.
Hey, OHH, ONN, UMM.
You're all here.
How did you get here?
Where is your mom?
She went to the market.
Do you know where's my father?
He moved. He's moved to Chiangmai.
He's moved to Chiangmai?
ARPHA Publishing.
She's not here.
When?
Are you sure?
Did you look all over?
Did you ask the maid to
check inside the apartment?
Stay here, Ninja.
It's better than staying
at the apartment.
Hey, where's the bottle?
Oh.. Here it is.
What's this?
Something to ent?
Baby powder may be.
Torefill the empty can.
Oh year, this brand?
Would you get me some hot water?
Why not.
Hurry please.
Don't cry UMM.
I'll make you some
just take some water.
How'd you know
my daunght stole her brother?
Any witness?
It needs no witness.
It's your dauhter who come in here
and asked to take care of the baby.
You can say anything you want.
But you have to take
full responsibility.
A baby just disappeared from here.
Do you think you can deny
your responsibility.
We should discuss this
at the police station.
Don't threaten me!
I'm not afraid.
I'm in this business for many years,
and never had a problem.
Once I took in your kid,
it's all kind of trouble.
I'll refund your money.
Refund? That's too easy.
Shut up!
You son of a bitch!
Do you know how I trusted you?
I had you handle it.
Did you know how much
that's gonna cost me?
You dumb shit!
Get him here.
You too!
Untie them.
If you can't get my srufff buck.
I'm gonna sell you to the farm,
understand?
Get the hell out!
What're you looking at?
You're careless,
that's why he's really pissed.
What a skin here.
Don't cry, you deserve it.
SUAY.
The agent is bringing
in some new kids.
Let's take a look.
Let's see how new they are.
Follow me.
Hey, you there, stop crying.
Come on. Nobody's gonna kill you.
- Are they new?
- I want to go home.
Home? How?
Your parents had you come with us.
Are you going to disappoint them?
This is how your parents got the money
to repair your home,
don't you know that?
Come on, come down here.
This one is really new.
Don't you want to get hurt?
Now don't cry.
This is something easy,
soon you'll be going home.
Take her to see MOM.
Have you heard anything about Eurng?
Still missed her?
No one can be cured
from that dicease,
that's why MOM get
to get rid of her.
What apity, she's still so young.
Here, go get me something to eat.
You can keep the change.
Nothing at all?
Please let me know, it she calls.
Thanks.
Shouldn't you call their father?
May be he can do something.
Where's the wing?
Come on.
Don't just stick to the right.
Switch this side, come on.
Switch to the left!
Coach.
It's your phone.
Take 10.
We'll try again later.
Hollo, Damrong here.
Hello.
This is PHA.
What happened?
Our children are gone.
OHH took her brothers
back to the house.
Once they learned you weren't there,
they all disappeared.
I've already reported to the police.
I also called all OHH a friends.
But nobody sees them.
I can't think of anything right now.
I'll fly to Bangkok rightaway.
Why don't you try it again?
How can I?
- They already recognize us.
- You guys want to help, or what?
Okay, it's okay.
Just remember,
it's a round rattan basket,
with a yellow sheet.
What if we can't find it?
The BOSS would kill us both.
I won't be around for him to kill.
I'll take off to Pataya.
I"ll be with BOSS KIANG.
Hey, let us go with you.
I'm gonna take sun bath everyday.
You bastard,
aren't you dark enough?
You blackie, black.
Let's get something to eat.
Wait for me right here,
and watch your brother.
- Hey, I'm going out.
- See you later.
Okay.
Is that Phonelink?
I have a message for 177099.
Here.
An ending Please,
"I love you doddy."
Thank you.
Let's go.
I'll be damn.
Hole it.
NOKLAE. Where the heck do
you think you're going?
You can't get in there.
See some relative off.
Since when did you have a relative?
Who cares.
You...
Hey THONG!
Go tell the BOSS,
I've found the basket.
It's on 7 o'clock train to Chiangmai.
It's leaving.
I'll follow them.
Tell him to pick me up.
Pick you up, where?
Where the hell does it stop?
Lopburi, koraj,
Kampangpetch, Machongsorn,
- those are where it stops.
- Lopbburi.
Pick me up at Lopburi.
You're bullshitting, smart ass.
PHA...listem,
I've just got a page from OHH,
they're taking 7 o'clock train,
bound for Chiangmai to see me.
I think you'd better go
to the Bangkok Station
to see if there's anything
we can do.
I'll be waiting for them here.
Okay, let's make it this way.
I'll catch this train in lampang.
From lampang to Chiangmai,
I'll surely find them on that train.
Okay?
What?
Not finish yet?
Not yet.
Anybody out for the parts?
Yes, they'll be here tomorrow.
BOSS! BOSS!
What's up?
NOKLAE has found the stuff?
My stuff?
Whoever got it is
on the 7 o'clock train.
NOKLAK is going after them.
The train just took off.
That train?
He wants you to pick him up.
Quick! Get the car.
Where does he want me pick him up?
Lopburi.
That's dumb,
why all the way to Lopburi.
ONN.
No, that can't be done.
I don't have the authority
to stop the whole train,
Just to search for the children
who want to go to Chiangmai
to see their father.
But they are runaway children.
If they'd already connected
your husband
to pick them up
at the Chiangmai station,
it didn't seem to be
any problem at all.
Thank you.
UMM, quiet...don't cry.
He may be hungry.
Yes, he must be hungry.
Oh no...no more hot water.
I forgot again.
You have to get it
from the dining car.
ONN, watch your brother,
I'll make him some milk.
Where is the dining car?
There, two cars that way.
Keep your eyes on your brother.
Where're you guys heading for?
To see our dad.
Where?
Chiangmai.
Hey, my home is also in Chiangmai,
first time on train, right?
You live in Chiangmai,
do you know where my father is.
His name is DAMRONG.
He's a football coach there.
Let me think.
I should know...
a football coach,
his name is DAMRONG, right?
Right.
I know all football players
in Chiangmai.
Your father shouldn'be hard to find.
Ticket...
tichket please.
Where are you going?
Can't make it BOSS,
by the time we get to this station,
they'll be gone.
Go for Lopburi then.
Where have you been?
I went for a walk.
OHH, he's from Chiangmai.
If daddy doesn't pick us up,
he'll take us to him.
Be quiet,
dad will pick us up,
no matter what.
Sleep...
If you keep crying,
I won't take you to see daddy.
Better tell him father's tale,
he likes it.
That's right.
Get me that box.
You lay down here, okay?
Here it is, see?
Once upon a time,
there are children living
in a village.
Those children run away from home,
to play in the garden near a castle...
The cat started crying,
and the dog was crying too.
The elephant was larger
than other animals
and he could talk,
so he told the Prince
about what had happened.
The Prince was very pity on them,
therefore he promised that
he would take the children
back to their family.
Check it out. Did he get off?
There he is.
Let's go.
- Hey, NOKLAE.
- It's not him.
What the hell is he?
Did he say Lopburi?
He might catch another train.
What another one? Go find him.
Stop complaining.
Yes.
Check all the cars.
He's here, BOSS.
- Hey, NOKLAE!
- NOKLAE, you son of a bitch.
NOKLAE, wake up!
Son of a bitch!
Pardon me.
Is the 7 o'clock train
to Chiangmai here yet?
Coming in right now.
Will they make a stop here?
No mam, still a long way.
Mister, how many more stopa
before we get to Lopburi.
It's almost 3 o'clock,
we passed lopburi long time ago.
Oh yeah?
He'll kill me for sure.
Hurry up.
Get on the train
and bring him down here.
Make sure you get my stuff back.
Excuse me...
OHH.
ONN.
PHA.
What a hell?
Where's the stuff?
In the basket...
I can't get to it.
It's under the baby.
- What're you doing?
- Quick! The train is moving.
OHH!
Help! Somebody help!
Just don't worry,
I've searched from the 1st car.
Before reaching Chiangmai.
We'll find them.
- Kidnapper! Stop the train!
- Help! My brother!
I want my brother back.
OHH
Are you ok?
They took my brother.
Hurry up!
Don't take my brother!
Help!
OHH!
OHH...
Someone call the police!
Hey kid, don't go.
Stupid! What's the baby for?
Help!
- OHH.
- Help...that's my child!
Help!
Where's the stuff?
No time BOSS, let's go first.
The stuff's in here.
OHH
Don't take my brother!
NOKLAE, take the baby.
Police's here, take her in.
Come on...Help get her in!
Hurry up!
Let go my sister.
Where's the car?
Over there!
Get the car!
Lampang 143 calling kelang.
The key.
Shut up!
Where's my stuff? Let me see it.
Quick, NOKLAE.
Come on...Hey.
It's all torned,
he also pee on it.
Here's what left.
Goddamn it!
I'm gonna kill you!
We came the wrong way.
I know.
Do something then.
Don't raise your voice at me.
I'm not the one who started all this.
Is this how you take care
of the children?
How much? 20,000?
You bitch.
She's a brand new piece,
She even smell new
and not from the north.
No more than thirteen.
A vergin.
I want 40,000.
Okay! 30,000 you bitch.
Only cash!
I'll bring her in,
no later than tomorrow.
Hey Jua, I got one for you.
Not even a year old.
Sure, I'll send it over
before we talk the price.
Hey, how about a 5 years old?
I know he's too old.
If no one in Malaysia would want him.
Why not sending him into the Factory?
Come on, cheap Price.
I'll let you have him
with chenp price.
Damn it!
Nothing here.
Come on, hurry up.
Put the girl and the baby in the car.
I've already sold them.
I'm gonna get my money back.
BOSS, aren't you gonna let them go?
What?
With all the trouble you brought,
still you had a ward?
Open the door.
Let me go!
Let her go!
Boss, what about him?
Leave him here,
he's not even old enough
for the Factory.
What a mess!
This is real stink.
Take this too.
It's for the baby.
Take good care of him,
he's bringing a fortune to us.
I'm sending his sister
to CHALAO's whore house.
I asked for 40,000
but that bitch only agreed on 30,000.
BOSS, I'm coming too.
OHH.
OHH...
ONN...
BOSS, are you really selling them away?
Don't sell them, BOSS.
I'll work to pay you back,
anything you want me to do.
Get the hell out of here! Get lost!
OHH...
I want my brother
and my sister back.
What do you hit me for?
Don't you see he cause I was trying
to help your brother and sister.
Why are they taking them away?
Just keep your mouth shut.
Come on, let's pick up the things,
we have to find our way out of here.
Or do you want to stay here?
Now what? Are you coming?
So this is your parents?
Why keeping those?
They're only paper.
They're my dod's fairy tale.
Pardon me, is there any news?
Not at all mam.
Excuse me.
PHA...
Does this belong to your children?
Where are they?
We found this paper doll
by the road heading for Bangkok.
They try to avoid the main highway.
I've already notified the authority
along the route
all the way to Bangkok.
You could wait here.
But I think it'd be better,
if you will go back and wait
for any progress in Bangkok.
Here's a name of
the case's officer in Bangkok.
SAKE, watch the baby.
Come on girl, get down!
Drag her out!
No! Let me go! Let me go!
I'll take care of her.
- Come! Down here!
- Let me go!
You dare?
Let me go!
Shut up!
Otherwise I'll kill your brother.
Go ahead, take the baby
out and bury him.
No! Don't!
UMM...
Shut up! Or I'll do it.
Keep the baby quiet!
UMM..
Come here.
It you don't want your brother to die,
you must stay here.
But if you refuse
or make any trouble,
I'm gonna kill your brother.
UMM...
Go! Keep going!
CHALAO!
I've brought the girl.
Okay? Nice?
Not bad.
Give me the money.
Half.
What do you mean, half?
That's all I got today.
If she's really brand new,
by the day she does her first trick,
you'll get the other half.
All right, but don't screw me.
Come on.
Here, let's go...my lock.
Hey, wake up.
Here, it's Rongmueng.
Did you know which part of Rongmueng
your parents live?
How are you going to find them?
We're home.
It's stink.
Stink is better than having no home,
no place to sleep.
Hey, wake up!
It's my bet, get up!
The BOSS is really pissed at you.
Screw him.
Come, get some sleep.
Keep your mouth shut and don't cry.
I'll help get his brother
and sister out.
I'll handle the BOSS
that bastard kicked me
out of the car.
You're asking for trouble.
I'll spend the night at Somsak's.
If there is anything, just page me.
It not, them I'll be here
early tomorrow.
You may spend the night here.
Come on in.
It's beautiful.
I don't have anything
for you to change.
It's okay, it's fine with this.
I'll find my way tomorrow.
ONN's room.
That one is OHH's.
You may take any room you want.
Wake up! Everybody out!
It's time for you to move out.
The BOSS wants me
to take over everything,
including your delivery job.
Like you?
I'm not bullshitting.
Look at these, see? How's it?
And this money, he gave it to me.
This house too, he give it to us.
You guys'd better get back
to the street,
and find some other place.
I'm not going...
any problem?
You'll see,
I'll tell the BOSS to get you.
Go ahead, I'll be waiting for him.
How should we do, NOKLAE?
The BOSS will get us for sure.
He will never find us, don't worry.
We'll go to the Condo.
Let's move, get your stuff.
We'll be starving there.
Still worry about that?
See mom, how's this outfit.
Would you want it shorter than this?
Must be your school
that wear short skirt.
Come here, girl.
If there're some kind of ranking,
you'll get at least 4 stars.
You should be proud.
From now on, this is your home.
You're going to live with me.
Be my daughter.
And if you behave well.
I'll take good care of you,
buy you beautiful clothes,
and even some gold to wear.
Call me "MOM" than,
they call me "MOM" here.
Try, call me, MOM.
You...
- Witch! You Witch!
- Oh, shit.
Are you asking for it?
- Easy MOM, no damage.
- You'll get it!
CHAI, call Mr.PENG,
Chief PAIBOON and Mr. LENG,
whoever offers me the most,
can have this bitch's virginity,
either tonight or tomorrow.
Tell them she's a student,
a 4 stars guarantee.
My pocket!
Somebody picked my pocket.
Stop! Stop the bus!
Somebody took my wallet.
Is this what you called "Condo"?
Yeah, this is it.
Nobody knows or ever been here.
NOKLAE found this place.
We'll wait for NOKLAE,
then we'll make out a plan
to help your brother and sister.
We? How can we?
If NOKLAE said it can be done,
then it shall be done,
you've got to believe me.
If he is not that good,
the BOSS wouldn't have
trusted him that much.
They call him "tough".
He never cry.
The BOSS used to whip him
to the skin,
he didn't utter a word.
If he decided to take on the BOSS,
and help your brother and sister,
you can bet on it.
May the BOSS go to hell.
May that fucker go to hell.
Hey, is this too early
to say a pray?
What pray?
A magic pray to kill the beast.
Did you find them?
- Only the sister.
- OHH...
She was there for sure.
Did she got pop yet?
I don't know.
Why didn't you help her?
What did they take her for?
You don't want to know.
Hey SEAR, go get something to eat.
Wow!
Hey, money's my business.
I'll go with you.
- None of your business. Back off!
- That's big bill, where did you get it?
What a hand.
You bastard...
you're spitting at me.
When are you going to help
my brother an sister?
You fucker...don't push, will you?
We can confirm now,
the boy's name is "NOKLAE".
He's the leader of
those homeless boys.
Do you know where he is?
Did you get him?
We're still looking for him.
The problem is...
They never stay in one place.
For NOKLAE, he usually hang around
the Bangkok Station and Rongmuang.
We've checked over the whole area,
but they all seem to disappear.
What about our children?
What to do now?
We'll find them somehow.
NID, do you remember
a story we published
about a teacher who started
a school for homeless children?
Yes, that one.
Would you look for his number for me?
There's something urgent
I'll have to ask him.
Okay, I'll wait.
What? The appointment was set?
How about asking Mr.NIRUM
to postpone for now?
What? The big guy is going abroad?
I've to postpone it anyway.
Just get me that
teacher's phone number now.
Easy, hey,easy.
Here, eat.
You bastard, where' s my change?
Oh shit, I forgot.
Nice try.
Take it easy, man.
What a hell?
With just this food,
is this all change left?
Are you trying to cheat me?
Let's get him!
I didn't take a shit, damn it.
Oh yeah? I'm gonna kick your ass.
I didn't take a shit.
Hey, it's here.
Give it back!
He bought one of this.
I've been wanting it for so long.
You bastard, it's my money,
it's for something we can eat.
Hey, this is fun.
Let me play too.
Give it to me, you bastard.
I must be the first to play.
- Hey, I'm a kid.
- Beat it!
I bought it.
You don't know how to play.
You're breaking it.
Stop.
Bastard! It's my money.
Give it to me.
Everybody stop.
Stop.
You bastard! Stop!
When are we going to help
my brother and sister?
RAMBO, I want you to spy on
what's going on in the building.
We'll be waiting outside.
If CHALAO put his sister at work,
just let me know right away.
Taking her from a customer
is much easier thean
from that bitch
and her bodyguards.
What about my brother?
I don't even know
where's your brother.
Okay SEAR.
You don't have to come along
just go and find out where
the BOSS keep the baby.
After we got his sister out,
we'll go for the baby.
Come on.
May the BOSS go to hell.
How about it?
- Wait till my turn.
- Let's do it again. I'm first this time.
Hey, the teachers!
Hey...Why don't you take your friend
to class. It's been days already.
It's their business,
they don't want to go.
Where're you going?
They'll do us no harm.
Don't let them go.
Hey kids, hold it.
If his name is NOKLAE.
And looks the way you've told me.
Just don't worry.
I know him and
I think I can find him.
I've found her...
they've taken her
to the customer just now.
Are you sure it's her?
It can't be other person.
If she's in school uniform
and has long hair.
It gotta be her.
You, stay with him here.
Let's do it.
Be careful.
Hey.. Be careful there!
Hurry!
Hey.. Hurry! They're here.
CHAI, MOOD, hey!
Hey! Hurry!
Come on!
Here Mom.
Shut the door.
Did you send in someone else?
He doesn't want anyone else.
He already left.
Lucky, Mom.
Lucky my butt!
That damn BOSS.
Always bring me troubles.
Chicken out Mon?
Me chicken out?
I just wanna be careful.
I don't want to be arrested
and being charged with many counts.
Here! Ruin my luck...
- It's rat!
- Rats!
- It's this room.
- Let me.
Hey, what the hell's going on?
Rats.
They're running all over the place.
What rats?
What a noice here?
You're frightening our customers,
you bitch!
Get rid of them!
Make sure they're all out!
What the hell are you
coming in here for?
What?
Come on inside Mom. Have a sent.
What for? What is this
"take a seat" all about?
Be comfortable Mom.
Say...One, two, three!
Quick! Get out...
ONN's waiting outside.
Stop them! Stop NOKLAE.
There, they took that girl.
Hurry up, stop them!
Tell her I want, the rest,
of the money.
BOSS, NOKLAE is taking
that girl away.
- Go! Don't be afraid of him.
- You bastard! Got a gun?
- Watch out, NOKLAE.
- Go!
Stop them! Don't let them get away.
Get them!
BOSS.
Come on.
OHH.
ONN..
Let go!
NOKLAE!
Hurry!
Where is UMM?
Stop them!
Don't come any closer.
What're you afraid of?
His gun is home made,
he has only one shot.
Don't be afraid, you stupid!
Do you wanna try? Come on.
Let's go.
My ankle.
Whoever move first gonna get it.
Hurry up...let's get out of here.
Hurry!
NOKLAE, you son of a bitch!
Don't forget what you did to me.
You all gonna get it.
Hurry up. They're after us.
Hey! You idiot.
So what, BOSS?
You two hit the street.
Find out where they hide
and take them in.
No new at all?
What about that boy?
Thank you.
Something like this
shouldn't happen to us,
the other day they still..
It will not happen again.
How can you be so sure?
Before they're grown up.
They do not want
just only one of us,
but they need us both.
No way, it 's already finished for us.
Even for our children?
Never bring up the children.
For them?
What did you do for them?
Having fun with them?
Always told them stories
and had them spoiled?
They're just living with nonsense
and fantasy, don't you know that?
How come they mode such a decision?
I'm tired.
I'm the on who'd been doing
nearly everything,
so don't ever make
the children a reason
for me to take it anymore,
even when you're fooling around
with someone else.
- But that's not true.
- It's true.
It is not true.
Okay, there're some talking,
but nothing else.
Liar!
Okay, suppose it's true,
but for the children,
wouldn't you let it pass
and forgive me?
Why didn't you think
about the children then?
It's already passed,
It's not even true,
I'm talking about what's going on...
Now!
We still can't even find our children.
But once we found them
can't you just forgive me.
And return the good things
to their life?
"I love you dad."
Hey, eat.
What do you bought?
Roast duck.
Here.
I don't like duck.
Just eat, man.
This is already something,
don't you know that?
Eat some.
How long have you guys been together?
Sometime...
Do you have a home?
Why do you ask?
Yeah, why?
I'm eating, why the hell?
Crazy again?
Don't talk about home
when he's around.
His parents abandoned him
ever since he was just a little baby.
NOKLAE found him in a box somewhere.
He never has a home.
You have home?
Ever think about going back home?
For what?
This is what we guess.
Maybe he was thrown away
by his parents too.
What about you?
Of course, I do.
Ever think about going back home?
For what?
I never even know my father.
I don't know how many men,
my mother has.
We are all like this.
Otherwise we wouldn't want to be here.
NOKLAE!
NOKLAE.
Hey, I've found where
they hid the baby.
Where?
Oh, I'm hungry.
You bastard,
can't you just wait for a moment?
Where the hell did they keep him?
At the BOSS's shop.
I've found out
from one of Mr.JUA'S boy.
They planned to have the baby
delivered tonight.
The BOSS is really mad at us.
His men are looking
for us everywhere.
They want to take you in.
But nobody says anything,
just don't worry.
Once Mr.JUA got the baby.
It would be much more
difficult to get him back.
We've got to get him out
before the BOSS deliver him.
Be careful. Don't wake him up.
Easy.
Kidnappers!
Stop them! Get out and stop them!
OHH. Hurry up! They'll get us.
Quick! Follow them.
Close the back door, idiot!
If they follow us, you lure them
to the other way, okay?
Let's go! Hurry!
Here they come.
Go now.
I'll make sure they follow me.
Come on.
Hey, quick!
- Come and get me, you damn BOSS.
- Come on, we're here.
Not this way, stupid!
Follow the others that way!
Hurry!
Run! Don't stop!
Come on, ONN.
Come on, OHH.
You're dead, BOSS.
He's got the gun, watch out!
OHH, watch out!
AOM...
Cross there!
Hey!
UMM.
Careful...
Almost have a heart-attack.
Is he alright?
Is he hurt?
He's so smart,
he didn't cry at all.
I'll kill you all.
I'll kill you, NOKLAE.
Get me my gun. Where's the gun?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Does that really hurt you?
I'll kill you.
Come on.
May the BOSS go to hell.
When're you gonna let me
shoot your gun?
Sleep here
I'll take you home tomorrow.
Can I shoot too?
Oh yeah?
The gun is almost
as big as you are.
Be still.
I'll make you a pad to sleep on.
I only have few bullets.
We should save them
for only when necessary.
Once I get more.
You guys can shoot
as much as you want.
Hey, I got two.
Damn it, you're too young
to talk dirty.
Go, go to sleep.
It's almost down.
Okay, I'll tell you the story.
Where's all the children?
I'll cut up some more.
See? Here's the children.
I'm going to start the story now.
Listen.
Make it good, OHH.
Once upon a time.
There were children
who lived in a village.
One day, they went to play
in a garden near a castle
without knowing that
it belonged to a witch.
The witch captured all the children,
and used her spell
to change them into animals.
The parents tried to search
for their children,
but find no trace of them.
They were all very sad
and started to cry.
A prince and a princess passed by.
They felt very much pity
on the children,
so the prince used his magic sward
to release them
from the witch's spell.
Suddenly,
the witch appeared in the sky.
She landed in front
of the couple and the children.
"You are very brave to come here,"
"but you won't get out
of here alive."
Instantly, she called out
for her one-eyed monster, from a pit.
And used her magic sword
to darken the sky.
The prince swang
his magic sword around,
to recreate the bright stars,
till everyone was able to see again.
Then the prince
and the one-eyed monster
started to fight.
With his magic sword,
the prince striked
the one-eyed monster,
till it fell to the ground and died.
Then the prince burnt
the witch's castle down.
Which also destroyed
all her magical power.
The witch became a homeless
and helpless old woman.
The prince and the princess
then started their journey
to take all the children back
to their home.
And they all live happily ever after.
How about going to Pataya,
having some fun
before coming back
to see your parents?
I don't want to go anywhere.
I just want to know if my parents
have come back
to stay together again
so I can go home.
It's just a couple of days,
then we come back.
Pataya's gonna be a big fun.
I know some people there.
It's much better than here.
NOKLAE, hey!
The Boss already knows we're here.
How're we gonna do?
Who told him.
I don't know.
I heard it from the street.
We'd better move now.
Let's go pick up your stuff.
Hey, move.
Why.
The BOSS knows we're here.
- Quick! Hold them all.
- The one-eyed monster!
- ONN, run!
- OHH.
Let'go, come on.
Stop them!
Hurry up, jump.
Let them go.
Get the girl and the baby.
- Where you think you are going?
- Let go of me!
- Come here!
- Let me go!
- Quick! Take the baby.
Let me go!
Where're you going?
Here!
I'll find you a new job.
You've heard of "factory of hell",
haven't you?
And for you.
CHALAO is waiting for you.
Hello.
Teacher? Are they found?
Where?
A whore house.
Yes, I'm on my way now.
OHH...
We can't help what's already happened.
But we've got to get our children back.
Call the police.
I'll go with the teacher.
Our children are
in CHALAO's whore house,
at Rongmuang.
Come on.
Passing out?
Once your sister makes me
enough money.
I'm gonna send you all
for a trip down south.
In there.
That's the way in.
Good evening.
Looking for a date?
Yes.
Good, any kind you like.
I'll set it up.
Kid. Young and pretty.
About twelve years old.
Let us take a look at all of them.
It's jail, man.
That's my problem.
I'll take any price.
Good, this way man.
Come on.
How is this, like, like her?
First class.
You handle the rest, okay?
Don't worry, I know how.
Get in there.
Just wait right in here.
What? Where are they them?
- Don't! Please no!
- Come on. Fight.
- Are you cops?
- No.
How do you know
we have twelve years old here?
We'd bettle check it out ourself.
Excuse us, we're going up there.
- No. Let me go!
- I like this. Fight!
- Here!
- Let me go!
No! Stop!
Stop!
- Fire!
- Get out!
Help! Help!
What's happened?
She's crazy. She's really crazy.
Check that out. That smoke.
Go, quick!
Fire!
Put it out.
Fire! Everybody out!
Help!
Stop! Don't come near me.
She's crazy.
God damn it, it's burning.
Put it out, quick!
MOOD, damn it,
there's fire upstair.
Let's go.
Hey wait, what about this two?
Leave them here.
Teacher.
OHH. Help!
Call the fire department.
Sir, what're you doing here?
Don't tell my wife.
Don't tell anyone.
This way.
OHH.
NOKLAE.
OHH. OHH.
NOKLAE!
Mom, the cops are here.
Hey wait! Get that box and
my handbag in the cabinet,
also what in the drawer.
Commander,
you don't have to go up there,
there're fire and smoke all around.
It's no problem for me,
just take this lady outside.
No, let me go with you.
- My children are up there.
- Take her out.
Let me go, I want to help my baby.
Come on. Hurry up.
Hold it, you're all are under arrest.
NOKLAE.
- OHH.
- Daddy, I'm in here!
- ONN.
- ONN, daddy's here! Daddy!
- Daddy!
ONN.
NOKLAE.
Where's OHH?
I don't know.
Let's go.
Daddy, he's the BOSS who kidnapped us.
You recognize me, you should die.
Freeze!
Let the police do their job.
Let me go. My baby's inside.
Let go of me, don't you understand?
I'll let go of you,
but you can't go inside.
Come on out, hurry up.
Let go of me.
Easy, man.
Easy man, I can walk by myself.
You...
Where did you keep my children?
Take her away.
Why should you do this to my children?
Easy.
Oh, my baby.
Mommy.
UMM, ONN.
Where is DAMRONG?
What about OHH?
I don't know yet.
He's looking for her.
Hey, NOKLAE.
Is the ambulance here yet?
This boy hurts badly.
How's NOKLAE?
I'll be out soon, I'll get you all.
I'm not afraid of you, you fucker!
Hey, let's go see NOKLAE.
Help! Help!
OHH.
Run!
Watch out!
Help! Help!
- Hey wait.
- OHH.
I think it would be safer
if you get out of this building now.
- Okay, take him out of here.
- Let go of me, please.
We'll find your daughter.
Let me go!
My daughter's still inside.
Let me go! OHH!
Easy man!
We're doing everything to help her.
Get us some fire coats,
we've got to find her.
Come on.
Only one kid.
- Commander please.
- Calm down, man!
Can I have a firecoat too, please...
Okay, get him one.
Come on.
One more Firecoat here.
Wearing something.
OHH.
Did you see my daughter?
Did you find my daughter?
Did anyone see my daughter?
Teachers.
Where is OHH? Where is she?
I still can't find her.
Why can't you find her?
Hey wait, don't go in there.
PHA, wait!
Mom.
PHA.
- OHH.
- Hold it PHA.
OHH.
- PHA.
- OHH.
Hold it PHA.
- Hold it PHA.
- OHH.
Hold it PHA...
trust me, I've looked all over.
She's not here.
You better take ONN
and UMM back to your place.
I'll keep looking for her.
OHH, where are you?
OHH.
Where is OHH?
I can't find her.
Go back to bed.
We'll find her tomorrow.
I want to go home.
Oh son.
Will we find her, dad?
We will.
I'll find her for sure.
After dropping us off at home.
Daddy will go with the police,
looking for her.
The police has found her.
At a garbage dump.
Don't know where it is.
I know, but I don't know
how to get there.
It's okay son.
Let's get to the house first.
I'll take care of it.
I'll make a call to the police
and I'll get the bags out later.
Mommy.
Here, come on out.
Did the police really find her?
I don't know yet.
May I go see Ninja, mom?
Sure.
Mommy, Mom!
OHH is here.
Mommy quick, OHH's over here.
Daddy! OHH is here.
Dad!
Quick, mommy quick, OHH's here.
OHH.
Don't leave anymore,
we'll be here together.
"Girl at the garbage dump"
"is not your child"
"we're still trying..."
It's over.
Let's get inside.
It's all over.
Be careful, don't drop it again.
It's okay.
See? Like I said.
Hand it over to me.
See? UMM,
this turtle is really a fucker.
Hello.
We'd like to see NOKLAE and THONG.
Pardon me sir,
are you related to the boys?
Normally, not manybody
ever come to visit them.
We're not related, but...
NOKLAE, THONG and their friend used
to help our children.
I see.
Quick! Some boys are trying to escape.
Come on.
They're climbling the back wall.
I saw it from my window.
It's NOKLAE.
Hey, there! Student!
Hey, come down.
Don't go.
Come on.
Hurry up.
NOKLAE, don't go.
THONG, don't go.
Come on, let's go.
The bus is coming.
- Hey. Let's go.
- OHH.
OHH.
NOKLAE.
- Let's go. NOKLAE.
- Go!
OHH, don't go.
OHH.
NOKLAE, come back.
THONG, don't go.
NOKLAE don't go, THONG.
Whoever love us as their lives.
Whoever render an
everlasting sympathy,
whoever love us regardless
of our beauty,
their love are forever
and without harm,
Who are they?
Whoever share our sorro.
Whoever always care,
whoever love us like their hearts,
their love are greater
than the earth and the sky.
Making the world a pen,
taking the sky as paper,
turning all oceans
into colorful ink,
still it can not declare
how grateful we are,
Whoever love us with their lives,
whoever let us ride their backs,
whoever lead us into good dream,
whoever they are,
be hurry to show our gratefulness.
 