Tokyo University of the Arts presents
Sorry, that car just came in front.
It's fine, the road is so busy.
With the holiday season plus the weekend,
the roads get so busy.
You're the guest tonight
let them wait a little.
But I don't like to be late.
You do teach at a good school.
I know...
We already study high school curriculum’s.
And they're only in junior high.
So, you're a teacher?
Yes.
Of what?
I teach math.
Mathematics.
Would've studied more if my teachers were...
...pretty like you.
Thank you.
Lucky students.
Hey...
Can we make that announcement tonight?
That?
Okay.
Then you say it. Tomoya.
Me?
Kaho, you say it. I'm shy.
Come on, you're not shy.
You announce it.
Sanae!
We're here!
Happy Birthday!
Or belated birthday?
Yes, it's fine. Thanks.
Kaho, you get the birthday seat.
I feel special.
Kenichiro, you're dressed up today.
A funeral.
Really?
Not someone close. I'm fine.
Congrats.
Thanks.
Takeshi and Marie?
Not yet.
But they're the hosts.
Right?
As we speak.
Marie!
Happy birthday!
Thank you! How have you been?
Sorry, taxi was a bad idea.
Busy season.
So how's it going?
Doing fine. Better than you are.
Whatever.
Congrats.
Thank you so much.
29 years old.
I'm already 29 years old.
Not that bad, you're still in your 20s.
Is there something wrong about being 30?
No.
That's mean!
Didn't mean it.
Yes you did!
Things only get better after 30.
That's right.
You're a mother now.
I know,
it feels so weird that Marie is a mom!
I can feel it kicking.
Can I touch?
I think Takeshi will be such a good dad.
I'm looking forward to it.
Baseball to dollhouse.
I'll be an all-around dad.
You can adapt to anything.
Now I find all kids adorable and I never
used to feel that way.
It's amazing.
So amazing how things work.
People do change.
A bit over-excited.
Ah shut up...
What about you two?
Us?
So, what's up with you two?
Well actually...
We... are getting married.
Right?
Yes we are.
Congratulations!
You upset. Kenichiro?
I'm not upset!
You're upset?
No I'm not.
You gotta be careful!
Kaho, marry me when you leave him.
Whatever.
We'll see.
Hey hey hey.
Stop all this.
I'm so glad. We've been waiting for this.
Yeah. 10 years.
But it doesn't that long.
You first need a job.
I do work.
But you're still part-time lecturer.
All researchers wait for their chances
like that.
I'm lucky just to have a job.
Sorry...I'm just being too emotional...
Please excuse me.
I'm fine...
She okay?
I guess women are emotional creatures.
What time is it?
Now?
Little past 9.
I should be heading off.
...Maybe I will too.
Going to bathroom.
Taxi?
Early morning?
Yes. You can stay.
Have fun but don't overspend.
Take this. Okay, I'll see you later.
See you.
Oh yeah.
You forgot your keys.
Thank you.
Alright?
I'm fine. What time will you come back?
Don't wait up for me.
But you need...
Put it in mailbox.
Get good sleep.
Ouch!
What is it?
You just complicate everything.
Hey wait!
Making things complicated among friends.
I slept with Sanae just once.
5 to 6 years ago.
I'm surprised it happened, too.
You've cheated before, right?
No. I'd never cheat.
You're lying.
If not, you're just fooling yourself.
Hey, do you want to go to...
...Takako's place?
She wants to see you guys.
Takako Nomura?
You're still seeing her?
It'll be cheaper there.
...We'll go.
Let's go.
Is married life fun?
It's not always fun and exciting.
But it's not bad.
Not bad at all.
You'll change. too.
I'm hoping so.
Drop this subject at Takako's.
Her cat died or something?
She must be lonely.
She won't say it, but she probably is.
Pets are like family.
Hey...you!
Phone call?
Just telling her I'll be late.
...You fool.
Why? Just give it back!
Stop acting like a kid.
Go home when the train starts moving.
So much cheaper than taxi.
Either way, I'm calling to tell her.
Phone calls cost money.
Hey, Kenichiro!
No. Kenichiro!
Give it back...
That's it, Takeshi.
Back to being a mad dog.
I was like a mad dog?
Yup. before Marie chained you up.
Kenichiro, just give it back to me.
Sorry sorry.
Come on in.
Remember me?
Of course.
3-4 years ago?
Yeah. I was still getting my master's.
Can we come in?
Your coats over there.
Coming in.
Long time, Takako!
How's Professor Sakuma?
Perverted as usual.
My doctor thesis wasn't accepted.
Well, he is strict.
I need to learn that.
No worries.
You're already a pervert.
Using your sink.
Thank you.
I'm sorry about...
No. no need.
I had you guys come to cheer me up.
Let's just have a toast for her long life.
She was really old?
26. About 120 years old in human age.
So she was with you since childhood?
No. she was my aunt's cat.
This house is also my aunt's.
She offered me this place
to take care of Rabi...
...when I was house hunting for college.
Is beer okay?
Rabi is the cat's name.
You know Hana Yoshino?
The writer?
Never read it.
That's my aunt.
And this is my aunt's house.
Because the cat lives with the house...
...she left her here
when she moved to Kamakura.
So she keeps this house for the cat.
Does she know of Rabi's death?
Of course.
But I guess she has a deadline coming up.
So sad.
Tough for her.
You're the sad one.
Can I heat this?
Sure, go ahead.
This one became a movie.
"My Love Fell Off the Plane"
You know it?
Of course I do.
She recently had like 2 bestsellers.
You've got to see it. Makes you cry.
Yeah. I called you guys up. Not enough.
We'll pay.
It's fine.
No it's not.
What does she write?
Basically, something about
a loved one dying.
Sounds like a seller.
A seller?
To Rabi in heaven.
And to your marriage.
Oh really? Congratulations!
What.
And to Takeshi's baby.
Really? Congratulations on that, too!
Anyways. toast to Rabi.
Then. to the dead Rabi
and the baby on the way.
...and the engagement.
Cheers!
Can I smoke?
Didn't you quit?
Out on the balcony.
Bring some beer.
Need help?
It's fine.
No. it's hot.
Thanks.
It's cold.
Close it. it's cold.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Give me your hand.
Palm reading? Oh no.
Changes in 3 years?
How scary.
You should stop seeing that girl.
And what about job changing?
Turned it down. Don't want to be too busy.
My job now is fine.
You know what?
You've never really fell in love.
What do you mean?
When you really fall in love,
you'll feel the need for money.
I just need enough.
You'll want more
when you find that true love.
You just don't get it.
Emotion line used to stop here,
but it's longer now.
You really remember?
Not always, just yours.
I think you've become more emotional.
am I right?
...Weaker with age.
No. not what I meant.
Marriage line is hardly visible...
Maybe around 40.
Seriously?
Do you want to marry?
But I want kids.
Without a husband? How immoral.
Look who's talking about morality.
Hey, what about that deadline?
I couldn't write until I saw Rabi.
Buried nearby, take you tomorrow.
Are you Kenichiro?
Hey...
No. Hana. Kenichiro isn't here.
We were just toasting together
for Rabi's good life.
Without me?
Because I thought you had deadlines.
Just join us and have a fun night.
Alright?
She was old enough to die any day...
...but I thought
maybe she could be immortal.
She really lived for long.
Yeah.
Rabi didn't really like me.
Really liked Takako.
Really? That's not really true.
She wouldn't come to me
even when I got home.
She didn't come to me, either.
Probably too old to move.
Nope. I'm right.
She just liked you better.
Cats choose their favorites
differently than dogs do.
You had cats?
Both dog and cat.
Dogs like authority,
so listens to the dad.
Or mom in some households.
But cats like to look after others.
they choose the most...
...weak or lonely one in the house.
I was always bullied by my sister
being the youngest one.
The cat would come and lick me
when I was crying by myself.
So Rabi probably stopped coming to you...
...because you became stronger.
Or someone weaker came into this house.
Talking about me?
No. but cats are loyal...
...and loyal to only one.
Thank you Takeshi.
Sorry for hitting you.
No. I'm really okay.
I just get so emotional sometimes.
Just heard about a nasty guy before.
How was he nasty?
A guy that can sleep with a girl
he doesn't even like.
You thought that was me?
I really am sorry.
But most guys are like that.
Not every guy is like you.
I'm not talking about me.
Kenji
Kenji, are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine, really fine.
He's really just a quiet guy.
Anything else but beer?
Need to buy some.
I'll go get some.
No. I'll go get some.
What do you want?
I want some red wine.
Please.
Store is far.
I know.
Going to get cigarettes.
You. Takeshi?
I'm okay.
Only need some.
Okay. we're going.
Would you like one?
Sure, thanks.
Picking up?
Not going to.
Some things just can't be done
or solved no matter what.
Well, maybe.
I can't figure out writers.
Just a second please.
Yes...
Thank you.
It's raining a bit.
Yeah...
Can't you smoke inside if
this is your house?
Don't want walls getting dirty
and it's a habit.
Rabi hated cigarette smokes anyways.
The house was for Rabi, you giving it up?
Not immediately, and also.
...I have some memories here.
Still smells of Rabi.
And Takako would have nowhere to go.
This house is the problem.
What?
I know that guy, Kenichiro.
that you were talking about.
He's not at all a bad guy.
But it's the girl
who gets hurt in those situations.
Regardless of the age.
Yes true...
When I came to this house, I thought...
...a girl without earnings shouldn't be
living here.
It's complicating.
Maybe it is my fault...
Though if someone offered
this house to me,
...I'd definitely live here. So nice and big.
What?
It's funny.
Oh yeah.
Can I come visit your office someday?
The plant?
Sure, it's fine.
Hey, just a moment.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Just tell give my name
and you can visit any time.
But you won't find anything for your
love novels at a meat-packing plant.
I don't always write about love.
Besides, I just like plants.
And I'm sure there's love going on
inside the meat-packing plant.
Maybe part-timers?
Yeah. with...
...plant managers.
To be honest, I've never read your books.
Oh it's fine.
Hurry up. Come on.
Don't push.
We're back.
Hana?
Takeshi?
Not in the balcony.
His cell is off.
Sure, you turned it off.
Look for them?
No.
They are mature adults,
so leave them alone.
Takeshi
Hana's gone.
Oh.
She wanted to write.
Said bye to you all.
Busy person.
She's such a free bird.
Don't scare me.
What?
Oh, it's Hana's.
Maybe it's her?
I don't think so.
Hello?
I'm sorry.
I have to tell you something.
No. I'm outside now.
Looking for you.
I'll be a father soon.
I'm married.
That's why I left.
Sorry if I hurt your feeling.
But...
...talking to you is very exciting.
You're cute.
You're wonderful.
You know that.
You have my card? My number's there.
Think they met?
I guess so.
He'll be a father soon.
Are you disappointed?
I don't expect anything.
Can't reach him.
She's always like that.
Free and reckless.
You like that?
Sure, it's attractive. She's charming.
You like all charming women?
Sure, I love charming women.
You too. Takako.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
And Kaho?
Sure, she's great. She is the one.
Right?
Sure.
What's so good about her?
Her chin.
She's kind.
Has beautiful skin.
Earnest.
Self-contained.
Her ears.
Her nose and fingers.
All about her looks.
Her voice. I love listening to her voice.
A good cook.
That's good.
Makes amazing food.
She's honest.
Is it different from earnest?
Shoot.
She dates a guy like you...
...and will marry.
That hurts.
I like you.
I love Kaho more than you.
Kenichiro doesn't know anything
about Kaho. That's why he wasn't good.
Kenichiro is a bad person.
Not as bad as you.
Takeshi!
Hey...
Were you awake?
What time is it?
Oh. It's about five.
Where were you?
Guess.
I don't want to guess.
Where do you think?
Stay, I'm coming to bed.
I'm thirsty.
Hey.
Just a cup of coffee.
Thanks.
I don't see the key.
Locked out?
How careless.
Hey.
Hi. Kenichiro.
Were you awake?
Waiting?
I couldn't sleep.
Don't you have school today?
Take a nap.
No. I'm fine.
I can only sleep about an hour.
We are having coffee. Want some?
Thanks for asking.
Where were you?
Bar, and then a book cafe.
I called you once.
It didn't have reception.
Oh.
I worried about you.
What book?
You wouldn't know.
Like what?
Fumi Yoshinaga.
Don't know.
See?
Want coffee?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hold on.
How about you, Kenichiro?
You haven't had any sleep?
Um...
Just a little bit.
Kaho
Are you okay?
Get some rest.
I'm fine.
Today's the last class of the semester.
You're fine?
Yeah. Thanks.
I'm fine.
Okay. That's it.
Collect papers from the back.
The papers will be returned tomorrow.
Review over the winter break.
Give me a few minutes of your time.
I won't ask who brought flowers for Togawa.
Thank you.
We don't know why Togawa
killed himself. But...
...we don't commit suicide without a reason.
I believe there was violence.
That completely destroyed Togawa's life.
Let's talk about violence.
That leads us to think about
Togawa and our own lives.
Tajima
Have you ever used violence?
I think so.
Why did you do it?
I don't remember, but I was irritated or
things didn't go right.
Would you do it again?
I don't want to.
Why is that?
Well...
Violence is wrong.
Why is it wrong?
It hurts people.
But you don't get hurt.
But it might come back to me.
So, you don't use violence
because you might get hurt?
That's one side.
Even if you don't use violence,
you might suddenly get hurt.
What can I do?
Can't help if I met a random killer.
Hmm.
Probably. there are two types of violence.
What do you think. Yaguchi?
Verbal violence and physical violence?
Yes. It's a typical way to group.
But, they're actually the same.
Anything else?
Men's vs women's violence.
How are they different?
Like sexual harassment.
Men's violence includes sexual harassment.
But, women does the same.
Anything else?
As Tajima mentioned.
...there are violence that comes
from and to ourselves.
Kawaguchi
Am I you?
No.
Can you see what I think?
I can't see yours either.
We are different.
We can't see through each other.
Sawada
Do you think I will hit you?
No.
Why?
There's no reason.
Punishment isn't right.
But I might hit you.
I might have a reason to hit you.
If I decide to hit you, you can't stop me.
This violence comes from the outside.
But for me, it comes from the inside.
Now, you understand.
"I "
"Sawada"
"Violence"
This " I " happened to be me, Kaho Tanemura.
But this " I " could be anyone.
This "Sawada" could be replaced.
"Others"
It sounds obvious, but we are all " I ".
But from others, we are all "Others".
As I showed,
we can't stop violence from "Others".
But, we all as " I " can stop
using violence to "Others".
This "Others" can easily use violence.
But I can decide not to use my violence.
This is all we can do against violence.
Ms. Tanemura
Nagase
Sawada could have stopped you.
He could have hit you back in self-defense.
Yes.
He could.
But it doesn't stop violence. Why?
That's violence, too.
That's right.
Right, Hyogo.
" = Violence"
We can't respond violence to violence.
If so. violence grows.
When violence balances, it seems peaceful.
And seems to disappear.
However. violence is right next to us.
" I " can only stop violence.
So, we shouldn't use violence
even if we are used?
Yes.
That's not fair.
I don't like that idea.
But you shouldn't use violence.
So, just accept it?
Yes.
The only way to face violence is
to accept it.
Forgive violence.
Even get killed?
Yes.
How can you forgive that?
Maybe to be killed is the way to forgive.
I don't want to be killed.
I want to live.
Me too.
But you decide to live,
and choose to live.
Killing takes away all that possibilities.
Killing won't let us choose.
It's the most heinous violence.
It cannot happen.
Then. what's the law for?
Law gives punishment.
Law is a form of violence.
It makes violence invisible.
But violence don't disappear.
We can only stand against violence
by accepting it.
We each can choose to accept it.
This is the only way to stop violence.
Ms. Tanemura
Choose?
Yes. We get to choose because we have will.
I hit Hyogo in the bathroom.
Really?
I didn't punch his face,
but kicked his stomach several times.
There was no choice.
Why?
I don't know.
I just wanted to punch and kick him.
It didn't have to be Hyogo.
Like the chart you drew.
No violence comes inside from us.
Violence comes from outside.
And. we don't get to choose that.
Can you forgive me?
Forgive me in front of Hyogo.
Hyogo chooses to forgive.
Hyogo. can you forgive me?
Kasai
You did the same to Togawa?
Yes.
I did the same.
But it's not just me.
Stand up if you've done
something to Togawa.
He forgives us.
There's more of us.
Stand still.
I'll be right back.
Hey.
You were late.
Want pasta?
What sauce?
Meat sauce.
I'll have some.
Hold on.
Thank you.
Sure.
Did tutoring?
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Next week will be rough.
It's going to be rough.
Why? It's almost winter break.
Tomoya
Please stand by me.
What happened?
Too stupid to tell you.
Okay.
I want to quit.
Seriously.
Quit teaching?
I don't see anything.
Why don't you quit
if you really want to.
Huh?
I don't know.
What do you want me to do?
Just stay by my side.
I want to, but I may not be able to.
Why?
Well,
I might have to move from Tokyo someday.
I may not be in Japan.
If you continue teaching,
I can't stay close to you.
Although I want to.
Then. I'll quit.
To be honest, you shouldn't quit.
Why? Money?
That's one reason.
but women should work too.
Women should be economically free.
So that they can decide
when they have to.
Talking about divorce?
It's possible. We need tension.
I want security.
Then. I may not be the best match.
What if
I got raped or killed?
What would you do?
That's a bizarre question.
But it could happen. It can be reality.
I'll kill him.
I will find that person,
and torture and kill him.
Hey.
You alright?
I don't know.
I'm mentally and physically unbalanced.
Tomoya
I haven't heard the important word.
Oh, yes.
Please let me marry your daughter.
Do you really want to marry her?
Yes.
I believe you better not.
I'm not suitable?
Well, I won't stop you
because you are both adults.
Mom
Is that because
I don't have much salary?
That's not a big problem.
Then is it about my personality?
Well, yes.
I guess I don't like you.
I felt this way when I first met you.
I should have said something then.
Didn't expect it to last.
You...
...don't have sincerity.
I don't feel anything.
Sincerity...
Truth.
You don't have the truth.
I can't trust you.
I've only met you once before.
I can tell. It's obvious.
Mom, I want to marry him.
I chose him.
That's why I can't stop you.
But, Tomoya
Can you keep this relationship?
If you marry her.
our relationship will continue forever.
If you say more. I will never
see you again.
You know your father.
Don't overlap your mistake to us.
Him and I are different people.
Let me ask you again.
Do you really want to marry her?
Did you really choose her?
Hey, what's up?
Sorry.
Is it okay?
Why didn't you call? I have a guest.
I'll leave.
Bye.
What's wrong?
I...
...wanted to see you.
If it's okay.
It's okay.
Come in.
Oh, no.
It's Kenichiro.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Why? It's my friend's apartment.
Don't disappoint Kaho. She only has you.
I know, but it's none of your business.
Leave now!
Don't shout.
He's my guest and he was here first.
Do you want to join us or leave?
Then...
...I'm going to Kaho's.
Why didn't you do so?
You should have gone.
Kenichiro
Leave.
Don't come again.
I won't.
Good bye.
Hey.
Sorry.
It's late.
What?
What a day. Do you want to come in?
No. it's okay.
Come here.
Hey.
What?
Come in?
No. Did Hana come to get her phone?
Yes, this afternoon.
Okay.
Can you give me her number?
Why?
To apologize.
Don't worry. She wasn't upset about you.
Um. yeah.
But I care.
Send her a fan mail then.
Anyway. I can't give her number so easily.
It's so strange.
No. it's not.
Come in.
Why you say that?
Now he sounds like him.
Don't keep talking there.
Come. come in.
Want some drink?
No. I'll leave soon.
To where?
To my home.
Had a place to go?
I'm not you.
You like Hana?
I don't know.
You better not. It happens a lot.
I guess so, but I need to see her.
Why?
I want to know.
Know what?
Myself.
You are such a fool.
I know I sound absurd, but...
...I'm a lot better than you.
I've been sincere to one woman.
I got married and will have a baby soon.
I have a decent life than you do.
Then. why are you here?
I don't know. That's why I'm here.
You might disagree,
but we both have a steady partner.
But, came here for someone.
Not someone. Want to see Hana.
Nothing will happen.
You missed the chance.
Once you miss it, it's over.
You never know.
Hana is over with you.
It's an embarrassing past.
Yes, but you can give him her number.
Who are you two?
Don't look down on me.
I just met Kenichiro.
I don't know what you were doing.
But, I'm different from you.
Wait.
None of your business, but
there's nothing between us.
Kenichiro?
We both don't have steady partners.
But no love.
That's the problem.
Wait a minute.
You came to know something.
I got something I want to know. too.
Stay here. I want you to be here.
Drink.
Come on.
Give this.
Drink this.
Takeshi
Why?
Just drink this for me.
Please.
Good.
Let's play a game.
Let's talk honestly for an hour.
There's a fountain in Mexico.
It's called Fountain of Truth.
If you drink it, you can only say the truth.
I had some, too.
Doesn't work, then.
But, we just had
the real Fountain of Truth.
Are you okay?
What do you want to do?
I don't mean to reveal my secrets.
Want to know who I really am.
Is that fun?
No. it's rather painful.
Pain comes before fun.
After an hour, we forget everything.
Is there a winner?
If you don't tell the truth.
you become looser.
Help each other to find
new sides of everyone.
How do we do it?
Well...
Someone tells the truth,
and then the person can ask a question.
By answering that question honestly,
that person can ask something.
Doesn't sound like it'll work.
Don't care about your confessions.
I don't either.
I also don't want to confess.
How would you know if I spoke honestly.
Why are we doing this?
You came here to know yourself, right?
That's why we'll do this.
It's to understand yourselves,
not me or her.
It's about being honest to yourself.
I know being honest is tough.
But, we might....
Whatever, ask.
I'll confess.
Then. ask a question.
Other rules will follow.
We both answer the question?
One. We fight for the right to ask.
Just start.
She lied about our relation.
We did it three years ago.
It's my latest affair.
I thought we're not revealing.
Had to say this to be honest.
I just said we had an affair,
but it wasn't.
I was serious.
Wasn't afraid of anything.
But she had something with Kenichiro.
I think Takako loves Kenichiro.
But Kenichiro loves Kaho.
Kaho loves me and not interested
in Kenichiro.
That's why we lasted.
I avoided change.
But I regret it now.
Want to change it tonight.
Is that what you wanted to say?
Basically, yes.
I'll forget soon.
That's the rule.
So, you join this game?
Ask a question.
Do you like Kenichiro?
I don't.
Why?
I just answer. right?
Sure
But you're not honest.
so let me ask you again.
What a vague rule...
I don't think you hate him.
Why don't you like him?
So irresponsible.
Is he?
He sleeps without love.
And that definitely hurts her.
That's a tough question.
Like you know. Kenichiro is really gentle.
So, I think Takako wanted Kenichiro.
Am I right?
I don't need to answer.
I see now.
What?
I don't like Kenichiro
when he's with you. He spoils you.
He should have stolen Kaho.
That's the problem.
So, you don't like me.
I guess so.
What don't you like about me?
Can I ask?
I don't like everything about you.
Why are we even friends?
You're immoral and insincere.
I don't like your face.
You think you're better than others.
I don't.
Hey.
Be honest!
Do you think you're better than others?
You can answer this.
You think you're smart? Huh?
Let me answer.
I do think I'm smart.
Sometimes others look stupid.
But I know that's not true.
People have something
that they're good at.
You know better about factory line.
You're not fair.
I don't like that either.
You pretend to know your weakness,
and place yourself in safety zone.
You're not honest.
What do you think about me?
Your question is...
It's not over. You're not being honest.
Answer my question.
Like I said. You're stupid.
All you say makes me vomit.
You live in your small world.
The world you believe is all fake.
You love your wife?
Then why are you here?
You don't even know what you don't know.
But, I like you.
You can do what I can't do.
I sometimes wish I were you.
I said all this,
so that you can understand me.
I'm happy cause I'm stupid?
Who do you think you are!
You did and still do look happy.
But you'll eventually see.
You're not who you think you are.
Fine, but let me say this.
I don't know about academics,
but you can't live outside that world.
All you say is full of shit.
You are the one who's empty!
I've said my honest feelings. Can I ask?
We're still doing this?
This is just swearing. Let's stop.
No.
What do you think of me?
I've said it.
What if nobody answered?
If nobody answered less than a minute,
two people will answer.
Now it's more like a game.
Well, I think...
You are, um...
...a sad person.
You pretend to be something.
You want to look shallow.
You look painful to everyone,
and you know that too.
Why don't you be yourself?
You are a timid person.
Live a life like that.
Well, then why...
...did you sleep with me?
Cause you looked pitiful.
I'm not a volunteer.
Well...
...you do have some attractive parts.
What's so funny?
I mean. I like men.
It's nice to be asked out.
If I don't hate that person,
I can go beyond that.
But, now you don't want to do it with me.
I'm just tired.
I really don't like tiring stuff.
Today is the worst.
She is honest.
Okay.
But you asked Kenichiro. right?
That's a different story.
It's my turn to ask.
Come on.
A question...
What's the most embarrassing moment
of your life?
Confessing and being honest is different.
Fine, let me answer this.
I was a freshman in high school.
It happened when I got
my first girl friend.
We became intimate.
I know it's late.
Thought you'd be awake.
Tomoya is at another girl's place.
Won't come home.
Want to come out?
It's cold, but if you wore a coat.
Let me get my coat.
Funny. right?
No way.
Didn't she get mad?
Of course. she did.
It was her first, too.
That's hard for both.
Tell me about Hana.
I can't answer that.
What you like about her?
Don't know.
Her face?
No.
Personality?
Like you said. it was the timing.
Takeshi, ask a question again.
Have you ever loved a person?
Have you?
Answer the question first.
I haven't thought about it.
My wife means a lot to me.
I know that for sure.
I don't think I have.
I'm not sure.
I don't hate anyone.
I don't even hate Tomoya.
I just lack that ability.
It's like the ability to run
or the ability to catch.
I just don't care.
Want to love seriously?
It's my turn to ask.
I answered his question.
Not yet.
You weren't honest about Kenichiro.
Why do you ask that?
Well...
...sex isn't always fun.
It's sometimes a hassle. but you do it.
That's why I think you love Kenichiro.
You just don't want to realize that.
What do you mean?
Takako just doesn't know how to love.
And you're trying to teach me how?
I don't know either.
That's why we are alike.
I thought Kenichiro and I were similar.
We don't ask much from the other.
I felt relaxed with him.
I don't know if I liked him.
but I liked being around him.
Good enough?
Okay. You can ask.
What don't you like about your partner?
Why look for someone else?
No answer?
Then both have to answer.
I'm not unhappy with Kaho.
You have to be honest.
I don't have to say bad things.
You need to answer my question.
Small things.
She sometimes can't understand my feeling.
Of course. it's vice versa.
It happens to anyone.
And that's why it was never a big issue.
You think I'm different?
No. I think we're more different.
See, that's it.
It's better to communicate knowing
we are very different.
Kaho has nothing to do with this.
I'm simply attracted to you.
Thank you.
But I didn't ask that much.
Any questions?
That's real insensitive.
Me?
Sure this guy is like shit
but he is serious.
This game is just his excuse to get to
know you and each other more.
Give him a chance.
Takeshi
I'm just respecting this game.
Takeshi, it's fine.
Let me ask again.
Do you want true love?
It's not something to ask for.
Maybe when it happens,
but I don't know where to start.
So you're waiting.
I'm not waiting.
If it happens, it happens.
I'm not changing myself.
Nothing happens without desire.
I don't want change.
Fine, never mind.
I'm leaving. This is stupid.
What about Hana?
Just get it on without me.
I don't want that.
If you really want this woman, you've got
to start by understanding her.
She's not who you think she is.
It's faster to just hit her.
What are you saying?
Why don't you try?
Something could change.
Hitting will do nothing.
No. you could change.
Stop it!
Hey, stop that!
Takeshi, stop!
Hey, stop.
Takeshi, what's going on?
Takeshi!
What do you want?
Hey, Takeshi!
Takeshi!
Smile, go ahead and laugh!
Laugh!
What are you doing?
Takeshi, stop!
Has something ever happened to you that
was a miracle?
A miracle.
Not really. Has to be a miracle. right?
Yes.
Miracles are miracles. Do you have one?
My grandpa came back to life.
Really.
When I was about 5 years old.
He had died from a stroke.
and at his funeral I kept thinking...
...something just smells terrible.
And families sit close to the coffin.
Yeah they do.
You figure it out?
I think everyone smelt it.
Next to my father whose arms
were around me because I won't sit still...
...holding me down.
Sounds unlike you.
I kept on crying. "It's smelly, smelly!"
Then obviously people started reacting
because they all think it smells.
They took me to the bathroom thinking
it was me.
I'm the one crying. couldn't have been me.
That's true.
And then...
...when I came back he was taken out from
the coffin
...with a dirty bum.
Crowd just starts, "He's back to life!"
Kind of gross...
Maybe dirty for a miracle?
But I'm sure it happens.
I think so. but it was a real miracle
for the family.
Thanks to you.
They complimented me for a while.
It's like "The Emperor's New Clothes."
If I didn't cry out,
he could've been cremated.
But he never gained back
his consciousness...
...passed away after 3 years in bed.
My mom was also a teacher but...
...had to quit to take care of him.
About 6 months after his death, my parents
got a divorce.
I guess you just never know.
Though I got compliments, I didn't know.
If I'd kept quiet, grandpa would've died
but my family could have stayed happy...
Not your fault. It really smelled, right?
Yeah.
See, not your fault.
I thought about it again in junior high.
That it really was a miracle.
Or, not just the coming back to life,
but all of it.
My parents' divorce and my grandpa
dying twice.
Even if something didn't happen
in the world...
...everything is part of the miracle,
and if a miracle happened...
...I could prove that this world itself
is a miracle.
Then. everything just became clear.
As if I traveled back to the beginning
of the universe.
After that. I was okay with anything.
...That's not true.
And your words don't mean anything.
If everything is a miracle, then nothing
is a miracle. Meaningless.
I'm always like that.
I think so much. but it's all meaningless.
You should really sort out,
what's good and what's bad.
Saying all is a miracle is the same as
giving up thinking.
Yes, but...
...when I think everything is a miracle...
I realized I should just take care of what
is meaningful to me.
Even if it's all meaningful, you can't
choose it all.
I can only take care of things that
is valuable to me.
Why don't you wake up...to face reality?
It's clear that you're just hiding
from negatives.
Tomoya doesn't love you. probably won't.
and will keep hurting you.
Everyone but you knows this.
If I don't know, then it's okay, right?
He's with another woman right now.
He'll be back in morning.
And that's the problem.
It's simple if he just left you.
He could ruin your life.
Choosing him means hurting your future.
You know...
...I really do like you.
Tomoya probably does, too.
So...
...it would make me so happy if you would
just celebrate us.
I know I like you so much more.
Thanks for being so considerate.
Why can't it be me?
It's not that it can't be.
You're being mean.
Give me 3 minutes to tell you
what I like about you.
Your pretty eyes.
Cute facial hair on forehead.
You have a pretty chin.
Your ears...ears are...
...sticking out cute.
Kind of like a monkey.
I've always loved your pretty long fingers
and nails.
Beautiful hair.
It's hidden now, but your neck is nice.
You're a kind lady.
You smell nice.
Didn't know that.
You have a weird nose.
Different.
But I really love that.
Small lips, but...
...gets real wide when you smile.
Your cheek is cold.
I've never been told pretty and cute this
much before...
That's sad...
Just wait here.
Hey!! It's morning!!
Time to get up!!
I'm sorry.
I wish I could've chosen you.
I tried...
...but I just can't.
I'm home.
Hey.
I was just with Kenichiro.
Yeah.
You knew?
Kind of guessed.
He told me he liked me.
Yeah.
We kissed.
But I ran away.
That was mean.
I was?
Yes.
Yeah. I guess that was very mean.
But I have something meaner to say to you.
I like someone else.
...You want to break up?
Yes.
Does that person like you?
No.
She thinks nothing of me.
I learned that clearly today.
I was just at her house.
But you still want to break up with me?
I can't be with you anymore...
...because I like this person. I'm sorry.
Even if I don't mind?
Don't say that. You're too good for that.
Don't make me an excuse.
I don't love you anymore.
Not one bit?
It's not about the amount of love.
I didn't know that until yesterday.
And so I thought I could be with you.
But it doesn't work like that.
What's different about me compared to her?
I didn't compare you.
I just want to be with her right now.
For everything that I've got now.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
I'm happy.
Was going to tell you when I got home.
To really fall in love with me.
Until now. I never thought
it really mattered because...
...I was scared you would leave me
if I said it.
But I was just worried.
That maybe I was ruining your life.
Because you're kind.
What are you saying?
Life with no one to love is meaningless,
right?
I need you, Tomoya. to fall in love
with me but...
...couldn't do it.
But...
...I came home thinking that's wrong.
...I wanted to make you change.
I wanted to be responsible for your life.
But...
...there's no need for that now.
To leave me for someone you could love
on your own...
...is really the best way.
So I'm happy for you.
Though it's very sad that I couldn't make
you change.
Hey.
Did you ever...like me?
I did like you.
I always have.
What did you like about me?
...Your pretty eyes.
You have a pretty chin.
Weird ears and nose, but so cute.
Beautiful neck and pretty voice.
Your lips are cute.
I've always loved your fingers.
I'm not just saying this.
Thank you.
Did you ever have fun with me?
Most worried about that.
It was fun.
What was the most fun?
There's a lot of things...
Remember our trip to Mexico?
Yes.
Rode bicycles through Mexico City.
You scared me because you kept on riding
facing backwards.
Was worried you were right behind me.
You could have just slowed down.
That's true.
Remember the water of Fountain of Truth?
Really didn't work.
Maybe it's working now.
...I have to go.
Where?
I left everything I need for class
at her house.
Have to go get it.
I see.
I will come get my stuff
during winter holidays.
Okay.
Thanks for everything.
No. thank you for everything.
Don't force yourself.
I'm fine.
Good bye.
Bye.
Please forgive me.
Give me one more chance.
Please.
Aoba Kawai. Ryuta Okamoto
Kiyohiko Shibukawa
Fusako Urabe, Nao Okabe
Written and directed by Ryusuke Hamaguchi
English subtitled by Yuko Watanabe