Shown in the 1968 arts festival
a nikkatsu production
Grandpa! A rat! A rat!
Kame!
Kametaro!
Brother?
Brother!
Uma...
Hide it, brother.
Grandpa will give you hell if he finds it.
How's taro's illness?
He's not eaten since this morning.
There's a curse on him.
You've been to the sea,
haven't you, brother?
No, I haven't.
You're not supposed
to leave the pit at all.
If they find you poaching fish,
they'll kill you.
I haven't been!
I hope not.
Grandpa's coming.
Nekichi?
Has uma been here?
I don't know.
Right, kametaro...
Taro! Taro!
- He's better!
Toriko, you mustn't let taro
drink too much water.
Uma, you must leave nekichi alone.
I haven't seen him, grandpa.
What would happen
if people found out?
How would you explain it to ryu?
Long ago
long ago
very long ago
there came to the kurage sea...
A brother and a sister
a god and a goddess
together, they created an island
this is their tale
the tale of how the island began...
Then one day, the god of heaven
called the male god to him.
He told him to become
the guardian deity of an island.
The god of heaven gave him
a bright red rock.
The male god was overjoyed
and threw the rock into the ocean.
It made an enormous splash.
Lo and behold!
All of a sudden, kurage island
appeared in the ocean.
And then what?
And then the male god
tried to go down to the island.
But he couldn't.
"I must get down somehow,
but I can't!"
So he begged the god of heaven,
"I beg you, bestow upon me
the part of my body that I lack."
The god of heaven was astounded
and said,
"what part of your body
do you lack?"
”The part of my body
that I lack...
”...is that of a woman
”I lack the body of a woman ”
Profound des/res of the gods
Imamura productions
screenplay by imamura shohei
& hasebe keiji
directed by imamura shohei
cinematography by tochizawa masao
art direction by omura takeshi
Original music by mayuzumi toshiro
editing by tanji matsuo
Cast: Mikuni rentaro,
kawarazaki choichiro, kitamura kazuo
okiyama kazuko, matsui yasuko,
kato yoshi, komatsu hosei
hosokawa chikako, ogi chikage,
hamamura jun, tonoyama taiji
Fumoto!
How's the fishing today?
So-so!
Pig overboard!
Turn around!
Fumoto, turn around!
- Damn shark got it!
- Shark!
Come on!
Tomari...
Tonoshiro...
Ohama... ohama!
Ryu's share.
Here, toriko.
That's for me.
We're heading back!
We're off!
All right, kame...
Brother...
We, the futori family,
are the oldest family on the island.
In recent years, our transgressions
have caused trouble on the island,
therefore, I now promise the gods,
that the futori family
will never go out to sea,
and I will keep nekichi in shackles.
We will topple the rock
and restore the paddy fields
of the gods.
Once we have made good
our promises,
please let us associate
with the islanders again,
please let us
go out to sea again,
and please let us participate
in the dongama festival.
Please let us restore
the way things were.
The paddy fields of k urage island
are floating fields
stamp on the paddy field paths
and the ears of the rice plants
will quiver
the breasts of running girls
they quiver too,
they quiver too!
When their breasts quiver,
they make the blood run wild
all the boys and girls
run down to the beach
and dance all night long
in the shade of the Adan tree...
The boys have come out
to play with toriko.
Run down to the beach
and dance all night
in the shade of the Adan tree
Show us more! Come on, toriko!
More! More!
- Toriko?
- What?
Whose wife are you, toriko?
Toriko is kametaro's wife!
I'm kametaro's wife!
Toriko is nekichi's wife, nekichi's...
Toriko is... nekichi's... wife!
She says she's nekichi's wife!
Grandpa!
- You beasts!
- Bastards!
Sister-fucker!
Don't make fun of us, you bastards!
Grandpa!
Grandpa! It itches!
Grandpa! I can't bear the itching!
- There, there.
- It itches!
Toriko...
There, there...
What are you doing, nekichi?
- Toriko...
- My ear itches, grandpa!
Your ear?
- Where?
- My ear! Scratch my ear, father!
Here?
Who taught you this, toriko?
Grandpa...
Toriko knows nothing of pleasure.
That's why they call us beasts, grandpa!
Thanks to you, we all have to suffer.
What are you talking about?
The reason they call us beasts
is because you broke the rules.
I told you not to,
but you used dynamite to poach fish.
What's that?
They all used to do it!
They didn't do it so openly,
like you, you fool!
And on top of that, you laid hands
on another man's wife.
But sato was my comrade-in-arms!
He couldn't love his wife, so I did it
for him. What's wrong with that?
It's always about
"comrades-in-arms" with you.
He was my comrade-in-arms!
He was my friend
during the happiest time of my life.
Better than this forsaken place,
where they call us beasts
all the time!
All because you're insane!
Idiot!
A man should always
look after his woman.
Ushi's husband rejected her
so I loved her.
- There's nothing wrong with that.
- What? You bastard!
Ushi was your own daughter!
What about it?
I made her feel happy, didn't I?
She died happy, didn't she?
No one would marry her
because she was carrying your baby!
You owe your own life to her!
How dare you insult your own father!
Hot today, isn't it?
Working hard?
No, times are hard. See you!
Are you mr kariya?
I'm ryu ryugen
of the kurage sugar factory.
Was it choppy?
We were expecting your predecessor,
mr shimajiri, to come,
but he had other business.
What kind of man has come
come to catch me?
Tempt me with sweet words?
- Nekichi?
- Oh, my comrade-in-arms!
- What's up today?
- An engineer's arrived from Tokyo.
He's going to dig a well for the factory.
- Ryugen! Nice to see you.
- Honourable elder. Here...
I just brought you a little something.
- Blessings be upon you.
- Please accept it.
In actual fact, I'd like to borrow
kametaro as the engineer's assistant.
He's like family to me,
so I'd very much like to give him the job.
Kametaro belongs
to the futori family,
he has to dig the pit
for the islanders.
Of course, that's important,
but there's plenty of time for that.
- Uma's agreed, as well.
- Uma? Why?
Uma's also a futori!
She wouldn't halt digging the well.
But all the farmers on the island
make a living growing sugar cane.
The machines in the factory can't
function without water. We'd all die!
It was you who had the whole island
switch from growing rice to sugar cane!
The island can't thrive otherwise.
But I want to be
the engineer's assistant...
I've already mentioned kametaro
to the island elders.
If he helps the engineer, then he can be
in this year's dongama festival.
In the festival?
Thank you for saying so.
Blessings upon you.
Comrade...
What's kametaro's daily wage?
500 yen a day.
Nekichi, you mustn't accept any money.
The engineer's a god
from across the sea.
You can't accept payment
for working for a god...
Keep out of this!
This is between comrades.
Honourable elder,
the world has changed.
Work means money.
That's why people work,
for the money.
I don't understand.
Since ancient times, those who render
service to the island are seen as gods.
So working for a god is...
I don't understand.
Nekichi? Nekichi!
Nekichi!
Come on, hurry!
Mr engineer?
- Good evening.
- Oh, good evening.
- You're the engineer from Tokyo?
- Yes, I'm from Tokyo.
Konoe... konoe...
Konoe?
The konoe army division
from Tokyo.
Oh, you were in the konoe division?
How I miss Tokyo.
Ryu ryugen is a fairly decent man,
but the futoris are fools!
- The futoris?
- Kame, kametaro!
- Oh, you mean kametaro's father?
- Mad, totally mad.
They're beasts!
This engineer is the favourite
son-in-law
of the higashi sugar
company's chairman.
- So work hard.
- Yes, sir.
I'm the headman of the island
and the manager of the factory.
You are a youth of the island.
You must say nothing to the engineer
about this island's shameful past.
For the sake of your parents
and your siblings. Understand?
If there's anything that you don't
understand, then ask me.
They're late.
May I introduce your predecessor,
mr shimajiri.
Why haven't you reported
to the company, mr shimajiri?
No word for 6 months.
I'm very sorry.
Either the water supply's no good,
and we close down the factory,
or it's fine, and we push ahead
with the work.
It's one of the two.
The company is waiting
for your report, you know.
- My report?
- Of course.
Why is that?
Why? Obviously all employees
have to write reports for the company!
The company pays your salary,
doesn't it?
But I haven't received any salary.
Of course not!
Your wife and child in Tokyo receive it!
Mr engineer, sir,
all these fields used to be
paddy fields in the old days.
These are the remains
of the "hitomasuda".
Long ago, a bell was rung
to gather the islanders.
Those who arrived late were killed,
in order to control
the population numbers.
There were cruel practices in the past.
Thank you all.
Blessings upon you all.
Ryu, you are a man of high morals
and greatly respected by the islanders.
Thank you, thank you!
Blessings upon you all.
Long ago, these were all paddy fields,
but now they are sugar cane fields.
Oh, I see.
It's so hot!
- Let's press on.
- Yes, sir.
Eh? Didn't we pass this way before?
- Yes, that's right.
- What do you mean?
I'm so sorry about the heat, sir.
I want all the workers to see you,
that way, you can give them hope
for the future.
What are you on about?
Enough of this!
Take me straight to the factory!
Yes, sir.
How are things at the central office?
What? Well, the sugar business
isn't going too well.
But I'm just an engineer,
so I don't really know.
Must be hard on your father-in-law?
It doesn't really affect him,
he owns plenty of other companies.
It's so hot!
The company hasn't paid
the balance of last year's advance yet.
The islanders are worried.
But they place great trust
in chairman higashi's name.
Newspaper! Newspaper!
- Deliver it to my house.
- Morning edition?
No, the earliest edition we get
is already a week old.
Comrade! I delivered yours
to your home, comrade!
Thank you.
- This lot should have some water.
- That would be wonderful.
Excuse me, but would you have
a drink of water for the engineer?
Fine, fine.
Disgusting!
Many of the Wells have dried up
in the drought,
and the water's getting very salty.
How's the sugar cane?
Look, chairman higashi's son-in-law
has come from Tokyo.
The factory's secure.
So work hard, everyone! Right?
- What an amazing place!
- It's called "kuburabari".
- "Kuburabari"?
- Yes.
In olden times, they used to make
pregnant women jump from here
to control the population numbers,
so they say.
In feudal times, this island belonged
to an oppressive warrior clan...
Mr ryu, where's the water source?
I think there's an underground
spring here.
It comes out from under the cliff.
Can you see it?
Shall we climb down for a look?
- This place is no good.
- Eh?
- It's too far from the factory.
- It's the best on the island...
It may well be,
but it's no good for the company!
The water quality is good, isn't it?
The water quality's good.
- You've tried here?
- Yes.
That's where we bored a hole.
And?
- What were the results?
- Well, the results...
During the work, there was a wedding.
A wedding? Whose?
It was... mine.
Mr shimajiri was boarding in the house
of a woman who'd been made a widow.
Anyway, it's hard, this bedrock.
It's 5km from here to the factory.
Even if boring was successful,
manual labour costs would be enormous.
Labour costs are not something
you need to worry about.
Since the olden days, we've had
a traditional labour service.
It can provide free labour
when necessary.
Anyway, we have no other
sources of water.
So you'll have to draw
the water from here somehow.
What kind of man will come
come to catch me?
Tempt me with sweet words?
Toriko, you're working hard.
Look at these,
they're from america.
Very pretty!
Hey, you don't put them on your head!
They're panties!
Try them on.
Take your dirty ones off.
I'll give you a hand.
These are filthy!
Lie down.
You fool!
Oh, kame!
I brought over nekichi's coal.
Give me a pongee for it.
- Go away!
- Give me the pongee.
- Toriko, give me those knickers back!
What will you do?
They were 550 yen.
You've got money?
Hey, kame, want a fountain pen?
- Get lost!
- I'm going, I'm going.
Have the pongee ready for me.
I'll come tomorrow.
Brother!
Stop it!
Panties! Panties!
My ear itches!
Brother! My ear itches!
Scratch my ear for me!
Brother!
Brother, my ear!
My ear!
Scratch my ear for me, brother!
Stop it, toriko!
Stop! Stop!
Brother!
My ear!
Damn this island!
Hell hole!
Others must be at it too.
Nekichi, get up! Get up!
God of kurage!
Nekichi futori has disobeyed thee
by taking off his chains.
He has broken the law
in order to poach.
Fumoto! I wasn't the only one doing it.
Damn you, you all betrayed me.
I, yamamori futori, your humble servant
will punish him in thy place.
You all right, grandpa?
For taking off his chains, fifty lashes!
For poaching, fifty lashes!
One hundred, all told!
I will now begin his punishment!
One! Two! Three...
You're hurting me! My feet!
Six, seven, eight...
You unfilial son!
You damn idiot!
Lawbreaker!
Don't you dare!
You lawbreaker!
Please heal nekichi.
It hurts here.
Here?
Uma...
That rock will fall this year,
I'm sure of it.
- Is that true?
- It's true.
And when it falls,
I'll reclaim the paddy fields,
then we'll live together again.
I hope it's soon.
- Brother!
- Why not?
- Why is it bad?
- Because it is!
All the islanders call you my wife.
They say the futoris are beasts.
Anyway...
My late sister-in-law would curse us.
The gods would punish me.
Do you hate me?
I love you.
Thank you!
Thanks.
Are you ryu's daughter?
His wife, then?
Uma? Uma!
Yes?
Fresh air makes me hungry.
Thank you, thank you!
It's you, honourable elder.
Well!
Thank you so much
for the pumpkin the other day.
I offer these in return.
Blessings upon you. Thanks.
Thank you for all the kindness
you show to uma.
No, not at all.
And thank you for being so good
to kametaro.
- Where are you off to?
- My pleasure...
- Where's she going?
- To the sacred forest.
- What's with the white kimono?
- It's for a noro.
- Noro?
- What do you call it on the mainland?
- A sort of shaman.
- Ashaman?
- What's she going for?
- To pray for rain.
- For rain?
- It's a superstition.
What's that old man to you?
He's my grandfather.
- He and uma?
- Father and daughter.
Then what is she to ryu?
What do you call it
on the mainland?
Are you working before breakfast?
What is it?
- That bore we saw yesterday...
- But it's too far away.
Please have another look.
It won't take long by car.
- I have to send a telegram to work.
- But it's Sunday, so...
- I can't send it?
- You'd better put on this straw hat.
How about breakfast?
It'll be ready by the time you return.
Take him to the site first.
I must meet your father.
My mother died a long time ago.
I don't know if my father's at home.
- Let's go and see.
- You don't have to.
Yes, I do have to.
- It's dirty. We should clean up first...
- I don't mind.
Grandpa! Toriko!
The engineer's coming!
Put the pig in the sty!
Then boil some water.
Grandpa!
Fix your loincloth!
This is my grandfather.
The engineer.
So you're the engineer?
I am indebted to you for the kindness
you show to my grandson.
Blessings upon you.
You look very fit. What's your age?
Well... how old am I?
Nice place you have here.
For generations, we futoris
have served the gods as noro.
- Kametaro and his sister...
- He has a sister?
Yes.
- Where's toriko?
- I don't know.
- Kame, the engineer's a very nice man.
- Of course he is!
Once...
I catch...
A man in my clutches
I know...
I'll never let him go
I 7! Never let him go
come, come at night...
Hey, help me!
Let go, toriko!
- She's your sister?
- Yes.
She's a bit funny in the head.
Listen, don't act strange. Please.
I want to help the engineer
so that he'll take me to Tokyo.
- Tokyo, understand?
- Tokyo?
Yes. There are millions
of people in Tokyo.
There's electricity, trains,
universities, everything!
Once I'm a success in Tokyo,
I'll take you there.
Are you mr futori?
Oh, you're the engineer?
Kametaro's a great help.
What is this hole?
Twenty years ago, a tidal wave
washed up that big rock.
We're digging the hole to drop it in.
The sea water comes in here.
- You've been digging for 20 years?
- Yes.
We have to restore
those paddy fields
so we can offer rice to the gods.
The rest all became
sugar cane fields.
I see...
But how many more years will it take
for the rock to drop?
I don't know.
When nekichi grows old,
kametaro will carry on the task.
When kame dies,
his children will do it.
I see. Such hard work.
It's a fine paddy field.
There's sunshine, no wind,
and plenty of water.
Water?
Where does the water come from?
The water? Let me see...
The water comes from... well...
Engineer! Can you bring this up?
- That?
- Aye. Just pull that rope.
Do you have a cigarette?
There you are.
Mr futori, where does this water
for the paddy field come from?
I don't know.
Where could it come from?
Well, now...
Hey, I hear something.
Sounds like water!
We passed by here once before.
We can't go any further in.
No one really knows where
the water's coming from?
That's correct, sir.
It's getting dark. Let's head back.
- Just a little further.
- Soon the habu will be coming out.
- What?
- Habu. Poisonous snakes.
Tomorrow, then.
When did we receive the advance?
The end of last year.
They said they'd pay the balance
when they finished refining the sugar.
It's been four months since then.
"Recession, recession!"
That's all they say.
- Ryu must be taking the money.
- Of course he is.
We're too poor
to wait for the harvest.
He takes advantage of that.
I hate this dirty little island!
If you hate it that much,
why don't you leave?
What did you say, you digger?
I'm not a digger anymore!
What are you, then? Ryu's dog?
Or the engineer's dog?
Either way, you're not human.
I am human.
I'll be in the next dongama festival.
What about dongama?
It's just superstition!
Shall we try a little poaching?
Too risky with a dog on the team.
I don't want to end up like nekichi,
banned from the sea.
Damn, when will this drought be over?
Many have already left the island.
Those who remain are just losers.
What a bore! All we can do
is a bit of night crawling!
The girls in kurage
all have warm hearts
two snakes
writhing with each other
night crawling, night crawling
night crawling
brings such pleasure
once I catch a man
in my clutches
I will never let him go
night crawling, night crawling
night crawling
brings such pleasure...
Whisky.
- Can you give me some water?
- The water's salty.
Have any of you been
in the sacred forest?
- No one's been in?
- No.
There has to be water there.
Don't you know?
"Don't you know?"
Father?
What's the matter, father?
I can hear someone calling.
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
But lately, someone's been
calling me at night, "nekichi!"
Someone's calling me
from underground.
- Where did you get that key?
- From mr ryu.
- Ryu?
- He wants you to come over.
Here?
Over there, then?
Over there.
Tokusato lost his soul last night,
so he's looking for it.
It's just superstition.
- Do such things happen?
- They say they do on this island.
It's stupid, though.
Mr engineer, that's the wrong way!
Not that way!
Mr engineer, the proposed site
is over here.
This is the wrong way!
Mr engineer, this is wrong.
It's best not to go that way.
There!
Rain, rain, rain to fall
rain, rain, rain to fall...
Water!
- The source must be here.
- Mr engineer!
That hurts! That hurts!
Hurry, take me down!
It's throbbing!
Fool! Cut down the tree!
Our carelessness has delayed
your work. I am truly sorry.
It's not futori's fault.
I was too hasty.
It'll make a good story to tell at home.
Ryugen, why didn't you tell me
about that source of good water?
The shrine's well is the last water
left on the island.
This drought has lasted
for three months so far,
but nobody uses that water.
The gods punish those who touch it.
We don't tell outsiders, that's the rule.
Without water, the factory will close.
Then the whole island will suffer.
Yes, but we can't disregard
our island's traditions and beliefs.
It's better using this water source
than laying a 5-kilometre pipeline!
God's water or not!
I'm the factory manager,
but also the headman of the island.
Even more so, then. It's an opportunity
to do away with these old superstitions!
Kurage island lags fifty years
behind the mainland, so it takes time.
- There is no time.
- No!
Oh, thank you.
Blessings upon you.
Furthermore, I have absolutely
no influence over that place.
The noro are in charge of it.
- Ah, the shamans?
- Yes.
They have an unspoken
sovereign authority there.
So I have to get the noro together
and ask them first.
Will they agree?
I don't know.
That's why I must ask them.
I'll make some preliminary checks,
all right?
I imagine so.
- She's a very religious woman?
- She's my wife.
Then uma is...?
Unari, show him the shackles.
Back in feudal times,
the ryu family suffered greatly,
they worked as serfs
in the cane fields.
These are the shackles
that were used in those days.
We keep them to remind ourselves
of our ancestors' hardships.
And to prevent ourselves
from breaking the laws of the gods.
Lend me a match, please.
The people of the island
are deeply religious, aren't they?
What deity is it?
The whole of creation,
each blade of grass, they are all gods.
There are gods in the sea,
in the fields and in our homes.
If you take the gods away,
there would be nothing left here.
The boar trap?
Blessings upon you.
Will you let me see uma?
How dare you?
Be off with you!
And keep the chains quiet.
Disgrace to the island!
After nekichi returned from the army,
his wife died.
That's when he became wild.
He started poaching with dynamite
and stealing,
chasing women and
seducing other men's wives.
In the end, even his own sister!
Many islanders died
in the malaria epidemic of 1947.
Nekichi's crimes had angered the gods.
Is that true?
As proof, a tidal wave came
and swept a big red rock
onto his paddy field.
What an awful story.
So ryu made uma stay
in his house with him.
- Uma?
- Right.
Leading an honest life,
she was inspired to become a noro.
Her ancestors were all shaman,
so uma's the head shaman here.
So you could say that uma
is ryu's mistress, isn't she?
How do they call it on the mainland?
How do they call it here?
"Taking care of a woman," we say.
Anyway, it's lucky for us that ryu's
looking after the leading shaman.
- To get water from the gods!
- That's something else entirely.
Where have you been?
Praying on the beach.
- Is that true?
- Yes, it is.
You should serve the engineer.
A shaman's duty is to protect
the shrine and the island. Understood?
Go and comfort the engineer.
Go on!
- Here.
- Thanks. I've had quite enough.
- One more.
- No, I can't.
Mr engineer...
Are you hot?
Yes, so don't come close to me.
Do you dislike me, mr engineer?
It's not a matter of like or dislike.
Ah, it's too damn hot!
Uma, wait!
I don't know what this is all about,
but it's all a bit too much.
I'll sleep outside tonight.
Wait, mr engineer!
You should show more self respect.
Understand?
Goodnight.
Engineer!
You fool!
You can't even fulfil your duty
as a noro!
What happened tonight?
Nothing.
You didn't...?
You met with nekichi?
I would never do
such a terrible thing.
Damn you!
- What happened to you here?
- I stumbled on a tree branch.
- And here?
- Same thing.
- The same.
Where did you meet
that damn nekichi?
- Where?
- In the pit!
- What did you do with nekichi?
- We did nothing! Nothing...
- Is that the truth?
- Yes. We didn't do anything!
- Swear it to the gods.
- I swear!
To the dongama gods?
I swear to the gods!
To the gods...
Father?
Hey, kame.
Will you let me have this engine?
- You should've asked me first!
- You were fast asleep.
It took me half a year
to fix that engine!
I'm off to bird island to collect
some bullets to make gunpowder.
Don't! You'll break it!
You'll break it like that!
You try it, then.
I'm getting old.
I used to row easily
when I was young.
There's no wind for sailing.
She runs so fast!
Father... what if they find us?
We futoris aren't allowed out at sea.
They won't find us.
That's heading for Vietnam.
Kametaro, look...
Beyond the shining sea in the west,
there's holy island.
There are no rules,
no betrayers there.
There's enough land
to produce food for yourself.
There's no such holy island
in the west.
That's only in old folk tales.
No, I saw it during the war,
when I was drifting in a storm.
Not many on kurage island
know about it.
But some do.
They just never mention it.
Maybe they go there to poach.
- Why do they keep it secret?
- Because it's no longer part ofjapan.
It belongs to that country now.
How come no one lives there?
It's already enormous, that country.
No one would want to live
on such a tiny island.
Do you want to go there?
Why don't you go, then?
Because I'm digging the hole
to remove the rock.
- Why do you have to do that?
- That's the promise I made to ryu.
A promise?
Ryu was my comrade-in-arms.
I keep my promises to him.
Liar! You're digging
because you like it!
You idiot!
Everybody says
the futoris are beasts.
Father...
Did you really do the same thing
as grandpa did?
Is auntie your sister
as well as your wife...?
Fool! Don't talk stupid!
- But they all...
- Kame!
Human beings aren't allowed
to do such things.
Man must not imitate the gods.
He may be a war comrade,
but it's an old promise.
A promise is a promise.
Kame...
That rock may fall...
By the end of this year,
maybe even sooner.
Really?
When it falls, we, the futoris,
will move to holy island.
Not me. I don't want to go.
I want to go to Tokyo.
What for?
Whatever. I just want to go.
When the island first began
the brother god and the sister goddess
did not know how to have a baby
So the young god and goddess
they prayed to the god of heaven
and they asked him
They asked him for advice
they telephoned the god of heaven
to ask him!
Engineer! A letter, a letter!
It's from a woman in Tokyo.
- My sister.
- "My sister"!
The god of heaven told them:
"Go in opposite directions
around the well."
The two of them did
as they were told,
and they embraced
when they met again.
And the brother and daughter
became husband and wife.
Then the god of heaven sent down
birds and animals, all in pairs.
Thus people, birds, animals
and insects populated the island.
What is it?
Uma, no. It's far too hot.
Such fair skin!
- Oh, stop it, uma.
- It's so shiny!
Mr futori will come.
- Give it back to me.
- Please hold me.
- Give it back!
- Hold me, please.
Give it back to me.
What would we tell ryu?
I have a wife and children!
But your wife's having an affair!
How do you know that?
Did you open it?
Damn you!
Hold me or this will happen to me.
But I can't do that, I can't.
What did I tell you?
Show some self respect.
I'm not like mr shimajiri.
I'm sorry, but leave me alone.
This island's totally beyond me.
Beyond me!
Give me a hand.
This branch is in the way.
- Futori!
- Yes, sir.
One, two, three...
Break it downwards!
One, two, three.
What's the matter?
We must ask the noro first
about breaking any trees.
We're only breaking the trees
that block the survey.
- They are dead anyway!
- Yes, but...
But what?
- The gods will punish us.
- You believe that?
No, I don't believe it,
it's just a superstition.
Right...
- Cut down this tree then.
- No! I'll do anything else.
Cut it down. Go on!
Please don't fire me! Please don't!
I won't fire you if you do it!
You have to destroy
all these superstitions! Do it!
Quickly!
Stop this nonsense, you idiot!
If you won't do it, then I will.
See if I'm punished!
- That hurt.
- Are you all right?
What happened?
We hit something.
- Another interference?
- Seems so.
Pull it up!
It's blocked.
This is the third time. Shit!
It's so damn hot.
Mr kariya...
I approved a preliminary investigation,
but this is going too far.
What is the shamans' answer?
It's been a fortnight already.
At any rate, the very destiny
of the island is at stake.
That's rubbish!
You always exaggerate.
The islanders' beliefs are the foundation
of their love for their homeland.
I understand that.
The company must take this
absolutely seriously.
The factory gets cheap sugar cane
and low-cost labour
because of the islanders' love
of their homeland.
The company profits from that...
Until now maybe,
but such old ideas are out after this.
But friendship is the bond
between the factory and the people.
That's too outmoded!
You have to be more rational about it.
In that case, the factory must pay
the balance of the advance.
I've already asked the company about it,
and I've received no answer yet.
- Hey, shimajiri!
- But...
Futori!
In article 1 of the higashi construction
company policy,
it states "to be humane" as its aim.
I don't deny that. I'm doing this
for the sake of islanders.
Yes...
But I'm constantly being interrupted!
An improvement in your attitude
would help!
- But...
- I want to finish this and go home!
I know exactly how you feel.
You must be terribly worried
about your wife...
Make your stance clear
or I'll do it for you!
And I'll catch the culprit who's
sabotaging our work! Is that clear?
Chase him, futori!
Father!
Mr engineer, this way!
He went this way!
- I've discovered who the saboteur is.
- Oh, who is it?
- This man.
- Oh...
He's the criminal.
I took his photo last night and printed it.
I see. Well, well.
Who do you think it is?
Don't you think it's futori nekichi?
I don't think so.
Who do you think it is, then?
I don't know.
Futori.
Who do you think this is?
It's your father, isn't it?
I'm not too sure.
What? You've forgotten
your own father's face?
Are you sure you're not mistaken,
mr engineer?
Why?
Halt!
We all make mistakes.
Are you joking? It's definitely nekichi!
As you know,
nekichi's tied in the pit with iron chains.
Therefore it cannot be nekichi.
Someone must have let him loose.
- You! It must have been you!
- I didn't do it.
You've no idea, ryu?
- No.
- Then who could it be?
The insects are swarming!
The night has come!
It might be nekichi.
On the other hand,
it might not be.
Everybody, lie down!
Here, please, mr engineer.
What's this?
It's a superstition, I think,
a spell to ward off insects.
Don't make a fool of me.
Ryu, tonight I'll sleep at the site.
- Outside?
- Shut up!
You don't need to come any more.
Oh, it refreshes you
Coca-Cola!
What man will catch me
and tempt me with sweet words?
Weaving the traditional pattern
once it's finished,
I dedicate it to the gods
on a moonlit night,
I leave the house
- for the gods of the sea...
- Toriko?
The engineer's sleeping out
in the forest, near the machine.
Take him this sake.
And a pillow, too.
- Toriko!
- Kame...
Don't stop her.
She's getting a husband.
A husband!
But...
Snakes writhing together
night crawling
no, you can't come in, toriko! Toriko!
Aren't you... hot?
Aren't you hot?
Hot, isn't it?
Hot... hot...
No, toriko!
Stop it!
Toriko!
Stop it, toriko. No!
- Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
- Tomorrow?
Tomorrow. Honest.
Tomorrow. At the west beach.
West beach, all right, got it.
Now hurry, toriko!
Hey, what are you doing?
You're the saboteur!
What do you think you're doing?
- Why are you chaining me up?
- Fool. Ask yourself the reason.
I don't understand.
You grow older but not wiser.
You'll be punished simply
for walking around.
And now you've gone and hurt
the engineer!
And you've got ryugen into trouble.
No. Ryu himself told me
to protect the sacred woods.
My job is to sabotage
the engineer's work.
I know that!
But did ryugen tell you
to do it quite so overtly?
You've even had your photograph taken!
Nekichi, put out your leg.
Spanner, please.
- Can you look after the baby?
- What's up?
- My sister's in labour and needs me.
- All right, all right.
- He's wet himself.
- I can see that.
I'll do it. Hurry, go.
Thanks!
Mr kariya?
Oh, it's you. What is it?
Well... she's waiting
at the west beach.
West beach?
You promised her, so she's been
waiting since yesterday.
Who has?
My sister, toriko.
She hasn't eaten for two days.
She won't talk to anyone but you.
Poor girl!
Toriko!
You came!
Toriko, have you been waiting
since yesterday?
You've been here all this time?
I'm sorry, I broke my promise.
Mr engineer...
I waited for you.
Toriko's decided on a husband.
So you can join
the dongama festival.
And, kame...
I've been told to help put
a new roof on tsuchimochi's.
- Tsuchimochi's?
- Yes.
Long ago, his grandfather helped us
thatch our roof.
I couldn't die without repaying the debt.
My first work for the village
for 20 years!
Once the rock falls, we can be part
of the community once again.
When did I come here?
On the one hand,
it seems like only yesterday.
On the other hand,
it seems like a long time ago.
Mr engineer!
The wind won't let up for a while yet.
Let's leave the thatching for now.
Typhoon no 12's origins
are over the south seas.
It is now at latitude 24 degrees north
and longitude 130 degrees east,
moving to nne at 10km per hour...
Latitude 24 north is exactly
kurage island, isn't it?
Mr engineer?
This year's wind brings no rain.
- A dry wind!
- Grandpa...
The rock's falling.
Kame! Toriko! The rock's falling!
Get out of here!
Come on, mr engineer!
The rock is falling!
- The rock is falling!
- Fall!
Get under, everyone!
Damn it!
Just a little more.
God of the wind!
Please make the rock fall!
I beseech thee! I pray to thee!
God of the wind!
Please blow harder!
That's no good!
Lower your hips more!
You're getting slack! Try harder!
Feeling hungry?
Eat a lot to get stronger
and you'll make a good son-in-law.
Right, come on up!
Got a cigarette?
Mr engineer!
Is that all right, father?
I have to take him to kuburabari.
He's my son-in-law,
so he's only doing our work.
Brother!
Grandpa... grandpa...
What happened?
Grandpa fell from the roof.
He's dying!
Pray, uma!
Why aren't you praying?
Call him back!
Summon his soul back with your powers!
Summon him back!
Dear departed soul
of futori yamamori
Hold on.
He's returning to nature.
Why did I make you
the engineer's assistant?
To help the construction work
go smoothly.
Is he all right now?
The pipes are arriving from Tokyo.
He has work to do.
Yes.
Entering.
The island gods are entering.
The pain!
Reveal your name to us.
My head hurts!
Hurry, tell us. Who are you?
Say it clearly, tell us your name.
Who are you?
My feet slipped from the roof.
Grandpa...
I cracked my head open.
Everyone in kurage is one family.
All the families should help each other.
The pain!
What's hurting you? Tell us.
Nekichi...
Don't take off your chain.
It's so painful!
Mr engineer...
Don't desert toriko.
Kame...
Fear the gods of dongama.
Toriko is pregnant.
Mr engineer, return to the site.
The pipes are arriving from Tokyo.
You mustn't stay here.
What are you saying, kame?
He's your brother now.
Don't get in the way!
I promised ryu...
Ryu? Whatever he says, the engineer
is family now, he's toriko's husband!
Come on!
- Kametaro!
- What are you doing?
- Kame, I won't go.
- Why not?
- It's better here.
- But the work is hard and dirty.
- But I'm happier here.
- But the pipes...
I'll commute from here
when they arrive. Tell ryu.
- I can't...
- And bring my stuff here from his house.
It still hasn't rained
despite all our prayers.
It's all superstition.
Who believes in noro?
I envy that ryu ryugen.
He makes love to uma
and prays for rain!
What's this whisky?
Did you put sea water in it?
Pipe down! You'll have to wait
till it rains to drink fresh water.
What's up, kame?
The pipes are coming
from Tokyo tomorrow.
The company's in a hurry,
but the engineer's in a state...
So what?
Take the engineer back to mr ryu's
to dig for water in kuburabari.
What about toriko?
What about her?
- She's a futori.
- So you want to break them up?
Yes.
I get it. You're jealous
because he took your wife away.
Stop it!
Yamashiro, you could be
her husband too.
Fool! A lot of you had her before me.
But the first one was kametaro.
We'll never know.
The fish! The fish are coming!
- Who said so?
- Uma the noro said so.
There was a flash of lightning,
so a shoal of fish is coming.
The nets! Get the nets!
Let's go. They're not coming.
Let's go!
No, you mustn't give up
being a noro.
I am no longer a noro.
The gods have abandoned me.
The rain won't fall.
My prophecies never come true.
Your prophecies aren't the problem.
The sugar cane suffers in this drought.
And there's no fish.
The islanders are confused,
so they doubt everything.
We must show them the right path,
that's why the noro are needed now.
The gods have just told me
to hand over my duties.
- To whom?
- Toriko.
Fool!
Toriko's not fit to be a noro.
But the gods have spoken.
- Your mind is clouded.
- Clouded?
Ask yourself,
have you broken the divine laws?
Please come immediately.
Mr ryu's waiting.
I don't want to!
Hey! Kametaro!
- Don't be rough.
- Hey, father!
What's going on?
They've taken the engineer.
There you are.
- Congratulations!
- What's this?
- I don't like violence.
- Forgive me.
It was unavoidable.
Over there, please.
You've been promoted to head
of department. Congratulations.
- Head of department?
- Mr higashi informed me last night.
He's set up a new company,
the higashi tourist company,
and you are the head of sales.
Your task will be to develop
tourism in kurage island.
Tourism? I heard him mention
the subject before.
A letter from your wife
was also enclosed.
Tourism is your father-in-law's dream.
And as we've now been granted
permission to build an airport,
that dream will come true.
An airport?
Unari, where's uma?
She went to pray.
By the way, mr higashi will be
visiting the island in a few days.
Really? The chairman himself?
Here's the rain we've been waiting for.
Congratulations!
Welcome chairman higashi
it is with deep regret that
I have to inform you of this
on such a joyous day,
but the payment of the balance
of the advance has been cancelled.
In the face of a worldwide drop
in sugar prices,
all my efforts have been
totally in vain.
My deepest apologies to you all.
But I am confident about the talks
concerning land for the airport.
I am sure we can sell our land
at a high price
to compensate
for the cancelled balance payment.
For those whose land is not
on the proposed site,
well-paid jobs in construction
of the airport will be secured.
I have your best interests at heart!
Engineer!
Wait.
Why don't you come home?
My father-in-law is here.
Toriko's gone mad.
She won't eat or drink anything.
- Will you come home?
- Don't worry, I will.
- Don't make the baby fatherless.
- I know.
I promise I'll come back... later.
I'll be waiting.
Brother...
You mustn't go.
Settle the matter with money.
It's not a question of money.
- I'll talk to my father-in-law...
- Don't be ridiculous.
You'd put me
in a very difficult position.
Auntie!
Mr ryu has given me some money
to take toriko to the mainland
for an abortion.
Father will be so angry.
Tell me what I should do!
The gods have abandoned me.
I don't know anything anymore.
Must she have the abortion
for the sake of the island?
Auntie, tell me!
It's a terrible thing...
Where are we going?
A nice place. To the mainland.
To have fun.
There'll be cars, electricity
and pinball machines!
Where are we going, brother?
Don't worry. Just relax, all right?
Excuse me.
Let's go and play pinball!
Stay put, toriko!
The futoris are beasts after all.
It runs in the family.
How frightening.
I wonder what awful things
will happen.
Kurage island is cursed
because of the futoris.
It's rained but all the island's Wells
are still dry.
It's because of nekichi's pit.
The shrine well is almost dry, too.
Without water, we'll never get
a good price for our land.
Everyone says it's all because
of those beasts, the futoris.
Everyone says
it's because of nekichi's pit.
Jump! Jump!
I'm scared!
Jump! Goddamn it, jump!
Brother!
The brother god
and the sister goddess
they were laughing and smiling
they were happy
living together
but a violent god
appeared before them
he forced them to part
forced them to part
the brother's tears
became clouds
and the sister's blood
became the earth
the clouds and the earth
existed in Harmony
Leave?
You're telling me to leave this pit?
Yes, I am, nekichi.
You've laboured long and hard,
but your work is now over,
you can leave this place.
This is public property, so normally
you wouldn't get anything,
but after all your hard work,
I'm ready to pay you.
The rock's going to fall
in less than 10 days.
Good work, you must be tired.
It's time to take the money
and take it easy.
And uma?
Will you give her back to me?
Not right away, no...
She still has her duty
as a noro to fulfil.
I've been digging for 20 years.
I kept digging for 20 years
so I could get uma back.
I did it because we were comrades...
I didn't order it, the gods did.
I just followed their orders.
So when did the gods
change their minds?
First they tell me to stay here
and now to leave?
Damn fool!
Aren't you afraid of the gods?
Do as you please.
I won't leave!
Until the rock falls
and I get uma back,
I'm not moving!
And I have to protect the shrine as well.
No need, we're moving the shrine
to the south woods.
We need this place for the airport.
- You're moving the shrine?
- Yes.
Straight after the dongama festival.
The noro have agreed.
- Even uma?
- Of course she agreed.
She'd never agree.
She wants to stop being a shaman
and come back.
Nekichi, uma's over 30 years old.
She's not a little girl anymore.
She hasn't changed,
she's still the same.
The island's changed, uma's changed.
She's not yours anymore.
She's not changed!
She wouldn't change for you!
Uma's my sister!
The gods know of your sins.
It's not the gods, it's you!
You accused uma and me,
but we were innocent!
But I gave in,
because we were comrades-in-arms.
That's why I don't want
to force you to leave.
Listen...
Everyone is happy to sell their land.
They'll get an unbelievable
amount of money.
Your stubbornness will spoil everything.
Reconsider for the sake
of the island and the others.
No! I refuse!
- Even with compensation?
- Of course.
Go home, comrade!
- And send the engineer back here!
- I refuse!
Toriko refuses to talk.
The engineer must be sad.
Things change.
Everything must change.
Ryugen! You're the sinner!
It's you who should fear the gods!
Twenty years ago, we were falsely
accused by the islanders.
Amongst them, only ryugen and unari
showed us any kindness.
But he's changed.
Uma...
Have you changed too?
No, I haven't changed!
But you're ryugen's...
Mistress.
I was only 15 then.
I couldn't do anything about it!
Ryugen must have realised
that you were a virgin.
We're man and wife
in our hearts.
Can we be so, in our hearts?
The gods know everything.
No, brother. We mustn't!
Brother!
Wait!
Stop! It won't be long now.
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Stop! Damn you!
You're filling up the hole, damn you!
Uma, run!
I'm digging for the gods' paddy field!
I'm doing this...
For everybody's sake!
Stop! Wait a minute!
Spare me! Forgive me!
Won't you forgive me?
Spare me and I won't see
uma anymore!
I won't take off my chains
and I'll pray to the gods!
I won't go to the sea!
I won't poach with gunpowder!
I won't do anything!
I'll do anything you say!
I beg you!
Forgive me!
Thank you.
I understand you now.
I won't do anything bad any more!
Uma, give me a match.
Brother...
The rock's falling! Uma, run quick!
Brother!
Brother, where are you?
Father!
Brother!
Brother, are you all right?
Are you injured?
Father!
It fell...
Uma, it fell.
The rock fell!
Brother, the rock fell!
I'm so glad! I'm so happy!
It fell down!
Hurry, get on.
Father...
All the islanders are in trouble
because you won't sell this place.
Sell it for everybody's sake.
You'd get 250,000 yen for the field.
And you'd get land and a house
on the mainland.
A paltry sum. This field belongs
to the gods, I can't sell it.
- But father, everyone is...
- Bring that here.
The field is back,
and the futoris are back like before.
I wish grandpa was here to see it.
Auntie, mr ryu wants you back
right away.
Why?
For the dongama festival.
You're a noro!
I was abandoned by the gods.
I can't take part.
Toriko...
You have to take my place
as a noro.
The gods want you to.
Toriko, do you understand?
The boss of the company
wants me to go back.
I have to go back to Tokyo
on the next ship.
Tokyo?
I'll be back no matter what.
That's the truth!
Ow, that hurts!
Toriko... believe me.
I hate Tokyo.
I don't like my wife or her parents.
I love you more than anything!
So listen to what I have to say.
Toriko... what is it?
Watch out! It's still alive!
Wait, toriko!
- Let's go to west beach!
- All right, let's go.
Tomorrow! Let's go then!
- Tomorrow?
- Yes, before the ship leaves!
What? Futori got 250,000 yen?
Yes. I only got 150,000
for the same amount of land.
Of course, futori's special.
Because it's the gods' paddy field.
Fool! Uma is ryugen's mistress.
But nekichi hasn't sold it yet.
- The rock fell but he's still holding on.
- He wants to raise the price.
At night, uma works on ryugen.
Damn!
The rest of us work so hard.
We didn't even get
the rest of the advance.
Nekichi's the smart one.
We're all fools.
Shit! We should have buried him
in that pit.
Kill that beast!
Kame, from now on,
you pay for all our drinks!
Why?
How much were you paid
for being ryu's dog?
Father and son, both beasts!
- I'm not!
- You are!
- I'm in the dongama...
- It won't make you a human being.
It's just a superstitious festival
for the natives!
But you'll all take part, won't you?
We won't help ryugen anymore.
You won't catch any of our families
being his mistress!
But if you don't take part,
mr fumoto will give you a hard time.
- Who's fumoto?
- Just ryugen's shadow!
- Who's ryugen, anyway?
- Who cares!
The festival's just a fake
coming-of-age ceremony!
- We won't go!
- Never!
Fuck the dongama!
Master, please don't do this
to me any more. Spare me!
Only you know my true feelings.
Only you.
I can't take part
in the dongama festival.
I can hear the drums.
Make up your mind.
The dongama is our most
important festival.
A noro must attend.
What will we do without you?
Who will save our island from evil?
My prophecies don't come true
anymore. The rain...
How many times do I have to tell you?
Obey the gods
and your powers will return.
Let toriko... become the noro!
Idiot!
All this talk of a tourist industry
for a pathetic little island like this,
so the people become greedy
and doubts arise.
I understand the love the peasants
have for their land,
but we must introduce
a new system to kurage island.
We have to get rid of those
who oppose it as quickly as possible.
You know I only care about
the happiness of the islanders.
Uma, attend the festival
and receive the divine message.
Then tell everybody
that nekichi opposes it.
Tell them he's against tourism
and against mr higashi, uma!
I won't do that!
Spare me this! Please!
Engineer!
Kafiya!
Damn you...
Are you disobeying me?
Forgive me, master!
What did you do with nekichi?
Tell me, or I'll hit you like this!
Forgive me!
Never!
I won't give you up
to the likes of nekichi!
Never to the likes of him!
No matter what happens
to the rock or the pit...
You're mine!
Master...
Master!
You're here?
You said you wouldn't come.
You came, too.
My father cried when I said
I wouldn't attend.
Mine, too.
It's hard when old people cry.
The dongama is our most
important festival.
We'll never be able to introduce
any reforms like this.
But if we don't get along with others,
we can't live on kurage.
But it hurts getting clubbed
at dongama.
Do you or do you not believe
in the god dongama?
- I do!
- Really?
- It's true.
- Arms up!
All right! Bring the sake!
Don't choke! Drink it all!
Don't drop your arms!
Mr ryu, it's time for the oracle.
Mr ryu?
No ryu...
Not here? Since when?
Since we started, I think.
Not at all? Why?
I don't know.
Where's mr ryu?
Mr ryu? I don't know.
Do you know where uma's gone?
- His wife!
- Ryu's dead! He's been killed!
Who killed him?
He's chained... with shackles...
Nekichi...
- It's nekichi.
- It's nekichi!
The oil store!
- Who set fire to it?
- Who?
- It's nekichi! The beast!
- Find him!
Nekichi, come out!
He's run away.
Father...
Uma...
Do you think toriko's all right?
She's fine.
Once I've built a paddy field and house
on holy island, I'll go fetch her.
But that'll take at least three months.
Don't worry. Kametaro's there.
We can't count on kame!
I know he'll go to Tokyo.
Ryu's wife will look after her.
But toriko's half-witted.
Toriko's a noro. A true noro.
The gods will protect her.
What is it, uma?
Nothing, only...
Are you thinking about ryugen?
What will people say about us
not attending his funeral?
That's why we asked unari
to take care of things.
But...
It's already Autumn. We must hurry.
I told unari that I'd visit
ryugen's grave later.
When the dongama and the funeral
are over, it will be storm season.
That's why unari told us to go at once.
Uma, feed the chickens.
The engine's overheated.
I need to give it a rest for a while.
Eat.
You'll lose energy if you don't.
Brother!
I love you, brother!
We're alone. There's no one but us.
We're all alone!
We have much work to do, uma.
There's no one on holy island.
We'll work, just the two of us.
We'll farm the land, catch fish
and build up our farm stock.
Aren't we just like the gods?
We'll be the founders of holy island.
Won't we, uma?
We'll found a new island.
Brother! I love you more
than anybody else.
More than anyone else.
To the west. They must be
headed for holy island.
Kame, how long will his motor last?
Not very long.
- How long?
- Five or six hours.
All right. Pretty soon, then.
Uma, drink this.
Why not? Do you feel ill?
Are you seasick?
Cheer up!
We still have a long way to go.
You need to drink.
Kame, water!
Tsuchimochi...
I've found it! I see a red sail!
Damn it!
Who are you?
Is it fumoto?
Kametaro, brother!
Uma! What's all this about?
Maybe they're bringing toriko?
Sacred wine! Drink it!
Kame...
It's hard, but you've got to drink,
it's the rules!
Put on your masks!
Hey, who are you?
Uma's sick!
Take off your masks!
I know who you are anyway!
Don't be silly!
I know the helmsman's fumoto.
Take off your mask!
Is toriko there? Kame!
Kametaro!
Uma, what's going on?
You tell them! Don't they know
what happened?
Uma! Tell them!
We didn't do anything!
Ryugen died of natural causes!
We are innocent!
Ask unari, if you think I'm lying!
Unari knows everything!
Kame! If you're there, tell them!
Are you there, kame?
Kametaro!
Paddles up!
- Punish him!
- Brother!
Brother!
Why do they...? Uma, come to me.
- He's my father!
- Kame!
Brother!
Brother! Brother, I loved you!
Let's head back. Row!
Put on your masks!
Take your paddles!
Five years later
- Hello, it's been a long time!
- Long time no see.
I hope you're well.
This is mrs higashi, and this is my wife.
- Mr fumoto, the factory manager.
- Blessings upon you.
Once upon a time
a long, long time ago
a brother and a sister
a god and a goddess
they founded an island together
this is the story
how the island began
this is their tale
a red sail on a sabani boat...
Cold Coca-Cola!
Ice-cold Coca-Cola!
Should we give him money?
- How much is appropriate?
- Ten yen is enough.
What's the song about?
It's hard to understand.
It's an old song about our island,
a traditional song.
This way, please.
One day, the sabani,
all on its own...
What's a sabani?
It's a canoe.
They have motors attached now.
Even now, on evenings
with a west wind,
you can see the red sail
of the sabani of the gods.
- Really?
- No, no, it's an old story.
Not something you'd see
in modern times.
But I've seen it
and so have other islanders.
Dear oh dear...
Why did you come back?
You suddenly disappeared.
I was worried.
Sorry I left the position
you recommended me for.
Why? Didn't you like Tokyo?
No, it wasn't that...
You had a reputation at the factory
as a hard worker, for five years.
I'm sorry.
I heard there was work here
on the anniversary of my father's
and sister's death.
It's better for you to be back home, right?
No, it's not.
It pains me more to be here.
But...
In Tokyo I didn't feel like myself.
I was in pieces...
I was troubled there.
I wanted to reflect
on what my father had done,
what I've done,
and what you did...
I was in a difficult position.
No, I'm not trying to blame you,
mr engineer.
Why did you leave toriko to her fate?
Why did I kill my own father?
Was it really for the sake of the island?
I want to think it over,
here on the island.
Mother, look at that unusual rock!
They say it's a girl who turned to rock
while waiting for her lover.
What a romantic story!
It's called "toriko rock".
It really happened not so long ago.
- Really?
- Sure!
Mr kariya knows all about toriko.
Do you, darling?
The islanders aren't particularly clever,
so they get their stories and reality
all mixed up.
It just shows
how simple and pure they are.
Kurage island is steeped in emotion.
Toriko?
I'm sorry.