PARTICIPANT IN
THE 1966 ART FESTIVAL
A DAIEI FILMS PRODUCTION
RED ANGEL
PLANNING BY IKUO KUBODERA
ORIGINAL STORY BY YORICHIKA ARIMA
SCREENPLAY BY RYOZO KASAHARA
CINEMATOGRAPHY
BY SETSUO KOBAYASHI
ART DIRECTION BY
TOMOO SHIMOGAWARA
MUSIC BY SEI IKENO
ASST. DIRECTION BY SHU SAKIYAMA
CAST:
AYAKO WAKAO
SHINSUKE ASHIDA, YUSUKE KAWAZU,
JOTARO SENBA, RANKO AKAGI
JUN OSANAI, DAIGO INOUE
TAKASHI NAKAMURA, KENICHI TANI
DAIHACHI KITA, KYOSUKE SHIHO
SHIN MINATSU, KEN NAKAHARA
YASUO ARAKI, KEIICHIRO YAMANE
MASAKI NANDO, IKUJI OKA
KILLED IN ACTION
APRIL, 1938
CHIZURU KO,
TAKAKO ONISHI
YAEKO NAKAGAWA,
REIKO KASAHARA
DIRECTED BY
YASUZO MASUMURA
My name is Sakura Nishi.
I left Japan for China in May, 1939,
as an army nurse.
I was assigned
to the Tientsin Army Hospital.
Nurse Taniguchi and you four, surgery.
Nurse Nishi and you three,
general medicine.
- Nishi.
- Yes.
Half of your patients are critical.
The rest are not.
They're mainly T.B.
and mentally ill patients.
- Some aren't sick at all, so be careful.
- Yes.
Many can fake a fever
by agitating the thermometer.
Mental patients who have recovered
pretend they're sick.
They prefer being here
to manning the front lines.
Seeing through their lies
is not my job.
As you'll be with them every day,
that responsibility lies with you.
Understand?
Outwardly, it's just like
a military hospital in Japan.
But in fact it's a field hospital.
- You're new here, aren't you?
- Yes.
Where was your last post?
After graduating, I spent three years
at the Tokyo Army Hospital.
Were you born in Tokyo?
Me too.
From Kiba, East Tokyo.
Kiba? Smart.
So, your family's in the lumber trade?
I think my grandfather was,
I don't remember.
How come?
My father died
a month before I was born.
My mother died when I was two.
An aunt raised me in West Tokyo.
- How old are you?
- I'm 24.
I'm Private Sakamoto.
Also from Tokyo, so be nice to me.
Tokyo, eh?
Damn it, I wish I was back there!
- Nishi, time to make your rounds.
- Yes.
ALL THE WORLD, UNDER ONE ROOF!
ADVANCE!
What are you doing?
- I'll scream!
- Who cares?
Let me go! Let me go!
There's no use fighting back.
Everyone's bored.
They'll enjoy the show.
I reported everything the next night.
I see...
Private Sakamoto again?
You're his third victim.
He isn't fully recovered,
but this can't go on.
Hello, Nurse.
I'm being sent back to the front line.
A death sentence.
Hey... congratulate me.
Thanks for everything.
Good luck.
I really enjoyed it.
Next time it's my turn.
Stuck here all day,
a man needs a woman.
My next posting, two months later,
was even worse.
Hell couldn't be much worse.
It was a front line hospital.
FIELD HOSPITAL
Move them over here!
Move them!
- Bullet wound.
- Bullet wound! Surgery!
- Dead.
- Dead!
- Surgery.
- Surgery!
Hey, bury this one!
- Amputation.
- Amputation!
For burial!
- Dead.
- Dead!
Put my foot back on!
- Forget it, son.
- Put it back!
- Amputation.
- Amputation!
Help me!
All right, son. We'll stop the pain.
- No saving him.
- Yes, sir.
Surge“!-
Help me! Please!
Hey, control yourself!
- Separate the dead.
- Yes, sir!
Amputation at the thigh.
- Anesthetic?
- Just local.
He's a kicker.
Hold him down, Nishi.
Idiot! Get back here!
Mother!
Alright, he's ready.
I'll sew him up.
Get me a bandage.
Two hundred operations
over three days and three nights.
Lieutenant Okabe, the surgeon,
as well as the medics and nurses,
all went without sleep.
Arm next. Hold him down.
More and more men
were brought in.
Many died waiting for surgery.
Some died during surgery.
Others died after the operation.
They all went to the morgue.
Hey, get their tags
or we won't know who's who.
There was a mountain of tags.
It was the end of the third day...
His pulse is strong.
He's lost too much blood.
We can't help him.
Nurse Nishi...
It's me... Sakamoto.
Nurse Nishi, save me, please.
I'm sorry about what happened.
I don't want to die.
I want to live!
I'm begging you. Please save me.
Don't leave me!
Nurse Nishi...
Please don't let me die!
Don't let me die!
- Doctor.
- What is it?
He needs a transfusion.
Anesthetic.
Only colonels and above
get blood transfusions.
I know this man. Please, Doctor.
How do you know him?
He was my patient in Tientsin
for a while.
He's not kin, or even a friend?
No, sir.
We're swamped.
These others have a better chance.
If you come to my quarters tonight, Nishi,
I'll do it for you.
Thank you, sir.
Just this once!
I didn't want him to die.
I didn't want him to think
that was my revenge...
that I'd deliberately kill him.
However, the transfusion didn't work.
By the end of the shift,
he was dead.
- Sakamoto! Sakamoto!
- What's up?
No pulse. His pupils are dilated.
He's been gut shot,
it kills them every time.
What a waste of precious blood.
We'll take him out.
Throw him on the pile.
One more dead!
- Who is it?
- Nurse Nishi.
- Come on.
- Excuse me.
So, you actually came?
- Were you joking?
- No, I meant it.
- Pour me some wine.
- Yes, sir.
The spoils of war.
Dr. Okabe...
The man we gave
the transfusion to has died.
That's no surprise.
It would've been a miracle.
I'm sorry I caused you trouble.
Nishi, don't play favorites
with the patients.
Soldiers aren't human beings.
They're objects... just weapons.
Then, why did you operate
if you knew he'd die?
Before I was drafted,
I was a specialist surgeon
at a large hospital.
But here I'm no doctor.
I have to decide who will live,
whether I can save them or not.
Sometimes I long to be a doctor again.
I knew he'd die,
but I did my best anyway.
The last vestiges of professional pride
made me go through the motions.
Hey, have a drink.
You'll sleep better.
Yes, sir, I will.
What can I do to save
those truckloads of soldiers?
Ruptured blood vessels,
smashed bones...
Blood loss or gangrene
gets most of them.
We've no blood
and hardly any medicine.
So I cut off their arms
and their legs.
Even those who don't need it.
They say that I'm an expert at it.
I've cut off hundreds of limbs.
I've crippled hundreds of men.
God knows how many.
But you had to try to save their lives.
You think those soldiers believe that?
They'd be better off dead.
What I'm doing is wicked.
I either let them die, or I cripple them.
That's all.
Am I a doctor?
It's a wonder I don't go mad.
The war's to blame. Not you.
The war?
As we attack,
our lines get longer.
The enemy turns around
and attacks our rear,
where our defenses are weak.
China's too big.
It's a stupid war.
But that's the Army's problem...
not mine.
Get undressed.
I can't get drunk in front of a nurse.
That's an order!
Yes, sir.
There's no tomorrow
on the battlefield.
We live from day to day.
What happens today, whatever we do,
it all fades away tomorrow.
You need not worry.
Now come here.
What's your first name, Nishi?
It's Sakura.
Sakura? As in "cherry blossom"?
Yes.
Just think, if you live long enough,
you'll become
a 60- or 70-year-old Sakura.
Cherry blossoms only last
a few brief days.
I love my name.
I'd like to live up to my name.
Who named you?
My father, who died
before I was born.
In photographs, he looks like you.
Enough drinking.
I need a shot now.
It's all in that drawer.
What kind of injection is it?
Never mind. Just do as I say.
Yes, sir.
It's morphine, sir.
Hurry up. It's almost dawn,
there's no time.
I just want to sleep,
sleep and forget everything.
Nishi, will you stay here
until I fall asleep?
Yes, sir.
Summer nights are cold here.
If you're cold,
you can share my blanket.
I was exhausted.
I just wanted to sleep.
Hey, next!
Are you awake?
It's noon.
You've slept for ten hours straight.
Get some more rest.
I have to go.
They'll manage without you.
I've told them that you're exhausted.
Doctor...
What?
Did anything happen?
You think I took advantage of you?
You undressed me.
I didn't touch you.
Not that it matters.
What does that mean?
You wouldn't understand.
I'll go back.
We nurses went back
to the hospital in Tientsin
in a truck with the sick and wounded.
By that time, I couldn't get
Dr. Okabe out of my mind.
Perhaps I'd begun
to fall in love with him.
TIENTSIN MILITARY HOSPITAL
So, how was the front line?
Do I smell strange?
What kind of smell?
The smell of blood.
I almost scrubbed my skin off, but...
You're imagining it.
That's how you become a real nurse.
Matron, what's Dr. Okabe really like?
He's a fine officer
and an excellent surgeon.
Nishi, I'm putting you in charge
of surgery this time.
Excuse me, Nurse,
can you help me urinate?
Just wait.
Why were both of your arms
amputated, Orihara?
The left one was blown off.
Gangrene set in on the right arm,
so the doctor cut it off.
Thank you.
Which doctor?
Dr. Okabe. He caught the tetanus
in time and saved my life.
How many months have you been here?
Six months.
My wounds have healed, but...
You can't return to fighting.
You'll be going home. Have you got a wife?
I shipped out two months
after we married.
You can't wait to go home, then?
Yeah...
But, for some reason, I can't.
I only bother the others here.
Home will be better.
Matron, Private Orihara's
almost fully recovered.
He hardly feels any pain.
Why hasn't he been sent home?
I wonder.
But that's not our problem.
We're short of beds as it is.
It'd be best for him, and for us,
if he's sent home.
Nishi, that's quite enough!
It's not a nurse's place
to make those kind of decisions.
Yes, ma'am.
It's just... I feel sorry for him.
Nurses do not have feelings.
It's your duty to keep quiet
and get on with your work.
I've given up.
- I don't think I'll ever go home.
- Ever?
Thanks.
Not that I think the war will last forever.
Why can't you go home?
A soldier who'd lost both legs
was finally sent back.
They kept him hidden
in a hospital in Hakone.
He wasn't even allowed
to see his family.
They'll probably keep him
institutionalized forever.
That's my fate, too.
But why?
If people at home saw me,
they'd realize how terrible war was
and hate it.
Some people would think
we were losing the war.
The Army brass
wouldn't like that at all.
Sometimes... I wish I was dead.
That's how I feel.
You poor man.
It must be agony.
I'm used to it now, though.
The one unbearable thing...
What is it?
It's...
No, never mind. It's nothing.
Let's wipe you down.
Nurse Nishi, would you mind
doing it at night for me?
Why? I can't show you
any special favors.
I don't want the others to see me.
Tonight, after Taps.
Can you wipe me down then?
Please?
Right, let's wipe you down.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Nurse Nishi...
Can you come every night
from now on?
If you want me to.
Please. I'd like you to.
All you nurses take care of our meals
and everything...
with never a frown.
It's our duty.
But there's one thing
that no one does for me.
Do you follow me?
Nurse Nishi, I'm a man, too...
I'm crippled, but I'm still healthy.
The others all manage somehow...
but I have no hands.
I'm helpless.
It's starting to drive me mad.
Do you understand me?
Yes, I learned about that
at nursing school.
Nurse Nishi, I'm asking you...
Please save me.
Please... touch my body.
I beg you.
Have you... asked this
of the other nurses?
No, ma'am,
I've never asked anyone before.
Only you, Nurse Nishi.
I see.
Nurse Nishi, I'm just a filthy man.
A hateful man.
But I'm going to die
without ever seeing my wife again.
Nurse Nishi... please help me.
Blood banks, medicine,
everything was scarce.
Poor Dr. Okabe could only
amputate patients' arms and legs.
However trivial, I decided
that I would try to ease his burden...
in my own way.
Nurse Nishi, am I asking too much?
Not at all.
Thank you.
You're the only one
who cared to save me.
You poor, unfortunate man.
Nurse Nishi...
Please let me kiss you.
Just once.
Miss Sakura.
I want to touch your body.
I don't mind, but...
Since I lost my hands,
my toes have become very sensitive.
I can feel with them
just like my hands.
So...
- So?
- Please.
Please let me put my foot
between your legs.
Please.
Alright.
I'm glad.
I feel happy.
Let Private Orihara
go out for a walk?
Yes, he can walk fine.
I think it will be good for him.
But all alone?
I'll escort him. Today's my day off.
I see. Alright, then.
We can't do much else for him.
Have him wear a coat
so his arms won't be too obvious.
Treat him to something nice to eat.
What is it?
Where are we going?
- Let's find a hotel.
- A hotel?
Just leave everything to me.
Come on.
Let's take a bath together.
A bath?
I'll wash you. Come on.
You can look at me
all you want to, Orihara.
You can do anything you like.
Tell me anything
you want me to do for you.
Why are you doing this for me?
No particular reason.
I have no arms, but I can do things
to make up for it.
But what we're doing
won't happen again.
- This is the last time.
- Yes.
Probably.
Remember it.
I'll never forget
what happened today.
I'm truly very happy-
Nishi, Private Orihara
has committed suicide.
How? He has no arms...
He jumped from the hospital roof.
He died instantly from a fractured skull.
He's been taken to the morgue.
I can't believe it.
This was found under his pillow.
He wrote it with a pencil
in his mouth, I guess.
It's addressed to you.
I haven't told anyone else.
"Miss Sakura, I'll never meet
anyone like you again.
"So, there's no point in living.
"Thank you.
"Farewell, Orihara."
Will you inform his family?
He'll be listed as killed in action,
and receive a promotion
to Private First Class.
I believe I killed him.
I tried to help him,
but I tortured him instead.
This does not concern you!
In war, it's everyone for themselves,
or there's no surviving it.
Forget about Private Orihara
as soon as you can.
There's too much to forget.
I can never forget.
Private Sakamoto
and then Private Orihara...
I killed them both.
A month later,
we five nurses were transferred
back to the front lines.
I'm back again.
Have you been keeping well, sir?
We meet again?
It seems like you and I are fated.
You've been promoted.
Congratulations, sir.
The more people we kill,
the more stars they give us.
It's a strange life.
Is there a major battle?
Yes, Chiang Kai-shek
and his allies made an attack.
Our army is stretched very thin.
They were cut to pieces.
The wounded are arriving in droves.
You have experience,
so I'll have you removing bullets.
Can we manage?
We have to!
A handful of Japanese soldiers
are pitted against all of China.
It's no easy war.
The number of wounded will increase
and we're badly undermanned here.
You'll have to work twice as hard, Nishi.
If not, good men will die.
Yes, sir. I will, sir!
The wounded are arriving, sir.
I'll be right there.
Water! Give me water!
Water!
Be careful!
Don't bring dead bodies in here!
- The bullet's still in there. Remove it.
- Yes, sir.
We began operating,
and did so for two days and two nights.
I, alone, removed 160 bullets.
Can't save him. He's cut to pieces.
He's lost too much blood.
Nishi, do you know
why the enemy did this?
No, sir.
He swallowed this.
It's a secret code.
A communications officer.
No time to burn it,
so he swallowed it.
They cut him open to get it.
While he was still alive?
Yes.
A fine soldier.
You did your duty well.
A hero's death.
He's dead.
Sew him up and ship him out.
Shrapnel in the lower back.
I'll have to operate.
Anesthetic.
I've changed my mind.
Close him up.
Next patient.
Why did he stop?
That was a waste of anesthetic.
There's something different
about him today.
By the third night, all of the soldiers
had been treated.
- Is that you, Nishi?
- Yes, sir.
- Come in.
Sit and have a drink.
May I ask you a question, sir?
What is it?
Why didn't you operate
after administering the anesthetic?
Officers don't need to explain
to lower ranks.
I'll explain, though you probably
won't understand.
Why is that, sir?
You're a woman, but you have
no marital experience.
What has marriage
got to do with it?
He was wounded in the sacrum.
Here.
All the sensitive nerves...
that govern sex are located there.
If I'd operated on those damaged nerves,
what would be the result?
He'd lose his masculinity. Forever!
It made me think.
If it doesn't fester,
he has a chance to live.
If a good doctor operates
back home,
he may leave the nerves intact.
That's why I changed my mind.
I see.
I have no confidence
in the work I'm doing here.
It's all wrong.
I kill those who'd recover.
And men, better off dead,
live as cripples.
However...
for men, becoming impotent
is worse than being crippled.
I'm tired.
Give me a morphine shot.
I want some sleep.
Nishi, stay until I fall asleep,
like you did last time.
Hold me, if you want to.
- If I'll do, sir.
- I wouldn't ask anyone else.
- Will you stay till morning?
- Yes, sir.
Don't worry, you'll be safe with me.
I won't even touch you.
Why not?
These days, I have no interest
in women at all.
We're in different worlds.
I only want to sleep.
But why, sir?
- You really want to know?
- Yes.
Very well, then. I'll tell you.
Since I started using morphine,
I'm not a man any more.
I haven't been for a long time.
You have a wife, don't you?
She died three years ago,
so it doesn't matter.
Please stop using morphine.
Why?
I want to be held in your arms.
What?
I think I love you.
I want you to touch me.
You love me?
What a strange girl.
You remind me of my late father.
- A substitute, am I?
- No! I really love you.
It's no good,
I can't give up the morphine.
Why not?
I'm a doctor...
but there's nothing I can do here.
Without the drugs, I can't go on living.
It's the same for the soldiers.
They kill and pass it off as patriotism
to help them forget the horrors of war.
There are so many things
that I'd like to forget.
Nishi, it's no use talking.
Just give me the shot.
Oh, sir...
Inject me then get into bed!
Yes.
Nishi...
I... really missed you.
Goodnight... Lieutenant Okabe.
You bastard... letting maggots hatch!
You swine!
What's the matter?
He removed a bandage
and let flies settle on the wound.
And now it's festered!
Why did you do that?
He was afraid of being sent back
to the front line with such a minor injury.
He's just trying to get sent home!
What if the infection gets worse
and you lose your leg?
Living as a cripple
is better than dying.
My wife gave birth after I shipped out.
I've never seen my son.
Nurse Nishi, Dr. Okabe wants
to see you immediately.
Nishi... I'm off to the front lines.
One doctor, two nurses
and three medics.
We leave tomorrow morning.
- Were you ordered to?
- That's right.
It's a tough battle.
There's only one doctor there.
He can't cope alone.
It's an emergency.
So, it's goodbye for a while, Nishi.
Doctor, please take me with you.
The front line's too dangerous.
You could be killed. Stay here.
No! I don't want to leave you, Doctor!
Why not?
Because I love you.
Love?
Do as you like, Nishi.
But don't expect us
to have a life together.
This is war.
We could die any day.
I wonder...
The only way to survive
is to regard everyone as a stranger.
So stay.
Matron said that as well.
But I refuse.
- It's an order.
- I refuse.
- You'd disobey an order?
- Yes.
A traitor to Japan.
Doctor, what I'm afraid of
more than anything...
is working apart from you,
and dying apart from you.
It'll be fine. I'll be back.
- Wait for me.
- No, please take me with you.
You're stubborn.
Who else, then?
Nurse Tsuruzaki.
She's new and inexperienced,
I'll take care of her.
We're even further from Japan.
That doesn't bother me.
We're nearer to death.
I don't care.
Are you ready to die?
The cherry blossom
has such a short life.
The sooner the better.
Halt!
- Is Surgeon Lieutenant Okabe present?
- Yes. What is it?
- I have your new orders, sir.
- Go ahead.
You are to stay with us
until further orders, sir.
Very well, we're in your hands.
It's extremely dangerous ahead,
so we'll escort you, sir.
Good man.
We've arrived, sir.
Excuse the men, ma'am.
It's the first time they've clapped eyes
on a Japanese nurse.
They're ecstatic.
Time to head back.
HEADQUARTERS
Lieutenant Ishida, in command
of this outpost, sir.
Please be seated.
Our headquarters are situated
fifty kilometers from here.
The enemy has commenced
a large-scale attack.
They've broken through our lines,
and we've been cut off.
I see. So that's why our journey
was cut short.
Yes, sir.
The enemy are better equipped
and outnumber us.
We're unable to break through.
- So we're surrounded?
- Yes, sir, and they've attacked twice.
A mobile squad helped fight them off.
And there's just one platoon here?
Yes, sir, equipped with four light
machine guns. That's all we have.
Any civilian Chinese?
A handful of children
and elderly civilians.
- Doctor...
- What is it?
One of the comfort woman
has diarrhea.
I suspect it could be cholera.
Please could you examine her, sir?
Attention!
No mistake. It's cholera, alright.
She's badly dehydrated.
Nishi, quarantine her
and give her warm water for 48 hours.
She may pull through.
How many comfort women are here?
Two more, sir.
They may have it, too,
so isolate them.
Disinfect this hut thoroughly.
- It's off limits to the men.
- Yes, sir.
Cholera? That's one more enemy
to deal with.
Is there nothing we can do?
No medicine beats cholera.
Just isolation and disinfection.
Ideally, you should raze the village
and withdraw all troops.
That's impossible.
This is a strategic point.
We've been ordered to hold it at any cost.
In any case, the cholera must be
contained, otherwise we all die.
Issue the men an acid gargle
before meals.
Sir, the soldiers want
the comfort women who aren't sick.
Here they are!
Back to your quarters!
That's not allowed.
They're in quarantine.
How about you, then?
A nurse would be much more fun.
What are you doing?
Nurses aren't prostitutes!
You're hungry, aren't you?
Hungry for a man?
I'll pleasure you.
You animal!
This is the front line.
We either kill men,
screw women or eat rations.
That's all!
We get what we can
while we're still alive!
You idiots!
You want to die of cholera?
Get out!
You doctors get your pick of the nurses.
We don't.
Twelve men and two comfort women
are infected now.
Plus seven dead.
How does it look?
There will be more.
The problem is that we've lost
half of our fighting strength.
If they attack, we'll be wiped out.
Sir, all of the remaining Chinese civilians
have slipped away.
Afraid of the cholera?
No doubt some spies
were amongst them.
Spies?
They must have introduced
the cholera virus.
They must have fed something to her.
That means... the enemy knows
our exact circumstances?
Yes. We can expect an attack any time.
You should contact HQ
and ask for reinforcements.
We can't, sir.
Our radio equipment is down.
Send a courier, then.
It would be certain death.
We're surrounded,
no one could break through alive.
We're expecting a truck
tomorrow morning.
We'll just have to wait it out.
What's the matter, sir?
Looks like I've caught it.
Sergeant, a signal!
That's bad. They'll attack tonight.
Nurse Nishi, the doctor's asking for you.
Go at once.
Take a break, nurse.
You've worked all night,
we'll take over.
- Nurse Tsuruzaki!
- Yes.
- Nishi?
- Yes, sir.
Enter.
Reporting for duty.
What's the latest count?
Four new cases, sir.
If I catch it, I'll pass it to you.
Same thing if you catch it.
Why did you summon me, sir?
It's time for my shot of morphine.
- I refuse.
- But I need it.
Nishi, that's an order!
Morphine is only for the most
critical of patients.
Nishi, I'm starting to suffer
from withdrawal symptoms.
Soon the fits will come.
I don't want the others
to see me half-crazed.
I beg you.
Bring me the morphine!
If you don't quit now, Doctor,
it will affect your brain and heart.
You'll die.
A man like me is better off dead.
It's also the drugs
that are keeping us apart.
Please give it up.
What would I gain?
You'd gain me.
You're a woman, Nishi.
Yes, a woman who loves you.
How do I quit?
Please do as I say...
as if I were a superior officer.
You're ordering me to quit?
I'll tie you up
and do what I have to do.
- Tie me up?
- Yes.
Well... we're caught
between cholera and the enemy.
This could be our last night.
Be my superior officer tonight.
Do what you must,
but don't let anyone in.
The Commander is down with cholera.
I shall take over the command.
An enemy attack is expected tonight.
Man your positions!
Just tonight...
They'll attack tonight.
Reinforcements arrive tomorrow.
We must not surrender the village!
Nishi...
- Nishi...
- Yes?
You had it tough.
I'm fine.
Untie me.
How long was I thrashing about?
Five hours.
Hey, two more have got it!
Please hold me in your arms.
Love me as a woman.
I can't.
I want to be a real woman,
not just a doll.
Make love to me.
I can't.
I'm not a man any more.
No... that's all in your mind.
Without the morphine, you can.
Nishi... touch me.
That's what I am.
You understand now?
- I can't love you.
- No, it's alright.
Hold me close,
as tight as you can.
It's no use, Nishi.
Don't give up. You can do it.
It's no good.
I'll never return to my old self.
No... you can.
Present time: 0100 hours.
Not long until dawn.
Hold out till then.
Their light weapons don't frighten me.
But if they bring in mortars,
we're all dead.
Nishi...
I can't believe it.
Nurse Nishi has won.
I'm myself again.
It's like a miracle.
Please say that you love your Sakura.
You want me to say
I love you?
I want you all to myself.
You already have me.
I want your heart, too.
Not in wartime, no.
There's only fleeting pleasure.
Not for me.
I don't want to be a passing fancy.
I want to be your true lover.
But I have no heart to offer you now.
Then I'll search for it.
It's 0200 hours.
Another three hours
and then we'll be safe.
The enemy likes to attack at dawn!
Stay alert!
- Sakura...
- Yes?
I love you.
Now I can say it truthfully.
I'll never let you go.
Tonight we reached
our greatest ecstasy.
Though by tomorrow,
we may be dead.
- You don't mind that?
- This is all that's important to me now.
Get me the wine.
It's my last bottle.
Let's drink a toast.
I didn't know that military women
were so sweet.
- Military women?
- I mean you nurses.
Put on my uniform.
Does it suit me?
You look wonderful.
You make a fine officer.
- Boots!
- Yes, sir.
Would they salute me
if I went out?
First, they'd laugh.
Sword and gun!
I'm afraid not.
Dr. Okabe, pour me some wine.
Yes, sir!
Here, Major Nishi.
- Sergeant!
- What is it?
The enemy!
I prefer being a woman.
Then let me give you
some pleasure.
I can hear your heart thumping.
It's the wine.
Nishi...
I wish we'd met in Japan
in peacetime.
Here comes the attack.
The enemy...
There's no escape.
- Will you die with me?
- Yes. By your side.
I've lived 40 years.
A long life, yet short too.
I guess this is the end.
I can die happy,
because I love you.
Your mark, Sakura?
I'll give you a mark, too.
Where?
The same place as yours.
Sakura... thanks to you,
I can die like a soldier.
You must not weep for me.
Enemy attack, sir!
Follow me!
You two stay here!
Keep your head down!
Hold your fire! It's still too dark!
Don't waste ammunition!
Wait till they're close!
- What's the situation?
- We're completely surrounded, sir.
They're using mortars to soften us up.
It's just before they attack.
It doesn't look good.
We still have an hour till dawn.
There's a slim chance.
Right!
Orderlies and nurses are soldiers, too!
You must take up arms!
Fire! Give them all you've got!
Hey, pull yourself together!
Protect your patients!
Here they come! Dig in!
Sir, the sergeant's dead!
Right, I'll take command.
Fight, Tsuruzaki!
Fire at least one shot before you die!
I'm scared!
- Come on!
- No!
- Come back!
- Stay here!
Tsuruzaki!
Grab her!
- She's gone mad!
- Following her would be suicide!
I have killed yet again.
She was my third victim.
Nogami! Nogami!
I was still alive.
Without a single scratch.
Anybody still alive?
Halt! Who goes there?
I'm an army nurse!
We're reinforcements!
We routed them! You're safe now!
Don't come any closer!
We have a cholera epidemic.
Cholera?
Send medical personnel immediately.
- Any other survivors?
- I don't know.
The cholera and the fighting
killed most of them.
Understood. Wait here!
Tsuruzaki... forgive me.
This is how I will end up, too.
All the bodies were stripped
of their clothing.
Weapons, clothing, boots...
The enemy took everything
that they could possibly use.
Doctor!
Lieutenant Okabe!
Doctor Okabe...
The End