A Cult Epics Release
You're strange.
That's your charm.
I'm Kenta.
Come see me tomorrow.
Sorry.
I've enjoyed myself as much as I can
for the last time.
Now I have to say goodbye.
Where are you off to?
To where women
aren't women.
SCHOOL OF THE HOLY BEAST
An abbey
is a mansion for women
who long for eternal virginity.
They try to live
with strict principles
to become brides
acceptable for God.
Sisters, we've just received
another stray sheep.
When a stray sheep
kneels down
in the light before God,
he will cause her
to suffer.
We haven't been forced
to choose our way as nuns.
Our own burning desire
for belief guided us here
through the gate of the abbey.
Now let me introduce
our new friend,
Miss Maya Takigawa.
Greet them.
How do you do?
I'm Maya Takigawa.
We make it the primary rule
to practice discipline.
The discipline comprises
73 chapters.
We are strict about...
adultery,
murder
and theft.
Can you promise you'll
follow these principles?
Yes.
If you break the rules,
you'll be punished.
I'll explain
about our garments.
The white means innocence,
the black, asceticism.
The asceticism
to follow the principles
is the only way
for us to attain the privilege
of the brides.
CHOIR NUNS
This room is for the choir nuns.
They're of a higher rank
than assistant nuns.
Don't forget to be polite.
How do you do?
ASSISTANT NUNS
Lord! Oh Lord!
Give me your strength.
Lord, beat me
with a whip.
Forgive me.
Lord...
Maya.
Surprised?
You'll get used to it.
Whenever we feel
we're tempted by sin,
we whip ourselves like that.
That's why we have whips.
Jesus Christ was born.
His mother, Mary...
was engaged to Joseph.
Jesus was immaculately conceived.
That's how He was brought
into this world.
Mary's husband, Joseph
was a good man.
Though he didn't want
to speak of it in public,
he was secretly planning
to get a divorce.
While he was considering this,
God appeared in his dreams.
"Joseph, son of David,
do not be afraid to accept
Mary as your wife. "
The baby was
immaculately conceived.
God said...
that His name
was to be Jesus.
"You need to accept Him
with His mother," God said.
Prophets had known
of this for a long time,
as God had told them of it.
And God said...
"Let the woman
deliver the baby peacefully. "
His name was
to be Emmanuel...
which means
"God is with us. "
Joseph woke up
from his dream
and accepted his wife
as God had willed.
But until the baby was born,
he would not know love.
"Do not commit adultery. "
"If you look at a woman
with desire,
you've already committed
adultery in your mind. "
The sin of adultery
is the heaviest
among the principles.
If you harbor the thought
you'll be stigmatized
as a dirty renegade.
We nuns should keep
our bodies and souls pure.
I have a question.
Go ahead.
What did Jesus say
to those who committed adultery?
They're no better than animals.
They live to be arrested
and killed.
They'll be punished
and ruined for their injustice.
Vice Abbess.
Sister Takigawa.
If our parents hadn't sinned,
we wouldn't have been born.
A surprising question.
Think of the Immaculate Conception.
Is it really possible?
Stop insulting Mother Mary.
She got pregnant
because she had a lover.
How dare you!
No use shouting.
If you don't have sex,
no baby will come out.
Mother Mary was a virgin.
You're insulting her.
What she said
was unforgivable.
Get rid of Sister Ishida.
We won't study
with assistant nuns.
- Expel them!
- Wait.
You can't judge all of us
by Sister Ishida alone.
We came here
because of our strong
religious faith.
What on earth brought
a person like her here?
We aren't any different.
An abbey
is a place for dropouts
from society.
You're probably
not even a virgin yourself.
How rude!
That's all for today.
We'll expel those
who make disgraceful remarks.
Good day.
You can't fall asleep, huh?
Let's have a drink.
I'm glad to have you here.
It's nice to have a girl
with a backbone.
It's funny to find someone
like you here in the abbey.
Pretentious women
irritate me.
I've always wanted to ridicule
the Vice Abbess in class.
Miss Ishida.
Even as a joke,
drinking whiskey at night
is just too much.
The abbey is more like a prison.
Your parents are
pious and respectable.
How can their daughter
be so vulgar?
My father owns bars
and night clubs.
My stepmother was either gonna
send me here or to a loony bin.
So I chose to come here.
You need
to learn perseverance.
Your parents want us
to reform you
here at St. Clore Abbey.
My parents must've
given you money or something.
By the way,
who told on me?
Don't talk that way,
Sister Ishida.
God knows everything.
Don't push alcohol
on somebody
who's training
to be a good nun.
I see. That new bitch.
Do we always
have to work so hard?
Not always. But it's usually
more or less like this.
They discriminate
against us
because we didn't make
any donations. It's unfair.
They give us such small meals.
My body can't go on like this.
They're so delicious
I feel like I could die.
It's been so long
since I enjoyed eating this much.
PERSECUTION ROOM
Now God is going
to punish you.
God gave us the whips.
Beat each other twenty times.
Go on!
Beat each other
until you bleed.
Kaoru.
What are you waiting for?
Beat the woman!
Okay, go ahead
and beat her.
The punishment was too harsh
for just stealing food.
How did they find out?
We were alone
in the storage room.
Strange...
Is there an informer?
That's right.
One of us is a spy.
You mean me?
No.
But since you came here,
they've been well-informed.
Janet...
You gave me
valuable information.
I'll recommend you
for membership in the choir.
Sister...
Somebody's there.
Sorry to interrupt you.
What are you doing here?
You'll be punished for this.
You two will be punished.
Or do they allow homosexual acts
between nuns here?
Don't be scared.
Nobody's shocked
by lesbians.
Why don't you forget
about spying and enjoy yourselves.
Don't tell anybody about us.
Who told you to act as a spy?
The Vice Abbess.
Well, well!
She wants us to be honest
and true while she spies.
I'll keep this to myself.
You must obey my orders
from now on.
Hurry!
It'd be terrible
if they saw us now.
"Michiko Shinohara"
"Christian name: Mary"
"Died of a heart attack. "
"Witnessed by Aya Ogasawara"
How are you?
Any better today?
Sorry for burdening you.
Not at all. It's my job.
You assistant nuns
have been busy
since I fell ill.
Don't worry. We can handle
the food. We're glad to do it.
Maya, who gave you this?
My mother.
You mean you're...
Michiko Shinohara's daughter.
Don't tell the abbess.
I came here
of my own free will.
Will you tell me
about my mother?
How did she die?
Where was my father?
I don't know.
She was a nice, kind woman.
You're spying again.
You get another
gold star.
Don't call me a spy again.
What?
Go back to the reformatory.
I can run away any time.
But not before I expose you.
Don't mess with me, kid!
Stop fighting.
You shameless girls!
What if people saw you now?
Mind our honor.
You can't hide the filth forever.
Shut up!
You'll be confined for three days.
Sister!
How are you?
This is for you,
from the field in the back.
Thank you.
How's father?
The doctor said he wouldn't
be able to work again.
I can't do anything for you,
for I'm already serving God.
But I'm always praying
for my family.
Each time I see you,
you've changed.
Have I?
It's as if you were talking
to a stranger.
I'll work as soon
as I leave school.
Mother wants you
to come back.
Father will die
if he isn't hospitalized.
She needs 100,000 yen
to cover everything.
All your praying
won't bring us money, will it?
Keiko, don't be unreasonable.
This is terrible!
What's wrong?
50,000 yen disappeared
from my drawer.
Are you sure?
One of the nuns stole it.
One of the assistant nuns
who cleaned the room.
Don't assume the worst.
Gather all the assistant nuns.
The money?
What's this?
How awful!
They're like beasts!
The criminal might be keeping it
under her garment.
"Criminal?"
Don't talk like a cop.
Let's strip to help
clear the suspicion.
Now investigate us thoroughly.
Strip, everybody!
Oh, no! How shameful!
Shall I take them off?
No. Keep them on.
Come on!
No thank you.
No use stripping.
The money won't be found.
What?
Whoever stole the money
wouldn't keep it in a place
that's so easy to find.
If she has a guilty conscience,
she'll confess.
Right?
Yes.
Vice Abbess.
We'd better stop investigating.
All right.
I'll take these pictures away.
I'll burn them, for sure.
Welcome, Father Kakinuma.
St. Clore Abbey
is well-disciplined.
Everything is managed smoothly.
This is an ideal abbey.
It's due entirely to your burning
religious faith.
Thank you.
I'll report to the headquarters
in Rome.
What's wrong?
Father.
You seem to be upset.
Tell me. I'll listen.
Father...
I stole the money
from the abbey.
I violated the disciplines.
My parents were against
my coming to this abbey.
My family is large.
We were living
from hand to mouth.
But I wanted to serve Jesus.
My father understood,
but he fell ill.
When I cleaned
the Vice Abbess' room,
I found the money.
I'd been thinking
of my father.
Before I knew it,
I had taken it.
Father, punish me.
I'm suffering.
I betrayed God
and I'm still
here in the abbey...
Only the innocent
can beat a sinful woman
with a rock.
Do you know these words
of Jesus?
He won't punish you.
Father... this money...
Pay fifty back.
Keep the rest
for your poor family.
Thank you.
Is your worry gone?
Yes.
Has your suffering disappeared
without any trace?
Yes.
Because God came to me,
to forgive me.
God never comes to you.
Never to you.
You make a confession,
and your guilty conscience
melts like snow.
God will never
come to you.
Did God ever come
to save men?
In the history of mankind?
Why not wait?
Why not wait for God,
who'll come to punish you?
Father!
Maybe God got you
ready for me
as a sacrifice!
Mother!
How filthy!
Oh, Jesus!
Why do men
do such filthy things?
Like dogs!
Tell me, buddy.
Will your girl really come?
Of course.
She wanted to see me.
Why did she have to go
to the abbey?
She was Influenced
by a movie.
Maybe.
Hi!
Is she your girl, Maya?
Yes. She's a nun.
- I'm surprised you got out.
- I have a fun idea.
Interested?
I'll do anything for you.
I'll disguise myself.
Hello.
The sex-hungry nun
is sleeping in here.
Give her pleasure.
I'll stand watch here.
All right.
Good.
Poor woman!
Wasting her womanhood!
I'll give her what she wants.
Me first.
No, me.
You're not hung.
How convenient!
Oh, God!
I'll take you.
This way you can
go to heaven quickly.
Who are you?
I'm a pure virgin for God.
Stop it!
Jesus!
Jesus.
Jesus Christ!
Let's switch!
I'm nearly exploding!
Forgive me!
Stop it!
More! More!
Mother Mary!
Amen.
My turn.
Where's the pussy cat?
Time's up. Get out
before they find you.
Come on! Hurry up!
Oh, no! How cruel!
Let's go.
Who are you? Wait!
This way.
Wait!
Maya, you've got guts.
I admire you.
You got men into an abbey
for women only.
She's my type!
You're flattering me.
Hurry!
Bye-bye! Hurry!
What are you doing?
Taking a walk.
Did you see the strangers?
No.
Let's go to the chapel
for prayer.
Excuse us.
Vice Abbess, what happened?
Did somebody
break into this room?
Control yourself!
Tell me what happened.
I resisted desperately.
But they forcibly...
"They?"
I kept my virginity for 32 years
and 4 months.
But the men...
they took me by force.
"Men?"
Men?!
Those suspicious nuns
were men.
Abbess.
Ryoko passed Maya
in the corridor.
She was with the strangers.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
It was dark,
but I saw their faces.
Bring Maya
to the Persecution Room.
We have to weed out
the Judas.
The 13th punishment!
Punishment!
Is she...
Sister Ishida!
You filthy hypocrites!
This is worse than prison.
Ishida.
She's a rebel
against the church.
She brought men
into the Garden of Angels.
"Angels?"
You're just a dyke.
Oh, no!
How could you call me that?
Abbess, it was me who
brought those men in here.
Is that true?
Yes. It's my confession.
You can count on it.
Punishment on Ishida!
Give her punishment!
Punishment!
Don't mess with me.
Hysterical bitches!
I'll handle this.
Why is sex wrong?
You look decent,
but you want to get laid.
Abbess, this is blasphemy.
Expel her.
She's like a gangster.
Maya, it's getting interesting.
Sister Ishida,
get out of this abbey.
All right. I don't care.
I'll go away, but...
don't bully Maya.
If you do, I'll have
your scandals publicized.
Remember that.
Dismissed!
Abbess!
Not enough evidence.
Sister Takigawa,
go back to your room.
Maya.
I'm going...
to the house of God.
I'll tell you the truth.
You must go to another abbey
as soon as possible.
I still remember that day.
I can't forget it,
even if I try to.
I was watching
from the shadows.
I watched a pure woman
who served God
change into a devil.
Michiko was going to be abbess,
but she violated the discipline.
The present abbess tortured her
when she was pregnant.
She looked like a demon.
It was December 25th,
Christmas Day.
When she hanged herself,
a baby was born.
I tied her rosary to the baby
as the mother's keepsake.
I took the baby to town.
It was you, Maya.
I don't know
who your father was.
That is all I know.
Maya, dear.
So it's you.
I won't forgive you.
But your mother
was to blame.
She violated the discipline
and had you.
I had to do it to protect the honor
of the abbey.
I don't want to hear
your excuses!
You must leave here today.
Go back to the time
when you only had
good thoughts of your parents.
You should return.
No kidding.
Who was my father?
- Tell me!
- I don't know.
Why not? You must know
everything that happened.
Maya, dear,
don't go any farther.
This is the realm of God.
"Realm of God?"
You should return now.
To where?
I came back to where
I was born.
I'll watch this rotten abbey fall.
I'll make it happen.
Why not expel
Maya Takigawa at once?
She knows too much.
Then arrange a ceremony
to offer her to God.
There should be
no "ceremony" for her.
Her mother
was Michiko Shinohara.
She's your daughter.
I'm scared.
Our sins of 18 years past
are standing before us
wearing a cloak
of hatred.
Past...
In the past,
you were extremely jealous
of Michiko.
You even hated her.
That's right.
We went to school together.
We were baptized
and came here together.
We were always
on the same path,
but she was always...
outshining me.
We were always compared...
I was always inferior to her.
I was miserable.
When I left
pregnant Michiko...
I fled to Rome, to school.
You dealt with her
after I went away.
That's how you earned
your present position.
It's true.
At last I defeated my rival.
With these
blood-soaked fingers...
Father...
I hated Michiko
because you loved her.
She was trying to live
out of love for you.
I was mad. Jealousy
made me cold and cruel.
I made love to you, too.
You did.
But I wonder
if you really loved me.
Love?
It's an illusion.
Then what have you
been living for?
God.
I'm waiting for God.
Even in the hell I lived through,
I waited for Him,
though he never came.
Father...
You still remember Nagasaki.
Even in Auschwitz,
He didn't come to save us.
Has He ever
shown Himself to men
who are begging for help?
Maya will never stop fighting
against you.
Hell has come.
For you betrayed God!
Hell.
Give a ceremony
to offer Maya to God.
What do you want?
I want to apologize to you.
I've been needlessly suffering
for 18 years.
I'll tell you about your father...
to atone for my sin.
But when you learn
the truth,
you'll fall in the hell of hatred.
- Hatred for my father?
- Yes.
Your father
is Father Kakinuma.
The priest?
Is that true?
Yes, it is true.
He also asked me
to dispose of your mother.
That's a lie!
It's true.
Look at the sea.
It hasn't changed.
This is where your mother...
met her lover.
She was desperately in love.
She forgot herself
in the transient gleam of love.
There's no going back for me.
I came to assist the abbess
of St. Clore Abbey.
My name is Nataly Green.
Any act of violation
of the discipline won't be missed.
I can smell the foul odor
of witches,
servants of the devil.
I'll catch the witches.
I'll expose them.
Don't give orders
on your own.
What can you do?
I know this abbey
like the back of my hand.
I'm in charge here.
Father Kakinuma
would disagree.
He sent me here.
Follow my instructions
from now on.
Hisako!
You're pregnant!
Who's your man?
Tell us who.
It's not an immaculate
conception.
Who were you with?
Confess!
Stop it!
Father Kakinuma.
It's his child.
What a horrible thing!
Frightful!
Unbelievable!
You're accusing him
to hide your disgrace.
What do you think, nuns?
Unforgivable!
How can she blame that strict, benevolent
priest?
It's true. It's true!
Liar! Witch!
I'll test your Christian faith.
Get salt water.
Drink all of it.
If you're true to God,
you'll never be able
to stain Jesus.
It's a method used in the Edo Era
to find secret Christians.
That's right.
If she wets the image,
she's a real witch.
How long
will we be confined?
Hisako hasn't returned.
They're still punishing her.
Attend the witch trial
or you'll be considered rebels.
It's the best way
to persecute the witch.
Janet. Onozuka.
Watanabe. Nakagami.
What are you waiting for?
Get moving!
Takigawa.
I will not go.
What?
You admit to being a heretic?
How long can you
have your way?
All right.
Come to the Persecution Room.
This woman is a witch.
Where's the priest?
He's coming.
Will you expel Hisako?
You care about her?
No wonder.
Her fate is the same
as your mother's.
Your father
made Hisako pregnant.
You're the fatal child
with cursed blood...
the doomed offspring
of the priest,
your mother and myself.
Hisako!
The rebel
has exposed herself.
Bless those who hate you.
Pray for those
who speak ill of you.
If any one strikes you
on the right cheek,
turn to him the other also.
From anyone
who takes away your coat,
do not withhold
even your shirt.
Do unto to others
as you would have them
do unto you.
Do not judge others.
Do not punish them.
Forgive them.
Bless them.
The witch will die tonight.
Thank me for picking
the night of Christmas.
This poison
will take you to hell.
It's your last supper.
When you reach hell,
I'll be in the arms
of Father Kakinuma.
Who are you?
Michiko Shinohara's daughter.
Your daughter.
You don't know me,
but I've been cherishing you
in my heart for 18 years...
not knowing
you were a beast.
You slept with your daughter.
You violated the discipline
in the most dreadful way.
Have a nice Christmas night.
Oh, God!
My God!
God is you!
You're God!
I don't know...
but on this night
18 years ago,
my mother died in agony
in this abbey.
You should suffer
for the rest of your life.
This is my
Christmas present for you.
God! I can see you now.
Your horrible figure...
God! You at last...
The End
Ripped by:
SkyFury