KOKUEI COMPANY PRESENTS
Father, are you going to
take a rest now?
Yes, as usual.
I see.
How is everyone doing today?
Yes, as usual.
I see.
Were there any problems?
No, nothing at all.
- That's good, then.
- Indeed.
There is no problem
whatsoever.
whatsoever...
There will never be any
problem with this, right?
Yeah...
There is no problem
whatsoever.
Everything seems to be going
according to the plan.
There will be no problem.
There is no problem
whatsoever.
Mother, you have lived
long enough.
Hurry up... kill me!
Mother!
You can die now,
and my brothers will continue
to live in agony.
I beg you... hurry up!
Quick, kill... kill me!
Thank you.
I won’t die.
I cannot die!
Mother, were you happy?
I won't die...
There is no problem
whatsoever.
SEX FAMILY
The Makers
Izuru Deguchi
Hideo Ito
Tamaki Katori
Miki Hayashi
Yoko Muto
Junko Miyashita
Joji Ichimura
Hiroshi Yajima
Takeshi Shima
Hiroshi Imaizumi
Koji Wakamatsu
Sakae.
Everything.
The whole world.
On the other hand, my mother died
because she couldn't stand my father.
Etsu!
Then, my older brother.
Me.
And my younger brother.
Then, there was his mistress.
Her daughters, Akiko,
Natsuko,
Haruko.
The three of them!
All of them are my
father’s women!
He made his mistress’ three
daughters his mistresses also.
His way of dominating the world
is simple and forceful.
On the surface, he has fame
and status...
as the Commander-in-Chief, but,
in reality, he is
the boss of a monkey family.
All males and females have
to obey him.
My older brother and I...
shared our father's women
and enjoyed sex in the house.
My mother lost her mind
and died.
I did nothing.
My mother died because
I did absolutely anything.
I killed my mother!
The one who made mother
kill herself... was me!
Go away!
How dare you?
Why did you tell me that you would
die if I didn’t come?
Why did you tell me you
killed your mother?
If you were that sad, why didn't
you attend her funeral?
At the funeral,
you should have told everyone
about our father,
that your mother committed suicide,
and that our father was the reason!
Shut up, you mistress’ child!
That's right.
I am indeed a mistress’ child,
but I attended the funeral on
behalf of the real wife's oldest son,
and even came here for you because
you told me that you would die.
I see, sister...
no, Akiko.
Let's run away!
Run away?
Why did my mother die?
My older brother and I...
No, you are also a member of
the prestigious Sakae family,
but, in reality, you are nothing
but father's puppet.
If we don't do anything,
we will continue to rot like this.
We will all continue to
be his puppets.
You will become our father's
and my older brother's toy!
Idiot!
Yes, I am an idiot.
But that's because I love
you so much!
Stop it!
I won't stop anymore.
I don't care you are my father's
mistress or my older brother's wife.
I fell in love with you
at first sight.
I have been waiting for
this very moment.
Stop it!
This is not what you told me!
Let's leave the house.
It's not just running away
from our father.
Let's become independent,
and prove that we can have
our own self-reliant lives.
Let's start over.
Let's change everything!
That kind of...
That kind of dream...
- I don't have it anymore.
- This is not a dream!
It is our own life.
Stop!
I can't do that anymore.
Why?
Why can't you do it?
Stop it.
We shouldn't...
We shouldn't!
We can't! We can't!
I didn't have any dream.
I didn't know why I did
all those things.
At any rate, I was hopeless
at that time.
That was my youth.
I didn't really love anyone.
I lived an agonizing life
without any dreams.
At any rate,
I visited him because I thought he
could find a solution for me.
Have your mother and
sisters been fine?
Give this to your mother.
You are now a university student.
Focus on your studies.
You see...
I am not really a university
student.
I am a mistress’ daughter!
And today...
I am going to quit being one!
Akiko!
What are you...?
When I saw his face,
I...
I couldn't lie to myself that I
was not a mistress’ daughter.
What do you think you can do?
Either I became a mistress’
daughter fully,
or I'd quit being one as an
independent woman.
If you hate being a
mistress’ daughter...
the only solution would be
to become a mistress yourself.
You will become my
mistress today.
I... will not!
Somehow, I didn't show
any resistance.
No...
Even if I had resisted,
I would have been just too
weak to do that...
since I was only a girl.
When I realized that,
I decided to become a
mistress,
rather than a mistress’
daughter.
Don't cry.
I am not crying.
Stop! Do you plan to make
me a mistress too?
What are you staring at?
That's right.
Our father sold me to your
older brother already.
Okay, let's end this.
No!
You know that's not possible!
Why are you here?
I am asking why you are here.
Mother committed suicide.
Mother... was killed by you!
Is that so?
Of course!
Well, perhaps you're right.
I might have killed her.
She might have killed herself.
I don’t think about people
once they’re dead.
She ran away from me, anyway.
So, I decided to forget about her.
That's false!
This is your usual,
fake way of doing things.
You are avoiding the truth.
Stop being deceitful!
Is there something wrong?
During the funeral,
I slept with a man today.
It was Koji, wasn’t he?
That’s right.
You are good at guessing.
I would happily sleep with him.
I felt I was almost being,
raped, though.
He tackled me suddenly.
It was such a crazy situation.
You see,
I have never seen him that angry.
I am serious!
His eyes were completely red.
He almost sucked my nose.
I'm not laughing of that.
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
No, it's not that.
I just have been thinking
about everyone recently.
Everyone living in this house.
I think you are attracted to Koji.
Why don’t you go have fun
with Koji tonight?
In other words, considering the
male and female combinations,
father and Haruko will
become a couple as usual,
even more openly than before.
According to the current custom,
the order is from the top
going down.
Therefore, Natsuko and Shozo
will soon become a couple.
In summary, I can be alone...
and finally leave this house.
It's been a while since you
visited my room.
Didn't you come here to do me?
I guess...
I'm fine with that.
I guess your medicine dose
has increased.
A little.
Do you want to leave this
house with me?
Let's see...
I am being serious.
I am fed up of everything here.
I know, me too.
But it's been five years since
I got stuck in this room.
I think it's time for you to get
some fresh air outside.
Fresh air...
The blue sky...
The blue ocean...
A white sand beach...
That's good!
It's fine, isn't it?
What do you think?
Let’s leave now.
No matter how hot the sun is,
staying here is not much different.
And I bet the wind outside
will be cold.
I am going back to
my workplace.
Come, let's go together.
Come, let's go back!
Everyone is waiting for us.
I have to do something
before that.
My father made them release me
on the same day.
Our comrades might think
I am a spy!
I will tell you about it later!
It must have been hard, Natsuko.
Father, you pulled a dirty trick.
I am different from my sisters!
Father, let’s make it clear.
I don't want to become a
mistress like my sisters.
You cannot control me
with your power!
This is exactly the mistress’
life I imagined.
How dare you live like this,
sister?
This is not different from
being a pig!
You might think you can dominate
everything in this world.
It's nothing but a bourgeois’
vanity!
I will pay you back everything later.
I don't want to see your face again.
Farewell!
When are you going to
pay me back, then?
Why don't you pay me
back now?
In other words, you will never be
able to pay me back.
So, do you want me to become
your mistress too?
Well, I wonder about that?
Say it clearly!
I don't know what you mean
by the word “mistress".
Considering that you are
my daughter,
being taken care of by me,
you should become one.
I understand.
Then, take as much as you
have provided until now!
It's not a big deal for me!
I am only throwing away this
19-year-old body and life.
I will use my life for more
precious goals later.
Father.
I am afraid to say I'm
not a virgin anymore.
You stay here.
The one who dominates and
the one who is dominated.
This world consists of
the two of them.
I...
I don't just own the
things I dominate.
I don't just love the things
I dominate.
You all exist because I am here.
You, the ones who are dominated,
exist before me, the one who dominates.
Take up, the starved people!
Now, the day will be soon!
Wake up, my comrades!
The sun has already risen!
In the day we can off the
tyrannical chains,
The Red Flag burns with our bloods!
We're distantly separated by the seas,
But let's go together joining hands!
Let's battle with...
I wonder if I despise myself?
That's what I live for.
I am a dying woman.
A dying woman cannot be revived.
Nobody wants a impotent woman
digging her own grave.
But...
I wonder how death...
feels like?
Damn it!
I won't be a block of a sex
pyramid forever!
Those people...
I absolutely won't do it with them!
Shit...
I'm in pain!
Pain...
Good morning!
Have a good day.
At the prosecutor’s office,
they were joking that you
were planning a coup, father.
Indeed.
Well, that kind of rumor circulates...
because of that incident
and the low volume
of criminal cases at hand.
Indeed.
There is no smoke without fire.
I am actually considering it.
Huh?
You can't possibly be a
virgin, right?
Do you have sex with our
father every night?
It's natural because the two of you
share the same blood.
You are going to become
a pig soon too.
Do you like our father?
Since I was born, I was raised
to become a mistress.
I am destined to be our
father's mistress.
Nice to meet you.
My father is persistent!
Okay.
Let's go.
That's good.
Alright.
That's nice.
Good.
That's it.
Alright.
Sit like that.
Good.
Relax now. Good.
Okay.
Well...
Look to the left.
This way.
Good.
Brother!
Now, smile.
- Do you take this kind of photos?
- I do.
I need them for gynecological
reasons.
Spread your legs please.
That's it.
Keep smiling.
Good.
Brother, our mother didn't
commit suicide.
I killed her.
Huh?
What did you just say?
I killed our mother.
What?!
I saw her suffering in the middle
of an attempted suicide.
So, I thought she had
chosen to kill herself,
that she was happier dying,
rather than living like she did.
So, I helped her.
That's enough!
If you are here to talk nonsense,
leave already.
And be sure to get some sleep.
Your eyes are red.
That idiot makes me sick.
I am serious.
I strangled her with my own hands.
And then?
Our mother was having a nightmare.
And she got naked while she
was suffering.
Then, I...
You raped and killed her, right?
Yes...
That's matricide and I am going
to get capital punishment, right?
Brother, can you prosecute me?
Get me arrested and
prosecuted right now!
Since our mother died,
you've been behaving
a bit strangely.
I will think about it.
Wait at home for now.
Yes!
I can't believe this.
Was he really serious just now?
First, this kind of thing couldn't
have happened in our house.
Second, there is no motive
for a murder at all.
Impossible!
Such a thing would
be ridiculous!
Nobody believes that I did it.
I wonder if I was wrong?
I shouldn't have killed mother,
but those pigs instead!
Are you pregnant?
I see.
Our father's or my brother's?
Whose child is it?
Your brother's...
You are nothing but a
useless baby pig.
Is she dead?
You pig!
Who is it?
What do you want?
I didn't know you were
a good man.
If you are here to sleep with me,
then you are wrong.
I am different from my
father and brothers.
Is that so?
That's unfortunate.
I thought you wanted a
woman too.
- Why are you here?
- For nothing.
Actually, I want to talk.
You see, your mother did
not commit suicide.
In fact, the one who killed
your mother was...
It was me.
It was me!
It's the truth.
I gave Natsuko sleeping
pills to your mother...
because she said she
couldn’t sleep well.
So, I made her die that way.
She took 40 pills, and it was
an attempted suicide.
She took 50 pills in total.
And it was me who made her
take the remaining 10 pills.
- That was what killed her.
- No way!
I'm pretty convinced that mother
was happier dying...
rather than being treated
as a dirty mistress.
Your mother was dirty too.
She wasn't!
She was different from you!
What are you talking about?
All of the women have been
raped by our father.
Our behaviors and thoughts...
Your father controlled everyone!
Shut up, you whore!
Yes, I am a whore!
Shit!
You have lost your mind.
You didn't have any reason
to kill my sisters.
I did, I sure did!
Women cannot understand it.
Hey, Haruko!
Yes, there is no problem
whatsoever.
I don't want to tell anyone,
including the police, about this.
My sisters’ deaths don't
even make me feel sad.
I am totally fine,
because I am able to
live my own life.
I am different from you.
I will continue to stick to father.
Father...
What happened?
Was there any problem?
There is no problem
whatsoever.
Nothing at all.
Katana.
The katana isn't here!
No, there is no problem,
as usual.
Silence! There is!
Damn you!
- You took it.
- Father.
Do you really need this?
No, it's fine...
You see,
I borrowed this...
to kill my sisters.
Father, I...
I was wrong, after all.
I have killed my mother
and sisters now.
I was wrong, after all!
Anyone can be wrong.
There are various ways
to correct yourself.
But what you need right now...
is to know how I'll absolve
your mistake.
You're wrong, father!
I am not talking about that.
I am here to...
And I believe I have been
right all along.
I am not talking about that!
I came here.
Here, here!
I came to sit here!
You...
Shit!
I...
I didn't come to just sit here!
How dare you judge me?
Are you that scared of
a murderer?
You, my brothers...
all of you want to sit here,
don’t you?
But you just couldn't
defeat our father.
However...
the one who is sitting here
right now is me!
I am sitting here!
THE END