Get back there, please.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Sergeant.
Morning, Superintendent.
Morning.
Inspector Learoyd's here.
Thank you.
Who is she, Phil?
Hello, Bob, no idea.
Bloodstained handkerchief in her pocket,
letter S in the corner.
You won't like this, Hazard.
She's very young.
Half a dozen knife
wounds, around the heart.
She died instantly.
What sort of knife?
Any sort, as long as
it was sharp, pointed.
No sign.
Who found her?
A couple of kids.
No blood on the ground or
any signs of a struggle.
Must've been killed somewhere
else, and dumped here.
How long's she been dead?
Between five and
eight, yesterday evening,
at the nearest I can put it.
Missing persons
have nothing to report, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Ground's pretty hard.
We've searched the area,
sir, but found nothing.
Nothing but the handkerchief, huh?
No, nothing.
Well, send her clothes back
along to the station, will you?
- Yes, sir.
- Come on, Phil.
Nice, simple things.
Are they?
Don't quite go together, do they?
These do.
There'll be some
hysterical, frightened boy.
I don't think so.
In my experience, an hysterical,
frightened boy stabs once,
well, twice maybe, and then runs.
But this monkey went on and
on, 'til he was exhausted.
No, this girl was killed
in hate, not fear.
I should say she was a student.
Now, she's in the habit of
going away for the weekend,
she may not be missed until tomorrow.
Get a list of every college
and academy in London,
see if a girl doesn't
turn up in the morning.
Particularly, any girl,
whose name begins with S.
Patsy?
David!
Where's Sapphire?
Isn't she in Birmingham,
with her brother?
I don't know.
She was going, and then
she changed her mind.
I don't know what she did.
Well, if you're worried,
why don't you phone him?
No, I don't want to
speak to her brother.
She caught the morning train, I expect.
Don't worry, Sapphire will
be in Foscari's for coffee.
See you then.
Hi, David.
Hi.
Congratulations on your scholarship.
When are you off to Rome?
Next month.
Lucky devil.
David!
David?
Mr. Harris?
We won't keep you very long.
I'm sorry, but we think
you may be able to help us.
Thank you, miss.
Hey, what's the matter with you?
Patsy!
What is it?
That murdered girl in Hampstead Heath...
It's Sapphire.
Sapphire?
Hey, Emma, coffee, quick!
How ghastly.
The police kept asking
me questions about her.
Who her friends were, I said us.
Well, of course!
We were all her friends!
What else did they ask you?
All about David.
The scholarship and everything.
If she'd had any boyfriends before him.
Oh, I couldn't tell them.
I've only known her, since I took
her to stay with me, at my digs.
Where was she living before that?
Her dump in Earl's Court.
Landlady turned her out.
But why?
Sapphire was such a sweetie.
Who'd do such a thing to Sapphire?
I don't.
You say her name was Sapphire Robbins?
I'd like you to come down to
my office, ask a few questions.
Do you think you feel up to it?
We'll send you home in
a police car afterwards.
We were going to get married.
I'm sorry.
You say the last time you
saw her was on Friday night?
Yes.
Do you know what she did on Saturday?
Well, she came to my house,
apparently, just after lunch.
You weren't in?
No, I went to Cambridge to sketch.
I'm a student architect
at the Polytechnic.
What train did you catch?
I hitchhiked, both ways.
What time you'd get home?
About 11.
Who gave you a lift from Cambridge?
A chap in a black Consul,
dropped me at the post office.
What time was that?
About quarter to 11.
You wouldn't remember the
number of the car, I suppose?
No.
Somebody ought to tell Sapphire's brother.
We contacted Dr. Robbins in Birmingham.
He's on his way to London now.
Oh.
Did you and Sapphire have
a quarrel on Friday night?
No.
Thank you.
Sergeant, drive Mr. Harris home, will you?
Very good, sir.
You'll let me know if you
find out anything, won't you?
You're going to be informed, Mr. Harris.
Oh, Mr. Harris?
What time did you say you
got back from Cambridge?
About 11.
Thank you.
The truth, you think?
Well, not what I'd
describe as the whole truth.
I don't believe he came
in when he said he did,
but his grief seemed genuine enough.
You never know with these monkeys.
Knock their heads off, when it suits them.
Ring up the Yard, and
get them to ask the BBC
to broadcast for the driver
of that black Consul.
Fine.
Meanwhile, I'll dig
through that girl's room,
before her brother gets here.
Has she'd been with you long?
About six months.
Hmm.
Not really tidy.
Sapphire wasn't
naturally an orderly child.
She did her best.
Did you like her?
Indeed, I did.
I felt sorry for her.
Her parents were dead, and she wanted
so much to be counted in, to belong.
Did you ever meet her brother?
No, but I spoke to him on the telephone.
Sounded very nice.
This one's locked.
I'm sorry, I haven't the key.
Oh, I wish you wouldn't.
I never saw Sapphire
wear anything like that!
Hmm.
I wonder who she was dancing with.
Did she play the gramophone often?
All the time, very softly.
She was a student at the
Royal Academy of Music.
Mm, well, thank you, Mrs. Thompson.
You've been most helpful.
Evidently, there was a side
to Sapphire she didn't know about.
Yeah.
Maybe young Harris found the
same thing, and didn't like it.
Could be.
Unless the person she was dancing with,
found out about young Harris.
Jealousy's very near to hate.
Oh, Mrs. Farr?
Mrs. Farr, your brother's here.
David, what's the matter?
Millie, I've got to speak to you.
The girl's brother's
here, sir, Dr. Robbins.
Right, send him in.
Sir.
Dr. Robbins, sir.
Why it's very good of you
to come so quickly, sir.
How do you do?
Please sit down.
Thank you.
I suppose there's no
doubt, it is Sapphire?
No doubt at all, I'm afraid.
I know this must be painful for you,
but there are some
questions I have to ask you.
Of course.
No thank you.
I understand you
expected your sister for the weekend.
Yes, I did.
Weren't you worried, when
she didn't turn up on Saturday?
No, no, she rang me, said something
unexpected had stopped her.
With Sapphire, something
unexpected was always happening.
How did she sound?
Excited, I thought.
What sort of a girl was your sister?
Happy, lively, exactly as she looked.
No, no.
That's not quite true, is it?
Are you, were you
Sapphire's half brother?
No.
Our father was a doctor, white,
our mother, singer, black as iron.
You never know which way it's gonna go.
Since Sapphire came to London,
she learned to pass for white.
Did David Harris know that
your sister was colored?
I don't know.
I knew little of Sapphire's life up here.
She seemed happy, I didn't pry further.
My sister was 21, you know.
Why did you let her come to London?
She wanted to come.
I didn't see why she shouldn't
have the same chance,
as any other youngster.
I'm a bachelor, I could
afford to stake her.
Did she ever talk
about anyone else, besides young Harris?
I can't remember.
I hardly listened,
Sapphire chatted so much.
It's unbelievable.
I can see her now.
Sitting on the table
in my consulting room,
swinging her legs, laughing,
twittering like a bird.
Patients waiting, but on she went.
I could've slapped her sometimes.
Who would do such a thing?
Who would do it?
I'd like to see my sister.
I'll take you.
No, I'd rather go alone.
The New End Hospital, Hampstead.
Thank you.
About that girl we --
Oh, this is Dr. Robbins.
Detective Inspector Learoyd.
How do you do?
Hello.
You can get me at the Dorsett
Hotel, they take us there.
Thank you.
So...
That's the brother.
Yes.
I think I was right.
Hate killed Sapphire.
I think she died because she was colored.
She was also pregnant.
Three months, the autopsy's just in.
Young Harris, of course.
Well, I don't know.
We can't be sure now, can we?
I mean, might be anybody.
Dad, I've been trailing
everywhere after you.
What's the matter?
Girl on Hampstead Heath.
It was Sapphire.
Sapphire?
Yes, David's
had to go and identify her.
David?
I'm so frightened, Dad.
Don't worry, girl.
Where's David now?
He's gone home.
You didn't tell us you were
the father of Sapphire's child.
You didn't ask me.
Were you on the other side of that?
No.
It's the police, Ted.
They're in there with David now.
Don't worry, dear.
It's only routine.
Where do you think you're going to?
Up to my room, Dad.
I told him he could, and I want him to.
Show him, Millie?
I'm David's father.
Superintendent Hazard.
What's been said?
They know about the baby, Dad.
Well, what of it?
We knew.
She came here to tell us
Saturday, just after lunch.
My boy was going to marry her.
I gave her my word he would.
They want to know what time
I got in on Saturday night, dad.
About 11.
Did you talk to anyone in Cambridge?
Anyone might remember you?
Where did you eat?
I took sandwiches.
He always does.
We can't afford meals in cafes, you know?
Finished, Inspector?
Yes, thank you Mrs. Farr.
He went through David's
room with a magnifying glass.
I don't care if they take the
boards up, David's got nothing to hide.
Do you think they'll be gone,
by the time the twins get back?
They'll hear it at school, Millie.
You can't keep it from them.
You've got to make up your mind to that.
Excuse me.
Superintendent Hazard would like
to see you for a moment, Mrs. Farr.
Mrs. Farr, what time did you finish
work at the dairy, on Saturday?
About half six.
A little late, surely.
My assistant was away all last week,
I had the tidying up to do.
I see.
Did you come straight home?
This is your home?
For the moment.
My husband's away at sea.
Who was in the house, when you got here?
Nobody.
I was at the club, my wife was
at her sister's with the twins.
Twins?
My children.
Oh.
The girl, Sapphire, had
gone, when you got in?
Yes, she wasn't here.
How did she seem when you
saw her, earlier in the day?
Same as usual, full of life.
Did you know that she was colored?
We knew.
How long?
That's enough, isn't it?
I see.
I understand you've just won a scholarship
that takes you abroad.
Of course, you won't leave 'til
all this is settled, will you?
Don't worry, he'll be staying here.
Alright, Dad, I can answer for myself.
Is that all Superintendent?
There are the children.
I must get their tea.
Why, of course, Mrs. Farr.
Superintendent?
Hadn't you better advertise for the fella
that drove Davy back from Cambridge?
I don't want any slime
sticking to my son, you know?
We have that in hand, Mr. Harris.
You say this man dropped
you at the post office.
Did anyone see you at that
time of night on Saturday?
I don't know.
Yes, yes, Jack Ferris.
He saw me, Dad.
Local constable.
You wouldn't call him a liar, I suppose?
If Johnny Turnbul trot on
your feet, he didn't mean to.
Little boys are clumsy dancers.
Wasn't your feet he trot on.
Oh, mommy, he's always bumbling.
I hate dancing classes.
Last week, you loved them.
Hello.
Good day, Mrs. Farr.
Good day.
Thank you.
There's angel cake for tea.
Ooh, good.
They knew she was colored then?
Yes, but the point is when?
That's a very important point.
Find anything upstairs?
No, nothing.
All his clothes were clean and put away.
Mm.
Pretty rocky alibi, of young Harris's.
Familiar motive, too.
It's all too pat for my liking.
You know, if he'd married that girl,
he probably couldn't have
taken up that scholarship.
He wouldn't carry a grant for a wife.
Hmm.
Well, are we gonna have a word
with this local constable?
What's his name, Ferris?
Yes, right away.
Yes, sir.
I did see young Harris walking
home, on Saturday night.
What time was that?
Oh, it's near 11, is
makes no difference.
And he was coming from the post office.
From that direction, sir.
What sort of people are the Harris's?
Oh, very respectable, sir.
Cut above the average.
Mrs. Harris was a school teacher.
How long had they known
the girl was colored?
What?
Yes, she was you know?
Ooh, I shouldn't have thought
they knew that at all, sir.
He's very bigoted, Ted Harris.
And very ambitious for his son.
Oh, very.
Ted Harris has skimped
himself, to do for Davy.
Mind you, the boy's repaid it all,
with that scholarship he's won.
And the daughter?
Oh, Millie's her father, all over again.
Dancing classes for the twins, elocution.
Must have that bit extra.
Her husband's a sailor?
Merchant Navy, bit of a laddo, Sid Farr.
Doesn't seem to get much
leave, or doesn't want it.
Can you find out if Harris
used his van on Saturday night?
I'll do my best, sir.
He only saw him coming from the
direction of the post office.
That's no alibi, you know?
The boy looks truthful to me.
What's the track width of
Harris's van, would you say?
I don't know.
Four foot, four foot, six?
Hmm.
I think I'll go back to the
Heath, and take a look around.
Four foot, six inches, sir.
Yes.
Yes, it's more than possible.
_ Sir?
You shouldn't have come.
I wanted to see where my sister died.
Not here.
No?
No, she was brought
here somehow, and left.
There is no roadway for a car.
Oh, I don't know.
A small one could've just made it,
but the ground's too hard to show tracks.
Did David Harris kill her?
What makes you say that?
She was pregnant.
I've seen the autopsy.
Yes, but that's no
proof that he killed her.
If he did, we'll get him, rest assured.
There is no assurance for me
and my kind, Superintendent.
I've been black for 38 years, I know.
She may have looked white,
but Sapphire was colored.
Your sister was murdered.
We'll find out who killed her.
I'm sure that is your intention.
It is my intention.
It's also my job.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
When I was a child,
another boy touched me.
He then held out his hand.
"Look," he said.
"Nothing's come off on me."
Trouble is, something came off on me.
How do I get to Bloomsbury?
I'll give you a lift.
It's on my way.
Sorry, sir.
I'm full.
I don't want a room.
I've come to thank you, for
looking after my sister.
You've got the wrong address.
I take only white students.
My name is Robbins.
How much did Sapphire owe you?
Her rent was paid up.
May I come tomorrow, and
pick up Sapphire's things?
The police have sealed
her room, you must ask them.
Patsy!
You, in Patsy?
What is it, Mrs. Thompson?
That girl you brought here,
did you know she was colored?
What girl?
Sapphire.
Yes.
Yes, I did.
When did she tell you?
Well, she didn't.
A friend told me.
This house is my living.
If it got round that I
took colored students,
certain white people wouldn't
allow their children to stay here.
Well, I think it's a
damn silly prejudice!
I'm not saying it isn't,
but I can't afford to have my rooms empty.
To think that she could be so sly.
It's people like you, who made her sly.
Well, you jolly-well got
another room empty now.
Patsy!
Yes?
You took Sapphire home
to Guildford, didn't you?
Yes?
Did you tell your father
and mother she was colored?
No.
Well, then.
Don't be so quick to call me prejudiced.
You sure?
Right.
Well, Harris's van could've made it.
Not on Saturday night, it couldn't.
What?
Van was in the garage,
having a big end fixed.
Harris didn't pick it
up, until Monday morning.
Well, how the blazes
did he get her there?
Ask Sergeant Cook to come in, will you?
Thank you.
Red taffeta, under a tweed skirt.
Yes.
That's the black end
of the white, alright.
Oh, come off it, Phil.
Yes?
Oh, come in, Sergeant Cook.
Tell me...
What do you make of that?
I wouldn't know what to make of it, sir.
Oh, come, you're a woman.
Where do you suppose a thing
like that could be bought?
I wouldn't know, sir.
No.
Try Babette's, Shaftesbury Avenue.
And how would you know?
Just take my word for it.
They cater for girls, who
like flashy, pretty underwear.
It certainly isn't built for durability.
No.
Well, check on it, first thing
in the morning, will you?
Babette's, you say?
Shaftesbury Avenue.
There's a good girl.
I bet you her boyfriend
bought it for her.
Going in today, David?
Of course he is.
I'm not going in.
You've gotta face it some time, lad.
Better now than later.
It's in the paper this morning.
The autopsy --
They don't mention David.
Won't stop them guessing.
Oh, David, even made you get
mixed up with a colored girl.
I didn't know.
When did you know?
Last week.
By then, I didn't care.
That's what she banked on.
Never say you didn't
know, 'til last week.
Never.
What's it matter?
It gives you a motive,
that's what it matters.
It gives us all a motive.
None of us knew, 'til the weekend, did we?
No.
I'll never forget her,
standing here, Saturday.
When Dad said he'd see
her brother, and tell him
that Davy would stand by
her, she laughed and said,
"He'll be a shock to you,
he's as black as a pot."
Shut up!
Millie.
Then she laughed some more, and said,
"Don't look like that,
David doesn't care."
Have you done your teeth?
Hands well-scrubbed?
Smell.
Mm, lovely smell.
Oh, Janice, I've got something for you.
Here you are.
Now you've both got one.
Ooh, thank you, granddad.
Granddad, will you make me another one?
I can't find mine.
Well, you'd better look for it.
Buck up with your breakfast, you two,
and grampy will take you
to school, in the van.
Don't bother, Dad.
I'll take them to school.
Yes, I remember the girl.
She used to spend quite
a bit of money here.
She was a good customer,
for a little while.
When?
About six, seven months ago.
Did she come alone?
Usually.
Mm.
Except once.
Well?
She had a young fellow with her, then.
Tall, thin boy, fair?
No, I remember being very surprised.
She was such a dainty kid, and he
was a great, big colored chap.
Colored.
A great, big colored chap, she said.
Mm, the other side of the picture.
Hello.
Before she learned she
could pass for white.
Really?
It's a doctor in Bloomsbury, says Sapphire
went to see him on Saturday morning.
Tell him we'll be right over.
Alright.
Sergeant, ring up the
Royal College of Music,
and see if they have any record
of Sapphire's previous addresses.
Very good, sir.
Oh, and then you can go
over to the Harris's place,
and see if any of the neighbors
saw the girl leave on Saturday.
No, she wasn't a regular patient,
I had never seen her before.
She rang for an immediate appointment.
I saw her at 12:30, on Saturday.
Did you tell her at once?
Yes, she was bursting to know.
Was she upset?
No, on the contrary.
Excited, delighted at having
her own suspicions confirmed.
What name did she use?
The one on the card.
Mrs. Harris.
Did she tell you she was colored?
No, she didn't mention it.
I'll bet she didn't.
But you can always tell, can't you?
No, Inspector, as a
matter of fact, you can't.
What?
I can tell them, a mile away.
Oh, I don't know, Inspector.
Would you say you're a policeman?
What?
Well, you haven't got
very big feet, have you?
Don't they say, you can
always tell a policeman
a mile off, by the size of his feet?
Oh, that's bloody silly!
Yes, isn't it?
Well, I'm afraid
there's nothing we can do
about Learoyd's feet,
but regarding the girl,
was there anything else
about her that struck you?
Yes, I thought she was
a rather nice person.
Well, thank you, Doctor.
Not at all.
You've been most helpful.
Goodbye.
She must've been pretty
sure about young Harris.
At any rate, she thought he'd
take the doctor's news happily enough.
Perhaps, she summed the boy up wrongly.
Any of the girl's
addresses come through?
Yes, sir, a house in Bloomsbury,
and before that, a place in Earl's Court,
and another lead,
Chelsea Woman's Hospital.
We'll try Earl's Court first.
Yes, sir.
Yes, I remember Sapphire Robbins.
What sort of a girl was she?
Nice enough girl,
considering she was colored.
Oh, you knew then?
I guessed.
You can always tell.
Too eager to please, laughed too
much, noisy with her gramophone.
But I never mind, so long
as they don't look it.
Still, I had to get rid of her in the end.
Why?
Couldn't risk upsetting
the other tenants.
Some big colored bloke
started calling for her.
Black as your hat, he was.
Well, I run a white house.
You never can tell when
the others are gonna kick.
What was this fella's name?
I don't know.
Did she get any phone calls?
One or two, from the International
Club, with her brother.
Were surprised when
Sapphire got herself killed?
All depends upon how
much hate she stirred up.
Hate?
I dare say, she was passing for white.
So?
Would you be pleased with
a brass sovereign, Superintendent?
Is that all?
Yes, thank you very much.
These landladies.
They know it all, don't they?
I wouldn't say that.
After all, they've got a
living to earn, I suppose.
Chelsea Women's Hospital, isn't it?
Yeah.
Miss Mary Dawson.
Miss Dawson?
Yes?
My name is Hazard, this
is Inspector Learoyd.
You want to talk to me about Sapphire?
Yes.
I saw it in the paper.
It upset me very much.
Did you like Sapphire?
Yes, I did.
Tell me, was she fond of dancing?
Mad about it.
Who were her dancing partners?
Ray Landa, Paul Slade.
Mm-hmm.
How can we get in
touch with these people?
Ray Landa went home to
Nigeria, six months ago,
but I can give you Paul
Slade's telephone number.
And what is that?
Chancery, 2-4-9-6.
Thank you.
Paul Slade was a law student
then, now he's a barista.
Well, thank you, Miss Dawson.
You've been most helpful.
Tell me, why did you stop seeing Sapphire?
She stopped seeing me.
I'm rather distinctive, you know.
Hello, Ted.
He's down there.
He's been back and forth,
along that footpath, all afternoon.
What's he looking for?
Search me.
Whatever it is, he hasn't found it.
See you.
None of the neighbors saw Sapphire
leave Harris's house on Saturday, sir.
Yes?
Mr. Paul Slade, sir.
Oh, bring him in.
The dancing lawyer.
I beg your pardon, sir?
Huh?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
This way, sir.
Oh, it's very good of you
to come all this way, Mr. Slade.
Not at all.
Thank you, Sergeant.
I'd rather call on you,
than have you call on me.
My father's in London for a
conference at Lambeth Palace.
I don't think there's a Bishop
living, that appreciates
his son being mixed up in a murder
inquiry, however, indirectly.
Here, won't you sit down?
Here let me take that.
I understand you knew Sapphire Robbins.
Very well.
May I?
Please do.
Oh, thank you.
Where'd you first meet her?
At the International Club.
One of those, get together,
let's be brothers, places.
How long since you've last saw her?
Seven, eight months.
Has she any other
friends, besides yourself?
Chap called Ray Landa.
He's gone home, I believe.
Anyone else?
Not that I know of.
You sent for me to ask
where I was on Saturday.
I was meeting my father,
off a boat at Southampton.
We stayed the night, and I drove him
back to town on Sunday morning.
Thank you.
Did you ever have a photograph
taken with Sapphire?
Yes.
In a group.
Did you ever have one taken alone,
dancing at the nightclub?
Never alone, Superintendent.
Do you ever take her
shopping, in Shaftesbury Avenue?
Babette's, for instance.
Good lord, no.
Why?
Well, if you didn't, it doesn't matter.
What sort of a girl was Sapphire?
Oh, neither one thing or
the other, when I knew her.
I imagine she changed after she
got this yearn to marry light.
If you know what I mean.
I do.
That ruled you out, anyway.
The question of
marriage, between Sapphire
and myself, could never have arisen.
How's that?
My father would never have permitted it.
Why not?
Sapphire came from a good home.
Her brother's a doctor.
She was part white.
Is that all?
Well, for the moment, yes.
If we need you, we'll send for you.
Any help I can give.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Did he ask about Johnnie?
No.
Good.
My old man knew I'd been
around places like Tulip's,
he'd cut off my allowance,
and yank me back home.
Is this policeman likely to get onto it?
Shouldn't think so.
Didn't strike me as being
overburdened with brains.
Sanctimonious...
Always so careful to
have his hand out first.
I know.
We're all the children of God.
Forget it.
I see you've been talking to Slade.
I suppose he's got a cast iron alibi?
Yes.
Yeah.
But there's something
he didn't want me to know.
What's that?
I don't know.
He said he met Sapphire
at the International Club.
Get on to him, find out
what time all the kids
are likely to be there together.
Okay.
Yes?
What is it, Sergeant?
It's about young Harris, sir.
What about him?
He's up on the Heath.
He's been there all afternoon,
looking for something.
He pushed it down the drain, sir.
It was quite deliberate, so I thought
I'd best find out what it was.
Well, it's a piece of wood.
Must've been painted at some time.
Look, you can see the red and blue marks.
Yeah.
Been jointed at both ends.
Must've come off something.
Off what, I wonder.
Take this to the lab, and
see what they make of it.
Very good, sir.
Now, why on earth should that boy
be so anxious to find that,
and then get rid of it?
You didn't go in today?
Davy, this is a terrible
thing that's happened,
but you've got to pull yourself together.
In three weeks, you'll be going away.
Rome, it's a new world.
New people, new places, you'll forget.
I shan't.
I can't.
Davy, you did speak
the truth about Saturday?
You didn't meet Sapphire, did you?
Davy, what happened on Saturday night?
Mum, never ask
what happened on Saturday.
Never.
Davy.
You didn't meet Sapphire
on Saturday, did you?
Answer me, Davy, did you?
Granny?
There are the twins.
Answer me, Davy!
Granny?
Alright, kids, Granny's here.
Granny, Granny.
What's the matter?
I thought you'd gone to
tea with Molly Turnbul.
Her mother didn't want us.
Why?
She said we were a funny
family, and she doesn't want us.
What's happened?
What is it, Mother?
Go and take your hats and coats off, hmm?
What is it?
Mrs. Turnbul wouldn't
have the twins for tea.
I think they ought to go and
stay with Katie in Richmond.
Oh, I don't know what Sid would say.
Oh, stop pretending about Sid.
He doesn't care whether
they're here, or in Timbuktu.
He's a bad husband and a bad father.
Right, Mom.
I'll get Dad to drive them down, tomorrow.
Ring Katie now.
Alright.
Mildred?
What time did you leave
Sapphire on Saturday?
Half one, mum.
Then, I went back to the
shop, left her here with Dad.
Then only Dad was at home.
That's right.
Davy wasn't?
No, he didn't get in 'til 11.
Did you see him?
No, I was in bed, but Dad was up.
Then we've only got Dad's word that
he came in, when he said he did.
Mum.
What are you thinking?
Nothing.
I'll ring Katie, you see
to the children's tea.
Oh, dear, we'll never live it down.
Who says?
Molly Turnbul's mother.
What won't we live down?
I don't know, but it's something
to do with Auntie Sapphire.
She's dead!
Time to settle down now, children.
Mommy, why are we going
to stay with Auntie Katie?
Ask no questions, and
you'll be told no lies.
It's because of
Auntie Sapphire, isn't it?
No, and don't call her Auntie.
She's nothing to us, and she never was.
Night, my darling.
Good night, Mommy.
Good night, my love.
Straight off to sleep, no talking.
- Yes, mommy.
- Good night.
I've told you a
dozen, if I've told you once,
so why go on arguing about it?
David came in at 11 o'clock!
That's what I told the
police, and it's the truth.
What you told the police,
Ted, but is it the truth?
Stop accusing, David.
Please, Mum!
Millie, if we're to help him,
we've got to know the truth.
Lies are never any good.
Who says David's telling lies?
I don't want any supper, Mom.
I'm going out.
Where are you going, son?
I'm going for a walk, mum.
Don't be too late, will you?
I don't think you'll find who
you're looking for here, Superintendent.
We haven't seen Sapphire
for six, seven months.
We're merely trying to fill
in her background, Mr. Young.
As you wish.
This way.
Thank you.
I'll get some quiet.
Quiet, everybody, please!
Quiet, please, everybody!
Just gather around me, will you?
Won't keep you a moment, but these
gentlemen are police officers.
They want to ask you a few
questions about Sapphire Robbins.
Was anyone here a particular
friend of Sapphire's?
We all were, weren't we?
Once.
What do you mean, once?
I mean, she stopped coming here.
Why?
They drift away, Superintendent.
Grow out of us.
Sapphire didn't drift away.
She used to come here regularly,
then suddenly, she never came again.
Why was that?
Sapphire found she could pass for white.
I was there when it happened.
Tell me.
We've just finished coffee,
I went to pay the bill.
A white lady came in, took
one look at my black mug,
and said, "Oh, I see
you've let the jungle in."
She said this to Sapphire, you
see, like they were the same.
Sapphire left before I got my change.
When I went outside, she had gone.
Silly little peasant.
Did you ever dance with Sapphire?
No, not me.
Slade, Ray Landa, they were her
partners, and wishy-washy there.
Where did you dance with her?
Here, sir.
Did she mention anyone else?
Outside the club, I mean.
No.
Well, if you do remember
anything, speak to Mr. Young.
He'll know how to get in touch with us.
Well, I think you're right.
I didn't actually find anything here.
Thank you so much.
Everybody's been most kind of you.
I'll see you out.
Please don't bother,
you'll miss the performance.
Right.
He's a good pianist.
Yes, and he's lucky.
He'll be accepted for what he is.
What's that?
A good pianist.
There's a
young lady in the car, sir.
I thought as much.
Drive around the block.
Phil, get in the front.
Very good, sir.
Yes, I know a lot about
Sapphire they don't know.
Go on.
The rhythm of the club, it
wasn't hot enough for her,
so Paul Slade used to take her
to Tulip's, a dive in Shepherd's Bush.
Oh, dear.
His father, the bishop, huh?
Yes, I know his reverence.
He'd as soon see his precious son
in hell fire, as at Tulip's.
Paul got into a fight
there, over Sapphire.
Well, who did he fight with?
Oh, Johnnie someone.
Big, ugly fellow, he said.
Sapphire danced crazy
with him, real crazy.
Paul dropped her after that.
Poor Sapphire.
Oh, she couldn't care less.
She'd got Johnnie then.
Of course, he didn't last very long,
when his color went out of fashion.
How did you know that?
He rang up, left a message for her.
"Ring Johnnie at Tulip's."
Sapphire had gone white
then, so we never saw her.
I told him, he was mad.
They'd entered for some dancing
competition, cash prize, he said.
You didn't like Sapphire?
No, I was Paul Slade's
girlfriend, 'til she cut me out.
I hated that high yellow doll.
You can drop me anywhere
here, I'll walk back.
What are you studying?
Montessori, child welfare.
I shan't bother with it though.
Why not?
I want to get married, stay here.
I like the English.
Well, thank you.
Bye bye.
By the way, did you give this
Johnnie, Sapphire's new address?
Oh, no, I wouldn't do that.
Perhaps he got it from
someone else though, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Try Tulip's Club, Shepherd's Bush.
I will.
Good night.
Two beers.
No beer, sir.
Scotch, Irish, and Bourbon, sir.
Buy me a drink, copper.
Three beers.
Ever heard of Sapphire?
Double, sir?
Three beers.
The chick that was
dead on Hampstead Heath?
That's the chick.
10 schillings, sir.
Sorry I've got nothing smaller.
Keep the change.
Now then, ever heard of Sapphire?
Down the hatch, copper.
Is Johnnie in tonight?
Johnnie, is he in tonight?
Talking to me, sir?
Yes.
Lots of Johnnie here tonight, sir.
Johnnie Fingers...
Johnnie Heartbeat...
Johnnie Rags...
And Johnnie Tiger, over there.
Sure, all the Johnnies in the
world are here tonight, sir.
We want the Johnnie, who
danced with this chick.
This chick was never here at all, sir.
Can I help you, Superintendent?
Mr. Tulip?
That's what they call me.
We're looking for the Johnnie,
who used to dance with Sapphire.
This Sapphire.
You mean the chick that was cut
up on Hampstead Heath, Saturday night?
Mm-hmm.
She's new to me, I never saw her here.
That's a lily skin.
Your chick was a lily skin, wasn't she?
Hmm?
It's in the evening papers.
I think I would've remembered,
if she'd ever been in here.
Oh, you can always tell.
'Cause once they hear
the beat of the bongo.
Yes, no matter how fair the skin,
they can't hide that swing.
Your chick was never here, Superintendent.
Somewhere else, she
danced with her Johnnie.
Let's get out of here.
Blow, Johnnie,
and don't come back.
You're wearing too much trouble.
Johnnie!
Where was you on Saturday night, Johnnie?
You wasn't in the club.
Was you with Sapphire?
Was you, Johnnie?
You blow, Johnnie, blow!
Can't blow without loot.
I'll bring you loot.
That's him.
I'm in trouble.
The police, I got to hideout.
We have never been in trouble
with the law, and don't care to be.
Gone away with you, boy.
It's you and your kind, that gets
us respectable folk a bad name.
Trash.
The police, on my tail.
Get out, nigger.
We got copper trouble, too, but we ain't
got your sort of woman trouble.
Now, get out and stay out.
Dirty black pest.
What's the hurry, nigger?
Out of the way, nig.
On your way then, sonny boy.
And hurry!
They're after me, please.
Who's after you?
The teds?
Please help.
I daren't.
They'd break the place to pieces,
tear the shop down.
It's my livin', boy.
Please, mister.
I tell you, I daren't.
Dad, you've got to.
He's in trouble.
I tell you, I daren't.
You've got to, dad.
Come in.
This way.
Where were you on
Saturday night, Johnnie?
On the streets.
With Sapphire?
No boss, no!
Which street, Johnnie?
Down the West End.
Who was with you?
No one, I was on my pat.
Johnnie All Alone, eh?
The truth, Johnnie.
Come on, let's have the truth.
Where were you Saturday night?
Answer!
Davy, where have you been?
Walking.
Davy...
Where were you on Saturday night?
In a car, on my way back from Cambridge.
I told you.
Davy...
Ever since you were a little boy,
I've known when you were lying to me.
Now, where were you, sonny?
Mom, I told you never to ask
about Saturday night, please.
Saturday night, Johnnie, where were you?
Out!
Where?
On the street.
Who with?
On my pat.
When did you see Sapphire last?
I don't know Sapphire!
You phoned the International Club,
and left a message for her.
Now, where were you Saturday night?
Out, out!
Someone's gonna look
at you in the morning,
someone who saw you with Sapphire.
Want to change your story, Johnnie?
No, no!
Right, book him.
Come on, on your feet.
Why do you say you didn't know Sapphire?
You had a fight over her, at Tulip's.
Didn't kill her.
Alright, knew Sapphire,
but didn't kill her!
You were crazy
about her, weren't you?
No, we just danced!
No!
She went white and
dropped you, didn't she?
Then, you ran into her on Saturday night,
followed her, and knifed her.
No, we used to dance.
That's all, just dance!
Where is your knife, Johnnie?
Your knife, Johnnie.
Where is it?
Where's your knife?
Alright, take him away.
Find the knife, and we're got him.
Yes?
Johnnie Fiddle?
Out.
Upstairs, far as you can go, left.
Thank you.
There you are, the two of them.
In congress, aren't they?
No, I wouldn't say that.
She wasn't any delicate flower, you know?
Just the same as him, underneath.
Besides, he didn't look
so black to her then.
No.
Let's take a look around.
Look at this.
And this.
Looks like young Harris is in the clear.
Looks that way.
Let's see what the lab
has to say about it.
It's quite a long trip.
What?
From here to Hampstead Heath.
It's the other side of London.
How the devil did he get there?
Oh, there'll be a simple answer.
The transport.
You'd really like it to be
this colored boy, wouldn't you?
Message over the car radio, sir.
There's a gentleman at
the station, says he drove
Mr. David Harris from
Cambridge, last Saturday.
Hey.
There's your transport for you.
These spades are a load of trouble.
I reckon we should send them
back where they came from.
We wouldn't have half this
bother, if they weren't here.
I suppose you're right.
Just the same as you
wouldn't have old ladies
being clobbered by hooligans,
if there weren't any old ladies.
So what do you do?
Get rid of the hooligans,
or the people they bash?
Look, Phil, given the right atmosphere,
you can organize riots against anyone.
Jews, Catholics, Negroes, Irish,
even policemen with big feet.
Is this the boy you gave a lift to,
just outside of Cambridge on Saturday?
Yes.
What time did you put him down?
I dropped him at the post
office, around 6 o'clock.
He said it was only 10 minute's
walk away from where he lived.
Are you sure?
I wouldn't be here if I wasn't.
Do you deny this?
What's the use?
Well, thank you, sir.
I hope we haven't wasted
too much of your time.
Oh, that's quite alright.
Sorry, old chap.
Well, sit down, Mr. Harris.
What time did you get home on Saturday?
11 o'clock.
You heard what the man said.
I got back to town at six,
I didn't get home until 11.
Then what did you do, in between?
Walked about, then I
went to the pictures.
Why didn't you say this before?
I didn't want my father to know.
He worries if I go to
the pictures too often,
in turn time, thinks it strains my eyes.
Give me your glasses.
Which cinema did you go to?
The Ritz.
What were you doing on
Hampstead Heath yesterday?
If I told you, you wouldn't believe me.
Well, just try, will you?
I wanted to see where it happened.
I had some idea I might
stumble upon something.
Something I'd recognize, and you wouldn't.
And did you?
No.
How about this?
Why were you so anxious
to get rid of this?
I didn't.
I never saw it before.
I'm told it's part of a
child's doll, a wooden doll.
A leg, possibly.
Is that what you think it is?
Why, I don't think it's anything.
Just a piece of wood I was doodling with.
You admit picking it up then?
Yes.
You just said you didn't.
I had forgotten.
Stop lying, Harris!
You were seen, pushing this down a drain.
Why?
I don't know.
I don't know!
You mean, you won't say?
Now, on your way home from the post office
on Saturday night, was
it then you met Sapphire?
No, I never saw her!
Was it then she told you about the baby?
Look, I tell you, I never saw her!
How long had you known she was colored?
I didn't care, I didn't care!
But you did care about your scholarship.
It didn't carry a grant
for a wife, did it?
If you married Sapphire,
the scholarship was off!
I loved her!
I tell you, I loved Sapphire.
Where were you when she was killed?
Yes?
Excuse me, sir.
Mr. David Harris's father
is here, with a solicitor.
Right.
Alright, Harris.
You better go with him, Phil.
Ralph Pigot, Pigot North,
and Pigot Sentry Payment.
Mr. Harris asked me to come
and look after his son.
Can I see my client, please?
He's all yours.
Tough monkey, that father.
Must've moved like the wind
to get a lawyer around here.
Yeah, there they go.
Hmm.
I wonder where he was on Saturday night.
They're getting into a taxi now.
To The Ritz to find a witness, I'll bet.
That was a very human lie.
Boy didn't want to upset his father,
couldn't own up later, he was in too deep.
Where was he on Saturday night?
Who?
Old Harris.
The local social club.
Did we check it?
Alright, don't look so horrified.
We can't think of everything, not even us.
Constable Ferris is also
member of that social club.
No, sir.
Ted Harris didn't come into the club,
'til late, on Saturday night.
About 10, that's definite.
Alright, Ferris.
Sir.
Not until 10, eh?
Well, he gave us the impression
he'd been there all evening.
No, he didn't.
No, his daughter took it for granted,
and we naturally followed.
I'll go 'round and see her, try
and bounce her into giving something away.
We still haven't heard the report
on Johnnie Fiddle's knife.
No, we've got that to come.
Drive 'round to the dairy, will you?
Of course Dad spent
the evening at the club.
He always does Saturdays.
My information is,
he didn't get there until 10.
You're not trying to suggest
that he had anything to do with it?
I'm not saying he did,
I merely want to know where he was.
Then ask him, Superintendent.
Did Sapphire
often go to your house?
Yes.
Then I suppose really,
you were all as much to blame as David.
What do you mean?
Well, you shouldn't
have made her so welcome,
if you didn't want him
involved with a colored girl.
We didn't know she was colored.
Not until --
Not until when, Mrs. Farr?
Not until Saturday, was it?
The day she was killed.
My father didn't do it,
I swear, Superintendent.
You can search the house
from top to bottom,
you'll not find a speck of
blood, or a trace of Sapphire.
Thank you, Mrs. Farr.
I'm peckish, Lilly.
Slip across the Max and get
me a ham sandwich, will you?
Well, go on.
No, old Harris can't be back
yet, or he'd answer that phone.
Now, wait a minute.
She'll ring again.
Who?
Mildred.
Oh, there's no one in.
Mrs. Harris has gone down to Richmond,
and Millie's at the dairy.
Oh, thank you.
You might find Mr. Harris
in the paint shed, but, sir,
you'll have to go around the
yard at the back, for that.
Thanks.
No, he's not here.
I'd like to know what's
underneath that dust sheet.
We haven't got enough evidence to get
a search warrant for this place.
No.
It was expecting too much.
Saturday night, packed house?
How could she remember?
You didn't make this up in the
spur of the moment, did you?
If the boy says he went to the pictures,
he went to the pictures.
You sound like the police.
If I'm gonna help you, I
gotta think like the police.
It's no use boggling.
They've got a very good,
circumstantial case.
They've got no case at all!
The boy didn't do it, and if
you can't clear him, I will.
You hope you can, that's what --
I know, I can --
Shut up, talking across me.
He's never talked to
me like that in his life.
Perhaps, there's a side to the boy
you've never seen, Mr. Harris.
I know my own son.
He didn't kill Sapphire.
I know he didn't.
Tell Sergeant Newton
I want him right away.
Very good, sir.
Right, thank you.
Report from the lab, Bob.
The blood on Johnnie Fiddle's shirt
is the same group as the girl's.
His knife could've inflicted the wounds.
Alright, let's hit him up.
Okay.
You wanted me, sir?
Oh, Newton.
Get a warrant to search
all the sheds at the back
of Oakland Road, say we're
looking for stolen lead.
I want to see inside Harris's paint shop.
Gotcha.
Is this yours, Johnnie?
No, boss!
No!
Then what was it doing in
your mattress, on your bed?
Someone put it there!
He, he put it there!
What?
Alright.
The blood found on this knife,
on your shirt, matches Sapphire's blood.
What about this?
You and Sapphire, isn't it?
Did you kill her, Johnnie?
Did you?
No, boss!
No!
The blood matches.
Not Sapphire's blood!
Then whose, you big lug?
Horace Big Cigar.
We fight Saturday night.
Why the hell
didn't you say this before?
They say I kill him boss.
They say?
Who saw this fight?
Them.
Them, who's them?
Alexander, Gin Rickey, Big Sam.
Where do we find these people?
Number 16, down the
street from my place.
It was self-defense, boss.
Horace Big Cigar attacked me.
I not mean to kill him.
I'll bet.
No, no, no, I cover.
I cover.
What's your name?
Horace Big Cigar, what's yours, man?
This man's the law.
Now no ignorant, foolish talk, men.
- Alright, boss.
- Yes.
According to our information,
Horace, you're dead.
Incorrect.
Not ready for my coffin yet.
Where were you Saturday night, Horace?
Right here, boss.
Why you in bed?
Sick man, boss.
Very sick.
How come?
How'd you get that?
Oh, hit by a jumble car.
What car?
Knocked out, had no
opportunity to see the vehicle.
Johnnie Fiddle one big lie then, huh?
What'd you say, boss?
What'd you say Johnnie Fiddle done?
We're booking for the killing
on Hampstead Heath, Saturday night.
That's what Johnnie Fiddle done.
Sapphire?
That chick that got cut up?
The same.
That sure is one big pity.
Johnnie Fiddle's in big trouble, eh?
You hear that, men?
Saturday night.
Really booking Johnnie Fiddle, boss?
Unless you can give him an out.
He says he was with you.
You sure are wastin' your time.
I got no out with Johnnie Fiddle.
You go, hang him.
Is that where the jumble
car knocked you down, Horace?
You sure a wise man, boss.
Alexander?
Yes, boss?
Gin Rickey?
Big Sam?
Yes, boss?
Why did you tell Johnnie Fiddle
he'd killed Horace Big Cigar?
Johnnie Fiddle wears
too much of a high hat.
We seek a way to knock it off.
Make that big bush run sweat, boss.
Were they all here Saturday night?
All here, boss.
Right, names.
You.
Alexander.
I'll go, Ted.
We're in here.
Did you find what you wanted?
I think so.
Well?
I've just seen Sapphire's brother.
I've asked him to call 'round here.
Not her brother.
We don't want him here.
You had better
tell him that yourself.
He'll be here in a minute.
I said, we don't want him here.
I want him.
I wonder if Sapphire
would've been happy here.
What do you think, Mr. Harris?
Why shouldn't she be?
I don't know, I'm asking you.
Answer the door.
How do you do?
I'm Mrs. Harris, will you sit down?
Thank you.
Dr. Robbins.
I've asked you to come here, because I
think you may be able to help us.
If I can.
Did Sapphire want to marry this boy?
Yes, I think she did.
Well, David's father here,
has been insisting all along,
that he was willing to let them marry.
That's right.
Assuming he's telling the truth,
that would've left the
decision with David.
Did your sister give you the
impression that he would've married her?
I don't know that I can answer that.
I mean, we never really discussed --
I've told you over, and over again, yes.
But, supposing your father were lying,
and didn't want you to marry her?
I didn't care.
But you cared about your
scholarship, didn't you?
You cared about your career.
Marriage would've stopped all that.
It wasn't me that was
mad about the career.
So you say.
I wouldn't know.
You may have thought that
a bit of fun was one thing,
but that marriage was too
high a price to pay for it.
This boy couldn't do anything like --
Don't need you, to defend our David.
Mildred.
How about you, Mr. Harris?
You had your reasons, too, didn't you?
I didn't wish her any harm.
Of course not.
She was gonna marry David.
That's what you said, wasn't it?
That's right.
I gave her my word he would.
But she didn't marry him, did she?
She would have done.
Would have done?
If you hadn't stopped her,
is that what you mean?
That's not true.
I didn't wish her any
harm, none of us did.
We liked her, we liked her!
David wanted her, that was the end.
That was good enough.
Shut up!
Why don't you tell them the truth?
You hated her.
All you ever wanted, was
for me to be an architect.
My boy, an architect!
You were gonna send me away, but you
hated her so much that you finally --
Get him out!
Don't want his hands on my kid's toys,
don't want him near my kids.
Don't want his dirty hands on my children.
Tearing up my family, they're mine.
You really hate colored
people, don't you?
You really hate them.
With Sapphire, you
couldn't control yourself,
and that's why you killed her.
It wasn't like that.
It wouldn't have happened, if
she hadn't come to the dairy.
I'd locked up, drawn the blinds.
She banged on the door and called to me.
I had to let her in.
Said she was fed up, waiting
for David, wanted my company.
She sat on the counter, all
the time I was tidying up,
sweeping, doing Lilly's work,
swinging her legs and laughing.
She couldn't see what she
had done, she didn't care.
Ruining David's life, ruining dad's dream.
When I said she'd better watch out,
David might refer to
give her 10 bob a week,
for the yellow brat, and
keep his scholarship,
she laughed in my face,
and said David didn't care
what color the baby was, or what
color she was, he wanted her.
I had forgotten what that was like.
I had forgotten what it
was like to be wanted.
She was taunting me, with
Sid never coming home.
Then she jumped down from
the counter, put her hand
on my shoulder and said,
"Give the twins Auntie Sapphire's love.
"Tell them they'll have a
new little cousin soon."
New little girl.
There was a knife on the counter.
Then there was blood.
I'm sorry, dad.
I know, son.
You thought I killed her.
I don't blame you.
We all had hate in our hearts.
I loved Sapphire.
I loved her.
Yes, I believe you did.
Are you going back
to Birmingham tonight?
Yes.
Can we give you a lift to the station?
Thank you, I'd like to walk.
Well.
We haven't given you very much
to take back, have we, Doctor?
No, but then I see all kinds
of sickness in my
practice, Superintendent.
I've never yet seen the
kind you can cure in a day.
Cases don't get solved,
without somebody getting hurt.
You know that.
We didn't solve anything, Phil.
We just picked up the pieces.