It was just after my daughter
Amy's third birthday.
She ran up to me,
threw her arms around my legs,
looked up and said...
"Daddy, I've loved you
for four thousand years!"
I gazed into her little face.
A deep happiness enwrapped
my heart, body and soul.
Brian L. Weiss
Toshiko...
Toshiko!
Want to drive!?
You got your license, right?
Tomorrow you have to.
I'm quitting the hotel.
You should, too...
...when you've saved some money.
That guy's weird.
Original Story by
Minetaro Mochizuki
Is something wrong?
Could you check this again, please!?
I'll go make a call.
Hotel Symphonia...
Your savings! Gone!
No, they're not gone.
I got a good stock tip,
so I invested them for you.
You can't just take
someone's savings like that...
Hello?
Hey, you!
Money, please.
Written and Directed by
Katsuhito Ishii
SHARK SKIN MAN
AND PEACH HIP GIRL
Two years later
My dad quit the mob,
but he couldn't quit the drugs.
With a regular job,
he had more money to buy them.
He hid it from us,
but he was high all the time.
He got caught twice,
but he had the money for bail.
Me and my mom and my brother
always used to say...
"Why don't you just stay in jail
for a while?"
He'd be eating ice cream
all the time.
You know, that white stuff...
Like the ice shavings!?
Yeah, the stuff with that kind of
hard ice in it.
Our fridge was full of it.
I mean, obvious or what?
When I was in middle school
I was sniffing glue in the living room...
...when the cops raided our house.
I ran upstairs...
...to hide my stuff in the closet.
But when I opened the closet,
all these bags of white powder...
...came falling out
where my dad had hidden them.
I had it tough.
When my old man was caught,
it was in the paper.
At school someone pasted the article
in the class paper.
People made fun of me,
and I hadn't done anything.
Adults, too. Not just kids.
Adults made fun of you?
We'd go to someone's house,
and I couldn't go in.
"Do you know what your dad did?"
their parents would say.
"I didn't do it, you jerk!" I'd say.
"You know your son sniffs glue?"
When I see that in the papers,
I think of the kids...
They're the ones who suffer.
If kids came to my place,
they'd think the juice was spiked.
As if you'd put speed
in orange juice!
When I was a kid,
I thought a tattoo...
...would appear on your back
when you grew up.
I really believed that!
What are you doing, Toshiko?
Did you sleep in?
Yes. I'm sorry.
I stayed up reading...
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'll be right there.
What!
Nothing.
You saw it, didn't you?
So what?
Nothing.
It's enamel.
Enamel?
Advertising posters like this.
They're called "enamel posters".
You collect them?
- What's wrong with that?
- Nothing at all!
It's great.
I think they're very nice.
You have to come way out here
in the country to find them.
I know.
You've got hobbies, don't you?
Yes!
If you see one of these, stop.
Posters...
- You are laughing at me...
- No, sir!
You think you can find them
anywhere, don't you.
Don't you!
No...
I think my grandmother
might have one...
What kind?
An Ohmura Kon poster
for Oronamin C.
-You're...
- Sorry!
- What are you apologizing for?
- Nothing.
There are about ten types
that I know of.
The Ohmura Kon posters...
Are they the good ones!?
This one's normal.
The ones with "Golden Bat" or
"Attack Number I!" are rare.
Rare...
Rare.
Toshiko, where are you going?
Post office.
Say, "I'm going
to the post office."
I'm going to the post office, Uncle.
Not "Uncle"...
Manager.
Where's the guy who threw this?
Looks like he's gone.
- There were two girls there...
- Girls?
Is that all you think about?
Why did Mr Tanuki go on ahead?
Well, I don't know.
Just bump him, Sorimachi.
May I! Die! Die!
Sorimachi... he's getting away.
It's freezing in here!
Doesn't this damn heater work?
Aren't you cold?!
That's her phone...
What the hell?
Toshiko...
Are you at the post office yet?
What's going on? Where are you?
Get off my back!
I cut him off...
Hotel Symphonia. Mail.
Are you all right?
The poster.
Bring it.
Why didn't you wait?
What are you doing here?
The old man told me to come
if I wasn't doing anything.
Then do something! Well?
Don't ignore me!
And... heave!
Here's Tani...
Excuse me...
You still here?
Um... can I use the toilet?
Please.
Sawada here...
You stink. Get out of here.
You stink! Get lost!
No!
Stop!
Man, I'm lucky!
This is a great jeep!
Lovely. Well nice.
Really nice.
Come on! Mr Tanuki's gone in ahead.
He'll be mad again!
So what? I like this jeep.
Just come on.
You can drive it later. Let's go!
Nice...
Well nice.
Tani-san, come on!
This is great!
We're going! Come on, Tani-san!
- Let's go!
- Nice.
That guy pisses me off.
What can you do!?
He's the boss's son.
So why are we here!?
Insurance. In case they need us.
"Insurance"?!
Didn't you teach Samehada anything?!
Sorry...
- Mitsuru...
- What!?
You shouldn't talk like that.
Like what?
You don't tell people to stay back
just because they stink.
- Go to hell.
- You go to hell!
Sorimachi...
Sorry.
Smell anything?
Yep.
Shampoo, rinse and
a woman on the rag.
You in there!?
It's locked.
Hold it here...
No, here.
Here?
What are you doing!?
Mitsuru says there should be
a smell from the ground.
Well, he's not
under the ground there!
I guess not.
So what are you doing?
- No, what are you doing?
- Over there.
Turn your walkie-talkie on!
Get going.
Well?
- Hey!
- What?!
- The woman!
- What about her?
What happened here!?
Out the back! Who said
go down in the basement?!
You did!
What's the woman he's with like?
I don't know.
I think you do...
- What?
- Piss off!
Asahina!
Which way did he go?
I'll ask...
- What?
- I got shot!
Samehada's that way.
Where's Samehada?
Where's Samehada?!
Can we go this way!?
I came here when I was small.
Can you hear me?
Mitsuru, can you hear me?
What!
You know what.
Ah, Mr Tanuki...
You know who it is.
Idiot!
What's going on?
Who's an idiot?
Don't talk to me like that.
Where's Samehada?
He's crossed the river.
I can't smell him.
You can't smell him?
He crossed with a woman.
Why can't you do that?
I'll get wet!
So what?
I hate water.
You hate water? You're not a kid!
I'm a kid with pubic hair.
Pubic hair? We're not here
to talk about pubic hair.
These clothes are bullet-proof.
It's not your regular leather.
There's iron in them. If they
lose shape, it never comes back.
What are you talking about?
Are you out of your mind?
Well? Are you?
Samehada...
The money...
Where's the money!?
It's only 100 million yen!
You know what happens
if you steal syndicate money?
That's why I'm running.
You think you can run?
Why do you think I'm running!?
Watch your mouth, son!
Where's Sorimachi?
Why?
I want to ask him something.
What!
Not you, asshole!
Stop calling me that.
Are you all listening?
Hey!
- What?
- Do you all know?
Know what?
About your toupee!
Samehada!!
This is starting to be fun!
Ow! Damn it!
Why do you want to come
with me!?
It's my birthday.
Today's my birthday.
What's that got to do with me?
I ran away.
I don't know
what's going to happen...
Hey, what's the matter?
Huh?
I never want to go back there!
Then...
you don't have to go back there.
Don't cry.
It'll be OK.
Let's go.
You don't have to go back.
It's true.
How do you know?
Maruo told me.
- It's yoga...
- Yeah.
That's crap.
It's true!
It was "Yoga in One Month"
or "Yoga Friend" or something...
...but there was a book like that
right next to the body.
"Yoga Friend"?
I'm not sure of the name.
That doesn't sound right.
But the guy's neck was broken.
"Yoga Friend"?
I said I'm not sure of the name.
I've never seen a book
with a name like that.
Who cares about the name!
What was the other name?
"Yoga In One Month".
What!
There could be a book like that...
Who cares
what the name of the book was!
I don't understand.
-You don't?
- No.
I tried to keep it simple...
Look, if I don't understand,
I don't understand!
Put it in more concrete terms.
I'm lost at sea here
'cause of all those English terms.
OK, I'll tell you again. Listen.
Go on.
OK then, the soul...
Well, the body, first...
By the body you mean a kid...
That's right.
So the soul comes to the body...
...when it leaves the woman.
So you're saying
abortion's not necessarily bad?
No, I think it's a bad thing.
I do, too.
Mr Sawada told me not to
worry about it, so I felt better.
I told you not to talk to him!
Yeah, but...
I feel better when I talk to him
about my problems.
Bring your problems to me!
Yeah!?
Hey, Dog...
Dog, get the door.
Coming!
Good work, guys.
I told you not to put that
by the heater.
Oh, sorry.
- Is there food for us, too!?
- Yes
We'll heat it up for you.
Dog, put this in the microwave.
Want to sit down?
It's cold out there.
We've got to eat and run.
It's hard, isn't it.
Damn right.
We should be out looking, too..
What's this? Wild boar?
Eh?
What's that!?
I'm not sure.
It's the wrong color.
Who are you!?
Who are you, I said!
Yamada! Yamada! Yamada!
You were watching me, Yamada.
You were.
Weren't you!
What!
I hate you!
What are you doing!?
Everyone had left
by the time I got the bandage on.
When we find Samehada,
we'll call you. Take a break.
Don't tell me what to do!
Sorry.
You don't need all that!
I'm going to work on it.
It'll look great.
I don't know
if we can believe them or not...
Who are you giving orders to?
Samehada's your buddy, isn't he?
Find him and kill him!
What's that look?
Him?
Sorry.
I hate him! I hate him!
A man?
That's right, Yamada.
Toshiko found herself a man
right under my very nose!
Listen to me, Yamada!
She took off on me!
She found a man and ran away,
Yamada!
Yamada...
This is bad. Bad!
What do you think?
It's beautiful.
But listen...
What!
- Your ex-wife...
-You're the one that killed her.
She was ugly.
Stop it!
She played around.
- Don't say it.
- I will.
A dog. A real dog.
Ears like this.
A dog. A dog.
Your wife was ugly.
She fucked a dog.
No mistake this time!
I won't kill Toshiko.
I've know her since
she was this little.
It's the man I want you to kill.
Proof?
I don't have any proof.
But it was a man
who answered her phone.
That means she's with a man!
Maybe she just ran away.
Even if that's all it is,
bring her back...
OK, Yamada?
I took two days off work for this!
Bastard! Bastard!
Don't do that, Yamada!
I told you not to phone me
except for work!
You know what my work is,
don't you!
Bastard! Bastard! Bastard!
Yes! I want you to kill the man
Toshiko took off with!
The charge is the same whether
there's a man involved or not.
Bastard! Bastard! Bastard!
OK.
I'll pay.
You're a nice man.
Cut that out!
Stop.
What the hell?
What's this?
Damn thing.
I...
I never want to go back
to that place!
What does Mr Tanuki say?
He says he's going to look
by himself.
You know what I think,
Mr Sawada?
There hasn't been any one woman
in the time we've been after him.
Yeah, you're right.
He hired those two
and did it with them all night.
Maybe like Mr Tanuki says...
...the long-haired hotel girl
is the one.
Maybe she's local.
Local girl?
It looks like Samehada
and a girl with glasses were here.
"It looks like" doesn't sound
like an answer.
The hotel clerk recognized
pictures of them.
Who's he?
No connection.
Mr Tanuki!
The local yakuza says...
...they're headed this way.
This way?
No, this way, I thought...
No, this way, I think.
This way? Which way?
Hello, CQ? CQ?
This is JI2CRX, Yamada.
Y-A-M-A-D-A.
"Yamada". It's Yamada!
Come back,
anyone in Area I or Area 2...
Looking for a man and a woman...
...in a black '8 Corvette Stingray.
A couple in a black '81 'Vette.
Come back, please.
Something like that.
And then?
Then the scene changes...
...to a farm. I'm taking a walk.
I've got a cute flowered dress on.
Not in Japan...
Old Europe, maybe...
Suddenly a propellered plane
lands in front of me.
A sharp-looking man gets out.
We go into a barn...
...and take a nap there.
Then what happens?
After that...
...there's food of some kind,
and music...
We all drink wine.
It might be my wedding.
To the guy in the plane?
More like a man who lives nearby...
What happened to the guy
in the plane!?
He's gone.
But...
...all through the wedding
he's on my mind...
I keep thinking about him...
And then what?
Then I wake up.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, but I'm getting
out of the business, too.
There's never an end to it.
Why don't you let him go!
If you know what's going on,
help me on this.
The point is, that I catch him.
If I'm not the one who does,
I'm in trouble.
So if you want me to keep my mouth
shut about that other thing...
Buy me some juice, OK?
Juice? Just juice?
I'll be right back.
Out of Service
That hurts!
That hurts.
I hate that!
Who are you!?
Yamada.
- Yamada?
- Yamada.
Your nose is bleeding, Yamada.
What!
I like you.
What's with you?
I don't know who hired you, but...
I'm sorry.
- You'd better keep your day job.
- Yes.
- Turn around.
Sing something.
"Donna Donna."
"On a wagon bound for market...
there's a calf with a mournful eye."
- Come out when the song's over.
- Yes.
"High above him, there's a swallow...
... winging swiftly through the sky.
How the winds are laughing,
they laugh with all their might...
...laugh and laugh
the whole day through..."
- What's that?
- Some retard.
Ow! I'm bleeding!
What happened?!
Ow! It hurts! Ow!
What hurts? What happened?!
- It's burning!!
- What is?!
What!
What do you mean, Yamada!
You're coming home?
Why, Yamada?
Huh?
What!
You've failed? No, Yamada!
That was Toshiko's man, right?
Wasn't that the man?!
I'm coming back.
I'm sorry.
Why!? I don't understand.
I know you're sorry.
But you've got to kill him, Yamada!
I've filed the marriage forms
for Toshiko and me!
You are...
...a bit weird.
There's something...
Anyway, I'm coming home.
What do you mean, Yamada!
Hey, are you...
Are you in love?!
I'm sorry.
Can I come home!?
You are in love.
- I'm coming home.
- OK, OK.
Forget about the guy.
Just bring Toshiko back.
I can't do that.
I can't do that to him.
Yes, you can.
I'll pay you like I said I would.
You need money, don't you?
You don't have any, do you...
Is this OK?
Yeah.
We can depend on this old guy.
Whenever I need help,
I come to Shiota.
It's fine.
Just fine.
Careful...
What's this?
We're here.
This is a mess, Samehada.
The whole syndicate is out
for your blood.
It's fun, though.
I'd like to try and
rip them off once, myself.
Since the guys at the top
found out...
...the old man with the wig
is in big trouble.
Anyway...
Who are you!?
Momoijiri Toshiko.
I don't mean your name.
- She's with me.
- With you?
I'm with him.
Oh, man!
Well, what should we do?
First, get out of those
filthy clothes.
That's a nice smile.
What do you think?
It's a bit cold, though.
I liked the last one better, though.
Tickets, maps, exchange rates,
everything.
Do the contacts hurt!?
They're fine.
You're beautiful...
That's sharkskin. One of a kind.
Now, that's you!
What do you think? Cool, huh?
Super cool!
You're a great couple.
We'd better hurry.
Thanks.
- What?
- The money, first.
But I paid you...
That's just for you.
You've got to pay for her. too.
How much?
Double.
- Double?
It costs money to do up a woman.
Listen, Samehada...
...even I heard
you had a woman with you.
That was a pretty dramatic escape,
but I'm on the line here, too.
I'll send you the money.
- Now.
- Now?
- Now. In cash.
I can't!
Well, forget it, then.
Listen, Samehada...
Your ass is on the line here,
but so is mine.
What happens if they find out
I helped you?
I've got to drop everything
and get out of here!
The movers told me...
...I've got too much stuff
and they can't take any chairs.
I'm a chair collector!
Chairs are my life!
Don't you understand?
I'm going to leave them behind
and run! I'll need money!
You understand that, don't you?
I'll need money!
I'll be back in two hours.
You watch her.
What are you doing!?
What do you think?
I think it's best
not to get involved.
Why?
Never get mixed up
in man-woman problems.
Why not?
My wife's just run off on me.
With a young guy who came around
selling fire extinguishers.
I'm sure
he was a good-looking guy.
If he'd only been a jerk like you!
Then she wouldn't have gone.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I've got Samehada's girl.
I should be there...
...in about 90 minutes.
Then...huh?
Where's the girl?
Sawada took her.
Get out of here.
Get going, now!
I told him you'd be gone a while.
He believed me and took the girl.
Where!?
If 1 tell you, you'll follow him.
OK, I did a deal with Sawada.
I'm sorry.
But this saves your neck.
You don't need to be like that.
You don't even know her well.
She doesn't mean anything to you.
It's true!
Sorry.
An Oronamin C poster...
...with a "Golden Bat"
or "Attack Number I!" on it...
From a gum machine?
- Yeah, a gum machine.
- One of those 20-yen prizes?
Not those. They're 200 yen now.
The Masked Rider figures.
They're great.
What's the cop got to do with that?
It's embarrassing, though,
being there with all those kids.
What about the cop!?
There was this guy
always hanging around the arcade.
And he was a cop!?
Yeah. I figured him
for some kind of weirdo...
...but then I found out
he collected these things too.
We started trading,
like, at McDonalds...
...Then I found out.
He's the guy who told me.
"Yoga Friend"...
"Yoga Friend"?
The book next to the body.
That was "Yoga Castle".
"Castle"? Like in "castle"?
Yeah.
Where can we get it!
Shit!
Are you OK?
I can't do it. Damn!
Sawada? Sawada!?
Don't you even know
who Sawada is!?
Fuka-chan...
Who's Fuka-chan?
- Huh?
- He was Samehada's buddy!
What did he say?
I just got shit because
you and Sawada were buddies!
Where is Mr Sawada?
He disappeared.
Maybe he's hiding somewhere...
Hey!
Gonna piss.
Watch your manners
or I'll get mad!
I don't want to go inside.
Where's the girl?
Where is she?
Don't shoot!
Where is she?!
She and Sawada disappeared.
Where's the money!?
Toshiko! I've been worried!
Samehada!
Yamada...
Yamada!
You can go.
Go.
I hate you.
You've got to work
tomorrow morning. Go home.
Go home, damn it!
My bank account...
I know that, damn it! Go home!
Go home, I said!
Go home! Get lost!
Scram you idiot.
Let's go somewhere.
I know where we can go.
He's out cold.
Chair.
Not for you.
If you don't talk, you die.
Mr Tanuki... there's no money
in his briefcase.
Samehada...
The bat.
Sis...
I'll be in my room.
The bat.
Would you like some coffee?
Yeah, good idea...
This happened before...
when I was young.
A silly woman ran out on me.
Keep still...
We'll be married, soon.
Keep still, I said!
Keep still, you idiot!
Keep still!
Huh?
Shit!
What are those bastards doing
in my hotel?!
Don't move! I'll spank you!
Let me get a flashlight...
Don't move, I said!
Don't touch me, you pervert!
What!
Yeah, like that. Keep still.
Don't move.
An ambulance...
Call an ambulance, please.
This is good-bye, Samehada.
If you'd followed Sorimachi's plan
and took the money together...
...none of this would have happened.
The money was supposed
to come to me.
Where is it?
What's so funny?
Your face.
Drop the gun.
Drop the gun!
Don't try anything stupid, Tanuki.
Don't you either.
Get away from her, Four-eyes!
"Four-eyes"?
Samehada!
I remember now...
Money, please.
Someone call an ambulance, please!
Don't move, please.
But...
A little more, please.
There should still be more.
Thank you very much.
This is it?
Sawada and God
I keep having this dream...
They sit me in this chair.
In front if me is God, talking.
God?
I think that's what it was.
You believe in God?
Yeah.
"Help them both",
he keeps repeating.
"Help them both"?
Yeah. I wonder if that means
you and Samehada...
- Um...
- You can run if you want.
Now's the chance.
I'm not cut out for this job.
It's a good chance to get out.
So get going.
Thanks.
Starring
Tadanobu Asano
Sie Kohinata
Shingo Tsurumi
Kimie Shingyoji
Youhachi Shimada
Koh Takasugi
Daigaku Sekine
Yoji Tanaka
Hitoshi Kiyokawa
Yoshiyuki Morishita
Kanji Tsuda
Keisuke Horibe
Shingoro Yamada
Tatsuya Gashuin
Susumu Terajima
Ittoku Kishibe
You didn't look very real
when you got shot.
No?
Have we got a place
to get changed?
Yes.
Don't worry.
I'll get rid of everything.
I'm hungry.
Want to stop somewhere
after we change?
Yes.
If we go in like this,
the old lady'll have a heart attack.
The old lady...
The last time we were all covered
in blood.
That ain't too good...
Executive Producer
Hilo lizumi
Producers - Katsuaki Takemoto
Kazuto Takida / Kono Tsutomu
Cinematography
Hiroshi Machida
Lighting
Taro Kimura
Based on the original manga by
Minetaro Mochizuki