A SHOCHIKU FILM
SING A SONG OF SEX
Produced by
MASAYUKI NAKAJIMA
Original Compilation of Songs by
TOMOMICHI SOEDA
Screenplay by TAKESHI TAMURA,
MAMORU SASAKI,
TOSHIO TAJIMA,
and NAGISA OSHIMA
Cinematography by
AKIRA TAKADA
Production Design by JUSHO TODA
Music by HIKARU HAYASHI
Edited by
KEIICHI URAOKA
Ass't Director OSAMU YASUI
Ass't Producer TAKUJI YAMAGUCHI
Starring
ICHIRO ARAKI
AKIKO KOYAMA
KAZUKO TAJIMA, JUZO ITAMI
KOJI IWABUCHI
KAZUYOSHI KUSHIDA, HIROSHI SATO
NOBUKO MIYAMOTO
HIROKO MASUDA, HIDEKO YOSHIDA
Special Appearances by
HIDEO KANZE, YOSHIYUKI FUKUDA
HOSEI KOMATSU,
and FUMIO WATANABE
Directed by
NAGISA OSHIMA
Got a match?
Want one?
- I have my own.
It's No. 469.
Couldn't keep my eyes off her
during the exam.
If I fail, it's her fault.
You've found yourself
a good excuse.
You had your eye on her too.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please support our campaign
against the Vietnam War.
We must bring peace to Vietnam.
Please join us
in opposing the Vietnam War.
Thank you very much.
Please sign here.
X FUJIWARA
Thank you very much.
You two sign too.
You can't possibly
be for the war.
AYMA JOKE
GUY HU-SUX
Hey, cut the crap!
Hey, Nakamura and Ueda,
how'd it go?
A couple more years of study
won't kill you.
You must be relieved
the exams are over.
Look at me.
I keep taking the exams
just for that feeling.
Where are you going now?
Wanna go to the Lawrence
in Shinjuku?
Come to the Lawrence.
Pig!
What's the Lawrence?
Hey, Hiroi!
Cut it out!
The Lawrence?
He wants to fool around with a widow?
I saw a nice girl at my school too.
Her number was –
We have No. 469.
Forget yours.
Does he mean the Lawrence
of Lady Chatterley's Lover?
Don't bother figuring it out.
He's always saying stupid stuff.
I'm sure No. 469 isn't married.
She's a virgin.
I'm not so sure about that.
She is, I tell you.
Really good-looking too.
No. 469.
Was she that good?
Of course.
No one else like her.
I should've taken
the exam for your university.
Did he mean the movie
Lawrence of Arabia?
Use your head.
It's got nothing to do with heroism.
The bastard said it
in a really lascivious way.
What's "lascivious" mean?
It has to do with sex.
Lustful.
Like us.
- What's the name?
- Lawrence of Arabia?
No, her name.
- Fujiwara.
- First name.
Fujiwara, No. 469 from Tokyo.
- Who are they?
- I don't know.
What's in that box?
Probably nothing.
"One day I looked up
and saw a black flag
waving high in the sky.
It waved so high
I couldn't hear its sound.
I tried to bring it down,
but without a rope
there was nothing I could do.
The flag just kept on waving
as if flying off
into the depths of the sky...
into the depths of the sky."
ABOLISH NATIONAL
FOUNDATION DAY
Aren't you going to say anything?
Abolish National Foundation Day!
- Long live the Lawrence in Shinjuku!
- Long live No. 469!
Hey, look.
- What?
- He's with a woman.
- Who is?
- Our teacher.
- Ueda, go after her.
- Why me?
- Just do it.
- You go.
You go.
- What about you?
- I think I'm catching a cold.
Go on.
Excuse me.
What is it?
You've been following me,
haven't you?
- We're his students.
- "His"?
I see. And?
Nothing.
Forgive me.
What's wrong, Nakamura?
Did you see that mocking look
on her face?
- Yeah, full of contempt.
- Is that all?
- Why'd she make that face?
- Maybe they'd fought.
- Is she his girlfriend?
- Probably his plaything.
Dyed hair
doesn't make her a prostitute.
She is a prostitute.
Does he hold her
with that same solemn look?
"Hold me tighter, baby."
Think she undresses by herself?
There are all types.
What would I do if a girl said,
"Help me undress"?
No girl's ever gonna
say that to you.
That woman undresses on her own.
She just seems the type.
She isn't my type,
I'll tell you that.
Otake doesn't base
his choices on your type.
He sure seems to know
what he's doing.
You look up to him?
No. 469. Right, Nakamura?
Damn it, let's go find her.
- Should we call her?
- You know her address?
No, but the university does.
Hello.
I took my exams today.
Can you give me
the name of another examinee?
No. 469, a female.
Not allowed?
They can't do it.
Miss Sanae of Maebashi?
- Miss Tomoko of Maebashi?
- Miss Satoko Ikegami?
Miss Sanae Satomi?
This is shameful.
Let's go.
Miss Sanae?
Miss Tomoko?
Miss Sanae, No. 469?
Miss Tomoko, No. 469?
Hey, what high school
is your date from?
Tell these idiots
your appointment isn't a date.
- No imagination.
- Don't worry about that.
- We're going to see the teacher.
- Otake?
Better stay away from him.
Sure, he's good-looking
and lives in Tokyo.
How about coming to the Lawrence?
Don't be so crazy about Otake.
- We could go to graduate school too.
- Sure you're smart enough?
Otake's sleeping with someone.
We saw him walking
with an ugly woman.
We don't need you following us.
Today we fly to Kasumigaura
A great cloud of hope wells up
If you boys want
to go home now, feel free.
Maruyama, have some.
I'm fine.
Stop it.
Sir...
I want to live in Tokyo.
Should I rent an apartment?
- Yeah, you should.
- One with no lock.
That's not for me to say.
It's up to you.
And I want to read Henry Miller.
- His descriptions are so –
- Nakamura, stop it.
Mr. Otake, of Sexus,
Nexus, and Plexus –
You wouldn't understand
any of it.
What time is it?
Mr. Otake...
may I have some too?
Of course.
Sir, do you always go drinking
at restaurants like this?
You go to bars too, right?
Come on.
Finish eating already.
There are trains at 7:36, 7:58,
8:26, 8:38 –
Let's all take the 7:36.
What's the rush?
We all just finished exams.
You may have
to retake them next year.
I've been watching all of you,
and boys and girls
really are different.
What do you think
of the examination system?
Sir, don't men and women
sometimes go to protests together?
Yours had nice legs.
They didn't do anything
special when they parted.
Sir...
I peeled this shrimp for you.
Sir, I'll have some too.
Thanks for the meal.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Ask her parents'
permission first, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the second case, ho, ho!
Quiet, everyone!
Doing it with two sisters, ho!
Take the older one first, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the third case, ho!
Doing it with an ugly girl, ho!
Cover her face
with a wrapping cloth, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the fourth case, ho!
When doing it upstairs, ho!
Be quiet
so you won't be heard, ho, ho!
Let's go.
Sir, don't you hold
your liquor well?
A Soran tune from Hokkaido...
a Tsugaru-jongara tune from Aomori...
a Mugi-tsuki tune from Iwate...
an Ohara tune from Toyama...
an Itchaka tune from Chiba...
not to mention the amazing things
I heard in Enoshima.
Bridal songs from Yamanashi,
nursery songs from Mie,
ramming songs from Kumamoto,
millet-husking songs from Miyazaki...
and asadoya yunta work songs
from Okinawa.
Bawdy songs,
raunchy songs,
erotic songs,
songs about sex –
these are the suppressed
voices of the people.
An oppressed people's labor,
their lives...
and their loves.
Once people became
conscious of these things,
they naturally turned to song
to express themselves.
That's why bawdy songs represent
the history of the people.
Still, no need to force
the youngsters to listen.
I feel sorry for them.
They don't know
how to feel anything fully.
No politics, no panties,
no oppression –
They can't even sense
that they're oppressed.
So there's no other choice
but to sing for them like this.
Rising into the clouds
The high peak of Takachiho
So a doomed people sings
the songs of a doomed nation?
What's it matter?
Japan's full of doomed people.
"I remember three years ago,
when the village suffered a drought,
the family council deliberated
whether to sell the daughter or the house.
They decided to sell their daughter
and got 3,000 ryo for her.
They put lipstick on her,
powdered her face,
put her in a palanquin
bedecked with flowers,
and took her
to a well-known place
in the red-light district."
Knowing neither
my place nor my name
Unable to avoid
the most dreadful of customers
Sleeping alone
night after night
All this for my useless parents
Let's go.
What? Leaving so soon?
It's just getting interesting!
Please sing
for the Lawrence in Shinjuku.
What's the Lawrence?
I don't know.
Lawrence of Arabia was a hero.
He attacked Turkey.
I attack the "Turkish baths"
in Shinjuku,
so I'm Lawrence of Shinjuku.
Will you men be
Lawrence of Arabia
or Lawrence of Shinjuku?
The English are so clever
They use rubber and paper
Russians use their fingers
"Not a single one of our actions
can be divorced from rage.
Taking a break to catch your breath
and sleeping at night
are both a waste of time.
They will make you late for battle.
Even so, love is the only
true act of resistance.
They all trample upon love.
If you realize
that your parents or wives
have taken the enemy's side...
you must abandon them!
You can no longer...
fear hatred!
You can no longer
be ashamed to be a fanatic!
I have a grudge with them.
They nearly did me in,
didn't they?
Only when you embrace hatred
do you really feel this human existence.
Hatred turns poverty
into a nurturing cradle.
I know this quite well,
so I savor my rage,
and my hatred grows by the day."
Can you girls still catch
the last train?
We're staying here tonight.
You do that!
I'll put you up in a hotel.
Shall we catch
an exhibit tomorrow?
Fantastic!
After all, there's no school.
A long holiday in February
for the first time since the war!
Let's have fun!
Are you really wearing those?
You idiot!
Ueda's a simpleton.
He's so superstitious.
This is no superstition.
I passed math and English
because of these.
Didn't you say you failed
because of No. 469?
Ueda, go to the girls' room
like that and get some food.
Do they have any?
They must.
They're gorging right now.
In panties and slips?
Damn! There are three girls
right next door.
Three virgins?
- Go on.
- "You pervert!"
Go ahead.
Cut it out, asshole!
I'll strip you naked, bastard!
A virgin's here!
Don't put anything on.
Come in.
It's Kaneda.
Mr. Otake paid the bill,
so don't worry about that.
Please be sure to check out
by 10:00 a.m.
Ueda!
- Kaneda?
- What?
You got any food?
Yeah, rice crackers and doughnuts.
Go like that.
Idiot.
Then I guess I'll go.
I might even get in their room.
Hey!
What?
Thank you.
Take this key.
I'll try.
Will that key work?
- Why would it?
- It might.
Excuse me.
Please open up.
I need to talk to you.
We shouldn't let Mr. Otake
pay for everything.
Let's talk about the bill.
What a jerk!
That's pathetic!
It's 12:00 midnight.
Hurry home to bed, children.
Your mommies are worried.
Sanae?
Let's feel each other up.
Tomoko too.
- What?
- It's my turn.
What a drag.
Watch.
I'll show you how it's done.
Now it's Nakamura.
That's right – Toyoaki Nakamura.
Just ignore them.
Let's go to sleep.
Let them get all worked up.
Hey, I feel lascivious!
What?
- I feel lascivious.
- I don't know what that means.
I'll write it down.
What's wrong?
I forgot my pen.
Excuse me.
I came to get my fountain pen.
Mr. Otake!
Let's begin
with the first case, ho
Doing it with an only daughter, ho
Ask her parents' permission first
You still here?
- Good night.
- Yes, good night.
Bastard!
Going by yourself!
We'll strip you for that!
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Ask her parents'
permission first, ho, ho!
Now let's go on
to the second case, ho, ho!
You'd be ashamed
if No. 469 found out!
Doing it with two sisters, ho!
Take the older one first, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the third case, ho!
Doing it with an ugly girl, ho!
Take the older one first, ho, ho!
What's wrong with him?
He doesn't even care.
What?
Giving up so soon?
Stripping you is no fun.
Where'd you really go?
To Otake's.
- Why?
- I left my pen there.
You went back for it?
What was he doing?
He was fast asleep.
The gas heater was burning.
Get up.
- Sleep with me.
- Idiot!
- Hey, come a little closer.
- What for?
- Closer.
- What is it?
I saw it!
- Pervert!
- You girls are no fun.
"7000 Years of the Orient"
opens at 10:00.
Otake packed us together like this
so we'd have sex.
- That's why he sang that song.
- Ultra-pervert!
The first human civilization
was established 7,000 years ago
in the Tigris-Euphrates delta.
- Yeah, by men and women.
- That's enough.
If you're not coming,
at least go thank Mr. Otake.
What for?
We'll thank him
if you bring him here.
Let's go.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
I like that song...
Of course.
It's the best.
...when Mr. Otake sings it!
To be...
or not to be?
Checkout time.
You too.
To be or not to be...
What's that?
Tails.
What's wrong?
Please go away!
Stop crying!
Mr. Otake drank too much last night.
And he sang really loud.
Yeah, he did.
That's why...
...he died?
What happened because he sang?
He was tired and fell asleep
with the gas heater on.
The heater?
He was really drunk.
He kicked the heater hose
loose in his sleep,
and the room filled with gas.
He didn't know
the gas was killing him.
The police are there now.
This isn't a joke, is it?
Did the gas kill him?
I think he killed himself.
He only has himself to blame.
Aren't you even sad
that he's dead?
Of course we are.
He was kind to us.
But some people at school
will be happy.
- You idiots!
- Cut it out!
Nothing we can do about it
if he's dead.
But he did so much for you boys!
So what?
"That's what teachers
and parents are for."
- A man has died!
- Yeah, very stupidly.
An emperor or president could die
like that and people would laugh.
You're a madman!
An ingrate!
You aren't human!
Go complain to the guy
who died a fool's death.
How can you talk
about your teacher that way?
Now I get it.
You girls were in love with him,
and you can't stand
that he died such a stupid death.
Let's go pay our respects.
Yeah, probably best.
Seems like the thing to do.
Which of you is Hiroi?
That's me.
- Ueda?
- That's me.
You're Maruyama?
And you're Nakamura?
You boys accompanied
Mr. Otake here last night.
- That's right.
- What time did you leave him?
Around 10:30, wasn't it?
He asked us to stay a while,
but he was really drunk,
so we left.
Who turned on the heater?
Mr. Otake.
The cause of death
was carbon monoxide poisoning.
Anything else
you might have noticed?
Not really.
I did come back
for something I'd left behind.
Left behind?
- A fountain pen.
- A fountain pen, huh?
Come this way.
I wonder if he killed him.
Who knows.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
I didn't have any motive.
You look like you suspect me.
- Maybe.
You have to admit,
you had an opportunity.
Maybe so,
but I'm not that stupid.
People can kill for no reason.
This is ridiculous.
Why are you so suspicious of me?
I'm not particularly.
I'm just –
- Passing the time?
We had so much fun with him.
He even sang for us.
I peeled shrimp for him.
"We'll go to an exhibit."
Those were his last words.
I last saw him
at the demonstration.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Ask her parents' permission first
That's the last song he sang.
You're the one
who followed me yesterday.
We were trying to figure out
your relationship to him.
Did he really sing that song?
It couldn't have been that song.
His last song must have been
something better.
Isn't that right?
Three teas.
You must be thirsty.
Stop crying.
People are watching.
She bought a handkerchief.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
The four of us killed Mr. Otake.
- You did?
- Yeah, all together.
After you went to sleep.
We were mad.
Because you wouldn't let us in.
He talked so big.
You know that heater?
We kicked it over!
Let's take that train.
That's the Shinetsu line.
Doesn't matter.
We'll talk about this later.
Get on.
You were lying, weren't you?
Weren't you?
It's the truth.
They're watching us.
Shall we wave a handkerchief?
Did they really believe it?
Won't they spread it around?
You went too far.
Don't blame me.
Nakamura sounded really serious.
- Were you really serious?
- Yeah.
What did you tell the detective?
So you killed him
when you went back alone?
You kicked the heater?
I'm not like you guys.
If we'd thought of this last night,
at least one of those girls –
We could've had all three.
They were all crying.
Even ugly girls are sexy
when they cry.
But there were only three of them.
We'd have worked it out.
Sanae would be a pushover.
She's a crybaby.
She covers her face
when she cries.
- Then we grab her from behind.
- Of course.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing Sanae Satomi, ho!
We do it while wiping away
her tears, ho, ho!
I like girls who resist, like Tomoko.
More of a challenge.
We gotta be careful with Tomoko.
If she resists,
we'll rip her clothes off.
What'll she say afterward?
"Mother!"
Let's go on
to the second case, ho, ho!
Doing it with Tomoko Ikegami, ho!
Put some antiseptic
on one hand, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the third case, ho, ho!
Doing it with Sachiko Kaneda
Forget it.
Kaneda won't get us hot.
That's right.
Why's she like that anyway?
Let's go on
to the fourth case, ho!
Doing it with No. 469, ho!
Can't do it without
asking her name, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the fifth case, ho!
Doing it with No. 469, ho!
Do it on a desk
instead of a bed, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the sixth case, ho!
Doing it with No. 469, ho!
Do it during an exam, ho, ho!
What about the examiner?
There's only one.
There's gotta be more.
- Who'll handle him?
- Leave it to me.
You can't handle him, Ueda.
Ueda's too clumsy.
I'll do it.
It doesn't matter
how we get rid of him.
Yeah, just get rid of him.
No. 469.
Where's she sitting?
Near the front.
- Ueda knows her face?
- Who'll talk to her?
- Maruyama's a smooth talker.
- Yeah, let him do it.
- No, I'm no good at talking.
- Just drag her down.
- What about the others?
- It doesn't matter.
She's thrashing around like a fish.
- You're in trouble.
- She's a fighter.
- What do you do then?
- I can't exactly show you.
All he did
was wrestle with her.
He only got her shoes off.
Someone might try to help her.
Yeah, some do-gooder.
- Someone'll have to beat him up.
- Who?
- I'll do it.
- You will?
Ueda, go on.
Just don't get beaten up yourself.
You know her uniform
has a top and a bottom?
She's out cold.
He sure is taking his time.
Think he can really do it?
You're done already?
Chicken out at the last minute?
It's not like a simple fistfight.
My turn.
Is she unconscious
in Hiroi's version too?
Better that way.
More realistic.
- I'll rip her clothes off.
- Hurry up and do it.
It's not like a public bathhouse.
You gotta be kidding.
None of you guys
actually fucked her.
She's completely out
and just lying there.
My turn.
- Show us.
- Think you can do it?
- I'm not like you guys.
- You gonna do something weird?
What are you gonna do?
The others will rush to the desk
for their exam papers.
What'll you do
with them all around?
You guys might not see.
So what'll you do?
That was exhausting.
Think you could tell No. 469
what we just imagined?
Sure. Why not?
What do you want?
I... um...
Me? Sure I could.
What is it?
You have something to tell me?
No.
Turns out it's hard
to imagine telling her
what we imagined doing to her.
The house you see her living in
is too small.
If you're gonna dream,
dream big.
The four of us –
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Ask her parents'
permission first, ho, ho!
It was a lie, right?
You lied when you said
you killed Mr. Otake, right?
I'm glad I came back.
- Of course.
- Would we be sitting here singing?
- You came back to ask that?
- All the way from Fukaya.
No more singing?
May I sing one?
You know a song?
- May I?
- Sure.
Sounds like fun.
Okay by you, Nakamura?
One dark and drizzly night
Peeping through my window
Is a fool in a uniform
of the Southern Manchuria Railway
Fifty sen for touching
Peeking is free
If you give me three yen
and 50 sen
I'll be with you
until the rooster crows
What kind of song is that?
A women's song.
Where'd you learn it?
Are you coming in or going home?
Please decide right now
If you're staying,
take off your sandals and come on in
Paper is expensive
these days, mister
My boss is watching
Tip me 50 sen
Then I'll hold you tight
And give you extra time
And stay with you
until the rooster crows
That's all.
Maybe I did kill Mr. Otake.
The gas hose was loose.
I could've saved him,
but I left him to die.
Give me 10 yen.
Will you tell that to Miss Tanigawa,
Mr. Otake's friend?
Will you?
She wants you to hurry over there.
You hear me?
We're calling the university.
Hey, I know who No. 469 is!
We're gonna go see
Mayuko Fujiwara.
Gentlemen, we're thinking
of publishing his writings.
What do you think?
We mustn't leave out
his study of mounted nomads.
Then we must include the political
essays from his student days.
No, there's no point.
Maybe his diary
from that period?
His political essays from back then
seem immature today.
He'd hate for them to be published.
His diaries really show
his state of mind
and the circumstances of the time.
- What about his letters?
- Absolutely.
Miss Tanigawa, you have
a lot of his letters, don't you?
Miss Tanigawa.
Leave her alone.
Give her some time.
We can talk to her later.
Gentlemen,
let's sing some more.
Guard the way ahead
Young friends
Join the students in their songs
Don't let the bright sun
and blue sky
Be clouded by the fires of war
Even an atomic bomb
Can't cast a shadow
upon our friendship
Our fighting spirit burns bright
We must struggle for peace
Strongly united
Guard the way ahead
One more...
to give his death meaning.
A battle fought
In the name of justice
O you valiant –
Enough!
What the hell is his death
supposed to mean?
What's wrong with you?
He died
on National Foundation Day
to protest the revival
of that reactionary holiday.
- Bullshit!
- No death is meaningful!
Some are!
Its meaning depends on us.
Cut the crap!
Son of a bitch!
You're insulting the dead!
- I am not!
- You are!
Think about how
Miss Tanigawa feels.
Remember the time and place
before you speak.
A cloud of atrocities
blocks out the light
The enemy's storm rages
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Stop it! That's enough!
Cut it out!
Would you all please leave now?
Is this where she lives?
Yes, No. 469.
Mayuko Fujiwara's house.
Are we going to see her?
It's a folk song rally
against the Vietnam War.
- What do we do?
- We've come this far.
We at least have to go in.
Won't they charge admission?
- We're here on business.
- Let's go back.
Not before we talk to her.
Then hurry up.
I'm worried about Nakamura.
Ueda, you're the only one
who's seen her.
I thought it was smaller.
Let's go.
Maybe we should sing too.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Hiroi!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Let's go on
to the second case, ho, ho!
to the third case, ho!
Doing it with an ugly girl, ho!
Shall we go?
Here she comes.
Ueda.
Hiroi.
Maruyama.
Maybe I'm to blame.
I'm saying
I may have killed Mr. Otake.
He was asleep
when I entered the room.
It was full of gas.
I could have turned off the gas.
I can't believe it.
Don't if you don't want to.
Then why'd you come here
to tell me that?
Excuse me.
I forgot something.
Mr. Otake.
What did you do then?
Mr. Otake!
Why didn't you turn off the gas?
You didn't want to save him,
did you?
You wanted him to die.
What on earth were you feeling?
I didn't feel anything.
Go on.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Stop it.
That's enough of that song.
- I sang it just like that.
- Liar.
Not at a time like that.
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
You liar!
Everything you're saying
is rubbish!
What should I do?
Will you repeat
the exams next year?
Maybe I'll worm my way
into a crap university.
Yeah, don't waste another year
studying for exams.
Easy for you to say.
You think you passed.
My folks won't send
any more money if I don't pass.
I'll have to work my way
through cram school.
That'd be rough.
What happened to Nakamura?
He said he thought he passed.
No, I mean right now.
I'm sure he's fine.
But he's at Mr. Otake's apartment.
- With that woman.
- With the dyed hair.
- They're talking.
- About what?
Are the trains still running?
They've gotta be.
The path you travel is endless
This one's in Japanese.
So why clench your teeth
in such effort?
Why go to such great lengths?
The person you loved is gone
I'll go find Nakamura,
even if I have to go alone.
He's probably gone by now.
I'll bet he's pulling a Lawrence
right now with some sweet talk.
He isn't pulling a Lawrence.
It's something more important.
You leaving?
No, I'm going to sing.
Why?
For Nakamura.
On a dark and drizzly night
Peeping through my window
Don't give up.
Now let's go on
to the second case, ho, ho!
When doing it with two sisters, ho!
Do the older one first, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the third case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an ugly girl, ho!
Cover her head with a bucket, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the fourth case, ho!
When doing it upstairs, ho!
Be quiet so you won't
be heard, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the fifth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with the same old girl, ho!
Do it the same old way, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the sixth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an old friend, ho!
Let's go on
to the eighth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with
a grocer's daughter, ho!
Use a pumpkin for a pillow, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the ninth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with the principal's
daughter, ho!
Be ready to be expelled, ho, ho!
Let's go on
to the tenth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with a blueblood, ho!
Do it in formal wear, ho, ho!
Is that all?
Let's go on
to the eleventh case, ho, ho!
Doing it with Takako Tanigawa, ho!
Stop it!
Are you coming in or going home?
Please decide right now
If you're staying,
take off your sandals and come on in
Paper is expensive
these days, mister
My boss is watching
Tip me 50 sen
Then I'll hold you tight
And give you extra time
And stay with you
until the rooster crows
Thank you.
I'm Ueda from Maebashi High.
I'm Maruyama.
- I'm Hiroi.
- We're –
You're a wonderful group.
Please enjoy yourselves.
Thanks for coming all this way.
Was that a new folk song?
Who wrote it?
Well, it's a –
African?
A Japanese folk song?
"The steam pump...
behind the steam pump
I let you have me.
That's when it began."
What's that?
"The assistant foreman would give me
a special assignment if I let him."
It's a women's song.
You always knew this would happen,
didn't you? Well, I –
- I didn't expect this.
- Not at all?
Who to do it with?
Who will do it with me?
What shall I do?
That's a song about
farm boys and girls, right?
You know what it means?
A man and woman can do it
out in the paddies.
Even in a boardinghouse.
- You're wrong.
It's not that easy
in a farming village or coal mine.
I did it in front of my dead teacher.
It's not usually that easy.
People had to make up a special song
to get into the spirit.
Just like you and I did.
I'm different.
Young female coal miners
used to wear white undergarments.
They called them mine shirts
and mine skirts.
The skirts only went
halfway down their thighs.
You could see their white legs
down to their knees.
The young girls
went dressed like that
every day and night
down into the deepest pits.
When the girls came up,
the boys went in.
The boys would tease the girls
by touching their thighs.
The girls would then slap their own thighs
and break out laughing.
Once there was a boy
entering the pit for the first time.
The girls made fun of him,
as they usually did.
The boy was beet-red
going down into the pit.
There was one young girl who took pity
and treated him kindly.
Though they never spoke, at some point
they began to nod to each other.
Who to do it with?
They only saw each other
inside the mine.
They snuck away and made love
in an old abandoned shaft.
When winter turned to spring,
she asked the boy
to meet her parents.
She was asking him to marry her.
Who will do it with me?
They planned to meet
above ground for the first time
so that he could meet
her parents.
What shall I do?
What do you think happened?
I don't really care
I don't know.
The pit was dark,
and the work was strenuous.
No matter how hard you worked,
disaster could strike at any moment.
No matter how great your love,
you could be separated at any moment.
You never knew
what the morning might bring.
Even the man who told me
this story died a sudden death.
Mr. Otake?
One spring seven years ago.
The next day,
the boy visited the girl's home.
The young woman had died.
- That day?
No. She'd died
before he'd ever met her.
Her parents told the young man
he'd seen her wandering soul.
Her soul, huh?
He was wedded to
the dead girl's mortuary tablet
and lived with her parents
ever after.
Was it all in his imagination?
In any case, he married
her mortuary tablet.
What did I imagine?
You imagined Mr. Otake's death,
but you should be over that by now.
I imagined something else.
You killed another person?
I raped a girl.
Maruyama, Ueda, Hiroi, and I
fantasized about raping a girl.
Who was she?
They've gone to tell her about it.
And then what?
I wonder that myself.
They went to tell her
they fantasized about raping her?
They're lascivious.
You know what that means?
Who is she?
Where is she?
She's probably prettier
than that female coal miner.
Let's go.
What for?
Let's go and see.
For their sake?
For the girl's sake?
For our sake.
Our sake?
Or more precisely,
for each of our sakes.
That dress!
Did they...
Sons of bitches!
What happened?
Stop singing!
Idiots!
Bastard!
Shall we go?
Let's sit down.
That's her, isn't it?
I wonder if they told her
about that fantasy.
You told her, didn't you?
That's why
this happened to Kaneda.
No, we couldn't do it.
Sorry about what happened.
Let's be friends.
Peaceful coexistence.
Drink this.
Nakamura.
Are you hurting?
You must be.
It's better to feel the pain,
Kaneda.
I don't feel anything anymore.
Even when Otake died,
I wasn't sure
I was really sad.
We'd been together seven years...
but we never married.
Of course
I dreamed about marrying him,
but it was nothing more
than a dream.
It wasn't because of differences
in thinking or lifestyle.
We no longer had
the time or place to feel pain.
If I'd married him,
he wouldn't have died.
If I'd been able to feel pain,
he'd still be alive.
I killed him.
Kaneda, don't forget
the pain you feel today.
Remember it all your life.
I wonder if she understood.
One dark and drizzly night
Peeping through my window
Is a fool in a uniform
of the Southern Manchuria Railway
Fifty sen for touching
Peeking is free
- That dress?
- It's hers.
In 1949, I was born.
In June of 1960,
I was born once again.
Women and blood.
Now, in 1967...
we're still in the hands of the gods.
The god of January 1st
gives life to a girl
who has no reason to live.
January 15.
The girl has a piece
of white paper in her hand,
but in a minute
it's snatched away.
The god of freezing February
teaches a girl how to love
and a boy how to die.
A black sun
Is rising
Spring in Japan
We raped you.
The four of us fantasized
about raping you.
On that day
The peach blossoms
withered and died
And the nightingale's
throat was torn
We raped you in that classroom.
Don't stop loving
We raped you
in the examination hall.
Don't let go of what you've found
We stripped you naked.
Believe us!
We raped you!
In freezing February
we learned how to love and die
Don't you believe us?
Stop it!
The festival of the black sun
is upon us
Spring in Japan
Plunder the festival
Shoot at the sun
With tender love
and cold, hard death
Let's go to that imaginary
classroom of yours.
Please begin.
Exactly as you imagined it.
2,627 years ago,
on February 11,
Emperor Jimmu was crowned
first emperor of Japan
at Kashiwara Shrine in Yamato.
He was dubbed
"founding emperor of the land."
But there was another emperor
who was given that title:
Emperor Sujin,
the tenth emperor.
The Kojiki says Emperor Sujin
had yet another name:
"the founding emperor
from Mimaki."
Mimaki means "Mima Castle" –
the imperial palace in Mima.
Let's begin
with the first case, ho, ho!
Doing it with an only daughter, ho!
Where was Mima?
Mima, or "Imna" in Korean,
is in modern-day South Korea.
"Princess Kushinada,
pregnant with child,
sought a suitable place
in which to give birth.
She came to Japan
and proclaimed,
'What a deep valley!
I shall call it Bear Valley.'"
The father of
Princess Kushinada's child
was Prince Susanoo.
When he went to slay
the eight-headed serpent Orochi,
he turned Kushinada into a comb,
placed her in his hair,
and set off.
According to the Nihon Shoki,
Susanoo once traveled
to the kingdom of Silla.
It's said he traveled from there
to the Hi River in Izumo.
Silla... or present-day South Korea.
From the third
to the fifth centuries,
mounted nomads from Manchuria,
Mongolia, and North China
poured into the Korean peninsula
with horses and new weapons,
and then into Japan, landing in
northern Kyushu or western Honshu.
The Izumo clan,
centered around Izumo Shrine,
had created a culture
of wealth and leisure.
The Izumo Shrine
rose high into the sky,
nearly twice as tall as the Marunouchi
Building in modern Tokyo.
Yet the mounted nomads
chased off the members
of the Izumo clan
and sent the shrine
crashing into the Sea of Japan.
The Japanese come from Korea!
During the Taika Reforms,
Prince Naka no Oe drew his sword
and murdered Soga no Iruka
in the imperial palace.
After witnessing this carnage,
Prince Furuhito staggered
back to his chambers
and said to his aide,
"The man from Han has killed
the saddler. I'm filled with grief."
"The saddler"
referred to Soga no Iruka.
"Han" was the name
they used for Korea.
"The Korean
has killed Soga no Iruka."
Why would he be
filled with grief?
The Taika Reforms
were really a revolution
in which the Yamato Court,
descended from Koreans,
wiped out the Izumo clan's power,
laying the foundation
for the perpetual rule
of the mounted nomads in Japan.
Let's go on
to the tenth case, ho, ho!
Doing it with a blueblood, ho!
Do it in formal wear, ho, ho!
Take me instead of her.
Wait.
I'm the one they imagined raping.
Don't pretend otherwise.
Show me if you can really do it.
Go ahead.
Fucking bitch!
Is that it?
It's real this time...
right?
THE END
Subtitles by
Subtext Subtitling, Los Angeles