Korean State Film studio
TEEN GUERILLAS
Directed by Yoon Yong-Gyu
Screenplay by Yoon Doo-hyun
Cinematographer Zak Ken Won
Music by Lee Kun Do
Starring
Choi Chang Yong - Teck Syk Сhin
Syn Kim Hwang - Kim Byung Yong
Lee Kwi Nam - Tien Duc Chi
Song Ho Min - Ben Tian Yong
Pak Ben Cheer - Teng Chang Hwan
Telephonist - Pen Chan Suk
Secretary of the district committee of the
The Labour Party - Son Min Nam
Ban Ki-hoon, a teacher - Kim Se Yong
The commander of the People's Army, Kim Eun Bae
Mother of Lee Kwi-nam - Moon E Bon
Kil Yon, brother of Lee Nam Kmi - Lee De Hong
Grandfather Chan Yong Choi - Do Kim Po
Commandant - Kim Gore
His assistant - Om Muck
The police chief of Syngman Rhee
- Tok Eun Ki
Kang Tae-Gu, a traitor - De Un Hyong
October
They say, our troops will leave the town by night.
Are the Americans going to come here, guys?
All the youth is leaving town. What are we going to do?
All the elder lads join the army.
Yes! Lucky ones. They are accepted, and we are not.
They say: grow older, someone should stay here.
That’s right. We stay here not just to watch them.
Scoundrels! What do they need in our land?
Brutes!
Revenge! We should revenge!
They’ll pay for this!
Look, guys, and remember everything
that they do here.
- We should stay and revenge!
- We must not leave.
We we’ll stay as guerillas.
Guys! We are pioneers!
Yes! We should struggle to the end.
This is how the Labour Party teaches us.
Let’s tell our teacher about it.
Right! Let’s visit him and tell him,
that we want to become guerillas,
soldiers of Kim Il-sung
They stay here. They want to help our struggle.
I know, they are brave guys.
You know them from school. Can we trust them?
Yes! They are sons of workers. All of them are pioneers
they are certainly reliable.
I think, it depends on the way they’re
organized and guided.
I charge you with that, comrade Park.
- I assume, they have thought up this decision
well. - We should support the boys.
- Comrade secretary!
- Yes. Who’s that?
- Head of the district committee.
- How many people do you have?
Uh? Thirty. That’s good!
You’ll help us get the.
Wait in the agreed place in thirty minutes.
You’ll have to take direction of the second guerilla squad,
but don’t forget about the boys.
Yes! I will fulfil the task of
the party committee.
Remember: the success of a guerilla squad
depends mostly on severe military discipline.
- Keep contact with the population. The population
will always support you. - Yes!
Yes? And the Sam Dong factory?
Seventeen people more?
Eighteen? Has everyone that are going to leave with me arrived?
Not yet? Move along and report the full list
by number 20.
Who is the smartest of these boys?
Choi Yong Chan is. He’s their leader.
He’s a very clever lad.
Is he the one whose father was killed by
the Japanese on the factory?
Yes, and he is so persistent. Just like
his father. He helped me at school.
He’s a good leader. I think he will
be very helpful to us.
Very good. Well, he should be a liaison.
- We decided to stay.
- Did the teacher approve this?
- Yes, he knows.
- Will you work together? It’s good!
Yes! This evening I’ll tell you everything. See you!
- Are you leaving? - Yes. Lots of
fighters have found asylum at our side.
Are you leaving not for long, right?
- Do you think, they are retreating for no reason?
- I know. That’s why I’m not going to leave.
Our side can only win! It can’t be other way.
Chang Yong is right. It’s not just a retreat.
We’ll come back here tomorrow by order.
Our people can’t be defeated.
Our people will stand for itself.
This retreat is a temporary strategic retreat.
Don’t worry. We will show these Americans!
- We’ll gather ourselves and start beating them stronger.
We’ll be back soon. - I think so, too.
- Struggle, too! Don’t lose courage.
- Yes!
- We’ll try to come back faster!
- Right! We will act, too!
- It’s time to go. So long!
- Mother, faster!
- Take this for the road.
- Thank you!
- See you soon. - Come back, we are waiting for you.
- Watch yourself. - Good luck.
- Why does our army retreat?
- It’s needed. They know better when
to retreat and when to attack.
- Did you get to know the situation?
- Yes, yes, the situation is hard.
We have ascertained that most of the population
are workers, the red ones. They are influenced by the Labour party.
Uh... We’re in trouble again.
Did you catch many communists?
- Yes, about 150.
- Why so few?
It’s hard to get the information. The population
is hostile to Americans.
I know one man, Kang Tae-Sik,
he can be helpful to us.
Who is he?
He is from this place, under the Japanese
he had his own rice mill in the town.
I think, he’s quite reliable.
He hates communists. He is dreaming of his own land.
I think he’s quite easy to buy. May I bring him here?
Certainly, now!
What do you think of your own land?
Yes, I think it’s good, I think about land
and about myself, too, erm.
- Do you know that land is not
free? - Uh?
If you agree to work for our UN forces...
… you will get the land, and if you’re eager
enough, you will get lots of money.
Yes, mister commandant, I’m at your service.
Have you remembered our words?
Yes, I did. I remember them well.
- Captain!
- Yes?
- We have 150 arrested.
- Yes!
- All the communists must be killed this nights.
- It will be done, sir commandant.
- Guard commandant should be strengthened!
- Yes, sir. Increase security.
And look, captain, pay special attention
to the communication.
Good! It will be done, sir commandant.
- First! Hello! Hello!
Operator Moon.
Yes? Fifty? Yes? Fifty? Yes? Eighty-fifth? I connect.
- Hey! Stop!
- Hey! Girl!
- Too many people were arrested, Mom!
- Hmm?
How do you think, is Gil Yon gone?
I don’t know. The special department evacuated
employees. I think he managed to leave.
Son, if someone will ask you,
tell that you know nothing.
You bet! I won’t tell them anything!
Stop! Here’s another one...
Her son was a member of the Labour party.
They lived well.
Now, perhaps, she doesn’t like it very much.
Everything comes to an end.
Where Yong Kil, answer quickly!
How do we know. He left the house long ago,
I don’t know where he has gone.
I warn you, I don’t believe this.
You’d better tell me everything you know.
How can we know where brother is?
I have nothing to say.
Ha! He didn’t even call on his
mother to say goodbye?
I have nothing to say.
Get her immediately! Now you’ll see!
You have no right!...
We need to teach her a lesson.
She’s forgotten everything.
Lucky hunt! Look, old chap, what a rooster I’ve got!
You have a rooster, and I have a hen.
Soup and stew.
- Do you see this? - Yeah!
Hello, girl!
Hello! Stop! Stop!
Hold on, babe!
Hello! Are you scared?
Wait, wait, why hurry?
Oh! She’s impolite.
We arrived in Korea by decision of the United Nations
and by orders of Commander MacArthur.
From now on you will live freely and happily.
We have taken the security of your life.
We brought a lot of products that
we’ll distribute to your people.
In America we love freedom and order.
Now we Americans have come to clean up
here in your land. But you should know ...
We will sweep away anyone who interferes.
We know that many of you enjoyed
living under the communist government.
We know that many of you have always
been on the communist side.
To these people we will be merciless.
Scoundrels!
Everyone of you have read my order
in which I worn you
that everyone who confesses in their guilt
will get land, money and honour.
But we will not have mercy upon those
who will stand against us.
I appeal to you to help us in bringing an order here
just like in our free America.
Americans are murderers! Everything
they write is a lie!
- Neighbour! I’m looking for you!
It’s amazing! - What’s up?
- Americans hung out a declaration. - Yeah.
- And someone wrote on it. - What?
- Americans are murderers! - Of course
they are. They’re deceiving us.
Yes! Their declarations and orders are lies!
It’s all the guerillas. We’ve got to wait
a real thing from them now.
- Tell me, neighbour?
- Mm?
Did you hear anything about Kil Yong’s family?
I think I didn’t. Why?
Americans arrested them. We should
get rid of Kang Tae-Sik.
Don’t you want to say where’s your son?
Why don’t you speak?
What can I say? I know nothing.
Well done!
Does she still keep pretending?
So? Don’t you want to speak with us?
You will respond for all the crimes.
The day will come!
Преступления? Это ты, ты растила такого
сына преступника, коммуниста.
Crimes? It’s you who grew such a son -
a criminal, a communist!
Oh! Kil Yong!
Well, so? Do you recognize your son? Uh?
Kil Yong, my dear! What did they do to you?
Calm down! I’m not afraid of them.
They can torture me and kill me,
but they won’t know anything.
I’ve completed the task of the party.
No, mother, I’m not afraid to die.
It’s only a pity for me that I won’t
live to see the day
when Korean land will be free
from murderers and traitors.
Brother, remember, the Americans and Syngman Rhee
soldiers are the most cruel enemies of our people.
All of them must be killed.
Shut up! Take him away immediately!
Scoundrels! You’re selling your Motherland!
American dogs!
You can not escape from the judgement of our nation.
The time will come and you will answer for
all your crimes and treason.
Jerk! He threatens you ... remove him!
What are you looking at?
Well, he won’t have to speak anymore.
He said it all. My son is a communist,
he is not afraid of death.
But you are afraid, you know that he's right,
and you fear of the truth.
Shut up! Otherwise I’ll finish you, too!
You can kill me, but you should know,
I'm proud that I raised such a son,
brave, courageous and
devoted to his homeland.
And you have sold yourself to Americans.
You will pay for that!
Do you think that everything can be
achieved with the force of arms?
But all the people can not shoot.
Homeland will curse your name.
You will be despised and hated
by all the pe...
Mom! Mom! Mom!
I’m standing on the mountain-ridge,
bloodstains everywhere...
They follow every my step,
bloodstains everywhere
Bloodstains on the helmets of those
who went to fight for Korea...
Everyone sees these stains,
red signs of blood.
O how do we love
the name of Changun!
Our native name of
Kim Il Sung, Changun!
I saw how they shot my mother.
They tortured our Kil Yong.
He said nothing, he remained faithful
to the people, even under torture.
They came to our peaceful country and
they kill our fathers, our mothers, our brothers.
Murderers! They bring death to our people.
They destroyed the school that we loved.
I will take revenge, friends, and
I’ll fight to the last breath.
I will take revenge knowing no rest, for my mother,
for my brother, for our people. I will take revenge!
You are right. We will fight aggressively,
and the we have the power.
But, guys, we should fight in an organized way.
The most important is to accurately perform
all the tasks of the elder guerrillas.
And now let's talk together about
how we should make our work.
Guys, I suggest to choose
Chan Yong as our commander.
- That's right!
Alright, guys! The Khan Chan guerilla squad
has started their work!
First, in the squad we should have
the strictest discipline.
Don’t forget that we are surrounded by enemies.
Without the discipline the squad
will perish immediately.
In the school you have seen the movie, called
“The Young Guard” about the soviet children.
They struggled bravely for their Motherland, and
stayed devoted to it until the end, we should follow them.
We will keep secret sacredly. That’s the second clause.
And the third clause is to help our fellow
guerillas always and everywhere.
It’s our honourable duty.
So vow to fight, selfless hard, maintaining
a strict discipline,
helping the elders and
sacredly keeping the secret of the squad.
- A squad of young guerrillas! We swear, guys!
- We swear! - We swear!
We swear that we will
be true guerrillas.
And now, planning.
It is necessary to make friends with somebody
in the commandment
to get information from there.
We should gain their confidence.
They should trust us very much.
Organize a group of kids for
cleaning yards and streets.
I ask to entrust it to me.
Here you are! Have a look, they clean it good.
You can check it out.
Cleanliness, order! You can not worry.
You should clean several times a day.
Of course! It's easy!
Try to work as it should.
Well, sorry for the dust.
Our valiant people's army retreated temporarily.
The day is near when it will return.
Curse of the traitors! They will not escape the court!
Not one handful of grain to the enemy!
Such flyers appear in broad daylight!
They write they’re not afraid! Well,
the Americans will get what they deserve soon!
Commandment?
Write down. The password for this night - Han Gan.
Answer - Taedong.
I repeat. Han Gan - Taedong.
Stop! Password.
- Han Gan.
- Taedong.
- In the nearby village a bridge was blown up.
- It’s the guerrillas.
They don’t let the Americans sleep well.
It’s definitely the guerillas. We get new proclamations
everyday. It’s not without purpose.
- You'll see, soon it all will end.
- They are afraid as hell even now.
What are you talking about here?
Is that forbidden?
I’m asking you.
Why are you bothering?
You are tired of life, right?
We were not talking about something illegal.
You dare!
You have few time for bullying.
Yes, surely.
It’s the communists, their work.
Are you sleeping? Why can't you catch these communists?
What does your police do?
Answer! You’re the chief!
The police are at the communist side!
Mr. Commandant! I swear ...
I know everything. But now
I can not believe you.
I can’t trust the police, which is led by the nose!
Telegraph doesn’t work again. Order number 18
hasn’t been transferred.
Look! Who’s destroying the
connection every day?
How to do now? What to do?
You are responsible for the connection.
I’ll check it in 20 minutes. Go.
Does it work?
No, it doesn’t.
I give you five minutes.
It’s the matter of your life.
Yes?
The line is not working yet. No.
Stop being ceremonious.
Liquidate the communists.
Yes! I will take action immediately,
you can be sure.
You will get a reward.
Yes!
They say, you keep connection
with the communists.
Me? No, you’re joking.
They’re dashing about the town.
Why aren’t you catching them?
You said you knew them all.
Yes, I did. And I do my best.
Tell, why everyday the connection falls
and some leaflets appear?
I know what to do, all the relatives
of the communists should be arrested.
Good! That’s a good idea!
But if it doesn’t work, that’s your fatal problem.
Good! I’ll try my best, you can trust me.
- Guvnor! Where are you going? To arrest someone again?
- Yes! I’ve had not enough sleep..
- Ah! And what street?
- Ask Kang Tae-Sik!
- Run away everyone!
- Come on! Go!
Leave! Quickly!
Go! Hurry!
Come on! Why are you standing? Pass!
- Murderers. But one can’t kill all the people.
- American rats, scoundrels!
Don’t talk. Pass.
Sit still. Otherwise you’ll be executed.
- Did they torture you?
- Yes, they did.
Silence! Silence! Comrades, please, be quiet!
Did you hear what he said?
Why did they take us?
I don’t know, maybe because
I wasn’t licking his boots.
They have few time,
our day is going to come.
Be quiet. It’s going to come, that’s for sure.
Forty people were shot.
Barbarians!
What do you need in our land?
Why did you come here?
Why did you kill my child?
Look at him!
Let it be your shame forever.
What? What do you want?
Isn’t it enough that I catch them?
Why should I kill them, too?
Nevermind! You’ll cope with that.
Don’t you think its difficult? It’s just “Bang!” - and it’s over.
But you forgot the guerillas.
You just sit to have a drink, and then they
appear out of nowhere - and you’re gone.
I want to live well, to get my
mill and land.
It happens to everyone who betrays
his Motherland and serves the Americans.
- Are they coming?
- Yes, they’ve passed the turning.
- Here they are.
Attention, guys! Get ready!
Hurry up, comrades!
Go to the mountains, comrades...
Hurry up, comrades! There’s no time to lose.
To the mountains!
Run faster! Run faster!
Hurry, hurry, comrades.
Hurry, comrades! To the mountains!
Hurry! Hurry! Run!
Quickly run, hurry, comrades!
To the mountains!
- Teacher!  - I’m glad to see you!
- Me too!
- Are things going fine?  - Yes.
- Let’s go, tell me about it!
Tell the guys that most of the people whom
you set free are in our guerilla squad.
You were right about Kang Tae-Sik.
Go on and on, you should know that
you help us very much.
People of our squad thank you
for very brave action.
The secretary of the Committee said
that he’s proud of such true guerillas as you.
He wants you to connect with Moon Ying Sun -
- the telephone operator.  - Yes!
They have a lot of grenades and machine guns.
Everything the squad gets will be given to the guerillas.
Good!
It will be useful.
But be careful. - Yes!
It’s very dangerous.
The guys shouldn’t get caught.
Yes! I will check it myself.
Good.
Inform the people about the message
from the headquarters.
I will do that immediately!
Listen! People’s Army have completely
destroyed six divisions of the enemy.
Yes! The guys will be happy!
It means that the army is already close.
Guvnor!
Do you have a son?
Shut up. I have no son.
And do you have a mother?
I have no one. Don’t bother me.
I want to have some sleep.
Comrades, in the enemy’s rear our
guerilla squads
have achieved serious success.
Brave and fast actions of the guerillas
support our army greatly.
Young guerilla squad of Hangu
helped us very much in these actions.
Recently they’ve recaptured the arrestants
who were conducted to the execution.
There are many our people in town’s prison,
we should save them at any price.
Comrades! Guerillas! The military-political situation
has changed in our favour.
We have already assumed the offensive. Don’t let the enemy
have any rest. Beat them and get them away from our land.
Is it heavy?
Nevermind! And to you?
I wanted to carry twice more.
Do you know how our guerillas will get happy
when we bring them this armour? And if Sin Khan will cope with his mission...
I’m sure that he will definitely complete
his task and get the armour.
Of course! He’s a brave guy!
We will bring it and get back. And tomorrow we will
take some more and bring it again.
Yes, we won’t even sleep!
We should save him...
We can’t help...
Whatever happens, I’ll go there.
But you won’t save him! You can’t!
They are coming! Let’s go!
Well, did he confess?
No, he’s silent! He makes no sound!
Did you cope with the boy?
I couldn’t cope. We did everything we could.
You can’t get anything with torture and
threat. There must be something different.
You don’t want to speak?
Maybe you’ll tell me?
Who teached you?
Well, don’t worry!
Think again and tell me everything.
Don’t be stubborn.
We know that you completed someone’s orders.
I will order to free you now. I know, you’re
a honest boy, you will confess...
Alright, stop pretending.
I know where I am.
I’m a young pioneer of the Republic,
and you won’t get anything from me.
Here you are! Well, you will feel sorry for that!
I think you’ve got not enough torture!
So, how’s the boy?
No result yet, but I hope...
What does it mean you hope?
They have agreed not to speak.
Even in case of torture.
Ha! It seems you already like them!
Why, captain? I’ve seen many
such lads.
They’re not afraid of anything. They’re all the same.
They should be shot immediately.
We should make him confess
where his accomplices are.
You’ll have plenty of time to get him shot.
Get him here.
We, americans, like young people. Oh!
Sit down, please! Your leg hurts, doesn’t it?
Do you want to be friends with me?
Oh! I know you’ve been deceived.
Leave, if you want to.
I let you go, but you must tell the truth. Who
taught you? Do you understand me, boy?
You must answer, when someone asks you a question.
Yes, I took armour to beat
the enemy.
Who’s your enemy, boy?
Americans! You are the first one!
Who told you so?
Tortures and suffer, blood of our fathers
and mothers who were executed here.
Did you act by yourself, boy?
Yes! But I have friends!
Who are your friends?
All our people, we hate the occupants
and we will make them leave soon!
How dare you!
Leave! Hands of Korea! All! What do you need here?
Our people despise you!
Be silent!
We won’t get anything from this lad.
You can do whatever you want,
don’t be ceremonious!
Yes! Americans are asassins!
Our people know that you’re not ceremonious,
but you’ll have to answer for that!
Until all of you get out of here, you should
know, we’ll never get calm.
I may die, but my people will take revenge for me.
You won’t leave alive!
We didn’t rescue him.
Don’t cry! There was no other way. We had no ability
to save him. What could we do?
We should take revenge for him...
- A misfortune happened! - What’s up?
- Our comrade Sin Khan... - What?
- Was executed... - Ah!
Sin Khan died as a true hero.
Killed by these assassins...
He won’t see our victory, but
it’s no use to be cast down, friends!
We will struggle with more strength and courage!
Yes! Listen, here’s the message from our teacher...
Our troops and chinese volunteers
pushed the enemy past the Chhunihonchan river.
Our troops are not far.
In 100 kilometers.
Now, guys, there will be more work.
Guerilla troops are already moving towards.
Our squad should get ready, too.
Well, friends, we have few time to wait!
- Wait! What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
I’m beating your ace of spades with a trump card.
I have no spades.
You are cheating! Isn’t that a spade?
I won’t play with you! Why are you
looking in my cards?
- Start another round now.
- How come? Game is over.
No. How did you change my card the last time?
Start all over again.
You are sleeping! While you are sleeping,
the commies are acting! The connection is broken!
Yes! They broke our devices.
How long will it go on?
- Repair immediately!
- Yes, but how...
Shut up! Carry out your orders!
Yes! Sir commandant!
You are doing it so slowly!
Why can’t you do it faster?
- We’re trying our best, captain.
- If you don’t want to work, you will fight.
- We can’t do it faster.
- I’m not talking to you. It should be done in an hour.
- Look what they’ve done!
- Don’t make any objections, idlers!
The People’s army and Chinese volunteers are pressing
and destroying the troops of American invaders.
Beat the retreating enemy to the end!
- I have no more leaflets.
- Neither do I.
- We should wait for a sign.
Break it up! I'll shoot!
The People's Army is coming!
Your slavery will end soon!
- Our troops are not far!
- Yes, they should come in time to save the people.
I’m from the headquarters. Today you should leave the town
before ten o’clock.
Our army is threatened with encirclement by
the troops of the People’s army, Chinese volunteers and guerillas.
Retreat!
You’re nuts!
- Our army is encircled from three sides,
sir commandant. - Oh dear!
- Only the south is free, hurry up!
- You could inform us earlier. - No!
- Captain! - Yes!
- Did you hear? Give an order
for immediate retreat. - Yes!
- Yes, just like this. - Yes!
We have no time to lose. All the arrestants
should be executed immediately.
Sir commander, the intelligence discovered that
the town garrison is retreating.
… the guerillas have cut down all the ways for a retreat.
…there’s only the punitive squad that has the order
to execute all the people in prison. There are
many children, women and old men.
Well! Comrades chiefs of squads!
Attention! Listen to my command!
- The first section comes in from north-east,
the second section from the north. The attack is by the sign.
- Yes!
- The third section joins the guerilla squad and cut down
the ways for retreat and not let them go to the mountains. - Yes!
- The fourth section follows me to the town. - Yes!
Hey, you!  Get up!
Come out! We’re setting you free!
Get out fast! Why are you messing around?
Comrades! Comrades! Comrades!
- Grandfather, do you recognize me?
- Erm. Is this you, darling?
- Hello, my friend!
- Comrade commander!
- Well! I said we’ll be back.
- Hello, grandfather!
- Thank you so much for saving us!
- You got here in time! They were planning to execute
all of us! - Yes, we know.
Comrades! All the tortures and suffering, that
you have to live though during the American occupation, are over.
You were set free by glorious fighters of
the People’s army and local guerilla squads from your town.
Hooray! Hooray!
Comrades! Korean People’s Army in cooperation with
squads of Chinese volunteers surrounds the
enemy and destroys it.
In some sectors of the front our army have already
assumed the offensive.
Ура! Ура-а!
Hooray! Hooray!
Comrades! Soon we’ll free all our land from the
American invaders! Forward to our victory!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
- It’s the chief of the police!
- Got him! - Kill him, kill him!
- Death! - Beat him!
- Kill!
- Wait! We should settle it another way!
- Let me.
- Well, now we will get the enemy off our land.
Will we meet? - Of course!
- Mother! Faster, faster!
Thank you!
Goodbye, my friends!
Stand! Dress! Attention!
To the left!
Forward, march!
Our secretary wants to see you.
He’s waiting. Let’s go!
The county committee of our Labor Party
is grateful for the dedicated work
to the glorious squad of the young guerillas.
Bold heroic struggle of your squad encourages
Korean youth. It will struggle with our enemies with more strength.
It is painful to realize that Sin Khan is not with us today.
He is killed by these butchers.
But his name will never be forgotten by our people,
and we will take revenge for him.
Friends! Today we are assuming the attack, and
we won’t stop until enemy troops leave our land.
You were good at war, but now you have to study more
and more. Exactly as it is demanded by our people and
our leader Kim Il Sung.
Our squad is indebted to you, sir secretary,
the party committee and our teacher, who led us.
Our squad has fought with the enemy in the name
of the Motherland. All the children of Korea want peace
and stand for peace in our land.
The End.