Marc2008 (2009), The Netherlands
Soldaat van Oranje - Soldier of Orange (1977).avi
After five dark, anxious years
the sun breaks through.
The Dakota bringing home
Queen Wilhelmina...
...lands in a free country.
It is a stirring moment
as the door opens.
Resolute and confident,
the Queen sets foot on Dutch soil.
After a warm welcome by
civilian and military authorities...
...Her Majesty leaves the airport.
A jubilant nation greets
its Sovereign Queen.
Her triumphant return
to The Hague.
Highlight of these first weeks
of liberation.
Without pomp, accompanied
by a single aid...
...Her Majesty passes
the cheering crowds.
Noordeinde Palace awaits her
at the end of the route.
Once more flying
the Dutch flag.
Children greet her with flowers.
As Queen Wilhelmina arrives
at her palace...
...the realization that the House
of Orange is home again...
...fills the hearts
of the Dutch people with joy.
SOLDlER OF ORANGE
Get inside freshmen!
Come with me!
Climb!
Hello, I'm Jack Ten Brink, sir.
Prick, you mean.
- Prick, sir.
- Up, Prick!
What do you think of Hitler?
Filthy exhibitionist!
He builds good motorways.
Are you for or against the sod?
Hitler's a bloody bastard.
Let him go!
Piss off!
May I introduce myself?
Jack Ten Brink.
You might know the name.
My father's on the Council.
Two more shirkers.
I'm Jack Ten Brink.
- Alex.
- Eric.
- Were they hard on you?
- I've been here a while.
Someone made me say
Hitler is a bastard.
- Must have been a Jew.
- Can we stay here this long?
They have three weeks.
Enough time for a game of cards.
Freshmen to the dining room!
On your butts!
- Jesus, dinner time!
- The Council.
Everybody rise!
Down on the floor!
On your belly,
prick to the floor!
And stay down.
Sit, sit, sit. Everybody!
And eat, eat, eat!
Bring them here.
Filthy shirkers!
You lot are in for it!
- Shirking, were you?
- No, sir.
- Perhaps you'd rather go home?
- I'd like to stay, sir.
- Would you?
- Yes, sir.
Sing for us.
Hum along.
Off key!
And again.
Off key.
Again.
Mr. President,
this is a grave matter.
He's bleeding.
Hi, Eric.
Can you drink this yet?
Of course.
Hi, Esther.
I'll stay put if you don't mind.
Eight stitches.
- Unbelievable.
- What happened?
It's a long story.
- We were...
- Not now, Eric.
- We're off to play tennis.
- No.
Tell us.
Well, it was the first evening...
- Hello, ma'am.
- Good morning.
...puts it on my head
and starts hitting it.
Wham, wham...
...and I kept singing.
Eric, you have a visitor.
The President.
Don't get up, Lanshof.
Your head after all.
Just a few stitches.
Telling your young friends
about university life?
- Well...
- I'd like a chat with you, Lanshof.
Please sit down, sir.
You were off!
Are you coming?
My apologies for last night.
It was uncalled for.
It was nothing...
It was my fault. Is that beer?
Would you like some?
I intend to look after you.
There's a vacant room
at my place. Want it?
Yes, thank you.
Your health, Lanshof.
Your health, sir.
- Call me Gus in the future.
- Right, sir.
Prick.
Thanks.
- Good, I'll copy them.
- You should attend lectures.
Mr. Particular.
You sound like my mother.
- I missed you today.
- I was boxing.
- Eric's at home.
- I don't blame him.
Shall we go up for a drink?
Let's surprise him.
On my shoulders.
Nico? Or are you afraid?
No.
Come along with us.
How's the sherry?
Disgusting.
- I've got something stronger.
- Nice.
Give us a hand.
Alex!
Pull!
- Gus might like a drink too.
- Call him, will you?
Gus!
Who's slinking about?
Professor Ten Brink.
I don't slink.
I was at Professor Teilders.
A prelim.
I passed!
A present...
...from my old man.
- That's a good one.
- A Leica.
German.
Excellent make.
- Want some?
- No, coffee. I'm in training.
I'll order some.
- One coffee!
- Hello, chaps.
- A drink?
- Please, one.
Take my chair.
- How's your love life?
- I can't keep the landlady off me.
- Good looking?
- A figure...
One coffee.
For this gentleman, Greta.
We'll take a photo.
Move closer together.
I'm going to Germany for
a few weeks. Like to come?
No way. Trainloads of Jews
arrive here every day.
- I don't like swimming upstream.
- Cut it out, will you?
Don't move.
Sit still. Watch the birdie.
It's coming!
As the nun said to the bishop.
Glass, glass!
Four, three...
...two, one...
Your health!
- Eric's good.
- You're better.
- Yes, at tennis.
- You should've played.
Guard duty.
Shut up!
Gus is a poor loser.
War!
- Jesus, war.
- Oh, the English...
We'll be neutral, as usual.
Don't be so damn stupid.
- What's with him?
- He's a Jew.
- I never noticed.
- Prick.
- What was the score?
- Deuce.
Come on, Nico.
Turn off the radio, Robby.
Pencil!
Look, he can write.
May 9th...
... 1940.
What's the time?
- How's the army?
- A lot of wimps.
We could beat the Papuans.
Nothing will happen.
Do you mind?
Yes. A spot of war
would be quite exciting.
Gentlemen, it's time.
Robby!
We must be off.
Nico will take us to the station.
Mr. Particular.
Coming with us?
She wants to stay.
We'll get her home. Right, Eric?
- No problem.
- Well, Es?
I'd like to stay a while.
We'll show you out.
See you next week.
Let's get going, Robby!
Off we go!
Bye, darling.
Why aren't you in the army?
Bad eyes. Everything's
fuzzy at a distance.
But close up I see
everything, perfectly.
Robby and I are getting
engaged next year.
Congratulations.
- Lucky devil.
- Who?
Both of you.
Want to dance?
Airplanes.
Are they ours?
We don't have that many.
Jerries.
Going to England.
Stop!
What do you want?
- We've come to volunteer.
- You must be mad!
- They're Jerries in disguise.
- We're Dutch.
Have them say 'sch'.
Germans can't pronounce it.
Scheveningen. Scheveningen!
Schele, schoonmoeder,
Scheveningen.
Let them through.
Eric, here.
We've come to volunteer.
Come back in ten days.
Officials!
We want to help.
Come back in ten days.
Ten days is quite reasonable.
- lt'll be over by then!
- The last war lasted 4 years.
Come back in ten days.
Come on.
Come on, Eric.
- See you in ten days!
- Or sooner!
Been to a party, have you?
Yes, a party.
With schnapps and women?
Let's pay and go.
A tip even. Decent of them.
A fifteen minute rest!
Lieutenant.
- My folks live here, may I visit them?
- Go ahead.
Come in.
- You can shoot the lot of them.
- The damn traitors.
Dirty fascist.
- Hello, Mother.
- Hello, Son.
Bunch of idiots.
Just because your mother's German.
Stupid. Stupid!
They think they can defeat Germany.
They'll pay when we get out.
The lot of them.
And how.
- You don't have it so bad.
- We'll see.
Did you hear about the Queen?
She fled to England.
And you have to fight.
German paratroopers!
Behind those wooden shacks.
- What's up?
- Paratroopers.
Look, there.
Check it out.
Cover us.
Wounded.
Jesus, what are you up to?
There's a war on.
So what?
April fool!
That's Dirk.
There's a madhouse nearby.
I fooled you! April fool!
Attention! Salute!
What's going on?
False alarm about paratroopers,
General.
The war is over.
Rotterdam's been flattened.
Thousands of casualties.
We've surrendered.
Surrendered...
- But it just started.
- It's over.
The politicians and collaborators
betrayed us.
But it's not our fault.
Holland can be proud of its army.
Men, I thank you!
Now what?
Line up!
In position.
Put it down.
In the water.
Go!
Come back, that's dangerous.
Do you want some more sand?
- Jerry slut.
- Mommy's boy.
You're attracting attention.
It's free.
There's Eric.
Outboard motor.
Gasoline.
Put some in.
- The forecast?
- Calm sea.
Good, or I'll puke my guts out.
Sure stinks.
Hope the Jerries don't smell it.
Screw it on tight.
Stand still.
Hey, bastards!
Fine little boat.
Sherry from Pa, cheese from
my mother for the trip.
- Got the charts?
- Couldn't get them.
You said you would.
There's only one England
and it's there.
No, it's there.
Why aren't you coming?
Someone's got to do
the dirty work here.
You're just afraid.
Let's leave it at that then.
Your health.
Celebrating something?
Alex!
- How about a swim?
- Good idea.
Haven't seen much of you lately.
At home. My parents
have had a tough time.
Who hasn't?
Call in some time.
Alex, I like you, but visiting
your parents is a bit much.
I'll see you around.
That's all we needed.
- The dirty fascist.
- Alex is a fine fellow.
- I smell petrol.
- What time do we leave?
The beach will be deserted
in an hour.
In two days we'll be in London.
Knock on wood.
- It's a sturdy boat.
- One leak and you've had it.
What can go wrong?
The petrol!
Let's get out of here!
Hello, Robby.
How about that Robby?
Hangs the wash for his mother.
You'll ask the English
to come and get me?
- Is that it?
- In code.
- Really?
- Yes!
I can hardly signal:
'Will London come for Mr. Lanshof?'
lsn't it dangerous?
If I keep it brief...
...the Jerries can't locate it.
We hope.
- A potentiometer.
- Want to measure my potency?
Good morning.
I'll make contact.
- How do they know it's you?
- I use a code.
I always begin with L-O-V-E.
Love.
Guess why.
Go!
She's on to something.
It stopped.
- Well?
- You can go.
- As a courier.
- Meaning?
Getting stuff from my group across.
That's fantastic.
When?
I'll let you know.
lmagine, me helping you!
Not a big area.
Next time he transmits...
...he hangs.
You seem to be very happy.
Did you tell Eric
about our engagement?
That's why you're
called LOVE.
- It's a tennis term.
- What are you talking about?
It's the best news
I've heard in years.
Let me know.
UNlVERSlTY EXCLUDES JEWS
Read Volk en Vaderland.
Volk en Vaderland!
Hey, look...
UNlVERSlTY EXCLUDES JEWS
Read Volk en Vaderland!
- Here, we'll give you a hand.
- Thanks, I can manage.
We're here to help one another.
We've got nothing against Jews.
That's fine, thank you.
No, we're not finished.
Do you have accident insurance?
You shouldn't have
got in our way.
Just an accident...
Send the bill to Hitler.
What are you staring at?
It was an accident.
Cheer up.
It could happen to anyone.
Get those things out
of the water.
- I suppose you're a Jew too?
- Yes!
I'll kill you, you bastard.
I'll kill you.
Don't be so stupid!
lnside!
You'll get yourself in trouble.
- I won't let them do it.
- Go out the back way.
All the Jewish professors
have to leave the university.
Yes, I heard.
First the professors,
then the students.
All the Jews will be
in the Polish salt mines soon.
Student boxing champ
and nowhere to go.
You can go to England
instead of me.
How? When?
You'll hear from me.
Robby's expecting me.
What's John doing here?
He's taking my place.
What kind of madness is this?
Robby, the Jerries
don't like Jews.
I could've sent Esther.
Yes, you could have.
Come on, we can't stay here.
There it is.
To the boat!
We'll meet again.
- In London.
- Hurry up!
See that you get this
to London.
Jerries!
Robby!
I'm stiff from the long trip.
The young one first.
Come along.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- I'm sure you'd like some coffee.
- Smells good.
Uncuff him.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Would you like a cup too?
You seem surprised.
We've provided for you.
Sugar?
Don't I get anything with it?
With your second cup.
Egyptian cigarettes...
...but quite good. Take one, please.
I suppose you were expecting
English ones this morning.
Mr. Weinberg, you realize...
...we want some information from you.
I know nothing.
I was going to England to fight.
The war is over.
- Not for me.
- Yes, it is.
People died today.
Remain silent and more will die.
I don't know any of them.
Too bad.
Then I'll see...
...if those papers are dry yet.
Up!
The English don't send planes
for no reason.
Who or what did they come for?
I know nothing.
You know nothing, do you?
You're tough, aren't you?
Boxer's muscles.
Turn him round.
Do you have muscles
on your kidneys?
Enough, Breitner!
We don't work like that.
Have you gone mad?
My dear boy, I'm sorry.
Sit down.
Drink the rest of your coffee.
Drink.
Just tell me what you know.
Today's affair didn't happen
by accident.
I wonder who let the cat
out of the bag.
The information...
...could only have come
from London.
Van der Zanden.
Do you know this person?
Van der Zanden...
He's our contact in London.
That's not true.
It's an open secret.
It's all for nothing, anyway.
I suggest you talk.
Talk!
That's your trick.
Butter up a person...
...and then beat him.
I know nothing.
Breitner will continue
working on your case.
Speak up! Who was there?
Tell me their names!
I don't know, I don't know.
Sorry about that.
Tell me what happened.
We tried to get John over
to England, by plane.
The big time.
- But it went wrong, totally.
- What a pity.
They got John.
LONDON BOMBlNG RESUMES
If he talks, I'll hang.
Amateurs.
Smirking, well-fed prick.
I'll hang.
So you come to me?
Gus, I need a place to hide.
Catch.
Key...
...to my front door.
Stay as long as you like.
RUSSlAN FRONT COLLAPSES
His lordship.
Prick.
You'll be safe at my place.
Hello.
Any around?
Up there.
It's teeming with them.
They're migrating.
A beautiful sight.
I'll try to get a bit closer.
Bye.
Is that him?
- And he's not after the birds.
- Thanks.
My money.
You're a good patriot.
- Is that all?
- It's the rate.
Well, if it's the rate...
Two beers.
You look pleased with yourself.
Will you take these to Nico?
Sure.
Photos of German bunkers.
What are you up to?
Be more careful.
Scared? Your health.
Your health.
Let me go! Too late!
Take them away.
Let me go!
It's nothing to do with me.
- They must have followed me.
- Nonsense.
- Shit. Why me?
- Risky business.
I hope I don't talk.
- Try to escape.
- How?
No talking.
Stop!
'The traitor is Van der Zanden
in London'
Come with me.
On toilet paper!
- You're Lanshof?
- Yes.
'Yes, sir.'
I'll be courteous when you are.
Did you write this?
Yes, sir.
What did you write it with?
With shit, sir.
You must be mad.
This is no way
to apply for release.
Perhaps I didn't have a pencil.
Next time I'll have you shot.
You may go.
Where?
Home.
- You can't just let him go.
- I'm not.
He'll be followed.
Bait? A lure.
Exactly.
He might try to get in touch
with the resistance.
- Then you'll have new guests.
- We have the space.
Here, or in the dunes.
I'll leave it to you,
Obersturmfuhrer. Goodbye.
Hello. Come in.
Let me take your coat.
- It's a wonder you're home.
- That's for sure.
I stopped by a few times,
but you were always out.
- I'm back now.
- Yes, so I see.
Sit down.
It's a bit of a mess.
I was working.
- Tea?
- No, I don't have much time.
No need.
Robby is back.
Has he been away?
You know quite well.
He told me about the plane.
We can stop pretending now.
Yes. Where is he?
In The Hague.
He wants to talk to you.
Come here.
See that man?
He tails me wherever I go.
Security Police.
- Robby wants to see you.
- lmpossible.
They'd grab him too.
Alex!
A friend of yours?
Yes, and so what?
Bloody bastards.
And they call themselves Dutchmen.
How have you been?
It was touch and go.
That vet had quite a go at me
on the kitchen table.
Decent chap, though.
My transmitter is operating again.
Join us, Eric.
John is dead.
I've lost the taste for it.
You're scared.
We were betrayed by someone
called Van der Zanden.
- How do you know?
- John told me.
And he's in London.
We have to pass that on, Eric.
Go ahead.
- You really disappoint me.
- Too bad.
- I'm being watched.
- Probably.
I'm a threat to everyone.
We'll decide that.
I'll decide for myself.
Did you see Robby?
Then we can open the curtains again.
Fine.
That chap must be wondering...
Let him.
Exciting?
It's a boy's book.
I'll be off then.
The curtains were a good idea.
The things you think of.
Here, your shoes.
Are you sure about this?
I want it to happen.
Sir...
Do you know where
Victoria Street is?
If you turn left there...
...you come to a square...
...then you turn right...
Come along.
Good day.
My compliments.
It wasn't easy to find you.
- What do you mean?
- Your transmitter.
It's on the garden shed there, isn't it?
- Do you smoke?
- No.
Do you mind if I do?
Thank you.
I have a proposition.
Would you work for us in the future?
No!
Look.
Your fiance I believe?
I saw her at Lanshof's.
She looks Jewish.
Jewish. She'll go to
a Polish labor camp.
Not so good for the health.
Many people die there.
Let's go.
Won't you reconsider working for us?
Graduated?
Yes.
Congratulations, Eric!
You're the first from our year.
- I thought it would be you.
- I can't get finished.
Better hurry.
The university is closing.
Damn Jerries.
I've heard some
odd stories about you.
The resistance?
All over and done with.
I'm happy to hear it, Eric.
We must consider the future.
Let's go for a drink.
Degrees will count again
after the war.
There's Robby's fiance!
How nice.
I graduated!
Congratulations.
Flowers for you.
Come for a drink with us.
Wait for me.
There they are.
Two gins. One with lemon.
So, a lawyer...
What are your plans?
- Take a holiday.
- On the Riviera.
That's impossible with the war on.
Jack, you're so wonderfully naive.
- Where are you going?
- To the bathroom.
Nico.
They're after you.
You're telling me.
Still want to go to England?
Are you joking?
There's a Swiss ship sailing
tomorrow. They'll take you.
Is it safe?
It's a chance.
Nice of you.
You're putting us in danger.
Here are your papers.
Your name's Jean de Kuyper.
Here.
Shake it.
We didn't rent this bathroom.
I'm disappearing for a bit.
We've got visitors.
- Your Gestapo.
- This might take a while.
Have another drink.
- Real Dutch gin.
- Prewar.
Lt. Thelen, Security Police.
Polzer, ship's captain.
Two gentlemen from the Greek navy.
- A drink?
- No.
You've taken on a Dutch crew.
We'd like to investigate.
They're not here yet.
But you're sailing in half an hour.
That's right.
In 28 minutes.
You can't sail until
we've seen the entire crew.
That's for us to decide.
- Where are they?
- One moment.
Come with me.
There.
Cordon it all off.
Man both ends of the gangway!
Nobody goes aboard!
Attention!
- This is an investigation.
- Jerries!
Stop! That will do.
Murderers!
A net, lads. Before he falls!
Hello, Captain. Hello, Mr. Snooper.
You're drunk. Blind drunk.
What did he say?
You're drunk!
Right! When do we sail, guv?
Nobody comes aboard!
What? Nobody?
Nobody!
We're not allowed on board!
Back to the pub!
Lower away!
Get away from my car!
Get out of it!
Filthy pigs!
That will do.
Have them come aboard at once.
No, I'm fully authorized
to have them locked up.
They're having a row.
The navy will decide this,
Herr Lieutenant.
Let them board.
Come aboard!
Form two lines!
Music!
Attention!
Salute!
You're sober?
To the stokehold.
We must put to sea before they
change their minds.
Ready, sir.
Eric.
We're on our way.
Gus. Well, I'll be...
We're on our way!
- How did you get here?
- Nico. And you?
Me too.
Mr. Particular.
lntermission, 99 sec
lntermission, 90 sec
lntermission, 80 sec
lntermission, 70 sec
lntermission, 60 sec
lntermission, 50 sec
lntermission, 40 sec
lntermission, 30 sec
lntermission, 20 sec
lntermission, 10 sec
Seasick?
We're sailing due north.
Nico said it was heading for Russia.
We'll have tea with Stalin.
What's that?
A battleship.
- German?
- I can't bloody tell.
English!
Wait, I'm coming too!
Goodbye, Captain!
- Bloody awful here.
- It won't take long.
The only English I know is
'fuck you'.
Hi, love.
- We're going to fly, with the RAF.
- Are you crazy?
- And you?
- The army. More peaceful.
If you get a nice uniform...
Mr. Lanshof?
Congratulations.
A daring bit of work, your escape.
Not really.
We could get a ship.
Not so modest.
You're one of 50...
...49 to make it over from
Holland alive.
Come straight to the Queen
when you've finished here.
We cherish our freedom fighters.
I'll arrange the audience.
Ask for General Van de Zanden.
You'd better give that to me.
Come along.
You've read too many thrillers.
I can manage from here on.
But you lack training.
Next time better.
That would certainly
please the Germans.
Eric! Come and join us.
- What's going on?
- We'll have a cup of tea...
...and then we'll have a chat.
Aren't you Mr. Lanshof?
You may take off your coat
and sit down.
I'll take this.
No, that's where Her Majesty sits.
- Odd way to come in.
- He couldn't find the front door.
That's a nice uniform...
- I'm starving.
- Eat, Willem.
Ma'am, what do I call her?
You call her 'Your Majesty'.
- Is it 'Her' or 'Your'?
- 'Your'.
It's 'Your'.
- No smoking in her presence.
- I hear she's strict.
- Not overly.
- There she is.
I bid you welcome.
You are my link with Holland.
Your Majesty, may I present:
Will Dostgaarde...
...Gus Le Jeune...
Your Majesty.
...and Eric Lanshof.
Mr. Lanshof.
Your Majesty.
Won't you sit down?
No, my guests first.
Do tell me,
what is the situation at home?
Home? Which home?
Her Majesty means the situation
in the Netherlands.
Not good. The Jerries are
stripping us bare, Her Majesty.
- Those German bandits!
- I mean, Your Majesty.
But when the war is over...
...what must we do
about the fascists?
Don't you worry
about those shitheads.
Mr. Van der Zanden,
what does that mean, shitheads?
It's a term, Your Majesty, expressing
how we feel about traitors.
Right, Mr. Lanshof?
- Who said I was a traitor?
- John...
...shortly before he was killed.
And then they simply let you go?
I don't see the connection.
It's simple. The Germans wanted
you to believe it...
...and then pass the word around.
What would they gain by that?
I am head of intelligence
and I'm Her Majesty's secretary.
They would love the Dutch people
to think I was a traitor.
They did a good job trying.
- How's the army?
- The dregs!
- I've got something else for you.
- What?
A trip.
Where to?
To Holland.
No!
- How did you manage that?
- I didn't, she did.
I thought someone
was lying in wait for me...
...with a gun.
Don't go totally bonkers.
- Still seeing her?
- None of your business.
Yes.
- Any progress?
- None of your business.
No.
Forget about her.
Shit, I want to sleep with her...
...while I still can.
Cold feet? For Holland?
None of your business.
We consider your presence in London
to be of the utmost importance.
Yes?
Mr. Lanshof, come on through.
Do you smoke?
Thank you.
- And you perhaps?
- No, thank you. I don't smoke.
Let's go for a stroll,
I find that very enjoyable.
You're returning to Holland,
aren't you?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I want you to bring several
people back with you.
lsn't that dangerous?
Our future leaders are in Holland,
in the resistance.
I want them to be here.
They, at least, are of the people.
Gentility belongs to the past.
Things will be different after the war.
The true nobles are
the resistance fighters.
Don't you agree?
Mr. Lanshof?
You're absolutely right, Your Majesty.
I hadn't looked at it that way.
True nobles...
Is there anything else, Your Majesty?
I wish you success.
ldiot, the Queen's
got a front row view.
Here, put your mind to this
instead of neuken.
Stop showing off,
you'll be shitting your pants.
I'm not even wearing pants.
Here. A matchbox to keep it in.
That stuff smells disgusting.
It's enough to make you puke.
...to make you puke.
We've stopped.
Come.
Throw some over me.
Your health.
Gus.
Be careful.
GERMANY WlNNlNG
ON ALL FRONTS
Filthy Jew
Good Morning.
I'd like birth announcement cards
for my daughter.
What's her name?
Wilhelmina Juliana Bernardina.
Come. They're waiting for you.
- Is this address safe?
- We'd not be here if it wasn't.
You're a Red, aren't you?
I remember seeing you
in the House.
Hardly a pleasant experience.
Possibly.
I don't recognize you at all.
Gentlemen, please...
I can't be part of this.
I refuse.
You've pledged yourself
to Her Majesty.
I promised the Germans
I would take no action.
General, the Queen has asked you
to be her adviser...
...for the postwar democracy.
Wilhelmina and democracy,
a belated vocation.
Or rather, she's always
been a little touched.
Religion.
This is her chance...
...to play Christ, to save the world.
Count me out.
What an odious way of saying
that you're scared.
If I were 20, I'd take exception
to that. Gentlemen...
Perhaps you have doubts
about the new democracy too?
New democracy?
We've never had democracy.
When do we leave?
You'll hear from me.
Fine.
Could we get caught?
If they get me and not you, tell
the Queen what the socialists want...
...after the war.
I'll warn them.
Goddamn it!
Waterproof.
Stone dead.
Nothing. How can
I tell London when we're coming?
They only confirm receipt.
lnstructions will come tomorrow.
- Anything else I can do for you?
- No, thank you.
I can do more than just transmit.
We'll phone if we need you, okay?
Fine.
See you tomorrow then.
Well?
I don't know their plans.
They're not talking.
Bad show.
They'd be on to me if I asked.
You're not trying hard enough.
Which of Esther's jackets
would this go best with?
I'd love to see you against the wall.
You'd be right next to me.
Goddamn it!
ldiot!
A present for your fiance.
Might be the last time.
Who's that jerk?
A friend from the resistance.
If that's one of your friends...
Darling, we can't always
choose our friends.
This device uses zinc coins only
Damn it...
An odd uniform.
- U-boat, I think.
- Or a destroyer.
Stop.
Get off.
The German Army
claims this bicycle.
Filthy, goddamn Jerry.
Right, beach huts at 11 pm.
You're going to England?
Police.
On your feet.
They're dead.
Damn. That was close.
We've got to get out of here.
To the car.
- What about me?
- You need a place to hide.
- Where?
- I'll fix it.
- Fix it? I just shot two Nazis!
- Scared?
Yes! Do I have to stay
and wait for them?
Don't leave me here.
I want to go with you.
I object.
I decide who comes.
It's only my opinion.
He's coming!
I'll answer for him.
- He'll need tails.
- There are some in the garage.
Let it ring.
They're gone. After them.
If things go wrong,
don't let them take me alive.
This'll do the trick.
Cyanide.
After them.
It worked.
No answer?
Where's Robby?
I don't know.
He comes and goes.
But you're engaged.
He's always busy with his transmitter.
A permanent place is too risky,
he says.
Don't you wear a star?
Forged papers, from Robby.
And the liquor, the chocolate...
From Robby too?
A man from Robby's group brings it.
We can't even get those
things in London.
Robby's in the resistance.
They can get anything.
Do you believe that?
I have to go to my parents' place
and get my tails.
Are you going to a party?
Yes... you could call it that.
Lord, where are you going?
- The lion's den!
- Don't worry.
If anything goes wrong I'll shoot.
Robby, shut up.
Papers, please.
Thank you.
My compliments.
An excellent forgery.
They're the real thing.
Mr. Particular.
Phone headquarters.
We'll cordon off the area.
Ah, this messy tomato sauce.
Have the cleaning bill
sent to Berlin.
The Fuhrer will gladly pay.
You there, get out of the way.
We're going to party.
I'll join you.
Come on in. Nice and warm.
Oh, you're a heavy one.
Everything is arranged.
We're here.
Stay with us.
Come on, let's go inside.
All right, I will.
It saddens me to see you
among all these fascists...
...bunker-builders.
Oh, it's war.
And it's a nice party.
I heard you were abroad.
Bullshit.
I heard you were in London.
No, I'm right here.
As you can see.
It's a shame we're not
fighting on the same side.
A shame.
A few years from now...
...the Germans and English will
both be fighting the communists.
I doubt it.
We won't see it.
We won't make
it through the war.
- I'll see if he's down there yet.
- All right.
To London, old spy.
Are you spying for the Germans
in London?
Will you bring back
some nylons for me?
What a lovely brooch!
The lron Cross!
- How'd you earn that?
- I blew up a Russian tank.
- Here, you earned it.
- Piss off.
Spying is a lot riskier...
It's mine.
Give it back, dammit!
- It's not a toy!
- lron Cross, lron Cross!
Gus!
It's running like clockwork.
No. We're in trouble.
What trouble?
We've been betrayed, by Robby.
No. He's with me.
- He's coming.
- Robby's working for them!
Jesus Christ.
- Where is he?
- Up there with the others.
Wait for me.
Filthy bastard!
Stay where you are!
Nobody move!
- Run to the beach!
- You are surrounded!
If you move, we'll shoot!
Stay where you are!
Don't move!
We're opening fire!
Split up!
I deeply regret what
has happened.
Mr. Van der Zanden?
Your Majesty?
We shall not repeat this.
Thank you very much
for your efforts.
That'll never get there.
So what?
Bread? Bread?
Hungry?
We're going.
We have to go. Bye.
'Love from Alex.' Your mascot.
He'll get a bomb
on his head tonight.
I'm not that much
of a bloody fool.
Shut up.
He's waking the dead
in their graves.
Open up.
We won't hear from him again.
Nuremberg. These Jerries
are good shots.
They're not drinking this Christmas.
- How much longer?
- 15 seconds. Cheers.
Bomb doors open?
- Bomb doors open.
- Christmas present ready?
- Count down.
- 10, 9, 8, 7...
...6, 5, 4, 3...
...2, 1.
Bombs away.
And back home.
Her Majesty wants you...
...as her aide.
Long live the Queen!
No, thank you, Captain.
This, I would prefer to do alone.
Couldn't you have accidentally
dropped a bomb on that palace?
Well?
It's short.
lt'll grow again.
A present from
our liberated compatriots.
Understandable.
I've no hard feelings.
I survived.
- You did too.
- Yes, that's true.
Except, you're a hero.
What will you do?
Work in the garden.
Clean up the mess.
Jack!
Good Lord, Eric!
Come in!
You look absolutely marvelous.
Medals!
How did you get them?
Did some flying,
dropped some bombs.
We scraped through.
Don't ask me how.
Would you like a drink?
I have a nice wine
for special occasions.
...universities closed. I took
prelims behind closed doors.
Risky business.
You had to take care.
We'll simply start where we
left off five years ago.
Here you are.
What are your plans?
I don't know.
To the future.
Your health.
Marc2008 (2009), The Netherlands
Soldaat van Oranje - Soldier of Orange (1977).avi