Fritz Lang's SPIONE was restored between 2003 and 2004
by the Friedrich-Wilhelm-Murnau-Stiftung.
As no original negative exists, various nitrate copies were used.
Due to its length and excellent condition, a copy from the Národni Filmovy Archiv, Prague, formed the restoration's basis,
as well as copies from the National Film and Sound Archive in Canberra
and the Cinematheque Francaise in Paris.
Some of the intertitles were copied from a copy in Vienna
and an internegative in the Moscow Institute Gosfilmofond
Lost opening credits were recreated
based on censorship cards.
Copying was carried out by L'Immagine Ritrovata in Bologna.
This version was used for 2K digital version.
SPIES
Distributed by UFA
Writer: Thea von Harbou
Director: Fritz Lang
Set Design: Otto Hunte, Karle Volbrecht
Camera: Fritz Arno Wagner
Cast:
Haghi... Rudolf Klein-Rogge
Sonja... Gerda Maurus
Kitty... Lien Deyers
Morrier... Louis Ralph
Chief Jason... Craighall Sherry
No. 326... Willy Fritsch
Franz, the chauffeur... Paul Hörbiger
Lady Leslane... Hertha von Walther
Dr. Matsumoto... Lupu Pick
Colonel Jellusic... Fritz Rasp
The novel "Spione" by Thea von Harbou was published by Scherl-Verlag, Berlin
Throughout the world... strange events transpire.
SENSATIONAL THEFT OF DOCUMENTS...
FRENCH EMBASSY... SHANGHAI
TELEPHONE
EXTRA!
Assassination attempt on the Minister of Trade.
The minister dies from his injuries.
Important documents have disappeared!
No trace of the perpetrator!
Are the officials in charge of state security so asleep on the job
... that our most important documents and secret files...
... can disappear without a trace?
I know... who...
Almighty God... what power is at play here?
I
Police Summons:Hans Pockzerwinski
For your interview, Hans Pockzerwinsky is required...
... his presence in room 2.R. Halle-Strasse 17A...
on Wednesday, August 15, 1927 between 10 and 11...
... present this citation.
Bring your identity documents.
POLICE STATION
Hans Pockzerwinski
From:Minister of Interior
From:Minister of the Interior To:M.B. Jason,
Head of Secret Service By messenger
Dear Mr. Jason!
Enclosed please find several new caricatures
and opinions expressed by the public concerning your department...
Isn't it time to bring this ridicule of the helplessness
of the Secret Service to an end?
The Minister of the Interior.
What's the use of all your precautions in bringing me here
when I am secretly photographed by one of your staff in your own office...?
Who's paying you... you scoundrel - to inform on me...?!
I'd sooner die like a dog than become a traitor!
Your fate is in your hands, Vincent... Who are you working for?
Find out for yourself!
And may God have mercy on you if you find him!
Who is he talking about - ?!
If I knew, No. 326, I wouldn't need you!
And the public wouldn't be making a laughing stock of us!
It's easy for you to laugh because, fortunately for you, you prevented
your picture falling into the hands of this... damned spy...!
... and no one knows what this man looks like - ?!
A few... people have known... but...
I would be sorry, No. 326,
if I had to put a cross after your name as well... >
The Enemy...
Copy photos 4 and 6...!
Distribute to all members of the surveillance squad!
His headquarters...
Morrier kidnapped from the gallows.
Sensational act prior to execution.
Masked perpetrators escape.
This time, Morrier, I have saved you from the noose,
because I can make good use of a scoundrel like you...
But if ever I sign your death sentence...
I am a scoundrel, sir, but a grateful scoundrel...
is on her way...
... to the Haghi Bank.
Miss Barranikowa shall report to me immediately
when she returns from Colonel Jellusic.
Colonel Jellusic, a man of interest to many people...
Are there letters under this box number waiting for me?
What box number did this man just pick up letters from?
Sorry, Lady Leslane,
Director General Haghi would like to see...
it will be only two minutes... a formality...
because of what happened ihere...
I would like to make a proposal, Lady Leslane!
I would like to find out from you, as the wife of Roger Leslane
when and where the Japanese Secret Treaty will be signed.
.. and who will be present!
If I hear nothing within 48 hours,
in the 49th hour your husband
will find out just where his wife spends her Tuesday and Friday evenings...
Your efforts are futile, Lady Leslane, I have the negatives...
I'm richer than Ford, Lady Leslane, even if I pay significantly less in taxes.
The day after tomorrow,
you will deliver the data in writing to the owner of the opium den you know so well
and in exchange you will get the negative...
How far have you gotten with Jellusic?!
I've got him eating out of my hand!
And for a kiss he'd sell me all his
fortresses and the entire army of his country!
You know what to do.
I expect a report tonight!
Save me - I shot him - !
... he invited me to come see him... about a tour... he...
he tried to force me... I didn't know what to do - so I shot him!
If you really want to help me... just let me leave!
It will be better for you and for me... if we never see each other again!
Choose whomever you wish for this project, but keep me out of it!
- I don't want to work against this man...
He reminds me... of my brother Sascha...
All the more reason for you to fight our enemies in the form of this man,
enemies who also were the enemies of your father, of your brother, or...
Have you forgotten?
SENTENCED TO DEATH.
They died innocent, two victims of the Ochrana of your Russian Czar -
... because they weren't smart enough to keep their thoughts to themselves!
My friend!
I owe you an explanation.
... I must see you again.
Don't tell me you've fallen in love with this fellow - ?
My friend! I owe you an explanation and must see you again!
Come tomorrow at 4:00 to have...
a glass of real Russian tea - with the woman you saved - S.B.
Parkstrasse 24
The Diary as Lifesaver
... so that you will cry no more..
I am so happy - so happy - !
I, too...
From Russia?
In memory of my father and my brother...
they died as victims of the Czarist Ochrana...
But, is there nothing at all that you want - ?!
Eight O'Clock Evening Edition
Final Edition - !
Make me a gift of this evening!
I'll pick you up at 9:00- we'll go to Danielli. Okay?
Wear it forever - it shall bring you luck!
At 12 o'clock sharp everyone is at his post...
JAPANESE DEPARTMENT
.. Danielli...
Go immediately to J. H.
Pay Jellusic the price demanded in exchange
for all the mobilization plans in his possession. Under the condition...
Under the condition...
...that he cross the border tonight.
You will not return home, but will report to me immediately. H.
The condition is...
... that you have to cross the border tonight...
But the night is still young, my lovely Sonja...
and you had promised...
The documents...
A farewell kiss, beautiful Sonja...!
A cavalier does not betray his lady!
Drive home!
Are you satisfied now - ?
<So you love that young man?
Your house has been cleared out - you will live
at headquarters and
not leave your room without my permission-
If the Barranikowa woman had not once again been warned in time,
I would have raided her house tonight!
You are hardly the first to have fallen into the trap of this master spy.
Nothing is to deter a man
from the path of duty...
not even a woman...
Why don't you go home, my child?
Please, let me stay here!
Don't send me away again!
I won't take up any more space than a little dog...!
Have I offended you? Must I leave again?
When I went looking for the fellow early this morning,
he had already decamped... without a trace!
I'll show you pictures of all the people suspected
of being spies that were taken over the last month...
Colonel Jellusic left this morning at 2:40 on the Orient Express!
Opera Ball 13
General Delivery, Main Post Office
I'll have this man watched by one of our agents as soon as he arrives.
A plane leaves in 45 minutes that will arrive down there.
... two hours after the Orient Express.
The Secret Service
reserves two seats
on the Aero Orient Express.
People like Jellusic can be had for money...!
If I offer him enough...
he'll betray those who are paying him!
Jellusic has to be put out of commission.
Denounce him as a spy to his Commander in Chief
... at General Headquarters!
Good afternoon, Mr. Jellusic...
So you don't deny...?
You are granted one last request, Mr. Jellusic...
I beg - in all - humility...
Surveillance Report Re:Signing of the Japanese Secret Agreement.
Location:Small conference room of the Japanese Embassy.
Time:5:30 a. m.
Present:The two treaty parties,
... and Chief of Secret Service Dr. Matsumoto.
The Embassy will be subject to the most stringent security measures.
I'll have this treaty in my hands tonight!
Gentlemen!
Gentlemen! One of these envelopes contains the most important treaty
Japan has concluded in a century...
You'll take three different routes to Tokyo... Whoever does not deliver
his letter with its seal unbroken
is not worthy of being called a Japanese!
Whose blood am I to wear around my neck, Haghi?
I called you, Sonja,
to clear things...
... between you and me.
Where is - he - ?!
He's trying to trace you through Jellusic.
SUDDEN DEATH OF COLONEL M.O. JELLUSIC.
As we learned after press time,
Jellusic, colonel extraordinaire at General Headquarters,
has died of a heart attack shortly after returning from a holiday trip.
20,000 pounds... in new bank notes -
with consecutive serial numbers...!
A blank telegram, please!
Find out immediately to whom the State Bank.
has issued notes in denominations of one thousand with...
... with consecutive numbers from 0319726 to 0319745 Stop
Return with next flight.
A special call...!
What - ?! The bank note numbers?!
You have to make up your mind, Sonja. Are you on my side - against him?
You still don't seem to know what I am capable of!
I have other irons in the fire...
- the house shall be yours... you will live
there as a little princess...
I have to go, Kitty...!
But not so fast - ! Not so fast - !
Just a few more hours - !
A few meagre hours...
Don't you see that I will die - if you leave me - ?
As surely as I shall win this battle, Sonja, I will defeat him...
Do you nevertheless stick to your decision?!?
And how long are you planning to keep me prisoner?
Until one of us is the victor, Sonja - he or I!
No. 326, who is coming back tonight, has sent us a radiogram that falls into your field of expertise...
Read it for yourself!
This matter has to be taken care of before No. 326 returns!
Find out immediately to whom the State Bank
has issued notes in denominations of one thousand...
... with consecutive numbers 0319726 to 0319745. STOP Return by next plane.
So I'll come tonight with No. 326 to your dressing room!
I'll take care of the postal censorship
- You see to it that all borders are closed!
If the treaty falls into the wrong hands, the war in the East is all but declared!
It's the last car -
... and it will happen in the tunnel...
if No. 326 falls into the trap
I have told you, Sonja, you will be free when one of us two men triumphs...
It is I who have been conquered... because I need you!
No one but you is skilful enough to bring
the photos of the treaty across the closed border...
Do me this one last service...
... and the road to the man you love will be open!
And you swear that he will be safe from you in the future if I say yes - ?
I believe they'll use a foreigner
to take the stolen treaty across the border
- and the sudden departure of the Russian courier is,
at the very least, suspicious...
... the more so now that 719 has determinedd
that the bank notes for Jellusic also came from Russian hands...
Unfortunately, I cannot leave here without destroying my cover
and jeopardizing my work as No. 719
But anyway I booked the neighboring compartment...
... to that of the Russian messenger...
Around 6 a.m. you will cross the border
that is the decisive moment!
I almost forgot what I found the other day...
The last car of the express train...
- crashed in the tunnel... -
You wretch!
Did Haghi send you to make sure that his damned plan was successful
You don't intend to betray us, do you... you scoundrel...?
Attention. Central. Central. Central..!
No. 326 is alive - ! Sonja has betrayed us - !
We wish to talk to Director Haghi.
Gentlemen, what could the police be looking for here - ?
A criminal - and the proof of his crime!
I order you to hand over to me the keys to all of the bank safes!
If the bank is not vacated within 15 minutes of receiving
this note, and the police have not withdrawn completely...
...the woman you love, whom I hold in my power, will die.
You have 14 minutes to live, Sonja,
... if he chooses not to obey me!
People's lives - in danger - !
The bank must be searched within 13 minutes,
and Haghi's secret room found - do you understand? -
Burn all papers...dynamite the safes...
In ten minutes the bank will be filled with gas!
Soon, Sonja, you will know all about the secrets of death.
- take with you a secret from my life!
The bank has been searched down to the foundations
- there is no trace of a secret exit.
Where is Haghi?
10,000 MARKS REWARD!
Who has seen the man pictured,
above, Bank Director Haghi, since midday?
Any type of information leading to his arrest..
... will receive the reward offered
WANTED
Not even a mouse would be able to leave the city
he has to be here somewhere...
There's a small error... I want to report...
It's just that... the numbers on the thousand pound notes...
which I have to deliver a receipt for...
The telegram contains different numbers!
No. 719... has switched the telegrams...! The Clown Nemo is Haghi!
A little music please - Mr. Conductor - !
Curtain - !
The End