No meat today.
Sorry, miss.
No coke, miss.
Sprite.
-  Senorita?
-Senorita?
Senorita, you tell to me
if you're intending
to remain very long.
Senorita?
-Senorita?
If possible
I will wait for you.
-Senorita?
Si, si, si, si.
So good to
see you again.
Young rebels
used to be so sexy.
Aren't you
looking at me?
-Are you coming?
-Yeah.
-Si.
-Are you coming?
-Uh-huh. Si.
-So, come!
What a fucking joke.
- You are getting
more skinny, eh.
If you get
any more skinny,
I don't want you
no more.
-Do you have
any talcum powder?
-Que?
No, talcum powder.
I must tell you
something.
Yes.
The moment has come
when I must
take your press card
and your letter
of authority.
What are you saying?
You're not a journalist.
Yes, I am.
No, you're not.
I am, too,
a journalist.
No, you're not.
Hey, hey. What...
Give me that!
And the press card?
-Where is the press card?
-I don't have my press card.
-Yes, you have.
-No, I don't.
It's back at the motel.
-No, it's not.
-Yes, it is.
It is invalidated.
Who invalidated it?
I am forced to.
One of these days,
the army will
arrest you.
And this letter
carries my name.
This is my name.
Veraguas.
-You understand?
-I understand.
Everyone who reads it
sees my name.
Fucking all pimps.
You're all fucking pimps!
Fucking jackass.
- Yes!
Yes!
I left many
messages for you,
but you never responded.
Why that is?
I am forced...
I am forced to wonder.
-You were
forced to wonder?
-Mm-hmm.
I am forced
to tell you that
you said you would
replace my phone
which you broke.
I'll be needing
some shampoo.
I will buy for you
the shampoo with
much pleasure.
Very generous,
Subtenente Verga.
I'm waiting for
my chauffeur.
If it is quite okay...
If it is quite okay
not to call me
under this name,
Verga.
My name, it's Veraguas.
And it is
"subtenente".
Subtenente.
- Where do
you wish to go?
- You wish
the InterContinental.
- Yes. I wish.
Car reeks big time
even with the mask on.
Senor?
Ola!
-  Gracias.
Martini, por favor.
Como estas?
-  Gracias.
May I have a cigarette?
Uh, evening.
I have none on me,
I'm sorry.
You're English.
I am.
London, currently.
Where are you from?
Uh, here and there
and yonder.
What about yourself?
Didn't we just do that?
Miguel?
Alphonso?
Roberto?
Si.
She's a little wet.
There's too
much vermouth.
Smell the bamboo
in here?
It's not the nicest
smell, is it?
You have the kind of
good manners
that eventually
get you killed.
Gracias.
We have 45 minutes
till the bar closes.
Long enough
to get swacked.
Wanna try a gin
with me?
What brought you here?
I came on a plane.
I suppose I met
all your motives.
I can tell you
my motives.
I wanted to know
the exact dimensions
of hell.
Are you for sale?
I'm press.
We're all press.
Then we're all
for sale.
I came here as
a special correspondent
up in the north area.
Really?
It's one of
the rougher spots,
is it not?
In a sense.
What made you leave?
It was nothing.
Girl scout camp
for refugees.
Right, right, right.
And what about you?
Me? I'm, uh...
I'm here with
the Watts people.
I say "with",
but I'm here alone.
The Watts people,
the oil company?
Yeah, on, uh,
a charitable cause,
you could say.
-Please don't go
into detail.
No, I just mean,
how many companies
do you think,
at the moment,
would consider investing
in a place like this?
Not many I'd imagine.
No, next to none.
That's all in the name
of profit, but, uh...
I don't know,
I still that the idea
of throwing
some business
their way has
humanitarian overtones.
Now that we know
each other so well...
...care for some supper?
I think
it's kind of late.
For a price,
I'll sleep with you.
- Your skin
is so white.
It's like
being fucked
by a cloud.
You're just a mist.
Yes.
A mist.
Don't panic, baby.
It's your room.
I wanna be paid
in dollars.
Everybody wants dollars.
There's talk
they're gonna roll up
the Cordoba.
Roll up?
Yeah.
- Fuck me.
Would I have to
pay extra for that?
I have no
dollar supply.
I live entirely on
black-market Cordobas.
Don't worry.
You don't have
to start thinking
how to ditch me.
I'm not here
for your dollars,
I'm here for
the air-conditioning.
You're thinking so
hard how to ditch me
that your head
is smoking.
What do you have
to say about that?
I was thinking
about something
quite a bit different.
I commit
adultery often.
I never really
miss anybody.
I feel I'm in
danger of throwing
my life away.
Shall we meet again?
Again and again.
Anytime you have 50 US.
Right. Of course.
I don't usually
fall asleep in
somebody else's bed.
I like your style.
Normally,
in my dark heart,
I look down on
the impoverished
lackeys of
pig billionaires
with their poor
report string back.
Take a shower
if you want.
I have running water
in my hotel, baby.
"Impoverished lackeys."
See how fast
the tropics sap you?
-Buenos dias.
--  Buenos dias.
No.
-- Hello.
-Hello.
-Hello?
Can you hear me now?
- I've got you.
I've got you fine.
-Okay.
-Hi.
First of all,
it's very early here.
I mean, I'll just say
what I said again.
Why would
a monthly magazine
that specializes
in sustainable
high-class travel,
be interested in
any events,
any person,
any fucking thing
from the continent
of Nicaragua?
Continent? Uh,
your geography is
a little off there, buddy.
But I'm saying that
I can get you
a wonderful piece
on a nature reserve
in, in Costa Rica.
You'll wake up
to the sound of
howler monkeys,
you'll have
a deluxe tent
and a private
bathroom,
which is a real steal
in the midst this pandemic.
Yeah.
Well, I'd love to
be woken up
by howler monkeys
at- 00 a.m.,
but not by you,
Trish. No offense.
Is this gonna be
another one
of these, like,
"Send me
X amount of cash
"and you'll never,
ever hear from
me again"?
Because we already
did that.
You're hearing
from me right now.
And if you could just
get me to Costa Rica,
I promise you
I'll get my act
together.
Things aren't
as simple here
as you wanna think.
Okay.
How about this?
Is this simple enough?
Fuck you.
-I am employed by you.
You have never, ever,
been employed by me.
Not never,
not never, ever.
You did some
piece work for us,
Trish.
That's it. You were
like a temp, okay?
-What are you
trying to say?
I'm trying to
say something
along the lines
of what I just said,
which is,
we don't need
your stories about
missing persons
or murder.
I can watch that
on CNN, okay? Just...
Why don't you just
admit to yourself
you're not a journalist?
All right?
And stop calling me.
-Can I please, uh...
-Trish? Trish?
Do you have my number?
Yep.
Good.
Lose it, okay?
Bye-bye, senorita.
Bye-bye.
Oh, use the other
fucking door
because this one
doesn't open?
Pay in dollars
or use the other
fucking door?
Just wait until
American tanks
come and crush
your hopeless country.
Either way
the American tanks
are gonna come
and fucking crush
your country!
-Only chicken today.
-Rum.
-  Gracias.
Um...
I'm an American
journalist,
and I'm going
home tomorrow.
Tomorrow
or the day after.
Muchas gracias.
Gracias.
No, I think
it's great.
It's just a matter of
how much time it takes.
- Great.
Um, it should
be fine...
-- Thanks.
-Welcome, sir.
I had a reason
for ignoring you.
It's okay,
whatever my
true feelings.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Consorting with
unescorted women is
no disgrace, Daniel.
No, it wasn't that.
I was...
I was concerned
for your reputation.
Who's that
friend of yours?
He has a project
to grow rice
with rainwater.
What I do
interests him.
He's a Costa Rican cop.
No.
Yes.
He's from the O-E-Jota.
What do you know
about the OIJ?
O-E-Jota.
Those are
the Costa Rican cops.
No, I know that.
This man's not a cop.
Yes, he is.
And he's waiting
for you
outside of the hotel
right now.
What have you got
to do with them?
Or do I not
want to know?
Is it cold enough?
-I'll take a beer,
thank you.
Are you familiar with
the American expression
"you've got your ass
in a sling"?
I'm familiar with most
of your expressions.
I'm familiar with
a lot of things.
If you don't mind me
saying so,
I'm familiar with
the way that whores
try desperately
to act as if
they feel superior
to those of us
who pay them,
when actually,
you feel quite inferior.
Actually, I think
you feel ashamed.
Ooh.
Why didn't you look at
the waiter just now?
Why don't you
look at me when
I'm talking to you?
'Cause there's
nothing to see.
If there's nothing
to see, then why
don't you look at me?
If I'm no one.
Okay.
Let's back this up
a little bit, okay?
Because, actually,
I'm not the one
the O-E-Jota's
waiting for outside
the InterContinental,
am I?
Well, he's not the OIJ.
O-E-Jota.
All right.
-Thank you.
Can I have one of
those Belmonts, please?
Does he say
he's your friend?
He does.
Then don't talk
to him anymore.
Did he say his name?
-He showed me his ID.
-- Okay.
You're so fucking
out of it.
Don't speak
with him anymore.
Forget him.
Do you have a gun?
Shoot him.
I don't have a gun.
I bet that
if we leave this
hotel right now,
he'll follow us.
He's waiting
for you outside.
And he's not gonna
let you get away.
You're drunk.
Would I be
sitting here
if I were the littlest
bit sober?
No, no.
Let's go to my room.
Do you have 50 US?
I have 50 US.
Good.
Give it to me,
I need to buy some
shampoo.
We're gonna go
to the Mercado Oriental
and you'll see
we're being followed.
Let's lose the cop.
Senor?
-- Okay.
--  Gracias.
-Come on.
Nothing like running
away in an old Toyota.
That's him.
That's him right there.
They have
the Costa Rican plates,
they look like the new
California ones.
-You know?
No, I don't know.
It's ridiculous.
I'm pretty sure,
he knows where
I'm staying.
We'll lose them down
at the Mercado.
- No.
What's going on?
Is he still there?
I can't see a thing.
Senor.
I understand.
- Thank you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
you all right?
You insist
I'm plastered.
I'm fine.
I have the use
of my legs.
Okay.
Okay, very good.
I need to buy
some shampoo.
- You didn't
like the one you stole
from me?
Okay.
I gotta get some rum.
Gracias.
Aww. Throw this away.
There won't be
any elections, babe.
I promise.
Happening next week.
Rum and shampoo.
Gracias.
I should get my hair
washed by a real
professional.
-Gracias.
-  Gracias.
- Mm.
Don't blink
or you'll miss
the whole show.
They'll postpone
the election again,
and they'll blame
the US.
It'll happen.
Why?
Why would they risk
losing all of this power
now that they have it?
Because there are
people here who still
have principles.
- Oh.
Like what?
What principles?
Democracy,
equality.
Starbucks.
I didn't know
why I bother.
Me neither.
-Go, go, go!
You, my friend,
just made
1,000 Cordobas.
-Fuck the Rica!
Fuck the Rica!
-You are a piece of work.
Hey. Stop, stop, stop.
What you doing?
-One moment.
What are you doing?
-  Gracias.
That Costa Rican
would've had
plenty of time
to shoot you
in your back.
-Right.
-Bang.
I can feel it.
Bang.
It's my pleasure.
This is my hotel.
- Where's
all the money from?
- That's not
your kind of question.
Are you
a little tense?
Should I be tense?
- Watch out
for dog doo doo
and kitty plop.
You're amazing,
you know that?
Nothing stops you.
Not rain,
not car chases,
not dog shit.
-Any calls?
-No.
Hmm.
It's, uh,
nice subdued lighting.
-One bulb.
You have a back door.
Mm-hmm.
This room was originally
hired by the hour.
So,
come through the door,
you pay,
nobody sees your face,
nobody gets your name.
For a life like that.
-It's a life like another.
I think maybe
I've made
a big mistake.
Hey, Englishman.
My sweaty,
sweaty Englishman.
You're gonna
be boiled alive.
Black. No milk today.
Por favor.
Isn't that what you
call my motel?
Today? Tomorrow?
Please speak
very loud and slow.
Yes. Okay.
Can I come
to the office?
-Please say yes.
-Yes.
Soon?
Before noon.
Okay, I'll come
right now.
Certainly,
but don't hurry.
Not to the office.
Wait for me
at my club.
Eat me!
Ola.
Si.
You know
how I like you.
Not only I like you,
I'm fond of you.
You're very beautiful.
Si.
Please.
Please, please
buy a plane
ticket for me.
Please.
No.
Miss Johnson?
Miss Johnson, it's me,
Subtenente Veraguas.
Miss Johnson?
-Hey.
-Hi.
To The InterContinental,
please.
Okay, sir.
Do you have
some time out of you?
Yes, sir.
Are you able to wait
for a few minutes?
If, uh, near the hotel,
if I ran up for
a quick shower,
and you can
take me to the Plaza
de la Revolucion,
to the Ministry?
-Yes, sir. Yeah.
-- Thank you.
We can stop here.
No, but this way today
to go to the...
No, no, no, no.
It's fine.
We can just wait
here for one,
for a moment.
Just one moment.
You see that guy?
Costa Rican scumbags.
What a bullshit.
They'll take anyone
at that hotel.
I have a room
at the hotel.
And a girlfriend
at the motel.
See, man,
this hotel is
high security for
foreigners like you,
not for us.
American puppets.
Your compatriots.
I'm not an American.
You've got problems
with your phone?
No, it's fine.
We can't get them
fixed in here.
It's fine,
thank you.
But what would
you do with it?
I will throw it away.
No, man.
Give it to me.
You don't want it,
you understand?
It's, uh,
it's dangerous.
No, man, not for me.
It's easy to
sell in here.
Show me.
I can make
them traceable.
-Can I keep it?
-Yeah.
What do we do now?
We do nothing.
We, uh, we just wait.
Yeah, fuck them.
I live at a height
above the things.
I believe you
can help me.
How did you find
our eggs?
I have chicken
at my house.
I am fond of eggs,
but I...
I don't need eggs.
I need to speak
to your coyote.
I can get beer,
come my friend's house.
And the man
who will get cash
right here
in the Plaza Espana,
is my cousin.
I can buy cash from him
at a good price.
Can I speak to
the coyote now?
Ola.
Gracias.
I want to verify you.
I don't want you
to verify me.
Then I have no money
for you. No US.
That much money
come from
the black market.
I don't want no trouble.
No.
No trouble.
Hmm. No passport,
no dollars.
-Fuck you.
-Fuck is a good word.
Fuck is the property
of the whole world.
You don't speak Spanish.
It's no good for you.
Very bad situation.
People from
Department of Defense
came to see me,
and ask for you.
They were very tough.
This is no good.
Okay. Did you
tell them where I live?
No. No.
But they can
find out easy, fast.
Wait, uh...
What did I do?
Some of them
very bad.
Go. Go now. Today.
But, I...
Let's go outside
and then you can
explain to me in Spanish
what's happening.
-I want to understand.
-No.
We can finish
our conversation
right now.
You're my only
friend here.
-Hmm.
-Please.
Yeah?
I hear you have
a new friend now.
Okay, um...
Fuck.
I appreciate
what you've been
able to do for me.
Hi. Uh, I would like
to speak to one of
your guests.
Mr. Daniel DeHaven,
please.
He's not here.
Uh, can I leave
him a message?
He has checked out.
Um...
Checked out?
You mean
he took his luggage?
He's checked out,
he's left?
Yes.
-Any calls?
-- No, miss.
The Englishman
in trouble
is still here.
The senora let you in?
I've been hiding
here all day.
Mm, really?
And just what are
you planning to do?
I need to go
back to my hotel.
They told me
that you left.
What do you
mean "left"?
They said that
you checked out.
You packed up
and you checked out.
They told you
I checked out?
I don't know.
I could have
got it wrong.
It was over
the phone, so...
Maybe I got it wrong.
Um...
Did you know
the Department of Defense
is after you?
You never said anything
about those people.
I didn't really
think that anyone
was after me.
Do you think it now?
Will you help me
get my things
from my hotel?
Certainly not.
No, I'm serious.
I can't. No.
If I help you,
then I'm going to
end up wishing
that I never
met you once.
Unless, of course,
you have a MasterCard
or an Amex.
Because when you
buy me a plane ticket,
then I'll see what
I can do for you.
I do have an Amex,
but I can't use it.
It's a company card.
I tried to get
money out earlier
and it's blocked.
You said that
you didn't leave
the hotel.
Hmm.
That's fishy.
Guy like you without
a card to his own name.
I do have a card
in my own name.
It's in my coat.
At the hotel.
I'm tired.
I'm tired. I'm tired
and I've got to rest.
And every time
I turn around,
they're jamming
something
under somebody
else's fingernails.
This is the worst
time of day.
This is the worst time
of my whole life.
What did you do
when you were
stateside?
If you don't
mind me asking.
A little of this,
and then a little
bit of that.
Mainly a little
of this, I suppose?
I suppose, that's what
you want to hear.
No, no, no,
no, no, no!
Don't go.
You're in danger.
I need go to
the Intercontinental.
Need to know
if I was checked out.
You're in danger.
Hey!
Wait. Hey!
You walk too fast.
I need a drink.
♪ So many dreams
we share
♪ Before we
shared each other
♪ So many dreams
we shared
♪ Like the stars
at noon
♪ In the heat
♪ Of the streets
♪ In the rain that
doesn't cool us
♪ And the earth
♪ Under our feet
♪ Under the stars
at noon
♪ And you say
♪ We've been
there forever
♪ Half close your eyes
♪ See them for yourself
♪ And I bought
my cigarette
♪ And only five or so
minutes later
♪ Just a half
♪ Breath away
♪ Under the stars
at noon
I'm sorry.
♪ And you said
♪ We've been
there forever
Do you dance
like that
with your wife?
♪ Half close your eyes
Of course.
♪ See them for yourself ♪
All the time.
I think a taxi
driver died.
I recognize
that cab driver.
He's from around.
It's too bad
you got checked out.
they took your gun.
What gun?
-No, no, no.
It's British Airways.
I don't control
when their offices
are open.
I told you this before.
Just one more call.
Por favor.
-No!
-It's quick!
I can pay you,
for God's sake.
-I can pay.
-No.
Hey, can you help me?
She doesn't understand
what I'm saying.
Ah, miss?
What's she saying?
She wants you
to pay for the room.
I can pay for the room.
I can pay for the room
and the phone.
So, what's this
about British Airways?
You're planning some
kind of quick exit?
Can you call the hotel?
They have
my ticket information.
Ticket information?
-Why not use
your phone?
-Please!
Please, just call them.
- Thank you.
Okay. Will you
ask for me,
Daniel DeHaven,
Watts Oil.
-Do you expect me
to find you there?
-I don't know.
Just see if
I've been completely
checked out.
And maybe someone's
left something for me.
-A clean shirt...
-Ola.
Says you've checked out.
Okay. Can I
speak to her?
--Can I speak to her?
Hello. This is Daniel.
In English, please.
I can't understand.
She's speaking
in Spanish. Can you?
I can explain
about the ticket.
Just give me a minute.
Excuse me.
Please.
Is...
Is something funny?
Hmm?
You're still...
You're laughing.
What is your
name, please?
Hmm?
I have a bad head
for names.
- I lived in the US
for four years.
Got married to
my wife there.
My two little girls,
they go to boarding school
in Virginia.
So, don't fuck with me.
Okay?
That is my statement.
Okay.
-I'm going back...
-Okay.
Excuse me.
No. No.
I told you already once.
Don't fuck with me
or I'm going to
fuck with you.
So, you better let me
take your passport.
-You can't have
my passport.
-I can't?
I'm under
the protection of
the Nicaraguan government.
You are?
You're under
the protection of
the Nicaraguan government.
Where are they?
I know your English
friend is inside.
Do you think
this is a fucking game?
Hm?
-I can't talk.
-What do you believe?
What do you believe?
You believe that
you can take this guy
to the Mercado,
fuck him, it's fine,
and then...
...it's finished?
Huh?
-Did you fuck him?
-Let go of me.
-Huh?
-Hey! Let go of me.
Let go of me.
Let go of me!
You're just
a Costa Rican cop,
and you have
no control over me.
I am listening outside
of your window, bitch.
Do you know how many
people are playing
in your fucking game?
A lot of people
are involved.
-Hm.
You have some
on you.
Huh?
You think you're
going to take
this guy, fuck him,
and then just like that,
you say, "It's finished"?
No. You're going
to have a lot of
explanation
to take care of,
goddammit!
You're just another
fucking cunt
playing games.
I thought you'd gone.
I'm still here.
- I thought
I got rid of you.
Come inside.
Did you see
who was out there?
Yeah. That's why
I came here.
Says he listens
to us fucking.
I can't think.
My mind won't function.
Fuck you.
I don't need it anymore.
I can get rid of it.
- Your phone.
- Yeah.
Who is he?
Who is that Costa Rican?
What's he doing here?
-What's happening?
-I don't know.
I don't know who he is.
I don't know if he's
operating by himself.
I don't...
I don't know who
he's in touch with.
Okay, well, you're
the one that's
supposed to face him,
and I'm the one
that's getting
my windows peeked into.
You came here to
do business, yeah?
Do you have
any contacts?
I don't have
any contacts.
Do you?
Yeah.
I have a half-senile
VC ministro
at the inter turismo
who can't get hard,
and a subtenente
that can.
And they both just
got done cutting me
loose because of you.
I'll be out, all right?
I'll be out by night.
You can't just
leave me now.
That's fucking horrible.
I'm caught.
All right. I'm caught.
I love you.
No.
Gracias.
You're right.
I told them my esposo
would pay for it.
I'm tired.
I'm having my period.
Be gentle.
You never
did it like this
with you wife?
I'm glad you let me.
Please keep me.
Vamos! Vamos! Vamos!
Get out!
Move it!
Let's go! Move it!
- You don't
want to sit up front?
I'm tired.
Need to rest.
Are you sure
you want to
leave with me?
You're almost
out of gas.
I guess so.
I don't know this city.
See, you do need me.
Yeah.
I need you.
Can you pass me
a cigarette?
This is our honeymoon.
I need to sleep.
Let's just die here.
Are we in a hurry?
Let me try and
take a shower first.
I stink.
Didn't you hear me?
I said we have
no towels.
You want me to think
that you're so tough
and cynical.
I know that you like
to be touched.
There's no need
to pretend to cry.
Suck me.
- Excuse me.
Uh, yes.
You want to...
Do you mind,
uh, sitting down
and watching me
eat my breakfast or...
Whatever I'm eating
is delicious.
Beans, eggs, rice.
Not from here.
Mm. Where's it from?
-Costa Rica.
-Ah. Costa Rica.
Of course. I'm sorry.
It's my first time
down in Central America.
I work for
a consulting firm.
Please, have a seat.
It's my treat.
We're the only customers
in here anyway, right?
-It requires money
to eat here, so...
-Mmm.
...you can bet
nobody in this town
has any.
It's a little hot
over here.
Do you mind moving
to the other side?
It's a little shady
over there.
Okay.
It really gets me
how rude everybody
is down here.
The way you
just ordered food was
just so impolite.
-Impolite?
-Mm-hmm.
Nobody says "please"
or "thank you."
I really miss
the States.
Where are you from?
DC.
This mash is pretty
good, though.
What's the full name
of the company
that you work for?
Because with
all these initials,
you just never know
who you're talking to.
You've got...
You've got "PS".
Mm-hmm.
MAPML.
Don't ask me
what that stands for.
And...
Well...
Then there's CIA.
Well, we're actually
out of Connecticut.
And, um,
consulting is such
a weird business.
Weird in the sense that
it gets completely blown
out of proportion.
I'm not kidding.
I can't even believe
what they pay me.
I'm working on
a report right now,
and if I need anything,
anything at all,
snap my fingers,
just like that.
Say I wanted to
hire you to help me,
hire you to
consult for me,
I could just, um,
snap my fingers, and
envelope of $20,000
in your lap,
like that.
Who are you
consulting for
down here?
Who on Earth would
want to do business
in this country?
Well, it's not
this country,
specifically.
You know, um,
Central America
as whole
is kind of like
a gambler's paradise.
You know,
everybody is giving
the odds a shake,
whichever game
they feel like playing.
But, uh,
in all seriousness,
there's, um,
wheat and rice
conglomerates
that are looking out
at the land
around here.
If you can
believe that.
You bet I do.
You're unbelievably
obvious.
So, I mentioned
oil before, and...
- Okay.
Um, anyways,
I mentioned oil
and parts of my report
actually touch
on the petroleum
outlook in the area,
and your friend
actually pops up in it,
a couple of times,
as a matter of fact.
And that is
if the guy you're
traveling with is
the same person
that I'm thinking of.
But...
Anyway, the local
businesspeople
are very level-headed
and serious.
What do you mean
about my friend?
Well, he's one
of the characters.
Haven't you noticed?
He's taking advantage
of the local elections
and meddling with
the balance of power
that was so difficult
to achieve.
-Uh, coffee, please.
-Okay.
What do you mean
about bringing up
my friend?
My report is about
this region,
and balance is
what this region
is all about.
And so, what does
your job have to do
with my friend?
Well, that's
your friend coming
right now, isn't it?
What does your report
have to do
with my friend,
I've asked you!
Well, like I said,
I don't even know
if it's the same person.
He just happened
to wander in
and receive scrutiny,
kinda like right now.
Don't mind me.
- Of course...
Of course not.
Um, you see,
Central American
countries
are looking for
the best way to
achieve balance,
both economically
and politically.
Even if that means
some sort of
American military
involvement, but, um...
It's not really
what we prefer,
is it?
But then again,
why not?
Why not indeed?
I'm just a consultant.
What do I know?
Maybe enough to tell me
what to order.
Oh.
Well, if you're hungry,
you should have
some of what I had.
It's not bad at all.
First gallo pinto
I've seen.
We're getting closer
to Costa Rica.
Is that where
you are, uh,
where you guys
are heading? CR?
What's going on
down there?
CR, Costa Rica.
Nothing special.
Well, I've been
in San Jose
for about a month.
I thought you said
this was your first time
in Central America.
Pretty accommodating guy,
that Vice Minister
in del turismo,
don't you think?
--  Gracias.
He's the one
that got me into
this whole mess.
Made me change
my dollars
into Cordobas.
Don't worry, babe.
He already knows
all about us.
I figured as much.
- I can give you
a pretty good
exchange rate on those.
If that's
what you want.
Somehow, I'm not
surprised to hear that.
Sorry to change
the subject.
The, uh...
The election
interests me.
Maybe we could
take a walk,
find a newspaper.
- I'm thirsty.
- Whores,
they all are.
- Excuse me?
- I mean,
they'll all do it
for enough money.
Any of these women.
Venezuelan, Costa-Rican,
doesn't matter.
Why don't you go
grab one coming
out of church one day
and give it a try,
and you'll see
what I mean.
They're all as
lonely as widows.
They haven't had
a man's hand
on their thighs
since Jesus
was in diapers,
or Moses
had a pacifier.
We should get going,
find that paper.
Cordobas isn't
your only problem,
I hear.
It seems you have
a passport issue
as well.
How long have
you known him?
Huh? Okay.
I know you haven't
known him for that long.
I can tell by
your body language.
Okay? Please.
How do you know
who he is, who
he says he is?
How do you
know he isn't...
Okay. I get it,
and understand
how exotic
everything feels.
Everything is
ten volts higher.
Okay?
And if I saw
somebody like you,
I wouldn't ask
for references.
So, you didn't
ask for references.
Big deal.
It's a mistake,
but it's not a crime.
Just another
absurd fuckhead.
Look, look.
Listen, Ms. Johnson.
Ms. Johnson, listen,
listen. Okay?
I'm just here...
I don't care
what you think of me.
I'm just here
to offer you
the best deal that
I could make
across two borders.
It's real
and it's straight.
I don't understand
what kind of deal
you think is being
offered to you.
I think
you're offering
to screw me.
Well, that is definitely
the one thing
that I am not
offering to do.
Excuse me.
Is that polite
enough for you?
What were you gonna do?
How are you gonna
cross the border?
By waving
the American flag, huh?
- Wait! Wait,
wait, wait, wait!
Okay.
Are you mad at me?
Hey, are you
mad at me?
Are you mad at me?
I know.
You're mad at me.
I know you're
mad at me.
I know you're mad
at me.
I know you're
mad at me.
mad at me,
but are you mad at me
to the point of murder?
- You're
a North American female,
prostitute drifter
with a press card
that's been revoked,
and you drink like
a fucking Apache.
You're gonna get us
both fucking killed!
Just please,
please level
with me.
- I need to
feel like I'm moving.
Fuck!
You don't have
a passport, do you?
And this whole
bloody mess
was so you could
turn me in.
- You're all wet.
We're passing
into Costa Rica.
I'm probably their
most-wanted fugitive.
- That's much
better for you.
Because from there,
we can just cross
over into Panama.
We'll be fine.
It's better for you
or better for me?
You really are
a whore.
- Vaccination.
Ah.
I would've thought
you'd been out of
the country by now.
I thought we had
some sort of
a connection before,
um, that maybe
you understood.
I guess it's possible
I was a little bit
too subtle
but, um,
I'll be more direct.
Your British friend
interests me,
and I wanna include
background on him.
Your report's
all about him?
You could say that,
but, look,
we're Americans.
We're two
Americans, right?
We're friends.
And, uh, let's
put it this way.
Your travel companion
works for a rival outfit.
And we'd like to
fuck up their action.
It's basically
that simple, so...
I just need
a signature on it,
and that signature
has to be yours.
I'm not
signing anything.
Don't you know
what an asshole you are?
what a delusional
asshole he is?
Giving charts
and documents
and a whole
economic future
to a rogue state.
I believe he did it
in the interest
of fairness.
Of course, he did.
Right?
---  Gracias.
-Yeah, he did.
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah!
And what if
the oil's not there?
Does that
blur the edges
a little bit?
We have a flat.
We have to turn
and buy a new one.
Go back.
They smuggle stuff
across the border
every night.
How much can
we pay them?
A stolen car?
Stolen, yeah.
-Give more.
-Uh...
I have some money.
Um...
Yeah. And watch?
Okay.
-Yeah?
-Okay.
Let me grab something.
I'm gonna change.
-He's saying it's white?
-Just put that on
because you can't
cross in a white
thing at night.
It's not too late
for you to stay
if you want.
- Move. Move!
- Let me see.
-I'm fine. It's fine.
-Okay. Let me see.
- Let's get down.
-- Jesus.
-Come.
We really fucked up.
Yeah. I fucked up.
- Cover me up.
Cover me up.
Cover me up. Cover me up.
I will practice
my English with you.
Your man from the CIA
saved you from death.
- The CIA?
It's obvious, I suppose.
You know, you work
for despicable people.
Maybe we could find
a room somewhere.
The senorita will
find herself a hotel.
But you, senor,
you come with us
and be arrested.
No. No.
-Hey. Hey. Hey!
Don't.
Daniel?
Daniel!
- You're
very much like a team.
We're an unbeatable team.
Uh, two beers
and a napkin.
Por favor.
American? English?
Ugh. It's terrible.
I don't like
people like you.
giving you money.
Now, if you just
come over here,
I need a signature,
please.
I know it's a little bit
of a nuisance, but...
That's good.
Thank you.
I'm not depressed.
- It's done.
- What did
they do to you?
Let me use a telephone.
I'm coming, too.
You could let us pass.
Senorita Johnson.
What are you
doing here?
I came to return
your passport.
I am forced to say
I am sad today.
I'm forced to say
I will miss you.
In a way...
In a way,
you were good to me.