Once upon the time, when the yen
was the most powerful force
in the world,
the city overflowed with immigrants
like a gold rush boomtown.
They came in search of yen.
Snatching up yen.
And the immigrants called the city
Yentown.
But the Japanese hated that name.
So, they referred to those Yen Thieves
as Yentowns.
It's a bit puzzling, but Yentown
meant both, the city
and the outcast.
If they worked hard,
earned a pocketful of yen,
and they returned home,
they'd be rich men.
It sounds like a fairy tale.
But it was a paradise of yen.
"Yentown".
And this is the story of
Yentowns in Yentown.
HOMELESS YEN-THIEVES
Name of the deceased?
I don't know.
What do you mean?
- She's a colleague of yours.
- No, she's not.
Don't lie to us.
It's true. I never seen her before.
Whatever. Just get it out of here.
Don't leave it lying around.
What do you think you're doing?
This isn't a fucking funeral home.
What's going on?
What's this?
You can't do that!
They stick cigarettes in rice
in your fucking country?
C'mon, get rid of all this!
What a bunch of freaks.
Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
You're burning down the place!
For fuck's sake!
She wasn't your mother, was she?
No.
Damn Yentowns!
We've never seen her before.
Please forgive me.
A proper funeral
would've cost a fortune.
It's OK, I bet your Mom's
made it to heaven.
Yuriko really stashed it away!
- Give it to me!
- What for?
- I'll settle with you later.
- What do you mean?
I told you, didn't I?
We'll split it later.
Well, it's no use to her now is it?
But I found it!
Take care.
Keep going.
Don't you forget us.
Good luck!
How come I haven't seen you
in so long? Drop by.
Hurry up, WU'-!
She was dealing heroin.
Bloody amateur. Didn't know what
she was getting involved in.
Selling stuff to anyone.
It's no wonder the
Shanghai liumang did her in.
Serves her right.
I'd look after her,
but I have a hard time.
Please help me out!
Would you please?
I beg you, please!
You're not the only one
having a hard time.
If she's too much of a nuisance,
you can do with her whatever you like.
Okay.
What's your name?
Your name?
I asked you a question!
I don't have one.
Bull shit!
Everybody has a name.
You really don't have one?
A pack of cigarettes
costs 250 yen.
A pack a day,
that's 7,500 yen a month.
My old man's a farmer.
He makes 400 yuan a month.
If a yuan is worth 12 yen
then that's 4800 yen.
He couldn't even afford cigarettes.
I never manage to save much.
I never manage to save anything.
It's so hard.
At this rate I'll never get home.
How many do you do in a night?
It's been really slow lately.
Economy's bad, what can we do.
I'm getting cobwebs in my pussy.
I came up with this great game.
I bet with my customers,
that they can't last.
If they come in under 10 minutes,
I win.
If they last longer than 10 minutes,
they win. Sounds easy, huh?
Of course they all think they can last.
If I win, I double the price.
If they come real quick, I triple it!
They win - they get a free ride.
- What do you think?
- Great if they're quick-shooters.
I learned a trick from this
quack doctor.
There's a spot between their ass
and their balls.
Oh god, it works fucking great.
I brought you something.
You shouldn't have.
It was given to me anyway.
Hang on, it's downstairs.
I wonder what it is?
What's your name?
Mine's Glico.
Glico's a weird name, huh?
Do you know what Glico is?
It's a kind of candy.
Japanese businessmen grow up
sucking on Glico.
Wonder what she's bringing me?
Are you Shizuko's sister?
I don't speak Chinese.
No Chinese?
Aren't you Shizuko's sister?
Then who are you?
You're so cute.
What's your name?
Doesn't have one, she says.
Call her anything you want.
- Is that all?
- Yes.
Everyone has to get by
on their own.
Work hard so you get out of
here soon.
Shall we go?
Have you done this before?
Obviously not.
Something like this,
would look great on you.
Look in the mirror.
You know, I...
used to be a school teacher.
I was pretty good at teaching.
You can call me "teacher."
Go ahead, say it.
Hey!
What do you want?
Forgot something?
This isn't enough.
What?
Give me a little more.
But that's all I've got.
Then forget it.
Alright, another 10,000.
Hey, how about 30,000?
Wait! I'll give you 30,000!
- He wanted to pay.
- Huh?
- That man.
- What?
I didn't hear him.
That place is a shit hole.
- Never sell yourself too cheap.
- I'm sorry.
- G/ico!
- Huh?
Who's that new face?
She's my sister
I didn't know you have a sister.
Yeah, from today.
Thinking of him with tears
swelling in her eyes.
Soaking her red sarong
and white blouse.
This?
- A butterfly.
- You like them?
Not really.
This one's called Ageha.
I came to Japan
with my two older brothers.
Ranki and Ryankai.
We planned to save some cash
and go home.
But it wasn't so easy
to find any work.
For a while we scavenged,
living like rats.
We used to rob people
in the streets.
Ranki would snatch their purses
and throw them to Ryankai.
Then Ryankai would dash off.
He'd run like hell and dump it
in a trash can somewhere.
My job was to pick it up.
We made a little money.
But then one day...
Ryankai was making his escape,
when he was hit by a car
and died.
He died instantly.
His head was split right open.
Then all hell broke loose.
Ranki and I tried to get to him, but
there was a huge crowd of people.
Then an ambulance came and a guy
in a white coat was yelling something.
I guess he was shouting
"Does anybody know this man?"
We didn't know any Japanese back then,
so we couldn't understand him.
Ranki and I didn't know
what to do.
Then the ambulance was gone,
and that was it for Ryankai.
I still don't know what
happened to him.
They probably took him to the hospital,
just another 'Yentown'
without a name and nationality.
One more unidentified body.
It'll be the same for me when I die.
It's the same for all Yentowns.
That's why I got this tattoo.
If I die, they'll know who I am.
It's something like an ID card.
Want one, too?
What happened
to your other brother?
I wonder where he is.
He sure is scratching
along somewhere.
You're still a kid,
so you get a caterpillar.
There we are.
DAgehan?
Yep, it's your name.
AGEHA
Ageha.
My name is...
It's too tight.
This is a 20, right?
30 meters...
Forty...
More than 40...
How do I fix it?
Let me see.
Wait! It's coming! Look!
30 meters.
Forty.
Shit!
Did you see that?
Did you see me get his tire?
That was fucking great!
Wait! Wait a minute! Bastard!
Oh shit!
CAR REPAIR SHOP
Hello... my car broke down.
My car is punc.
Car punc.
Please, help me.
FeFHOng!
What's up?
Ah! This tube is shot!
You gonna need a new one.
Please.
No time. Fast? Fast?
Okay, okay. Five minutes.
Get yourself a drink.
Hey, Nihat!
Over there.
There you are.
Thank you very much.
Where did you pick this one up?
You're adorable.
What's your name?
She doesn't speak Chinese.
Name... you got a name?
Ageha.
Age... Ageha?
I named her.
Is that your street name?
I buy her.
How much?
Oh, she's not for sale.
She needs a job... part-time.
Why? We don't need her.
Just sell her.
Please, please, please.
You can give her a job.
Right, Ran?
Ran said it's okay.
Did I?
I'm sorry!
Gasoline empty.
He's back.
Do you have... gasoline?
Hey! Today's not your day,
is it?
What do you want me to do?
Trash hunting.
Look for the good stuff.
See what you can find.
So, you run a recycling shop?
Not really.
See, this is how it goes:
We'll do anything
if it leads to the yen.
Anything... for money?
Like what?
That's what you have to
figure out. Think about it.
Like... killing?
Hey, pick that up.
But it's broken.
Fix it! Umbrellas always sell
when it rains.
You never know when you might stumble
across a chance to get rich.
God gives everyone that same chance.
It depends on if the person decides
to grab it or not.
"Heaven never created a man above another,
nor a man below another."
What's that?
Fukuzawa, the Yentown God
said that.
The wind from the coconut trees
stirs the silver waves.
The setting sun sneaks
behind the clouds.
On the golden beach.
Alone sits a beautiful girl.
Her eyes sparkling like the stars.
Her brows curved like the moon.
Dressed in a red sarong.
As red as the betel nut
in her mouth.
She is sighing lightly.
About that heartless lover.
Thinking of him with tears
swelling in her eyes.
Soaking her red sarong
and white blouse.
Ah, girl of the South China Sea -
It's time to go.
Come on, Ageha!
- Sing us another song.
- Next time.
Hey, gimme.
Oh Glico, sunshine of our hearts.
Who's your lover
in the early morning dark?
You're the belladonna of Yentown
Italian folk songs and
Chinese wine don't mix.
Huh?
Forget it.
BLUE SKY
WELCOME!
Ow! Wait!
What's wrong?
Nothing. It always hurts.
Hurry up!
It's coming! Hurry up!
Fei-Hong's knee always tells
us the weather. Right, Fei-Hong?
Ouch!
Come on! Get out of here.
- "Hey, Ran!
- Hurry up!"
Asshole!
Good luck!
When did your knee go bad?
This? I don't know.
Can't remember.
It's fate's fault.
Fate?
TVs, washing machines,
even those...
they get old and break,
then they die on you.
But we can fix them,
so they can move again.
People...
People just die.
And go to heaven.
I don't know.
Mama...
when she died,
she didn't go anywhere.
She was broken.
There is a heaven!
But nobody ever gets there.
You die and your spirit rises to the sky,
but as soon it touches a cloud
it turns into rain.
So nobody's ever seen heaven.
Don't look so serious.
I just made that up.
So, if people end up in heaven,
then I guess, we're in heaven.
Cut the noise!
I can't hear my damn TV!
Chill out, man!
Cut the noise!
I can't hear my TV!
You're gonna make me!
Hey, I can't hear my damn TV!
You think I'm playin'?
I'm gonna hurt somebody out here.
Aseha?
What's goin' on?
I never get this damn thing.
I can't work out
who's talking to who or what.
Hey, can you see the -
Hey, there you go.
The champ of the world.
Let me show you something.
Gimme a jab. A right hand...
A jab, right hand...
- That's my ex-wife, Kate.
- I know.
Oh I love that woman.
Almost more than I love boxin'.
Before a fight, she used to give me a kiss
in all the places I don't wanna get hit,
Like... my arm, my body, my jaw,
my nose, eyes... temple.
- You want some milk?
- No, thanks.
You know, them kisses used to work, too.
Shit, I never lost a fight. No.
Until that one day I forgot to ask Katie
to give me the damn kiss, you see.
Which I never forget. It was the...
fourth round, right?
And I... and I had him against
the rope, see?
It was left, right... I didn't see
that damn punch comin', see?
So all I remember is... it bein' dark
and me gettin' on off the floor, see?
Oh, if I'd have won that fight, I'd have
had me a championship, man... you know?
That's all right, though,
because I'm still bad.
You know who Mike Tyson is, right?
Cause he ain't nothin'!
Arrow. Want to see some magic?
The one you always do, huh?
Let me... let me cut
the light on for you.
- I'm only gonna do it once.
- All right.
Oh Arrow gonna go get it now.
I'm gonna get it.
- Sorry. I will try again.
- Go ahead.
'Cause I got my eyes on it now.
Oh Arrow's gonna get it.
See.
Maybe my fingers are stiff.
Yeah, let me see
what you got there.
- Let me try again.
- Go ahead. Go.
'Cause I think I got it now.
It's the way you move your hand.
Oh Arrow got it. It's the way
you move your hand.
Son of a bitch! How'd you do that?
You gotta... you gotta
show me that trick.
- Damn. I can't figure it out.
- It's not a trick.
Got a towel?
Isn't there one there?
Oh yeah...
What are you doing in here?
The music's too loud.
You're starting alone?
What are you doing?
- It's OK, I'll pay.
- This one's different.
I said I'll pay.
- I'm gonna call the cops!
- The cops... Oh yeah?
Calling the cops, huh?
Now try and call them! Yes, Sir!
Think you can?
You don't fucking get it,
do you?
A whore house is for
a good time, right?
Goddamn it, sit down.
Both of you, listen to me!
Go get Arrow!
Hold up. Wait a minute.
Just talk to me.
What's wrong?
What's wrong? What?
Talk to me! What?
What the fuck is goin' on?
Shit!
He's fine. He's OK.
- Glico!
- What?
He's still alive.
We have to get help.
Ambulance... ambulance...
What?
He's totally squashed.
Hey, give us a hand!
Let go. Help them! Help them!
- You scared?
- No.
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
Who knows?
- He got me.
- What?
What's this?
It's coming out of his stomach.
A parasite?
- What did you say?
- A parasite or something.
Parasite?
Parasite!
Quiet!
- What are you doing?
- There's something in here.
Between the intestines.
It slipped.
Behind the liver.
Ran, you're gonna burn in hell!
Got it.
What is this?
A cassette tape.
Hey, Glico. Sing something.
What?
Sing what?
Sing something!
Something happy!
Why would something like that
be in his stomach?
That doesn't sound happy.
Singing at a time like this.
- Sud0's disappeared?
- Yes.
We've been out of contact
for a week.
And our little item?
The tape!
It vanished with Sudo.
What did you say?
We are undertaking
a thorough search.
I can't sit around listening to this.
Why the hell are you still here?
Goodness! Going home already?
Boss, look. This is on the house.
At least have a taste
before you go.
What's this?
Boss!
- Oops, pardon me.
- Son-of-a-bitch!
It's all on the house.
Put your gun away,
so we can talk.
Can't you hear me, Tako!
Mao Foo, he's scary.
Shall I pop him?
No hurry, Wan.
Rio Ranki!
Hello, Boss.
So where does the rat
hide himself?
I thought, Rio Ranki
was a gentleman.
You should talk, swindling bastard.
- Wha.. What?
- The tape!
The tape. "My Way"-
What are you talking about?
You gotta be kidding.
You don't know "My Way"?
It's worth a fortune to a collector.
- Wha... what?
- So, I want it back!
Let's see your stomach,
you fucking kangaroo!
Oh, Mao Foo, I forgot my gun.
So, now it's two against four.
We're in big trouble, Mao Foo.
Four minus two equals
two survivors, right?
- Listen Ranki...
- So, two will be left standing.
Who wants to live? You, Boss?
- You're fucking insane!
- How do we decide?
Rock-paper-scissors?
Say, I'm sorry. But there's no
sense in having it out here.
Ranki, how about we make a deal?
We don't deal with small fries like you.
Why didn't you blow me away?
You think these are microphones?
Or maybe... a hair dryer?
Sudo has the tape.
Sudo disappeared.
Where is Sudo?
Where?!
We are looking for him.
What?
He ain't here!
He's been missing for a week.
He ran off with the tape.
When we find him, he's a dead man.
Lying sack of shit.
You can do better.
It's the truth!
We were just talking about it.
- Boss, lying's no good.
- It's the truth!
Let's try again.
Who took the tape?
Sudo!
Who gave the order?
Wan, bring me the bucket.
We're gonna have a blood flood.
I did.
You did?
Much better.
Now, where's Suds'?
I don't know.
Liars go to hell.
The Flaming Pit of Damnation.
Please don't! It's the -
Here comes the bucket.
- Chop it off.
- It's the truth!
Good boy, Boss.
Honesty brings salvation.
- Chop it off.
- But it's true!
He used to pick up Yentown
hookers around here.
A perfect place to hide.
Come with me. I'm cheap.
It's very rare,
that a 'Yent0wn' comes here.
He's not my type.
Don't know him.
Never seen him before.
Here, buy yourself a hit.
He was all squashed!
How long will this go on?
What?
Hey Ran, did you find something?
Nothing there!
In the Sunday Park
Light in the afternoon
I listen to the sound of my dream.
Coming through.
All the mountains of.
Blueberries and greens.
Fairy tale lullaby.
I was down last night.
Too much to handle here.
I didn't know how to carry on.
Still lucky.
All the mess in my
head is fading now.
Among the crowds on the streets.
I wish you'd come to my place.
You would be smiling so close to me.
I wish the day dream never ends.
Hey! What the hell
do you think you're doing?
10,000 yen please.
When I feel a single beat
of my lonely heart.
I can sing, I can cry,
without knowing why.
Yes I tried and tried
to the way to you.
Somehow life always leads
through a maze.
Everyday, every night
you live in my mind.
still pleasure and pain.
And those melodies
of memories will never stop.
You are with me
until the end of time.
Just a day dream
in the Sunday Park.
Our man is now 500 meters
away and closing.
And here's his picture. Hey!
He's in the third car, wearing glasses,
reading the Japan Times.
- I'll take his heart.
- No, I'll take his heart.
And you'll take his head.
- 10 seconds.
- Ready.
I wonder what they're after.
A murder?
Your looking at Sudo Kanji.
He is, or should I say was, a main man
in the Katsushika Syndicate.
About a week ago
Sudo disappeared,
and the "family" put on
a frantic search for him.
But now, the strange thing is
the gang itself has perished.
- Gone. Is history.
- What do you mean?
The boss and all the other
key people are missing.
Organized crime just can't work
without someone to organize it, right?
Now, here are your buddies!
Wan Shaun Shen and Mao Foo.
They're Shanghai Iiumang.
You know, Chinese Mafia.
Mao Foo is one cold blooded
motherfucker, or as they say,
"a pokerface-killer".
For some reason, they too have
been sniffing around after Sudo.
Why, Ran?
I thought I'd ask you
to find out.
And their leader, Rio Ranki.
He's at the top.
I'm talking Liumang King, sitting pretty
on his beautiful Yentown throne.
He looks pretty young to be -
He's only 28.
He was a punk, selling "hot" cars,
and worked his way up.
Before long people were
calling him "The Forger".
Rumor has it, he is already, or is planning
on counterfeiting Fukuzawa notes.
I'm sure he's gonna be called
"The Counterfeiting King".
So Ran, why are you so
interested?
I'm not.
What are you doing?
I don't know. We're doing
Ram's homework.
It's boring.
- Finished yet?
- A little more.
Let me see.
What's that?
It's a 10,000 yen note.
Except its magnetic data.
Every money go through
a lot of different machines.
Cash dispensers, vending machines,
change makers...
They can tell
if the paper's real or not,
by reading the patterns
printed on them with magnetic ink.
Like this pattern here?
Right.
Japanese bills...
are all the same height.
All you have to do to make
a 1,000 yen note the same size
as a 10,000 yen note...
is break that.
You see?
Yes.
So, what happens if you code
this with the magnetic data?
It looks like a 1,000,
but it works like 10,000.
No way, they spot that in a second.
Humans might. But to a machine,
this Soseki looks just like a Fukuzawa.
Okay, ready.
- It doesn't work.
- Wait a sec.
Weird.
Is the show over?
There must be something wrong
with the machine.
One thousand becomes ten.
So, we just made 9,000 yen.
So, by putting in ten of these,
we get 90,000 back, right?
We make a hundred of these
and we have 900,000 yen?
And with a 1,000 bills,
we have 9 million yen?
10,000, that's 90 million!
- That's more Soseki than Chinese.
- 100,000...
That's 900 million!
Theoretically speaking.
It's easy to make 100,000, though!
First you get rich,
then you just get caught.
And then get deported.
It's just a party-trick.
You don't even know how to party.
The money!
Pick it up! Pick it up!
We struck gold.
But it was paper gold.
Even though the sun shone
through the bills,
all I ever saw was the same face
staring back at me.
You're gonna leave your kids?
- Who?
- Your kids! They're yours?
No.
See you!
Hey, Ran!
Ran!
BYE-bye!
We laid our dream
on a wagon of paper gold,
and said good-bye to Blue Sky.
These are the counterfeit notes.
We've found nearly 10,000 in
a matter of days across the city.
Looks amateurish.
Actually it isn't.
Take a look at this.
This is the stolen magnetic data.
Rio Ranki, huh?
Kind of crude for his M.O.,
isn't it?
THOUSANDS OF COUNTERFEIT BILLS
APPEAR ACROSS CITY.
- Take it easy now.
- Bye!
Arrow and Nihat, they went home.
Fei-hong, Glico and me,
we went downtown.
That was the beginning
of our next journey.
That car is something else.
What a piece of junk!
This whole place is ours?
I don't have many properties
like this.
You were lucky.
You'll need a front man.
Yentowns aren't allowed to
make contracts.
The owner's gotta be Japanese?
Don't worry, we'll find someone.
Now, about the staff...
pick the ones you like.
They can start anytime.
It's not going to be
that kind of place.
Glico, stand here for a second.
Over here, right here.
What for?
You want me to be a stripper?
How's this?
Sing something.
Spending every day of my life with you.
Soon you can sing all you want.
This is going to be a live music club.
Your live music club.
We'll have a band, a lot of
customers, and you'll sing.
They'll come to hear you.
It will be the talk of the town.
It'll be standing room only!
Then we'll release a single.
It'll be a big hit.
A star is born! You'll be
the hottest singer in Japan.
What do you think?
You're nuts!
Frankly, it's rare for a live
venue to turn a profit these days.
Make it a girlie bar.
Why don't you get up here
and sing.
- They don't want me.
- Neither do they want me!
What's so funny?
This will definitely become
a live music club.
Not a goddamn girlie bar.
If you want singing,
make it a Karaoke bar.
- Mr. Fei-Hong may have a point.
- Keep out of this!
A legit club could be
a useful front.
Front, back, whatever.
It'll be a straight live music club!
That kind of life
is behind us now.
VeW 900d! Very good!
Great! You're hired!
He's only the first one.
Name?
Betty.
Real name?
Ikeda Yoshiko.
Expeflenced?
It's my first time.
Why "Betty" if you're just starting out?
Are you experienced?
Not very.
How old?
How old are you? Your age?
Twenty-three.
Liar!
Your name?
Well, I'm Asakawa.
Your instrument?
I'm supposed to be the owner.
- What'd he say?
- He said, he's the owner.
Owner?
Very impressive! Isn't he?
Here's the paperwork.
All under Asakawa's name.
But it's just a formality.
If the whole thing goes under,
his life is insured up to
ten million yen.
- Oh, he's an insurance agent?
- No, if the venture folds -
We're not even open yet.
Just in case the club folds and he dies,
you'll collect on the insurance.
- How did you get this guy?
- Too many bad debts.
He had to sell himself, right?
- You bought him?
- Yeah.
We'll take care of any killing
so don't you worry about it.
Our deal is off if they find out.
We're talking about you.
It looks like we've got
all the band together.
All right.
Hey! You're not really gonna
hire that guy, are you?
Why?
That's the only riff
he can play!
You guys are Yentowns, right?
Yentown has its own groove, right?
How can Jap musicians play
the groove of Yentown?
- But you're not a Yentown.
- No, I'm not a Yentown.
Both my parents were American,
but I was born and raised in Japan.
Thanks to the shitty Japanese
education system,
I can't speak a word of English.
- He said, he can't speak English.
- Don't you believe it!
You think it's funny?
Well, I guess it is.
So what am I,
Japanese or American?
The way I look, I'm always
treated like a foreigner.
But fact is, I was born
and raised here.
And nowhere else is home.
From the cradle to the grave
I'll sleep on tatami.
It's OK for you guys.
You've got a country to go back to.
Yentowns have their own
home countries.
How about you, sweetheart?
Where were you born? China?
Japan.
You think you're a Yentown?
- Yes.
- No, you're not.
Did your parents come here
to make money?
You're second generation,
but the Japs don't care.
For them, you're just
another Yentown.
Strange, isn't it?
So...
for us 2nd generation kids,
there should be a special name.
And I came up with one.
Wanna hear it?
"Third Culture Kids."
Good, isn't it?
And our music is called,
"Third Culture Music".
Okay, ya ya, sounds great.
So go ahead, let's hear you play.
- Your instrument?
- I don't play an instrument.
Said he can't play an instrument.
Wait a second. What the hell did you
come here to do, Mr. Third Culture?
Why are you here?
Why I'm here? Well... you could
call me a su... I'm a supervisor.
Super...
It's OK, just leave it to me.
I'll get you the best!
Sounds like the real thing!
Wanna sing? Come on!
Wait, hold it.
Time out! Let's ask our
madonna to sing!
No!
No way! I can't.
Come on up, what would
you like to sing?
I can't sing.
Hey, Glico. Sing "My Way"!
He's kidding?
"My Way" is a bit outdated.
It's music for grandpas.
That music has no soul!
Oh my God, he's really
gonna do it!
And now the end is near.
And so I face the final curtain.
My friends I'll say it clear.
I'll state my case, of which I'm certain.
I've lived a life that's full.
I traveled each and every highway.
And more, much more than this.
I did it my way.
Regrets, I've had a few.
And then again, too few to mention.
I did what I had to do.
Though I saw it through
without exemption.
I planned each chartered course.
Each careful step along the byway.
And more, much more than this.
I did it my way.
I faced it all and I stood tall
For what is a man.
What has he got?
If not himself, then he was not.
To say the things he truly feels.
And not the words of one who kneels.
The record shows I took the blows.
And did it my way.
Mama's alright.
She's got the taste you need.
She's got that smile.
But if you're in doubt.
Pick up the telephone.
Another reason for you to cry.
Another reason
that mama lied to you.
Who said you could put those
up here?
This is our turf. You wanna put
those up, you gotta pay.
No.
So you want a piece of me, huh?
Going easy on women
has gone outta style.
Told you I'm not jokin'!
Get up. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Are you OK?
Mama's alright.
She's got the taste you need.
She's got that smile.
But if you're in doubt.
Pick up the telephone.
Another reason for you to cry.
Another reason
that mama lied to you.
I never felt the real her.
I never touched the real her.
She may not be alive
But she's alright.
But Mama knows
her wrong from right.
And she will say so what.
And Mama knows to be herself.
So she can be with me... and now.
Mama's alright.
She's got the taste you need.
She's got that smile.
But if you're in doubt.
Pick up the telephone.
Another reason for you to cry.
Another reason
that mama lied to you.
But Mama knows
her wrong from right.
And she will say so what.
And Mama knows to be herself.
So she can be with me... and now.
Mama's alright.
She's got the taste you need.
She's got that smile.
Mama's alright.
She's got the taste you need.
She's got that smile.
- Mash Music?
- Yeah, I am.
Make sure you tell everyone
about the club.
Our show's at 7, every night.
You know "Mash Music", right?
How about "A|| or Nothing"?
You know "Free Flower"?
It's a big hit.
- What?
- Oh well...
Mash offered Glico a deal.
Wow!
Ever thought about your
dreams coming true?
I feel like mine have.
Before I dreamed them.
Hey, Ran! Check it out! This is
"A|| or Nothing" by "Free Flower".
Ran! Ran?
Hey!
Take it.
Hey! Hey, Ran! What's this?
Dori-seki.
Dream security.
Mr. Kusunoki of Mash Records.
Good afternoon.
Ms. Hoshino of Popland Music.
We heard your demo,
it's not bad.
Where are you from?
I'm from Shanghai, China.
Difficult to sell
foreigners in Japan.
You know Agnes Chan?
We used to have a band together.
How about Teresa Teng?
God rest her soul.
That's about it
for foreign singers.
Would you become Japanese?
Would be an easier sell.
That's a bit tricky.
The policy of the 'Yentown Band'
is kind of...
different from Japanese er...
The soul... is...
Doesn't sound hip.
Hip? There's no 'hip'
in rock'n' roll.
Do you have a visa?
You don't?
You can tell the truth.
We're not the police.
- Sorry, no.
- What do you think?
We can make it work.
Glico. What're they saying?
Quit being Chinese,
become a Jap.
- What?
- Otherwise I'll never sell.
No, no, no problem.
If it will make Glico a star,
we'll become as Japanese as you want.
So, who are you?
Are you two involved? Or what?
Involved?
No. I'm her...
personal assistant and
manager. That's all.
How will I take a piss,
when I'm a star?
- What do you mean?
- Will it be different?
You'll do it the same as now.
How about sex?
Will it be OK to have sex?
I think I'm gonna come.
- Really?
- Almost.
I'm sorry.
Fly. Fly. Fly-
(Fl)'-
She don't care.
Taking what you give her.
About the way you dress.
She don't care.
To talk to you 'bout nothing.
To thank you for your time.
Sit by the telephone today,
in case you call.
FeFHOng!
- What?
- A visitor!
Watching the telephone again,
it gets me down
I don't want this affair.
- Shit!
- Fei-Hong!
Wait!
Stop! I said stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Okay, okay!
Tell me just one thing.
Who the fuck sold me out?
I can't not speak English.
She don't care.
Taking what you give her.
I feel a little guilty.
She don't care.
Since he was kinda cute.
Thank you for your time.
- What's this?
- The guard messed them all up.
Yummy!
- How's Glico?
- She's well.
The Mash Music people are
coming every day.
Her single's gonna come out
on the 20th.
That's good.
Glico says hi and
sorry she can't come.
Mash Music is so strict.
It's all right.
It's a very important time
for her right now.
Tell her not to worry.
Made these yourself?
You're gonna make a good wife.
Yesterday,
with Dave, we all went to...
Record shop.
A record shop.
We went to a record shop.
And then...
We want to buy "one single each."
Bu? There's none.
We went to another.
But no singles...
there either.
Well, you can't expect too much.
A new band, a new record...
That's what Dave said, too.
But he was wrong.
A man came into the shop
and said...
Shanghai Baby, please.
"What", please?
Shanghai Baby.
The name of... Glico's... single.
The man in the shop said...
How do I say, "sold out"?
"Mai-wan-la."
Mai-wan-la?
Sold out? Amazing!
The customer...
The customer said...
He tried 7 shops,
but they were mai-wan-la.
Sold out...
These are very good
sandwiches. Delicious.
"| will" make them for you again.
I'll be deported.
What?
They'll send me back to China.
Deported. Straight back
to Shanghai.
Why?
Who knows?
Well, you know...
Give everybody my best.
And if you ever come to
Shanghai, look me up!
And...
Take care of yourself.
I Will.
What's music for you, Glico?
Everything.
And lastly, your favorite phrase?
Time is money.
Hey! Check it out!
You gotta see this!
- What?
- What's up?
What is it?
This Way!
- Okay.
- What is it?
Chai found something cool!
What?
Let's check it out.
Is it real?
- Here, just a little.
- No way!
Since you're the one who found it.
Stop it! All of you!
He doesn't want to do it.
Do it yourself!
Me? I'm not...
Scared?
- I'm not scared.
- Do it then, wimp.
Be a man.
You better not...
Feel anything?
Nothing at all.
Stop, please!
Help!
Help us, please!
Fucking kids, get out of the way!
What's all this? Stop a minute.
Help us!
What's goin' on here?
Rio Ranki! It's him!
Over there.
In here, Mr. Ranki.
We melted this...
and with a needle...
What's going on, Boss?
To the hospital!
Your sister?
Kind of.
She shot up. "Yentown White".
This little girl?
What is this world coming to?
Glico.
Glico?
You're a fan of the Yentown Band, huh?
- What?
- Yentown Band.
- You know the singer, Glico.
- What?
You're into rock, Doc?
"Rock Doc", I like that sound.
Obviously, you never heard
of the band, huh?
They're all the rage.
I did that tattoo.
And it's a masterpiece.
I came here
with my brother and sister.
You know, make some quick cash
and cut out.
Yeah, tell me about it.
It didn't work out, right?
My brother died in a car crash.
And, I lost track of my sister.
Now... it's been years.
When we first got here,
we had to think up
Japanese names.
Called ourselves the "Yaohans".
I was "Toyota Yaohan".
Ryankai, my little brother,
he was "Hitachi".
Only Japanese words we knew.
My little sister Xiaodie,
I named Glico.
Xiaodie was such
a little ball of energy.
You know that Japanese candy?
Japanese businessmen
grow up sucking Glico.
That's Opium Street.
Opium Street?
- Ever been there?
- You kidding?
The place is crawling with
mafia and traffickers.
Even the cops won't go there.
That guy Rio Ranki
is so cool, though.
Amphetamines was it?
I don't know.
No larceny, no assault, no drug
offenses. Looks clean to me.
- Destination?
- Shanghai.
That's about 80,000 one-way now.
Got any money?
No.
- Get some.
- Where from?
From your family.
Go on then!
I may go?
Clear out!
Lots of people are waiting.
Get out! Go!
Get the fuck out of here!
Hurry up!
Next. Number 629!
Un-fucking-believable!
Ageha!
He's back! Mr. Fei-Hong.
61, 62, 63,
64, 65, 66...
This is it. No more.
Forget about Glico
from today on.
Glico? Who's that?
I can't seem to remember.
But if I do, I'll be sure
to let you know.
One million, right on the money.
You want a receipt?
I know you're the one ratting
me out to the cops.
I can see right through you.
I'll do my best. So, Fei-Hong,
you do your best, too.
Huh?
That's what Glico said.
She won't listen to any of us.
You know, she's still chasing
after the bone you've thrown.
Is that what you call...
the power of love?
Lucky bastard!
Afternoon!
Grumpy bitch.
You got PMS or something?
Hey there!
What's going on?
Desperate for cash?
You piece of shit.
- What do you want?
- Blackmailing the manager?
- What are you so steamed about?
- Calm down!
- Stay out of it!
- Quit the fucking English, asshole!
Somebody translate this.
We quit.
- What is this?
- Fuck you.
I've had enough!
Ageha get over here and translate.
Ageha, translate!
- What...
- What's this shit?
Give it back you punk.
- What is it?
- It looks like a million!
How much did you get for Glico?
Let me go!
Put me down! I'm the boss, right?
I'll fire you all!
Out! Out! Out!
We don't understand Chinese,
you bastard!
Ageha, tell them!
They want to know,
how much you got for Glico,
and why you're so greedy.
Glico was a valuable business tool.
What's wrong
with making some money?
Go on...
Tell them!
He said, "Glic0 was an
important tool of the trade."
And, "What's wrong with
making some money?"
So, he really said that?
Yentown scum.
- Please wait a minute.
- It's over.
Wait a second.
Good thing they got out
before it was too late.
You've been let off
the hook this time.
Look out! Be careful you idiot!
Damn shit!
Hoan!
Hey, Boss!
- Where are we going?
- Opium Street.
I'm not going.
Are you afraid?
No, but...
What are you going there for?
Something good.
These people all
entered the country illegally.
They live here 'cause
they have no other home.
Excuse me. We're sorry.
He's dead.
That's opium.
Is this it?
It says "medical center".
URINARY ORGANS,
ACUPUNCTURE & TATTOOS
Hey!
Hi.
How've you been feeling? Okay?
No more shooting up, huh?
So, what's up this time?
You catch a cold or something?
Doctor, you do tattoos, right?
Yes, I do.
- How much?
- Huh?
How much would it cost?
You want a tattoo?
Boss, you're getting a tattoo?
Wow! That's great!
That's fucking great!
So, what kind do you want?
Butterfly. On my chest.
Ah, like Glico's.
But... this is all I've got.
No, no... it's not the money.
You gotta think of a tattoo
as a living thing you raise in your body.
See, a tattoo can change
your character...
can change your destiny!
So you just can't lay one
on anybody.
Here's the right wing...
Here's for the left wing.
The body, I keep.
I can't fly anyway.
Take your shirt off
and lie down.
Do most doctors tattoo?
Nah, you need many skills,
you know.
First, you gotta be an artist.
Then, you gotta have vision.
Like a fortune-teller.
- A fortune-teller?
- Yes.
You wanna come here
a little more?
Wow! You got beautiful skin!
It's begging for an exquisite design.
Will it hurt?
Uh-huh.
That's a girl. Hang in there.
Tell me about the first time
you saw a butterfly.
Just try to remember.
A small room...
with a window.
And where was that?
I don't remember.
I think, you do.
I heard a voice.
Yeah?
Somebody calling.
"Mama!"
Like a kid?
Maybe.
What else?
What's in the room?
Nothing.
Come on. There's gotta be
something in the room.
I don't remember.
Yes, you do.
A bathroom...
Kiyoshi, eat!
Eat!
She's playing...
By herself.
She's calling Mama
from the bathroom.
Why is she there?
She's always in the bathroom,
when Mama works.
If she calls out...
Mama scolds her.
So why call her?
She's trying to tell her
there's a butterfly.
She wants to catch it.
But...
If Mama doesn't hurry,
it will fly away.
Mama!
Was that my memory?
I wonder, if that was really me.
If which was...
The little girl watching the butterfly?
Or the butterfly
that got squashed?
How's that, huh?
Another masterpiece.
This butterfly...
It's called Ageha in Japanese.
Oh, yeah? What's it called
in English?
I don't know.
It's called a swallowtail.
'Cause it's shaped
like a swallow's tail.
Swallowtail?
It's gonna protect you,
no matter how hard things get.
Hey, believe me!
'Cause I gave it
that... magical touch.
- Ms. Suzukino.
- Yes?
- You've got a visitor.
- Where?
In the conference room.
I'm Suzukino.
May I ask your name?
Nice to meet you.
You write this column, don't you?
That's right.
I read it every week.
How may I help you?
Do you know a guy name
Sudo Kan?
Look, this guy.
You wrote this too, right?
Oh, the deputy of the
Katsushika syndicate.
I saw how he got killed.
What?
He fell from a window.
Glic0's window.
You know Glico?
I doubt it. I only know the Glico
from that Yentown Band.
Oh, so you do know her.
I suppose a customer
took this picture.
She used to be a prostitute?
This would be quite a scandal.
How much would you pay for this?
Can I have some more?
Thank you.
I was lucky to get this gig.
I'm a big fan.
Ageha!
Give me the tape.
The tape?
Why do you need it?
Make fake money.
What for?
Buy it back.
Buy what back?
Everything.
What's the story here?
This is Randy Heavens from Yoga.
Koichi from Suzugamori.
Chu Ba Jeh from Namamugi.
Shao Kampao from Gasu Bridge.
Chu-Bin from Tennozu.
They're a weird bunch,
but they can pull it off.
- Hoan.
- What?
Is that your woman?
Who do you think you're talking to?
What do you want, sweetheart?
Let's be clear, this is strictly business.
Business?
How's a million each sound?
Boss, that's too much!
What's the job?
I'll explain.
Wow!
I can't believe this.
- Here.
- Next.
Here.
Next.
Is that all?
Stop complaining.
Next.
Hurry up!
They'd never know
if we pinched some.
If they found out,
you'd be in deep shit!
Come on.
Hurry up!
Next.
Is that everything?
Let's have it.
- Good job.
- Thank you very much.
Next.
You did well to get so many.
It wasn't easy, was it Chu-Bin?
No big deal.
It's ripped.
What are you doing?
It's just one...
What do you think you're doing?
Got a problem with that?
What the hell?
- Good morning.
- Nice to see you.
- Hi, Ms. Glico! How are you?
- It's great to have you here.
Why don't you have a seat?
Yentown Band sure is popular.
Excuse me.
I'd like to ask a few questions
while you get ready.
Mind if I record it?
Am I the only one who's nervous?
- The new album's out on the... 21st?
- Yes.
OK, let's talk about that first.
Would you move the blue Porsche?
- Sure. Just a second.
- I'm terribly sorry.
What's that there?
- What's that?
- This?
- How pretty. It's a tattoo, right?
- Yes.
Isn't that nice!
It suits you're image.
But it's just like this one.
- This is you, isn't it?
- Dunno.
You don't know?
But it's exactly the same.
What is this? I don't know
what you're talking about.
OK. Let me put it this way.
What did you do with Sudo's body?
You know, the guy who fell
out of your window.
Remember? Back when you
were a hooker.
Look! Stop bullshitting!
What are you doing?
What've you got in your mouth?
Spit that out!
Hey, look at her! Spit it out!
You can't swallow it!
Alright, I don't care. Go ahead.
But this proves
that you were involved.
You're giving yourself away.
Aren't you?
Get it?
Now, give me back
that soggy picture.
Don't be so childish!
You're back?
I'll wait for you out back. Come alone.
Excuse me.
OK, I have to go.
Sorry about earlier.
I overdid it a bit.
If I hadn't done it, we wouldn't
be able to talk like this.
It's not like I'd publish
anything and everything.
It's more like you've
piqued my curiosity.
Know what I mean? It's my job,
like singing is for you.
I don't sing because I like it.
You don't like singing?
I hate it.
The singer who hates to sing.
That's a good one.
Why is that?
I don't wanna be the object
of your curiosity, thanks.
Guess I hit a nerve.
Open up!
- Open up!
- Okay.
Can I help you?
Want a bullet in the face?
Hey, you! Where's Sudo's tape?
Tell me where it is!
Get out!
Just a second.
Don't shoot, please...
Don't shoe Understand?
I'm stuck. Let me get the...
get the cigarette.
Duck!
Morons!
You know "Telekura"?
Yeah.
The name is "Lovely Friends".
Teen's recommendation.
How about you?
I don't know.
Good luck.
Telephone!
Can I get for you?
Hello.
Fei-Hong? Fei-Hong? Is that you?
It's Glico.
Hey Glico. What's up?
How are you?
Fine. And you?
Good. How's everyone?
Oh, very good.
Fei-Hong...
Were you on TV the other day?
Fei-Hong, listen...
Maybe it was someone else.
What did you do with that tape?
Tape?
O' My Way I.
There are some weird guys
after me.
They're looking for the tape.
They have guns.
What should I do?
It's probably llumang.
They'll kill us.
Where are you?
Where are we?
No idea.
We don't know.
Who's with you?
Fei-Hong...
If I get killed -
What do you mean?
Forgive me.
What for?
Becoming a singer and
leaving you all behind.
Cut the crap!
Forgive me.
Stupid, everyone's
happy for you!
If I get killed -
OK, tell me where -
If they kill me -
Who? You've never been
the timid type before.
I may never see you again!
Don't worry, I'll help you.
Where are you?
What's around there?
FeFHOng!
Hello?
Meet me at Blue Sky.
Fei-Hong? Fei-Hong?
What's going on?
I would appreciate it
if you'd explain to me...
just exactly what's going on?
Hey!
They're here.
I bet Mao Fee's having fun
with Glico right now!
All we got
was the faggot patrol.
Hey, I thought that was
right up your alley!
Shut up!
Was Glico really a whore?
Did you all get to stick it to her?
That's right. Jealous?
I can't see!
The blood won't stop!
You'll pay for this!
- Open up!
- Hey!
Hey taxi! Taxi!
Wait!
- Oh, shit!
- What's up?
My money! Mr. Fei-Hong!
Do you have the money?
Huh? Let me see...
It's not enough. More money?
What's With this bill?
What's this?
Will 10 be enough?
Keep an eye on him!
Money! I'll be back with 10,000.
What're you...
The God of Yen has not
forsaken us!
Mr. Fei-Hong!
Go in! Go in!
Huh? What kind of idiot
carjacks a taxi,
and then pays the fare?
Give it back!
What are you doing?
This bank note is invalid.
Where is Ran?
Ran! Ran! Ran!
Hey, long time no see.
Ran, she's my friend.
Hi, nice... I'm glad to see you.
Isn't he a nice man?
What's the matter?
Ran, do you have
that cassette tape?
What about it?
I just wanna borrow it.
Why?
- Come on...
- Let me have it!
What do you need it for?
Come on! Please, Ran!
Who's that?
More friends?
Isn't this overkill?
Shut up! Mr. Ranki's orders.
Just for one little tape?
That's stupid. Ridiculous!
It can't be helped.
Mr. Ranki's orders.
This is no fun at all!
Please Ran, the tape! Hurry!
It's not here.
What?
Ageha took it.
Aim!
Fire!
I'll find some other tape.
- Right?
- Other tape?
That won't work!
Buy me some time!
We're looking for it!
Glico!
Hey, look what I found.
Wait, wait, wait...
What are you doing?
Please, stop that!
- Stop it. I beg you.
- Ran!
OK.
This guy got a death wish?
Interesting. Very interesting.
Hold your fire!
Worry about the tape later.
Mao Fee's on the Warpath now.
He's a dead man.
Hey!
How about one-on-one?
If you get me,
we'll let you all live.
What's he saying?
One-on-one.
Mao Foo don't make
promises like that.
He's coming!
Glico. When I give the signal,
get down.
Okay. What kind of signal?
- Gimme any signal!
- Get down.
Today's not your day, is it?
What is this, a war?
Sorry, we're closed.
Oh, Ageha. What brings you here?
What's all this?
I want to buy it back.
The Yentown Club.
Will you sell it to me?
You may be a kid,
but you have a lot of cash.
- Where did you get all that money?
- It's a secret.
Did you rob a bank?
Oh, I forgot.
It's already been sold.
What! To who?
It's too late.
- I'll buy it off them.
- You can't do that.
Why not? Yes I can!
- But I've got all this money!
- No means no!
Go home.
Take the money with you.
The left print is from
the forgery.
They match, don't they?
It's the same guy.
Run a check on
Rio Ranki's group.
We may have something this time.
Liumang King, I'm gonna get you.
Who hired you?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Don't play dumb with me.
Lately, the same fake bills
pop up all over the town.
You did all that
by yourself, huh?
What's he talkin' about?
Then where did you get this?
I found it.
He found it.
Lying hurts, doesn't it?
Even a Yentown
can understand that!
Or, do you need a little
taste of death?
Hey, Yentown!
Who's your boss? Tell us
and we'll let you go.
Is it Rio Ranki?
I don't know.
He doesn't know.
Want money, Yentown?
Will you talk for money?
Yentowns do anything for money.
Talk!
Yentown!
Your whole fucking country
is nothing but a Yentown!
That's what he said.
Get up!
Bastard!
Fuckin' cop.
I'll kill that bastard one day.
God, it hurts.
Un-fucking-believable!
The guy was singing a song
all night long.
A song?
Yeah. "My Way".
You're right. He's dead.
Name of the deceased?
FeFHong.
What?
Hio Fei-Hong.
A Chinese?
From Fujian or Shanghai?
Yentown.
Glico.
The caterpillar turned into
a butterfly.
Hey! What are you throwing away?
How much was there?
Lots.
How much was it?
I forgot.
Shit!
Once upon a time, when the Yen
was the most powerful force
in the world,
the city overflowed with immigrants
like a gold rush boomtown.
They came in search of Yen.
Snatching up Yen.
And the immigrants
called the city Yentown.
But the Japanese hated that name.
So they referred to those
yen thieves as Yentowns.
It's a bit puzzling, but "Yentown"
meant both the city,
and the outcasts.
If they worked hard,
earned a pocketful of yen,
and they returned home,
they'd be rich men.
It sounds like a fairy tale,
but it was a paradise of yen.
"Yentown".
And this is the story of
Yentowns in Yentown.
Come on, lad. You're always
late. Get in there.
The target just passed the
2 kilometer mark.
Should be there in one minute.
- You know about tonight's main dish?
- Nah.
He's your buddy. Liumang King.
We're checking now, but...
We heard the Fuchen umang
were on the move.
The Fuchen are behind it?
It's hard to believe.
In any case, Mao Foo and the
whole gang have vanished.
The police have got wind
of the tape, too.
We should move quick.
If we get the tape, we can
cash in and return to Shanghai.
Or, maybe I'll buy this whole
town and fix the place up.
Yentown.
God, how I hate it.
' Stop! "Huh?"
Hey!
You're looking well!
Not too bad.
Stay out of trouble, okay?
- Shopping?
- Yeah, for my store.
- Your store?
- It's over there, across the highway.
What do you sell?
- Boss, we should be going!
- Right.
- You're a busy man.
- I lost something I need.
Gotta go.
Wait!
For helping me.
What's on it?
"My Way!
Don't you know "My Way"?
Hey!
What's your name?
Ageha.
Aseha?
Glico gave me my name.
You know, Glico the hooker.