Your tea, sir.
Thank you.
Bean-jam wafers, too.
That's wonderful.
There are still some left.
I'l serve them to
your guests tomorrow.
That would be waste.
Candied peanuts will
be more than enough.
I did enjoy
last week's meeting.
Everyone had such
interesting opinions.
Your riddle,
"Ten Nights of Dreams."
When d'you think it'll be solved?
A hundred years hence.
A hundred years?
Il have to be reborn
if I'm to see it.
Original Story by
Soseki Natsume
Ten Nights of Dreams
A First Night of
Dreams Hyakken
Directed by Akio Jissoji
Screenplay by Teruhiko Kuze
Thank you very much.
Your noodles.
Another goldfish has died.
May I get another?
Of course, if it's dead.
But they'll only die on you.
Itll die anyway,
so buy another breed.
You never even look at them.
Thank you.
Are you alright, sir?
I'm so sorry.
Notat all. In fact,
it makes me look more dashing.
Thank you, sir.
Goldfish for sale
Tsugumi.
Yes?
What time is it?
If's almost noon.
That's strange,
I'm not at all hungry.
Hunger is never requir,
it's not clockwork.
What did I eat this morning?
Chilled Tofu.
What about last night?
Grilled Tofu with Miso.
What's for dinner?
Sesame Tofu.
You may complain
Tofu is all I feed you.
But sesame Tofu isn't
made from soy.
It's ground sesame
mixed with potato starch.
How careless,
I left my wallet here.
Here itis, sir.
Good.
You're very thin,
you need to put on weight.
What are you now,
16 or 17?
} Master Hyakken,
is there money in writing novels?
I earn well,
without working hard.
By the way Madame,
what time is it?
It's just past ten.
I see.
Stop that, you pervert!
You're incorrigible.
-A pervert, eh?
How much is it, now?
I thought I'd written
over thirty pages...
No, I don't mean that.
How many years
have we been together?
Dear?
Darling.
Has it been fifty years?
A hundred years?
Despite the brevity,
I thank you for everything.
The time has come for me to
take my leave.
You're leaving?
Well, as of tomorrow,
there's no more work for me.
And being here alone,
with you, frightens me.
I mean, after all,
you are a man.
You have always
cherished me.
And yes,
I've been happy.
Recently, you seem to
have lost weight.
Your stomach is weak,
so you must only drink boiled water.
I've left you some stomach pills
in the buffet.
Be sure to take one pill
each morning.
Tofu is good for your digestion.
You can have it boiled,
or broiled.
It goes well with plain rice, too.
Have it boiled,
to go with your sake.
Are you going away?
You always knew I would,
from the very beginning.
No, this is the first time.
You've cherished me for
a hundred years.
Can you now wait another
undred for me?
As you know, the sun rises.
And then it sets.
The big red sun travels
from east to west.
Every single day
it completes its journey.
So can you not wait for me?
It matters not to me...
...that you may find another
to love when I am gone.
And with that...
...my time to die has come.
Bury me with the goldfish.
Time is going backwards.
A hundred Jars must have
already gone by.
Zigeunerweisen, Composed ♪
Recorded by Sara Sate in 1904
A Second Night of Dreams
Directed by Kon Ichikawa
My dream was as this:
You are a Samurai.
As such, }
you are open to spiritual awakening.
You came to sit in meditation,
didn't you?
You're taking too long
to be spiritually awoken.
So you cannot be a Samurai.
You are but the dregs
of mankind.
Does that make you angry?
If you feel chagrin,
show me evidence of your enlightenment.
I shall attain spiritual realization.
It will come upon me
before the clock strikes yet again.
In exchange for enlightenment,
I shall gain a monk's tonsure.
But to realize that,
I must attain enlightenment.
Should I fail, I shall die.
I could not live with
such a burden of shame.
Emptiness
Emptiness? Nothing?
Damn monk!
Empty nothing,
vacuum nothing.
What a hateful wretch!
I shall have his head!
Nothing.
You must awaken to emptiness.
Alas, my time is up.
I must die!
I cannot do it.
I cannot even pierce my flesh...
Enlightenment is upon you.
The End
Soseki Natsume's residence.
Waseda Minami, Tokyo
A Third Night of Dreams
I'had a dream...
A Third Night of Dreams;
My dream was about...
What was it?
Written & Directed by
Takashi Shimizu
The iceman!
Here's the iceman!
Don't run in the house!
Little Junichi will wake.
Don't go near the saw.
Don't get so irritated.
They're only children.
Don't run in the house!
Weren't you like that
as a child?
Why do I get so irritated?
It's easy to blame
the kids when I can't write.
You had brothers and sisters,
didn't you?
They say I had five brothers
and three sisters.
That's right
I was a child once.
But it's so strange.
I have no memories of
my childhood.
I wonder what you were like.
A sensitive boy
with a delicate stomach.
I was the last. They adopted
me out when I was born.
Not again.
Aiko,
play with your Dad.
Children!
I said don't wake the baby.
How did I grow up?
They're like a different species.
I'm not confident fo
have this child.
I'm sorry, dear.
1 had that dream again...
Junichi finally got off to sleep.
Dear?
What's wrong?
You look so serious.
No, it's nothing...
Are you alright?
Don't say that.
Did you have that same nightmare?
You know,
this is my sixth child.
Kyoko miscarried their
first baby ten years ago.
With the 2nd, she had a breakdown
and attempted suicide.
I'm sure this baby
will be fine.
I just feel confident.
When I was a girl...
...many stone statues lined
the mountain path near my house.
I used to play there.
One day...
I broke off one of the
heads by accident.
I was so scared.
I never played there
after that day.
Why tell me that now?
When I lost the first baby,
honest, I kept dreaming about
that headless Jizo statue.
A nightmare?
Yes.
The other day, I dreamt
it again after a long time.
That's a very strange dream.
I broke the head off
the sixth statue.
But I putit back in place.
really think this one is
our first child reborn.
Sorry, Junichi.
I woke you up.
Excuse me, dear.
I'l take him.
You get some rest.
The baby I was carrying
stopped crying.
I felt so sure that he's
my son.
But it was so mysterious...
When did you lose your sight?
Along time ago.
We're near the rice paddy now.
How did you know?
I hear the herons crying.
Herons?
I can't go on carrying
this monster.
I must dump him somewhere.
Why are you laughing?
Am I heavy, Daddy?
No, you're not.
Soon, I'l get heavier.
What do you mean?
You see those statues lined up?
Statues?
No need to count them.
There are six of them.
You know?
Wait a minute.
There are seven.
But one of them will break.
What are you saying?
Want to leave?
Let's go.
By all means.
You'll know as we
get further along.
It was a night like this.
What was?
You know what I'm talking about.
Somehow, I felt I knew it
Surely, it was a night like this.
Yes, if I keep going,
ll find th ih
But my instinct tells me
I shouldn't know.
I should never discover it
so I must hurry and dump the child.
I must be free from him
as soon as possible.
Yes, here.
You knew it all along.
1 had nowhere fo
run to any more.
It was the summer of 1880.
The Year of the Dragon,
wasn't it?
That was when you killed me.
Twenty eight years ago,
wasn'tit?
Yes, a dark night
Just like this.
I killed a child who was
unable fo resist.
Now I remember.
I'm a murderer.
Yes,
that summer I was thirteen.
That day at that hour,
1 killed myself.
...and I was but a child!
I knew there were six of them.
One of them will be broken.
Soseki's sixth child, Shinroku,
was born December 17, 1908.
But, two years later, his seventh child,
Hinako, died suddenly at age one.
The reason why is
unknown to this day.
A Third Night of Dreams,
My dream was as this.
Ill write it anyway.
I am carrying my six year
old son on my back.
He is surely my own son...
The baby finally got off to sleep.
Dear?
What's wrong?
You look so serious.
Mr Soseki Natsume,
thank you very much
for coming for a lecture.
I will meet you at the station.
Haruka Hyuga
A Fourth Night of Dreams
Directed by Atsushi Shimizu
She's not here.
I don't suppose you are
Miss Haruka, are you?
I'm a married woman,
Il have you know.
"Mr Soseki,
Urgent business, can't make it.
"Please take the bus to the
lecture hall. Haruka"
Fourteen, so far
Excuse me.
What time do you depart?
"4th district, Omokagebashi..."
"From Haruka Hyuga"
Hyuga's daughter was
spirited away as a child.
And not just her,
all the children disappeared.
And who was it
who took them away?
Strange.
Haven't we seen you before?
No, never.
Next stop is public hall.
Ifyou wish alight,
please press the buzzer.
Public hall?
I can't see it.
"4th district, Omokagebashi..."
That can't be right!
There are children everywhere.
Keep watching.
It will turn into a snake.
"Keep watching.
It will turn into a snake."
A snake?
That's ridiculous.
That's mine.
Give it back.
Hey, wait.
Come back.
"Keep walching.
It will turn into a snake."
This can't be right.
Spiited away?"
Silly superstition.
What?
That's me.
Welcome Soseki
Public alert!
A photo-chemical smog
Is currently upon us.
Blood...
It's all coming back.
I think this was where...
...I came to regain my health.
Soseki!
You're late.
What's going on here?
What's my connection with here?
Soseki.
Soseki,
are you feeling better now?
Can you come on the
excursion tomorrow?
No.
I don't think I can.
Right.
You have a fever.
But it's no fun without you.
Now I remember.
Soseki, this way.
Why?
How did I forget it all?
Missing Child
Kiyoko Kurata
Missing child
Shotaro Shiranui
Bring back our daughter
Haruka Hyuga
Flight 607
still missing
This is bizarre...
Hey!
I was waiting for you.
I couldn't make it.
I found this seashell for you.
Listen,
it sounds beautiful.
I hear nothing.
Then you can't join us.
What a pity.
But I'l give to you.
Farewell, Soseki.
You mustn't go!
But I will go.
I want to see it
turn into a snake.
Only you, again?
What?
Can't you add it all up?
When you awaken,
you forget your dreams.
But you must iy to remember,
even if you don't want to.
After this,
I'l never forget them.
Fifteen in all
This is the dream I had.
A Fifth Night of Dreams
Directed by
Keisuke Toyoshima
Yes?
I'll wait till dawn,
when the cocks crow.
Shotaro?
Mommy.
Shotaro, wait
Shotaro, please wait.
Shotaro?
Long time no see.
How've you been?
Mommy, Mommy...
Hideki...
What a great house.
You must be happy.
Stop it!
No, Shotaro.
You mustn't look.
Don't look!
It's coming, Masako.
Welcome home...
Who are you?
Welcome.
I'm back, take care.
I'll wait till dawn,
when the cocks crow.
..until dawn,
Dawn is coming,
you must hurry.
Damn it!
Shotaro, don't look.
Please!
Mommy...
Hideki.
-Mommy.
Stop gawking.
Get an ambulance!
Hideki.
Wake up!
Yes?
I'll wait till dawn,
when the cocks crow.
Shotaro?
Sorry, did I wake you?
No, I got woken up
by a nightmare.
You don't mind?
This is also me.
Not at all.
You don't mind?
A Sixth Night of Dreams
Directed by
Suzuki Matsuo
The End
A Seventh Night of Dreams
Directed by Yoshitaka Amano
& Simmei Kawahara
The End
An Eighth Night of Dreams
Directed by Nobuhiro Yamashita
That's huge!
-What bait did you use?
Fish paste.
Just fish paste?
That's unbelievable.
What bait?
It's awesome!
It's huge.
-He used fish paste.
-Really?
You caught this with fish paste?
Just fish paste?
That's awesome!
What were you using?
-He's lying.
-No, he's not.
Mitsu never lies.
If he said he did,
he did.
Listen, Mitsu.
You'll soon tire of it.
What if it dies?
Where can we dump it?
Ill feed it.
Il get stuck looking after it.
Riki, no!
Hello, Grandpa.
Listen to me, Mitsu.
We'll talk to uncle
in the hills.
Riki.
Will it change form?
I know it will!
That was delicious.
Soseki, forty one years old
The Eighth Night
by Loseki
I've previously written of Unkei,
the sculptor.
This is his place.
But what if it's not?
He's still asleep.
He sleeps in the daytime.
Who'll do it?
You.
No, let's all do it.
You started it.
Alright.
Say it together.
One, two!
Come on, say it.
Alright, I will.
One, two!
Master Ogail
The End
One moonless night,
Father went away.
I have received
my call to duty.
I shall perform
my military duties.
As a son of Japan,
I have longed for this opportunity.
I am honored to serve.
I ask you to care for my
eloved son,
and my helpless wife,
while I serve my country.
In your stead, I shall fight like
a demon for our sacred land.
I shall pit my life against
the enemy.
Thank you very much.
To the Japanese Empire,
anzail
Banzai!
A Ninth Night of Dreams
Pray for your Daddy's
safe return.
Did you say a prayer?
You're a good boy.
Don't go!
Are all present?
On my order, attack!
Go!
Darling.
Can't you do something?
Like what?
Must you leave us
and to go off to war?
I didn't marry a soldier.
I did it because I wanted
to share my life with you.
So you would be by
my side forever.
Daddy!
Heaven can be
wherever you are
Here he comes,
such a slacker is he
It's Onikichi,
the so fast on his feet
Yes, here he comes,
back for more...
Here I come, sweetheart.
Mommy!
You said you hated
the military.
Not so loud.
Walls have ears.
You told me you hated the army,
didn't you?
Let me explain.
Il be very careful and
I promise I'll come back to you.
What does that mean?
What will I do without you?
Without you
my life meaningless.
Calm down, dear.
Not my draft card!
It's not our war.
Just leave it there.
I beg you!
Look what you've done.
I don't care.
My draft card...
The time has come,
I tell you now
Take your time,
no need for haste
We shall meet again,
some other time, in another place
Directed by
Miwa Nishikawa
Look.
Isn't that Shotaro?
Itis.
He went missing, didn't he?
Someone go tell Ken
he's back.
Better tell him.
Good god,
he looks terrible.
Oh, he's dead.
A Tenth Night of Dreams
Directed by Yudai Yamaguchi
He's alive!
Are you alright?
Ken,
isn't that my panama hat?
Yes, you're right.
Sorry about that.
How on earth did you
make it back?
-What happened?
-I'd rather not say.
On second thoughts,
I haven't much time.
I'd best tell the story.
There's Shotaro again
with his panama hat and cane.
He only works afternoons.
at a loafer.
He's the best looking kid in town,
and he's got a good heart.
Women come from miles around
to see him.
But all he does all day
is stare out at the street.
What's he's thinking?
Look, here's another one.
I bet she comes
just to look at him, too.
His business does well.
The luck of the handsome.
No matter who itis,
he keeps his cool.
That's what you get for
being upright.
The ugly have no right to live!
Go to hell,
you ugly pig!
Excuse me.
Excuse me?
When the mysterious
Yoshino appeared,
Shotaro left town
as if bewitched.
He had no idea that
this would bring him
aliving hell,
worse than he could ever imagine.
Menu
Pig bowl (Large)
Pig?
I hope you like it.
Does its lusciousness
delight even you?
Go ahead, eat.
No need to hesitate.
Delicious!
Oh, I'm so full.
I've never expected pig
to taste so good.
"Very good!"
In that case,
Il show you how we make it.
Quch!
Are you ready?
Faster, faster.
Go, go!
Why are they so ugly?
~ Asyou can see,
all our ingredients are fresh and pure.
Naturally,
we use no artificial additives.
All of our processes use the
most hygienic materials.
Next, itis heated to 80 degrees
in a large pot.
And special, succulent slices
are added for flavor.
Itis then simmered to perfection.
Next, is our most
secret ingredient.
Special, selected spices
make for a perfect finish.
What a waste.
That was made especially for you.
You can't be serious!
That's not pig,
it's human!
Culinary Armageddon!
A filthy, self-absorbed killer,
like you,
deserves nothing less than that!
Who the hell are you?
At that moment,
he recalled the words of his friend,
Gennai Hiraga, the inventor.
If you're ever in the clutches of
maddened monsters,
just push this button.
No need.
It's highly unlikely to happen.
Now!
Thank you, Gennai.
Fart attack!
Shall I show you my true self?
You stink!
Smells like shit.
Forgive me.
I'l never kill anyone again.
I'am so sorry.
Please forgive me.
I'm sorry.
I beg you.
Please.
I'm really very sorry.
I apologize.
I'm ever so sorry.
Forgive me.
Is that right?
How did you get hurt?
You never mentioned that.
This, you mean?
As I was on my way back...
-That's all.
-Really?
I'd better get some sleep.
It's time to die.
But Shotaro did not die.
He lived on until his 138th year.
And he became the world's
first astronaut.
No way!
That'll never happen to me.
It happened!
Thank you, Gennai.
The End
A hundred years...
Is it here already?
"Ten Nights of Dreams"
Or will it take another
hundred years?