NIKKATSU PRESENTS
THE MOON HAS RISEN
Directors Guild of Japan
Produced by Eisei KOI
Written by Yasujiro OZU
and Ryosuke SAITO
Cinematography Shigeyoshi MINE
Lighting Ko FUJIBAYASHI
Sound Masakazu KAMIYA
Art Direction Takeo KIMURA
Music Takanobu SAITO
Assistant director Buichi SAITO
Film editor Mitsuo KONDO
Production Hiroyoshi HAYASHIMOTO
Cast
Chishu RYU as Asai
Shuji SANO as Takasu
Hisako YAMANE as Chizuru
Yoko SUGI as Ayako
Mie KITAHARA as Setsuko
Ko MISHIMA as Amamiya
Shouji YASUI as Shouji
Kinuyo TANAKA as Yoneya
Junji MASUDA as Tanaka
Miki ODAGIRI as Fumiya
Yo SHIOMI as Jikai
Directed by
KINUYO TANAKA
How time has passed by,
since we parted.
The years have fled.
I grew up a great deal.
And then she said:
"Time is far away
When my hair was
short like yours.
Today they are beautiful
and fall in the middle
of my back."
She said:
"Time is far away
when my hair was
short like yours.
Today they are beautiful
and fall in the middle
of my back.
You are the only pure being
allowed to gently
caress my hair."
They sang with melancholy.
The time when their hearts
had softened.
The father of a young lady...
Wataru Amamiya
It's been a long time.
- How are you?
- You're early.
- Did my postcard come?
- Yes. Come on in.
I just went to see Mr. Asai.
So? I'm renting a room here.
It has been a long time.
Why did you go to Osaka?
You know what
microwaves are?
What?
The highest frequency waves.
Used for telephones.
I'm doing data on them.
Sit down.
Using them, Tokyo and
Osaka are like local calls.
Sounds convenient,
from when?
Almost done now, from April.
The Tokyo-Nagoya-Osaka
TV circuit too.
So? You've finished
your work then?
Just about.
You can take it easy then.
Here's some fried seaweed.
Thanks.
- What are you doing everyday?
- Just loafing around.
Why did you quit
your last job?
Got in a fight and got tired.
There are bad people in Kobe.
So, you've been out of
a job since then?
Mr. Asahi's worried too,
but there's no work.
I could make something
translating.
You lead a good life.
Things are not what they seem.
Same with me.
It's quiet here.
Let's have a nap.
Hello.
All done?
This is Setsuko Asai.
This is Mr. Amamiya.
He's with Dai-Nihon Electricity.
How do you do?
I'm Setsuko.
- She's the youngest daughter?
- Yes.
Really? She's grown up.
He's going to stay here.
He'll eat with us tonight.
What do you want to eat?
Sukiyaki. I've got some eggs.
Tell Fumiya to buy some meat.
Thanks for everything.
- You're welcome.
- And to buy soy sauce too.
- How about sugar?
- Sure, and charcoal too!
- Are we buying everything?
- No, I already have some onions.
- I see. Anything else?
- You can also buy me a pan.
This is from Amamiya.
Thank you.
And get that washed.
It smells.
No, it doesn't... Sorry!
- She's gotten big. How old is she?
- Twenty-one.
That old?
How are the Asais?
They're well.
He's on some board in Osaka.
The eldest girl was
your brother's wife.
Ayako is the second one.
Ayako? She married yet?
Not yet.
So? I remember her still.
Mokichi Asai
Do you know Mr. Amamiya?
No.
You met him at the
Kugenuma villa.
When?
Shouji was still a student.
When he brought all his
friends. Remember?
I remember now.
All those rough boys
around, and...
Mother escaped back
to Kojimachi.
Was he one of them?
Yes, don't you remember?
I wonder which one.
He lived in Takanawa and
was the only one wearing a shirt.
Oh, him.
Mr. Takasu is here.
He came to offer
some incense.
Really?
- Welcome to the home.
- Haven't seen you for a longtime.
It's been my fault.
I couldn't come to your
husband's death-anniversary.
I was in Tokyo.
Not at all.
We received your nice present.
It was nothing.
Today I came to Nara so
I brought some incense.
That was very kind of you.
- Can you stay a while?
- Not really.
Do you know Mr. Amamiya?
Shouji's friend.
I remember him.
- Anyway, he's here.
- I see.
When did he come?
This morning, from Osaka.
Haven't seen him for
a long time.
Time really flies.
Been two years already.
That was a long hot
summer.
It seems like yesterday.
We ate here
during our school trip.
Someone got sick on
the eggs.
I got sick too.
I didn't.
That was May, wasn't it?
The Wisteria was very
beautiful.
My sister's asked you over.
With Mr. Takasu,
the teacher.
I made a mistake about
that Mr. Amamiya.
- Isn't he the one that played the piano?
- That's right.
- Nocturnes by Chopin.
- Is that what it was?
I thought he was that
good swimmer.
That was Shigeno.
The one with the tan.
They decided on tea.
Serve it them.
Is the water hot?
Let me see. You ought
to come once in a while.
If you loaf around,
everyplace is boring.
But that's not
Nara's fault.
But Nara's as slow as
a Noh drama...
Really?
Father, I always remember
Tokyo.
Where we were born,
there in Kojimachi.
That was long ago.
It's all changed now.
The Tokyo you remember
isn't there.
I'd like to see what
our house is like now.
All covered with weeds.
I wonder.
When did you move here?
At the end of 1943.
And you never returned
to Tokyo?
Two or three times.
And I had to take care
of the house.
- What are you doing tomorrow?
- Nothing.
- He's going to sleep late.
- Don't, let's go to Horyu-ji.
- Are you going?
- With my students, but let's all go.
- Shall we?
- You come too. - Shall I?
- How about it?
- I want to go too.
Go along then.
There's no Horyu-ji
in Tokyo.
How about you?
I have to go to Osaka.
Well, I...
How about Ayako?
Everyone's going to
Horyu-ji tomorrow.
Well...
Let's go.
Yes, go.
I wonder if I should go.
Let's go.
All right?
No, that's like a horse.
Why didn't Ayako come?
Why didn't she?
Our aunt from Tokyo came.
She called us from Kyoto.
I see.
- Why did she come so suddenly?
- I wonder.
Does Ayako still hate
watermelon?
How did you know that?
I was at the Kugenuma villa.
Really?
We always ate it
after we'd swam.
She'd always go look at
the sea.
She wore a morning-glow
patterned kimono.
When was this?
You were picking your
nose in primary school.
That's a lie.
Was mother still alive then?
You were always with her
back then.
You remember that?
No.
But I remember how the
evening primroses bloomed.
That's right.
Let's do something.
Like what?
Something interesting.
If she'd come we'd have
played mah-jong.
Sorry if I kept you waiting.
- Welcome home.
- I'm here.
Was she well?
She's coming tomorrow.
This is from her.
What did she want?
Always the same thing.
She wanted to take me to
the Minami-za Theatre.
I went, and
there was this man.
A marriage meeting?
Yes. I was surprised.
What kind of man?
I didn't really look at him.
It's not nice, so sudden.
I just looked at the actors.
She did this all by herself.
Is he the son of the
Miyazu Bank's president?
Seems so. Always bragging
about Amanohashidate.
She brags about it too.
No matter how nice the scenery.
I'm not going to get married for it.
That's true.
I'm here!
- I'm here.
- Welcome home.
- Is Ayako back?
- Yes, just now.
- I'm here.
- Welcome.
You should have come.
It was so nice, Horyu-ji.
Amamiya said he was at
the Kugenuma villa.
Really?
He remembered all
about you.
You used to go down on
the beach and sing at night.
I don't remember that.
And that morning-glow kimono.
Really?
Even remembered you
hated watermelon.
He remembered that?
And when you were sick
he went for ice.
It was at the lantern
festival.
I remember that.
I had a fever, but I saw
the fireworks.
You should have come today.
He's so nice.
He's very, very nice.
Why does he remember
such stupid things?
Stupid?
So? Amamiya's well?
He's well.
I haven't seen him.
Is he here for long?
Four or five days,
He's going to Mt. Hiei tomorrow.
Why? Hiei.
There's a microwave station
up there.
Really? I can see him then.
Guess I'll go now.
Take your time.
I can't. I've got to go
and make supper.
My mother's eyes aren't good.
That's too bad. Take care.
Here, take these.
Is it all right?
Translating them won't
make you much though.
You always do this for me.
I'm tired of doing nothing.
We'll find something soon.
Can't even make enough
to buy cigarettes.
- Say hello to Amamiya.
- My best to your mother.
Thanks.
Good afternoon!
Are you going?
Going back to make supper.
He's gotten thinner.
- He hasn't got a job yet?
- He brought me more onions.
- Want sukiyaki again?
- Good idea.
- You have any meat?
- No.
- Soy sauce? Sugar? Pans?
- I've got a bowl and chopsticks.
That's not enough.
- Where's Mr. Amamiya?
- He went to Osaka.
Sister had a marriage
meeting in Kyoto.
Who with?
A bank president's son.
- I feel sorry for her.
- Why?
I saw his picture, fat,
comes out to here.
What's wrong with that?
But he's so fat...
he's half bald too.
Just enough
to cover the front.
- Is he old?
- No, he's young.
- I feel sorry for her.
- She should refuse.
Yes. Aunt decided
all by herself about this.
I wouldn't want him for a
brother-in-law. Not at all.
- Really?
- Naturally.
How would Mr. Amamiya
be for her?
They'd make a wonderful
couple.
I think he likes her.
Why? How would you know?
I just know.
He remembers just
everything about her.
Really?
Yes. Why else would he
know she hates watermelon?
Just ask Mr. Amamiya.
- How?
- Ask what he thinks of her.
Oh, they'll just make
the most handsome couple.
Go ask him.
Me? Mr. Amamiya?
It would be wonderful.
Hiei Microwave Station
There are eight of these stations
between Tokyo and Osaka.
They send from
one to the other.
Really?
This station carries
486 relays at one time.
You can really see Lake Biwa.
When are you going
to get married?
Already decided?
Not yet.
I have someone in mind
for you.
- Who?
- Ayako Asai.
Ms. Ayako.
You like her.
- You said you liked her.
- Me?
Whoever said that?
Really?
It's too early yet.
That's all right.
Though you liked her.
Why?
She's had this proposal.
Then what did he say?
Said he never once
thought of her.
That's not true.
He remembers just everything.
I told him that.
And then?
Says he's practicing
memory training.
Said it was too early
for talk like this.
That's a lie. He's just
talking. He likes her.
Didn't you see how
he looked at her?
No.
You have to pay attention
to things like that.
His eyes changed color.
That's because he was
wearing sun-glasses.
And then his saying that he's
never once thought of her.
She has to hurry to escape
from our aunt.
Where is she?
She had her say and then left.
Ask him again.
- Why?
- Just once more.
Again?
I don't want to. You do it.
Me? Let's do it this way.
- How's that?
- Interesting.
Let's call Fumiya.
- Where shall it be?
- Where?
- Nigatsudo?
- Yes.
- Did you call me?
- Where's Fumiya?
She went out with Ms. Ayako.
Wait. You'll do.
- I have something to ask you.
- What, please?
Now this is a secret.
You'll call Amamiya tomorrow.
This is Ayako Asai...
It's a secret.
"I would like to have
a talk with you."
"And could you please
come alone..."
"At 3 to the Nigatsudo."
You ask him. You're Ayako.
That's too hard.
It's all right. It's for her sake.
You understand?
Just try it now.
Go over there.
No, further.
There, there.
Now you do it...
Hold the receiver.
- "Hello..."
He's on the line.
He's there.
- "Hello..."
- Stop saying hello.
"Is this Mr. Amamiya?"
"Yes, I'm him."
"I'm Yoneya Asai."
No. Ayako.
"I'm Ayako Asai"
"Not Ayako. Ayako."
"I'm Ayako and I have something
to talk to you about."
Sound more embarrassed
and younger.
- "I'm truly troubling you..."
- Don't say "truly"...
"Could you come alone at
3 to the Sangatsudo?"
Nigatsudo.
"Could you come at 3
to the Nigatsudo?"
How's that?
She's quite good.
Very good. You'll call then.
Don't forget. Nigatsudo at 3.
You practice tonight.
Ayako...
He won't come.
I wonder.
- What time is it?
- It's ten past three.
He should come.
Your watch is fast.
It's on time. He won't come.
He ought to have come.
He's come.
That's him.
Just look.
His eyes are different.
Looks like it.
Too bad she isn't here.
How long will he wait?
A long time.
It's cruel.
What will we do?
- Let him wait.
- I'll go ask Yoneya.
Mr. Amamiya really came.
What will we do?
I'm sorry but you go...
And say Ayako can't come.
Do it politely.
Hurry up now. Hurry.
Where's Yoneya?
If she hadn't gone how long
would he have waited?
He really likes her.
He came.
They'll make such a nice couple.
- You talk to him now.
- Talk to him?
- Then he'll propose to her.
- Propose?
- That's right.
- You think so?
- Of course he will.
- But does she like him?
- I'm sure she likes him.
- Why?
- She's strange since he's come.
- How?
That new blouse. She put
the sleeves on backwards.
She hard-boiled Father's
soft-boiled egg too.
And the other night,
when Mr. Takasu was here.
She sat next to Mr. Amamiya.
She loves sukiyaki
and she hardly ate at all.
She usually has three helpings.
I asked her if she was
sick or something.
She glanced at him and said...
"no", but...
- Think how she felt.
- You see a lot.
And after that she ate
two apples.
Usually she only eats half of one.
- You can see how she felt.
- I can see that.
It's true she loves him.
I went to Saidai-ji and
saw Tanaka.
No job. His mother's
worried about him.
- I wonder how his mother's eyes are.
- It doesn't seem too serious.
I'm going back to Tokyo
day after tomorrow.
Really?
You're going back?
Yes. You've been
very good to me.
No... but can't you stay longer?
No. I have to go back.
I'll come again.
When can you come?
Autumn next year maybe.
Next year?
Thanks for everything.
What'll we do?
It's just tonight and tomorrow.
How awful. His going back.
- How about having them meet?
- Him and Ayako?
Then we'll see if they
like each other.
That's the best idea.
Yes. And tomorrow's a full moon.
Just the two of them, and
the moon. How wonderful.
- What's Ayako doing?
- She's reading a book.
Not going out?
She should be.
What did you say?
Amamiya called. He had
something to talk about.
Please come to the park.
He wanted to see her.
What did she say?
"Really?"
Did she smile?
Not especially.
It's funny.
Has she forgotten?
Go tell her again.
"Time to go out.
What will you wear?"
Say it like that.
Is the moon out yet?
But the mountain's so bright.
But what if she doesn't go?
Can't be helped.
But that's no fun after
we tried so.
She'll have to go look at
Amanohashidate.
No, not that.
- How was it?
- I asked her. - Going out?
She just read her book.
The moon's out.
It's up. Make it go down!
That's one thing
you can't do.
I'll go see.
Sister...
What?
Mr. Amamiya's going back
tomorrow.
Nice if he could have
stayed longer.
Yes.
Wonder why he's going.
It's no fun.
He won't come back
for a long time.
Not till autumn next year.
Maybe he's going back
to get married.
I think so.
Are you getting married?
Mr. Amamiya, he...
- Be quiet. What're you talking about?
- Go downstairs.
How was it?
She got mad at me.
- It won't work.
- Why not?
She doesn't seem to like him.
But she should.
Look how high it is.
It's beautiful.
And I thought they'd make
such a nice couple.
What?
Ms. Ayako just left
by the back door.
Gone out?
Yes, in a hurry.
Really? That's good.
It's a beautiful moon.
Yes, it's very beautiful.
What was it you wanted
to see me about?
You said you had something
to talk about.
Me? But I came because
you telephoned me.
But it was you
who telephoned me.
But I didn't.
Neither did I.
Really? I'm very sorry.
No, it's my fault.
It's a beautiful moon.
Yes, it truly is.
You're leaving tomorrow?
We've done this before.
At the villa, remember?
After Enoshima.
And the moon came up.
That too was just before
I went back to Tokyo.
Was it?
"Is this the same moon
I once saw rise..."
"Over Mount Mikasa in
the land of Kasuga?"
What a nice moon.
Wonder what they're doing.
Don't worry about it.
I wonder.
What are they saying?
They're holding hands.
I wonder.
Maupassant has a story
called "Moonlight".
In the moonlight
these two fell in love.
If one likes the other
it will be all right.
I wonder.
More, maybe.
Maybe they're doing it?
- What?
- Kissing.
That's wonderful.
But would she?
Sure she would.
Like in Somerset Maugham.
Loving each other
under the moon.
- What happened?
- They did it under the coconut palm.
- Did what?
- Kissed.
- Why don't they settle it?
- What?
That they love each other.
What if they didn't say
anything and then parted?
But lots of people
are like that.
Yes, there are.
I feel sorry for them,
throwing away their happiness.
If it hadn't been for us
they'd never have known.
They ought to give us
a big meal.
I'm going to tell them.
So am I.
Look how high
the moon is.
So, Mr. Amamiya's going?
Yes, he's very busy.
Wonder if he has
any work for Shouji.
- I'm here.
- Welcome.
Come and look at the moon.
- I've just been looking at it.
- Really?
Did you call?
You come here.
Come here.
Did Mr. Amamiya call?
Fumiya, who made you do that?
Tell me.
Who was it?
Well...
It was Ms. Setsuko who did it.
Did she tell you to?
I'm sorry.
All right.
You may go.
- Is she back?
- Just now.
Is she happy?
She's very angry...
About that telephone call...
She got angry?
She shouldn't have gotten angry.
I'll go see.
No, she's seems very happy.
Really?
She's happy-
But just now...
She was just saying that...
You must notice her eyes.
- Is it like that?
- Yes.
But it's too bad.
He's leaving tomorrow.
Really?
Hello. Yes, it is.
A telegram? Just a moment.
What, it's in numbers?
3...7...5...5...
3755? Is that all?
I see, thank you.
What could it be
this telegram?
What?
3755. What's that?
I don't know.
Where's it from?
I don't know. Tokyo.
3755. What could it be?
Three thousand, seven hundred...
- Maybe it's a mistake.
- Doesn't seem to be.
What is it? 3755.
I'm hungry...
What could this mean?
A telegram?
3755. What is it?
Maybe it's some kind of
number code.
I see...
Do you understand?
- What is it?
- I wonder.
If we used the kana syllabary...
Yes, we could do that.
3755 would be "all are well."
The bookshop's number
comes out "all can read."
Dr. Ohara's telephone
number is "ears-nose."
Really?
- Ms. Setsuko...
- What?
That telegram's from Mr. Amamiya.
Now Ayako's sending
one to him.
But she could send it
by telephone too.
- It's a secret.
- What was it?
Numbers again. 666.
Six hundred, sixty-six.
That's "mu-mu-mu."
Six hundred sixty-six.
He sent her 3755.
That's right.
She sent him 666.
666.
Send it to the quiz
program on the radio?
Would they know?
Wedding bells?
You're thinking hard, Fumiya?
Think then. You took it.
Are you thinking, Yoneya?
You understand it?
- Won't Ayako tell you?
- No.
Just laughs and won't answer.
The telegraph office
has its own codes...
- But these numbers aren't listed.
- Show me.
Yonihi means
"Congratulations."
Nino. "Baby and
Mother Well."
Too early for that kind
of telegram!
Why are you all laughing?
Nothing.
- I wanted to ask you something.
- What?
I want to visit Tokyo.
May I?
What for?
I wanted to refuse
my aunt's wedding offer.
Well now,
can't you do it by mail?
And to meet Mme. St-Raphael
to test my French.
- May I?
- Well... are you going alone?
- Yes.
- When?
The day after tomorrow.
I see. It's sudden.
May I go?
Of course.
With your permission I'll go.
You do that.
Thank you very much.
You really held your tongue.
You didn't ask to go too.
But I really wanted to go
to Tokyo.
But Tokyo,
there's that mu-mu-mu.
She wants to go alone.
- I'd be a bother.
- Really?
- Do you know about things like that?
- Somehow or other.
That's really something.
But I'm an adult, father.
I'm 21.
I see. Then it's
your turn next.
What?
What did you mean?
I mean mu-mu-mu.
What a thing to say.
Do you understand it?
3755, right?
And the other is 666.
Well?
I don't know. What is it?
I'm going to call Tokyo
on the microwave.
Just dial 103.
- You talk too.
- To Ayako?
103? Tokyo, please.
Tokyo 40-2560.
This is 35-672.
Should I wait?
Hello.
Yes. I'm calling from Osaka.
Is Ayako there?
It's really fast.
Ayako, this is Setsuko.
I've understood.
3755-666.
It's wonderful.
You talked Aunt out of it?
That's good.
Here's our sister.
She seems very happy.
Hello. Ayako? It's me.
Shall I tell you?
3755.
What is it?
The Manyoshu poetry
collection.
"Beloved wife, so far away,
I think of you the more."
Means he's worried,
she's so far away.
As for mu-mu-mu...
"Though we met but for a moment,
how now I miss you more."
That's Sakanoe no
Iratsume's.
That's right.
Just paned and
dying to see him again.
Yes, a really passionate
telegram.
She really thought about it.
You caught on fast though.
Yes, I did.
She left her Manyoshu
on her desk.
She'd marked these
two in red pencil.
I have to go.
I'm leaving now.
Why so soon?
Shouji is waiting.
- Is he in Osaka?
- Yes.
- He's meeting his new boss.
- Really?
That's why you're so happy.
- Then it's decided.
- What?
But isn't it true?
I'm going.
It's their happiest time now.
That's true.
To send each other the
Manyoshu poem numbers...
Is it really old fashioned
or really modern?
It's both.
"Though we met but for a moment,
how now I miss you more"?
You're back?
I thought we might
see a movie. I waited.
Shall I peel you an
apple, or a persimmon?
How was it?
What kind of work?
Tokyo branch office.
Tokyo?
I gave it to Tanaka,
he went with me.
Didn't you like it?
No, it was good.
Why did you give it away?
Tanaka needed it.
I'll get something.
But can you find something
you like in Tokyo?
Why did you have
to do that?
I know perfectly well
he needs work...
I was wishing he would
find something.
But you really looked
for that job.
I worried about you,
loafing around.
Then you found this.
But, between us, I don't
need work like he does.
He's got his old mother
to take care of.
He had a hard time in the war
and only just got back.
Seeing all that, and his mother,
I had to do it.
I wonder.
I know why you felt that,
why you've been so good to him...
You gave him translation work,
you gave him clothes...
I thought what good friends
men can be together.
But I never thought
you'd gave him your job.
It's so only after you
yourself had a job.
I never thought
you'd do this.
That's so, but...
It's all over.
And Tanaka is very happy.
Of course he is.
It's only natural.
Only natural? What?
He has a nerve.
He knows you need work.
He didn't ask. I gave it him.
So what will you do?
I know how impatient you
were with your life.
Living like this everyday,
I felt sorry for you.
You needn't have been.
- Just mind your own business.
- But...
I feel good about it.
I did the right thing.
And after you'd gotten
a Tokyo job.
Then we could have
gone to Tokyo.
Is that what you
were thinking?
I wasn't hunting for a job
to take you to Tokyo.
If you want, go by yourself.
You've no rights on my job.
You're only thinking
of yourself.
I hate people who
think like that.
You go do what you like.
I'll go my own way.
I won't even talk to anyone who
thinks only of herself.
Go home.
Where's Ms. Setsuko?
You're back early.
How did Shouji do
with his job?
What's the matter?
Are you crying? Why?
You had a fight with him.
Why did you fight?
That's not nice.
If you just cry
I won't understand.
What happened?
Did he say something?
Why did you fight?
I don't know.
Don't worry about it.
Young people get over
their quarrels.
Silly.
You're getting your
dress all wet.
What a child.
Don't. Leave me alone.
You weren't at the Noh practice.
Haven't you two made up yet?
It's all right to fight sometimes.
You've got to learn.
But what are you going to do,
just stay around here?
I guess so.
But that was good,
giving your job to your friend.
Nowadays you don't
see things like that.
It's not much good,
but I heard of something.
What kind of work?
Teaching in a Tokyo
priests' school.
An old friend's the principal.
English teaching.
I see.
Things don't come to
he who waits.
Try what you can,
then you'll find what you like.
Yes, but could I teach priests?
Why not?
I don't know anything about
Buddhism.
Someone else teaches that.
You'll just teach English.
But I like to eat raw fish.
I like pork cutlets too.
Yes, and you can even
have some sake.
Really? Well, I'll try it.
Really? You'll try it?
Yes, I will.
- Teaching at a priests' school.
- Yes.
When will you go?
The priest said
I should go soon.
Nothing to pack.
Thought I'd go tomorrow.
Really. That's sudden.
It will be different.
I'll just leave
the stuff I borrowed.
Yes, do.
It'd be nice to have a farewell
meal, but you've no time.
You hurry up.
He's about to leave.
He's going to Tokyo.
You make up with him now.
Setsuko, you like Shouji,
don't you?
You tell him how you feel.
You can't just
pan like this.
If he goes off when could
you make up with him?
Hurry up now.
He's leaving. Hurry.
- You've been good to me.
- Take care now.
Take care.
That was really sudden.
So I thought I'd try it.
Better than loafing.
You can get something
better later.
That's what the priest said.
When do you leave?
Tonight's express.
Alone?
Not with Setsuko?
Why not?
Take her, she so wanted to go.
Have a fight or something?
- Take her along.
- No, she'll do as she likes.
She wanted to go with you.
No, it's all right.
It'll be hard for you all alone.
I'm used to it.
You ought to take her.
Thanks.
Sorry I'm late.
Thank you.
- Got your ticket?
- I've already bought it.
- What time?
- Nine-thirty.
So you leave tonight.
I see.
Hello...
From Osaka?
Oh, Mr. Takasu...
Hello.
Now what's this
about a fight?
Why not go to Tokyo
with him?
But he won't if you
fight with him.
But he's gone to
Tokyo by now.
Call your elder sister,
would you?
My sister? OK.
Just a moment.
It's a call from
Mr. Takasu.
Sorry to have kept
you waiting.
We were a nuisance
the other day.
You still moping?
Forget about it.
Then you shouldn't
have fought.
Would you go to
the temple and...
Bring the calligraphy book,
Shouji borrowed?
Stupid thing. You just
forget all about that now.
Girls who haven't married
have to smile all the time.
Wait...
Come here.
You still mad?
I came for you.
Won't you come?
How about it?
You'll go?
I can't tell by your eyes.
You're going with me
to Tokyo.
We haven't much money.
You'll cook for us...
You'll do the laundry...
You'll do it all yourself.
You'll get all dirty
with work.
And I'll be as good
as I can to you.
It won't be a life like
you've had here.
We won't have money,
we'll get hungry.
But you'll have
to laugh at it.
But I'll be really
good to you.
We'll build our new
lives together.
You're grown-up now.
You understand?
You've understood?
You can't cry. I just
said you had to laugh.
But, you're bad.
You're making me cry.
Don't cry any more...
Let's not fight too.
I'm sorry.
But that was very close.
If you had gone we wouldn't ever
have seen each other again.
We talked a lot about
Ayako's problems, but...
We never talked
about ours.
I never told you
how l really felt.
And I didn't tell you.
I'll tell you everything
from now on.
You don't need to now.
Why not?
To say it once is enough.
Thank you.
Sit down.
Do you like me?
Yes.
Do you love me?
I love you.
What a beautiful moon.
It's a month since
we saw this moon.
The moon's strange...
I wonder how many couples
have looked at it.
I'm going to remember this,
the moon over Nara.
The moon over Mikasa.
The moon on the
hanafuda cards.
What?
I'll teach you - more fun
than ordinary cards.
It's a nice moon.
Yes, it really is.
I suppose they're
in Tokyo now.
Probably at Ayako's.
They're all gone.
Aren't you lonely?
It can't be helped.
They all grew up.
I guess young people like
that dirty, dusty Tokyo.
It has it charms for
young people.
Guess so.
Nara's almost too
peaceful.
Do you dislike Nara?
You're young,
you shouldn't stay here.
Would you get
married again?
Father...
Widows can get
married again.
You've got happiness
coming to you.
It's your turn to be happy.
Go get married.
No, I don't think so.
No, I bet you are.
Next time someone
who won't die.
How about Takasu?
He's strong. He'll last.
You like him.
You help others
but won't help yourself.
Bashful?
Think about it,
make up your mind, soon.
What nice weather.
This good fall weather will last.
Nara's nice then.
Father...
THE END