Official entry
1963 festival of the arts
a nikkatsu production
o-wa-i-ya-re
where, 0/7 where
has the Y—sitter gone?
She went to town to buya dog
she'll be back soon
if you don't sleep,
the mice wi/I scamper over you
if you stay awake,
the n/ghtjars will fly off with you
The insect woman
Be strong!
- Oh, it hurts!
- Be strong, en. She's coming.
She'll be here any minute.
Drink this birthing potion.
Chuji, hurry up
and heat some water.
- Is the baby coming out?
- Any minute now.
- It's mine, isn't it?
- It's yours, all right.
It's my baby.
Mine.
Well, chuji, how's en doing?
Winter 1918
I'm not asking the name, you idiot.
The date of birth.
- Day before yesterday.
- What's that?
Day before yesterday.
You two were married
on October 3rd,
and the baby's born
two months later?
That's right.
Just like a little piglet!
It's my baby.
Sure, on paper.
Who's the real father? Onogawa?
Who knows?
Even en wouldn't know.
She'll sleep with anyone.
I said after we see
the soldiers off.
- I just have to talk to you.
- No, mr onogawa.
It's all right.
Not in here.
- What's it matter?
- Someone might come in.
Nobody knows we're here.
Where did you go?
May 1924
- papa?
- What is it, Tome?
Are you and mama married?
No, we're not.
You sleep with me,
so that means we're married, right?
That's right, we're married.
O-wa-i-ya-re
If you don't sleep,
the mice wi/I scamper over you
papa, what are you making?
A doll for the god of the mountain.
I want to put it up!
- You can't.
- Why not?
The god of the mountain
is a woman.
Look over there.
Spring 1942
Hey, Tome!
Your dad's very ill.
Your father's dying.
You'd better get home quick.
How's papa?
He's dead.
Really?
Just kidding you.
We called you back
to help on mr Honda's farm.
They're coming for you tonight,
so get ready.
What are you talking about?
I'm serving our country.
Mr Honda owns our land.
Serving him is the same
as serving your country.
And you know
we still owe him money.
Rui.
I can't go to the hondas'
while isamu's off fighting.
He could be killed any day.
You can't wait.
You're already 20.
Rui married into this family
to help her own.
Having an unmarried sister-in-law
isn't fair to her.
Where's papa?
He won't be back from work
until tomorrow night.
I have to talk to him.
He'll go crazy again
when he gets back.
Look at these scars
from the last beating he gave me.
We're not selling her as a geisha,
so it won't be as bad this time.
Anything about Tome
sends that idiot crazy.
No telling what he might do.
But if we don't say something,
that fool will sleep with Tome forever.
I don't really like shunzo.
I'll talk to papa.
Papa, always papa!
You're not a little girl anymore.
Are you going to sleep with him forever
and never get married?
Tome, you're just going there
to help out.
You don't have
to sleep with shunzo.
Honda just wants help.
It's a great day.
Singapore has fallen.
And Tome will fall tonight!
Here, have some.
Thanks.
Tome, shunzo's ready and willing.
That's right. Time to go, Tome.
My feet hurt.
Never mind her, just take her.
Come on, there's no need to be shy.
Tome, let's go.
My feet hurt.
Papa!
You're backjust in time.
Tome's going to help out
at the hondas'.
Congratulations, old man.
Tome's a lucky one,
marrying the landlord.
It's shunzo who's lucky,
getting such a beauty.
Watch out! Run!
Old man, don't!
Papa!
Father, stop! Stop!
Stop it!
Chuji, you can beat en
all you want,
but you can't fight
the will of the gods.
Papa!
Stop it!
Isaid I would go!
It's the only choice.
I'll do it for the family.
Tonight?
No, I'll make them wait
until tomorrow.
All right, kura?
Chujl; No matter
what you do, it's fate.
The god of marriage has tied the knot.
You can't fight the will of the gods.
Where does it hurt?
Here.
It looks bad. It's full of pus.
That hurts!
What's wrong?
Rui's watching.
If you sleep with shunzo...
I won't.
Mr Honda says I just need
to help with the work.
It's freezing.
My brotherjust sits
by the fire and drinks.
Damn it.
It'll be hard on you,
being the wife
of a poor landowner's third son.
- Tome...
- No, don't!
Why not? You refused last night too!
- Didn't kura tell you?
- What?
I'm just helping out,
and you aren't to touch me.
- That's ridiculous.
- Stop it!
What's the big deal?
I'll be drafted soon
to die for our country.
Do your part.
Papa!
How many months is it
since / left my home/and?
Hey, you little troublemaker!
I'll give you some sweets later.
Now go and play at your mother's.
You're it!
What? I'll get you!
I'm going to catch you!
Demon! Demon!
I don't like it there.
Why not?
- Shunzo has a mistress.
- You mean Kane?
They even have a kid.
You fool!
If you work hard,
you can become his lawful wife.
When his father dies,
shunzo will get this mill.
Then you'll be in charge.
Kane'sjust a maid.
Don't get distracted by things like that.
It's all for the family.
You understand, Tome?
Tome's dying.
Idiot! Women don't die every time
they have a baby. Now clear out.
Get out of here, you fool!
Boil some water.
The son of a bitch is always
ruining our plans.
Fancy beating up shunzo
just for sleeping with Tome.
Is he badly hurt?
Chuji beat him
with all his brute strength,
so he's in a bad way.
Kura, couldn't we just apologise
and get the hondas
to take her back?
They'd have sent her home
in any case for getting pregnant.
After that incident,
they'll never take her back.
I know, but...
Your mother and you both
had bastard children.
Don't go acting as if Tome's
the only bad one.
What a racket!
Will you stop that?
It's a girl.
Let it live or get rid of it?
Let's get rid of it.
We can't feed any more mouths.
Get rid of it.
Let it live. It's my child.
Don't be so selfish, you fool!
Let it live.
It's my baby.
New year's day 1943
Nobuko.
She won't feed.
Pa?
I need your help again.
Nobuko won't suck enough.
They hurt from too much milk.
Pa, I'm going to find work again.
Things can't go on like this forever.
I have to pay the hondas back.
It's 10 yen. I'll save it up.
That's all right.
It's wartime.
I can work for the country.
Don't worry.
I'll save up the 10 yen.
August 1945
air raid!
Air raid! Air raid!
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Tome, we've got to take cover!
How are you?
His majesty's about
to address the nation.
Shall we go to the dining hall?
You're in bad shape, huh?
Did you send all your ration biscuits
to your kid?
No wonder you're weak. Here.
Thank you.
You've got a fever.
Come on.
His majesty the emperor
will now address the nation.
Listen with due reverence.
Yesterday...
A soldier told me...
That Japan has lost the war.
It's a lie.
It can't be true.
Daikoku, god of wealth,
I'm listening
and I ask you with respect
to hear my prayers
and bring me glad news.
- Go away!
- No, you!
Stop making so much noise!
"Daikoku, god of wealth,
I'm listening..."
Masashige, go to your mother.
You brat!
Nobuko, come and warm your feet.
What's Tome doing?
Writing in her diary.
How's goichi's grandmother doing?
I just visited her.
She's sick in bed.
She's depressed.
Her only son died in battle.
Still, that's no reason to start
screaming in the village office.
One bundle of firewood.
That's one sen.
Thanks.
Make one more.
Then you'll have two sen.
- Is chuji saving money?
- Aye.
He says he'll repay the hondas
and keep Tome here.
Fools have foolish ideas.
A bear! I caught a bear!
Go away, masashige!
- Leave me alone!
- Go away!
Go away!
You go away!
Grandpa?
We're married, aren't we?
Right.
"Married"!
Tome, I need to clean in here.
I worked for my country
and family
but now / keep my diary alone
rui!
- Put this away.
- All right.
Wives are so reliable these days.
You can let them
do all the work.
Sawakichi, did you check
at the hondas' place?
Yes, it seems it's true.
All the landowners
are kicking up a right fuss.
The Americans have ordered
"agrarian reform" or some such thing.
Thank you. I'll be back again.
Thank you.
So tenant farmers like us
will become independent?
Whose name
will the farm be under?
No-one knows yet.
Excuse me.
Is Tome here? I'm matsunami,
chief clerk at the mill.
- Nobuko.
- What, mummy?
Here you go, some fish.
No, I'll have grandpa's.
What will you do, Tome?
The clerk came for you.
You'd better go.
That clerk's a good-looking fellow.
Don't say such things.
You talkjust to talk.
Tome, kasukawa ume
told me all about it.
Told you what?
When the war ended,
you didn't come home for a week.
You stayed on at the mill,
just you and the clerk.
I was sick. What else could I do?
The clerk had to settle
all the mill's assets.
You weren't feeding nobuko enough,
so I sent my rations home
and ended up sick.
That's rubbish!
Idiot! You should be ashamed,
talking like that.
And what about you two,
moaning all night long?
Tome, they're a young married couple.
What do you expect?
Besides, you never even
sent us money from the mill.
So it was money you wanted, ma?
All right, then.
I'll go back to the mill.
Tome, don't go.
I'm just a burden to you here.
- I'll go back to the mill.
- You're not a burden. Don't go.
What's so funny, you stupid cow?
You're so high and mighty
with your 10-yen dowry!
Stop it, stop it.
Tome, don't go.
I'm saving up the 10 yen.
Pa, 10 yen won't even buy
a kimono now.
I get harassed by men
all the time on the train to work.
The other day, a man grabbed
my hand at the movies.
A hand? That's nothing!
Before I knew it,
I was getting felt up all over!
"It's clear they control
and oppress us. Therefore..."
- Turn the switch back on.
- It's fine, carry on.
- Hurry or there'll be trouble.
- They won't listen otherwise.
"Therefore we must mount
a unanimous and vigorous opposition..."
Please listen carefully,
all of you,
to what mr matsunami
from the committee has to say...
I wouldn't mind,
but I'm afraid of getting pregnant.
- Then fix it so you don't.
- I'll show you how later.
Why didn't you come over
last night?
Doing it out here,
you can't fool me.
You only think of yourself.
Let's break up, then, Tome.
- So you like ishizuka more?
- Don't be stupid.
I know all about it.
Everybody's talking.
It's not that.
- I can't keep up with you anymore.
- What?
You're too intense.
I don't mind the union, but...
Who told me
to work for the union?
I did it all for you.
Tome, don't take this
the wrong way,
but I got promoted
to assistant manager.
I see.
You tell me now,
after we've had sex.
I like you, Tome.
That's why I'm trying to get
the company to go easy on you.
- Go easy on me?
- They want to fire you.
I have to get back.
See you.
My man is gone
I'm all alone,
gazing at the river
summer 1949
pa, we fought hard for this 5,000
in severance pay.
I'll give you 2,000.
Give half to ma, okay?
Tome, don't go.
I saved up the 10 yen.
Thank you.
But you can't use these coins now,
so you just hold on to them.
Why are you leaving?
When I save up some money,
you and nobuko and I
will live together.
Just wait until then. Okay?
Don't go, Tome.
Don't go!
Where are we?
Between the matsukawa
and kanayagawa stations.
What are we supposed to do now?
You can go back
the way you came, or...
I can't go home!
September 1950
I love you, midori.
- I can't stand it!
- What?
That maid's always eavesdropping.
I hate it!
Poor thing.
I feel sorry for all jap girls.
Well, don't.
Just feel sorry for me.
Hold me.
I feel most sorry for you.
Tome.
George is away,
so let's cook country style.
- How about stewed vegetables?
- Great. Make it spicy.
How about dried bonito
in the stock?
Dried sardines are cheaper.
I guess you're right.
But you don't really need a stock,
if you're boiling bracken
and bamboo shoots.
Our backyard was full of bamboo.
My father would cut some,
and I'd boil it with some miso.
It was so good!
We always used fish
instead of dried sardines
since we lived near a fishery.
George's family are fishermen too.
Do they dry sardines in america too?
I don't think so.
Cathy!
Cathy, go and play inside.
I'll play with you later.
Tome, what do you think of George?
I don't know anything
about Americans.
- But he's nice, right?
- Yes, he is.
But he's so huge.
Big body, big heart.
Big Japanese men are kinder too.
I guess you're right.
Remember when he went to Korea?
He was promoted to sergeant
for distinguished service.
He was the youngest sergeant,
just 23.
Really? That's great.
Yeah, but it means
he'll have to go back to Korea.
Really?
A lot of men are dying there.
You must be worried.
It'd be awful if he died
and left me with this kid.
What are you doing, Tome?
I was crying because I'm lonely.
Cathy...
What?
You must be lonely
with your mum always gone.
Yes, I am.
Poor little Cathy.
What will you do if your daddy dies?
I don't care.
O-wa-i-ya-re
o-wa-i-ya-re
if you don't sleep
the mice will scamper over you
if you stay a wake
the n/ghtjars will fly off with you
Next person.
You there,
come sit in the middle.
Go ahead.
Confess all your sins
and share all your troubles.
My marriage failed.
I have one child.
I was working in a silk mill...
And me and a man...
Speak more clearly.
I had an affair with a man there.
He had...
A wife.
But he was so nice...
So we had relations.
Talking about my life
makes me cry.
- Then what?
- Then...
The unemployment office...
Found me a job
in a Chinese restaurant.
Then the owner got fresh with me
and I ran away.
After that...
I became a maid,
and one day I eavesdropped...
On whom?
The American's mistress.
Their mixed-blood child...
Was scalded to death
when a pot of stew fell on her.
What are you doing
for her departed spirit?
All I'm doing is selling cosmetics.
- Not good enough!
- It's like doing nothing!
- Your sin is lust! It has deep roots!
- She must be shown the path.
It's lust!
Rain that falls on the parent
also falls on the child.
You sinned in a previous life.
The sin of lust!
Pray fervently for the little girl.
Next person!
I'm 28 years old,
and I drive a cab.
Everyone preaches peace,
yet we still harbour
meanness and hatred,
because we don't make religion
the foundation of our lives.
December 1951
hey, come here a minute.
- Come here a minute.
- What is it?
- You want some beer?
- No.
Is she really a sales assistant?
Or is she a prostitute?
You mean she isn't your wife?
Don't play dumb.
Call the madam.
You're really good at that!
So what'll it be? Ban the red-light
district and men will suffer.
It's not my doing,
it's all those women in the diet.
I don't run that kind
of business anyway.
My clients are management types
or old regulars.
That's true.
Excuse me, ma'am.
The guest in room 8 had a fight
with the salesgirl and said to call you.
What a pain! Play my hand.
Wait a minute.
Put this on and then take
some sake to room 8.
Nice move.
Hurry up.
Does she work here?
She just started.
Madam met her at god's place.
God's place?
The pure land buddhism sect.
Not bad-looking, considering.
There it is!
- Someone's asking for a virgin?
- Yeah, the drunk in room 6.
Okay. Where are the "virgins"?
- In the fridge.
- Oh, yeah?
Wow! It's frozen.
I'd better warm it up.
Watch out or it'll boil.
Boiling virgins!
Just shave the dried bonito, you idiot!
- Oh, no!
- I told you.
- Why not just use red ink?
- He won't fall for that.
It's okay.
I'll use my own blood.
Help me, take. Hanako, tie this.
You sure?
You just had a customer.
For 40% of 30,000 yen, you bet.
Go ahead.
Where is it?
O merciful Buddha...
Men are such fools.
What's so great about virgins?
Look! You're turning pale!
Keep going, that's not enough.
Can you handle it?
- What about the cat's blood?
- Good idea.
Come back, you little beast!
- Here's a real virgin.
- Lay it down.
Keep still, you.
- Hold it tight.
- Ready!
Here we go...
Absolutely not.
Then why did you get
all dressed up?
Because you told me to change.
Did I tell you to put on make-up?
You can always get out of having sex.
There's no need to scream like that.
But you violated my rights
by locking me in.
You took money from him,
didn't you?
I did. Why?
That's prostitution.
You never told me
this was a brothel.
This is outrageous.
Prostitution is evil.
I met you at church.
I thought I'd be safe here.
You idiot!
All this talk about prostitution.
People sell sex
because there are buyers.
We don't take people's money
like at the racetrack or the casino.
Our customers go away happy.
This is supposed
to be a democracy,
but you're turning
hungry women into slaves.
Hungry?
What are you talking about?
I feed you three full meals a day.
And when did I turn you into a slave?
You can leave anytime you want.
This isn't the red-light district.
I'm doing my part
by helping men forget their worries.
Here. If you don't like it,
get out now.
But a woman over 30
won't find the food and shelter
you get here.
Here, you get 12,000 a month
just for working ten jobs.
Don't want it?
Then I'll keep it.
Take it and go.
I'll deduct the cost
of the kimono over six months.
For the sake of m y child
I spur my weak body on to tail
I count my money
through hitter tears
a money order
for 3,000 yen, please.
3,000 yen?
May 1, 1952
- what about mizuno?
- He gave me 8,000.
What?
He'll pay the other 5,000
next month.
Always get the full amount
from public officials.
If they pay in full,
they keep coming back,
otherwise they brush you off
and never return.
Let's have some tea with this.
Yes, let's.
- What a mess.
- It's awful.
The radio said the Americans
are at war in Korea.
They're supposed to be
a peaceful country.
September 1955
Oh, it hurts!
Are you okay?
It hurts!
Hold her down.
Help me!
This is bad. An ectopic pregnancy.
I have to operate right away.
"Ma, how are you?
"I'm fine.
I'm living in the granary.
"I'm here with grandpa,
"because the family treats us
so badly.
"Please send money directly
to my school from now on,
"because uncle takes
whatever you send to the house.
"In order to save money,
"we 're growing our own food.
"But we still need 4,000 yen a month.
"I'm sorry to have to ask you, ma.
"I'm sending you a mountain god
thatgrandpa got from the shrine.
"He says to he sure
you put it up."
How are you feeling?
They say I can leave
when the bleeding stops.
I was in the neighbourhood
on a job for take.
I come here often for injections.
You mean our take?
She gets me jobs on the side
sometimes.
She takes 40%,
so it's good for her too.
What if the madam finds out?
She won't.
She just sits back
and rakes in the money,
while we abuse our bodies
and get sick.
Don't bother.
You're fine as you are.
No, I'm hardly presentable like this.
What's this?
A mountain god from my village.
You believe in this nonsense?
No, but it's still a god.
It's the same principle.
You belong to the pure land sect,
don't you?
- Well, yes.
- Then throw it away.
Listen, when you get
out of the hospital,
will you give me a hand
with the business?
I've become an official
in the pure land buddhism sect,
so I'll be away a lot,
and you're the only one
I can trust.
After all,
you're a sect member too.
Ma'am...
Have you heard about take?
What about her?
No, it's not important.
What is it? Tell me.
It's just I heard a rumour
that she's got some...
I don't know for sure, but...
Eh? Jobs on the side?
Yes. They say
she's doingjobs on the side.
That's right,
so I couldn't possibly.
Did you pay your hospital bill?
That was them calling.
I meant to ask you later.
You see, I have no money...
I can't pay it. It's the rules.
-But" - don't get carried away.
I made you head maid,
but you can't walk all over me.
I'm feeding you,
and don't you forget it.
Police, go home!
We want you to go home!
You're the ones breaking the la w!
Ma, what shall I make for dinner?
Anything's fine.
How about giblet soup?
Come straight home, won't you?
Don't do anything naughty at work.
Midori!
Tome!
He doesn't drink,
smoke or fool around,
but he refuses to get a job.
But at least
he's honest and decent.
Ma, this is to wash your hands.
You should wash too.
Thank you.
I'll wipe you.
Stop, behave yourself.
Go and change the water.
All right.
We'll go and change the water.
He's not Japanese, is he?
That's right. He's Korean.
His family all died in the war.
A respectable family, it seems.
I'm jealous.
You really seem to get along.
He's no direction in life.
These are for Cathy's grave.
- You shouldn't have.
- Not at all.
I'm not sure she'd be happy
if she were alive now.
- Don't say that.
- I mean it. Living like this.
- Are you that badly off?
- Can't you tell?
But you really do love him, don't you?
I guess.
But he loves me more.
He's really...
You know... amazing.
- Better than George?
- Well...
George was just a kid
by comparison.
You're sinful too.
I guess I am.
It's the sin of carnal desire
from a previous life. Really!
Madam'll be angry
if we don't get back.
I know.
Sorry. We don't need it anymore.
Take it back.
Listen, midori...
I have some work for you.
Good afternoon.
- Why did you bring him?
- He insisted.
This is no time to drag him along.
Give the money to him.
How can you be such an idiot?
Here comes the client. Let's walk.
Tome, here's what we agreed to
on the phone.
Thank you very much.
Mr sanada, I'll be going now.
See you soon.
Are they going to an inn?
What's it matter?
You got your money, now go home.
Grandpa!
Ma just sent us a load of money.
It's a lot this time.
I'll buy you some chemical fertiliser,
grandpa.
No need, nobuko.
Just buy things for school.
You bought such expensive stuff.
I told you to buy things for school.
It's okay,
I don't like school anyway.
Grandpa, come and get in.
I'll wash you.
I'm coming.
- You know mr karasawa?
- Yes.
He wants to take care of you.
I did cajole him quite a bit,
but now he's keen on the idea.
He hasn't said anything?
Now that you mention it, yes...
But I thought he was joking.
Leave me to arrange it.
But you have to promise,
no more work on the side.
Mr sanada told me you've been
setting up jobs in shibuya.
You're lucky to get
a big wholesaler for a patron.
And all because you work for me.
You do realise that?
I've always wanted
this kind of security.
Security?
You feel secure with me?
- Well, you have money.
- Money doesn't bring security.
If a sumo champion loses
three tournaments, his ranking drops.
And if a sumo grand champion loses,
he has to retire.
This is like a dream.
- Can I call you "daddy"?
- Why?
I don't have a real father.
I like the sound of it.
"Daddy" — it has a nice ring to it!
I'd like to live with nobuko soon.
I see you like it.
I do. More, more!
I'm getting cooked!
The police society fellas came in.
I'm skint this month,
we've just had a baby.
Come on, you're a rising star.
You guys never let up
on the pressure!
You're a stubborn one.
Who are you trying to protect?
Your madam suma?
She already told us everything.
We just need you to corroborate it.
Surely you get more than just tips.
Prostitution is common at inns
these days.
Her place is rife with it, isn't it?
/sn't it, Tome?
I'll tell you everything, officer,
but keep your voice down.
No-one can hear us.
Yes, it's rife with it.
And the terms are awful,
the girls only get 40%.
Meanwhile, she charges 10 yen
for vegetables and miso soup.
And she wouldn't give me a penny
when I got sick.
Seems madam got two months.
And not just a fine.
It wasn't you who talked, was it?
What are you saying?
The police already knew everything.
No, we don't do
that sort of thing here.
I don't know.
The madam's not here.
What a bother!
What a waste, turning them down.
We have no choice.
You never know who's listening in.
I'm in a bind.
I'm having a coat made.
Weren't you going
back to the country?
I can't leave at a time like this.
Though I did tell them
I was coming home.
Excuse me!
- Excuse me!
- Quiet!
It's a couple.
Masako, you go.
Masako, go on!
- Go around!
- I couldn't.
Will you be staying the night?
- No.
- This way, please.
Listen to me, all of you.
- If you want out, now's your chance.
- Want out?
There's no future here for me.
I've rented an apartment
in ikebukuro.
You'll live in fear here now,
it's too risky to do any work.
So we'll all live separately.
When I call,
you go and meet a client.
You'll meet at an inn
and look like a couple.
- Like call girls?
- That's right.
I'm the only one
with the client list,
so you can rest easy.
What's your cut?
I'll takejust 30%.
That's better than working here.
But you have to think differently.
You can't just sit around doing nothing.
You'll have to getjobs.
Office girl, shop clerk, anything.
So we only meet clients at night?
Exactly.
That way, no-one gets caught.
- Plus you'll be earning a salary.
- Will it be that easy?
What happens
when madam comes back?
Don't worry.
You know, I was once
head of a labour union.
I gave orders to 3,000
female factory workers.
Besides, if there's trouble,
we've got mr karasawa behind us.
Tome, I'll go with you.
April 1959
what kind of girl today?
Let me watch it, too.
You shouldn't all be here.
It's too risky.
Sorry about that.
What kind of girl
did you want today?
Ah, the girl you had last time?
Is that so? I'm sorry.
Today you'll get top quality.
It's 3,000 yen.
Thank you very much.
Miyako, you mustn't argue
with the clients.
Listen, everyone.
Men only like quiet,
gentle, obedient girls.
We know.
Look, she's so pretty!
She's good at tennis, too.
The crown Princess really is
different from the rest of us.
What's this?
Your cucumbers.
Thank you for your order!
Make some tea.
And then serve this.
And wash your hands, they're dirty!
Can you afford this?
It's fine. I need it for the business.
Hello. Midori?
5:30. You're a doctor's wife, okay?
East exit, outside the Niko restaurant.
He's 50-ish, with a moustache.
He'll be carrying a magazine.
I'll be there, too.
Oh, that feels so good.
I'm so happy.
So happy...
Father, everything's
working out so well.
Shall I make you even happier?
How about it?
Youlech!
I didn't mean that.
Your madam suma's inn
is up for sale.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
Can't work anymore.
What a shame for her.
5.2 million yen.
20% below market price.
I see.
Now's the time to buy.
What do you say?
- I should buy it?
- Of course.
Yes, but...
You won.
You're the sumo grand champion.
Daddy!
This is karasawa. What's that?
That won't do.
At hakusan?
Bring mr Yamada along.
That's right. If we don't get him on
our side, he'll make trouble later on.
What's wrong?
I need a good girl for tonight.
This guy is with fuji steel.
What time?
It's already 4:00.
Have her get ready now.
- How about miyako?
- Too young.
Bribing this guy is a major task.
She's no better than hanako.
He's a handsome man.
Are you suggesting that I should go?
That way,
I wouldn't have to worry.
If tonight doesn't go well,
my future prospects will suffer.
It's make or break.
If you'd bought the inn back then,
it'd really come in useful now.
I didn't have
that kind of money back then.
Do you have it now?
Are you kidding?
Never mind.
If there's no girl, it's all over.
If you agree to it, then I'll go.
But aren't you busy?
It's fine,
as long as you don't mind.
Darling...
You really don't care if I go?
Of course I do.
50,000 yen will do.
Can you give it to him?
I'll pay you back.
Very well.
Welcome back.
- Would you like dinner?
- Yes.
Oh, it's a blackout.
- Where's mr karasawa?
- He left soon after you.
Ow, that's hot!
It's not hot! You call that hot?
I can take a lot worse than that!
Put your hand in it. Do it!
Fooling around
with the grocery boy!
It isn't hot!
Could you make a fold here,
scrape the cheek bone,
and use that to build up the nose?
Impossible.
You have to use
other material for a nose,
like ivory or plastic.
Vinyl will do. It's cheaper.
It doesn't matter
what the client told you,
I paid you 60%.
Stop trying to cheat me.
If he paid 5,000, I should get 3,000.
You only gave me 2,000.
- And this isn't the first time.
- Now, listen...
Besides, you give all the others 70%.
Why do I only get 60%?
Enough of your tricks.
That's enough, mama,
let's go home.
Honey, wait outside.
Take this sweetie.
Go and wait outside.
I'm not leaving
until I get a 70% deal.
That's enough!
You certainly complain a lot,
but you know
what clients say about you?
- I don't care...
- You should!
I'll tell you
all the complaints I hear:
"No sex appeal." "Poor service."
And you drag that weirdo
everywhere with you.
It's bad for business.
He wants to come along.
What can I do?
- You have to be firm with him.
- I can't.
I love him.
There's nothing I can do.
- Is that Korean that good?
- What if he is?
He says he loves you,
but he doesn't care
if you sell your body?
He does care,
that's why he comes along.
- But he won't get a job?
- I don't want him to work.
I sell my body because I love him.
Got that?
I see.
You're so in love that you can't give
the clients decent service.
You just keep churning out
little brats.
Here's 20,000.
It's not because I owe you anything.
It's so you'll work harder.
All this talk about love
is nonsense.
- You just want money.
- What?
- You've forgotten what I did for you.
- What you did for me?
You became that yankee's
mistress for the money.
Just work a little harder.
Quit, by all means.
But at your age, you won't make
this much anywhere else.
Don't you want it? I'll keep it, then.
I want it!
Midori...
You can afford to be in love
because I take care of you.
Okay, it's over.
Let's go home quick.
Hanako!
They took your bandages off!
You look beautiful now.
Hello? Hello?
Miyako?
Why didn't you show up?
It was for 3:00.
The client got fed up and left.
I can't hear you over the phone.
I'll come over.
He only paid 4,000.
I get 30%, or 1,200.
That still leaves 2,800 for you.
What's wrong with that?
You're wrong! I only got 2,500.
- Where's the other 300?
- Taxi fare.
Taxi fare? You're kidding.
A roundtrip between ueno
and asakusa wouldn't even be 200.
Telephone and food expenses.
Don't be ridiculous.
I've seen your place. It's super-deluxe.
Look at me,
I'm living on rice and pickles!
What's this, then?
Can't I even eat salmon?
No, not ton/ght. I'm busy.
You're stingy!
Okay, then, 3,000 yen. Same place.
See you later.
What's that for?
Turning tricks on the side?
Who made you this beautiful?
Monster!
Everyone calls you a monster!
- Stupid bitch!
- Leave me alone!
You little brat!
You just exploit us
and give all the money to karasawa!
What's that?
You're all fake, aren't you?
- You're hurting me!
- It's all fake, you idiot!
I paid for your face,
and I'll tearit apart!
Nobuko?
Who was that?
She works for me.
Go on in. Hurry, go inside.
You could've telegrammed
that you were coming.
Pa should've let me know.
That girl disobeyed me.
But never mind about her.
She wouldn't listen to me,
so I had no choice.
Mama.
What?
Could you lend me 200,000 yen?
What for?
To start a farm.
A farm? Where?
- The kurumi plains.
- Kurumi plains?
It's close to town.
Perfect for a collective dairy farm.
We've already started
repairing the roads,
and we're all putting in money.
Who s we"?
Kanbayashi
and the other trainees.
What about high school?
I'm sorry, ma,
but I quit in march.
I've been working
on the training farm.
You quit?
I don't like studying.
I've been sending you money,
and you lied to me!
I'm sorry.
What about grandpa?
His legs are bad,
he says it's rheumatism.
Not that, you idiot.
I mean what did he say
about you quitting school?
He just said, "oh, well."
"Oh, well"?
Ma, lend me 200,000.
No way!
Forget these crazy ideas of yours.
You must move to Tokyo
and find a good husband.
I have a boyfriend.
You what?
He's helping with the farm.
It's jintaro from next door.
What do you do for a living?
One day...
I was going to tell you.
That's why I don't have
that kind of money.
You shouldn't be doing
such hard work anyway.
I was born a farmer,
I'm used to the hardship.
He's taking advantage of you.
He'd never do such a thing.
You never know with men.
He's all right.
He studies a lot,
but he's a little absentminded.
Was it fun, sightseeing in Tokyo?
Didn't see any sights.
She's a character, this one.
- She's just a country girl.
- That's okay.
- Wasn't there some dried roe?
- It's all gone.
Gone?
Soy sauce.
Where's hanako?
She left for work.
I'm 5 o r r v: M a! A m
I won't do jobs on the side anymore.
It's all right.
Don't just stand there, come in.
- What happened to her nose?
- Oh, that...
What happened?
It's nothing.
Nobuko brought this for us.
It'll give you strength.
I'm leaving tonight.
You haven't even stayed one night.
Grandpa's bedridden with bad legs.
I have to go.
Mrs matsuki?
Mrs matsuki!
- Yes?
- Telegram.
Wait, nobuko! Wait a minute.
You have to pee?
I'm going on ahead.
Don't die, pa.
It's all over.
How old was chuji?
About 65.
He was so hale and hearty.
Strong as an ox.
Grandma, how old are you?
I'm still...
91 years old.
Talk about hale and hearty!
Grandma should hurry up
and go too
and stop being such a nuisance!
What?
Ma, grandpa said something.
Pa, what is it?
Tell me.
"Breast"?
What's he mean, "breast"?
Grandpa? What do you mean?
Breast?
What are you doing, ma?
Pa, here's my breast.
Pa, it's my milk.
It's Tome's milk. Drink.
Drink.
Go on, drink.
I've really...
Done well for myself in Tokyo.
I'll be sending for you soon,
so hurry and get better.
Pa, I can't stand to see you die.
I couldn't bear it.
What's the idea,
taking all the condolence money?
You're so greedy.
I paid 10,000 for the expenses.
There was 12,000.
So? I'll be sending
all the thank-you gifts too.
So this is why you offered
to pay for the funeral.
None of you did your part.
And you paid with your money?
What?
Who put nobuko and pa
out in the barn?
- Mukaiyama's wife is so greedy.
- That's right!
She brought her seven brats.
They'll eat us out of house and home.
She's well known for that.
If there's a wake,
she starves her kids all day,
then brings them along to eat.
Well, it's a wake, after all,
even if it's just for chuji.
They'll be back again tomorrow.
You can't exactly turn them away.
Where's nobuko?
I don't know.
No-one's seen her
since we put pa in the coffin.
Thanks for coming all this way.
Good evening.
Where have you been?
Nobuko came to my place
but wouldn't say a word,
so I brought her back.
- Who are you?
- Kanbayashi yoshiji.
The son of yoshizo in kamigawa.
Nobuko's lover!
And quite a fancy fella,
after living in Tokyo.
How can he work in construction
with that scrawny body?
He couldn't.
That's why he returned here.
At least he's got virgin land
to plough!
Quiet! No-one asked any of you.
So you're the one
leading nobuko on?
I'm not leading her on.
What? Luring my daughter
away without a word.
Nobuko, I want an apology.
You're not coming in
unless you apologise.
I hope thatgir/ doesn't have
a bastard child too.
June 1960
no new us-Japan treaty!
We'll have to take a different route.
- Then the meter will go up.
- Nothing I can do.
What do you mean?
They're starving,
so they're demonstrating.
That's not my concern!
Nothing I can do.
I don't know, really!
Have you seen hanako?
She's not home.
I haven't seen her
in four or five days.
I gave her the rent money.
Did she pay it?
Hello? Sakura apartments?
Could you please call miss yokoi
to the phone?
She moved? Where?
What do you mean, you don't know?
Hello? Hello?
Sorry. Could you get miss seki
from next door?
She moved too? When?
Both of them together?
Together?
Damn them. They've run away!
Hello, is that karasawa enterprises?
The president, please.
This is mrs matsuki.
He's out?
This is mrs matsuki!
Am I sure I'm calling
the right place?
You're just an employee.
What the hell
are you talking about?
You're matsuki Tome?
- Where were you yesterday?
- At home with an upset stomach.
Spring 1961
You surprised me.
I'm the one who's surprised.
I told you not to come here.
Yes, but...
What happened?
Did you just get out today?
It was awful.
You never came to see me!
Think about it,
how could I visit you in prison?
I know, but...
Take this for now.
Thank you.
- Did you go to your apartment?
- Yes, but some stranger's living there.
There's a fujiwara real estate office
at otsuka station.
Go and see them.
They'll show you your new place.
Go and get some rest.
Your things are there.
I'll come by tonight.
Did you say... Fujita?
Fujiwara.
Idiot!
Mrs matsuki?
That's odd.
I think she's home.
Mrs matsuki, you have a visitor.
Nobuko?
I'll open the door.
Nobuko, what are you doing here?
Mr karasawa called me,
so I hurried over.
Why?
Haven't you heard?
I haven't heard anything.
Come in.
Have you been in Tokyo all this time?
When did you get here?
I ran away from home a month ago,
but you were in jail.
I had nowhere to go,
so I called mr karasawa.
200,000 yen?
Your mother hasn't got that much.
That's why I'm asking you.
I can't give you that much money
just like that.
But...
That doesn't mean...
That I don't have it.
Great!
I promised the others I'd get it,
no matter what.
I admire your zeal.
Yoshiji put in 50,000,
and ma gave me the same,
so just 200,000 more...
- Will the new farm make money?
- Lots of it!
We'll clear a million yen
by the second year.
In 15 years,
it'll more than double.
In 20 years,
when everyone's kids are grown,
we'll be even richer than...
Than me?
That's great.
But I won't give you
that kind of money for nothing.
And I do sewing for the neighbours.
And mr karasawa comes to see you?
Yes, about twice a week.
I'd like you to come and live with me,
but there's a phone, and you might
go back to your old ways.
Ma, go ahead and slap me.
I don't mind.
Ma, what other way is there?
We're poor, we have nothing.
Just wait four months,
until the crops are in.
Then come to kurumi plains.
Don't you understand why
I struggled so hard to raise you?
Don't you understand?
I'm sorry I was such a burden.
I'll pay it all back when I've saved up.
We'll all live together soon, ma.
Forget it!
I can't live
out in the mountains anymore.
You say to wait four months.
But it doesn't work that way
between men and women.
Things will change
in a couple of months,
and you'll be trapped!
- That won't happen.
- You fool!
You know nothing about these things!
That won't happen.
Is that it?
Is that how human beings are?
Yes. That's how life is.
- What about the money?
- The money?
You promised nobuko 200,000 yen.
Isn't that how much I gave you
over the years?
Running a small business isn't easy.
I'm grateful for the help
now and then.
I'm sorry, but nobuko is
a different matter.
This is too much.
You're too cruel.
There's nothing I can do.
Besides, you've had your good times.
What are you talking about?
Coward! You dirty coward!
You're the one who had a good time!
I'm a human being too!
- Quieten down. You're disgraceful.
- You call me disgraceful?
Fine, then.
I'll make sure your wife and workers
hear all about you!
Go ahead and tell them.
But you and I are finished!
I will! I'll tell them everything!
Betrayed by everyone that I've loved
I wander through this bitter life alone
I'm back already.
Oh, this again?
- I learned how to reverse today.
- That's great.
The instructor says I can get
my licence in two weeks.
You're certainly keen.
Did you tell that kanbayashi
you were learning to drive?
Isn't that your boyfriend?
Yeah!
So he knows this address?
What did you tell him?
I said I was helping my ma out
for four months.
I see.
What would he do
if he found out about us?
He'd be furious.
But he won't find out.
That's right.
All he talks about in his letter
is fertiliser.
He's trying really hard
to teach me all about the work.
I'll teach you a thing or two myself.
There are two ways we can go.
You're free to choose whichever.
I'm a great believer in freedom.
One is what we already agreed to.
The other is to stay in Tokyo
and run a shop here.
The shop is that boutique you saw
yesterday in dogenzaka.
It's up for sale.
If you want, I'll buy it.
It's small,
so you couldn't live there.
You could stay here
in the apartment,
or / could get a house in the suburbs
for you and your mother.
You 7! Pay your own expenses
from your share of the business.
I 7! Take 30%.
You 7! Make 100, 000 a month easy,
so that's 70,000 for you.
So will it be that...
Or the farm?
I won't interfere with your love life.
You can sleep with anyone you want...
Except for twice a week.
You're wonderful.
I won't let you go, even if it kills me.
Stay with me,
and I'll make you happy
as long as you want.
You've only seen
the surface of happiness.
I'll show you the real depths.
I'll buy anything for you,
do anything for you.
Nobuko, which will it be?
The boutique.
I'll give up the farm
and take the shop.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
But I have to go back
and see yoshiji once more.
I have to give him the money I promised
and explain things.
That's fine, but can't you just
write to him?
No way.
I have to talk to him face-to-face.
Let's do this...
I'll give you half now, 100,000 yen.
Then we'll send him the other half
when you get back to Tokyo.
You're so stingy, papa!
I'm not, I'm just worried.
It's only because I love you so much.
All right. We'll do that.
Nobuko!
You'll be a happy woman at last.
I love you, papa.
I'm sorry, papa!
You sure you got through to her?
Yes. We had a long talk that night.
And you told her to let you handle it
after I hand the money over to you?
Sorry, sometimes I'm just
a country bumpkin.
I hate getting old.
Used and hung out to dry
by a young girl.
On top of that,
when I went to pay the rent,
her landlord asked me
where the deposit was.
That means she ran off
with the 100,000 yen.
I don't know how she managed
to wangle that.
That girl's really something.
While I was still reeling from that,
this arrived.
"Papa, I couldn't tell you
because I felt so bad,
"but this is just a loan.
I'll pay it all back."
I hate getting old.
I'm lost for words.
You're no better.
You should try to talk
some sense into her.
Sorry, but I did plead with her
to come back in two or three days.
But it's been two months!
I'm really sorry.
Now that I'm working as a cleaning lady,
I'm always tired.
When I get back home,
I'm just exhausted.
I'm in love with that girl.
An old man's delusion.
An old man's perverted escapade.
I couldn't care less what people say.
By the way, I put a deposit
on the dogenzaka shop too.
I'm a businessman,
I'd hate to lose that money.
That kanbayashi fellow
knew nothing about me, right?
Supposing he found out?
What would he do, if he found out
about me and nobuko?
I guess he'd...
I'll pay yourfare.
Will you go right away?
All right.
Right away.
With every passing day,
she becomes more of a hillbilly,
and I get older.
I'll bring her back for you, daddy.
I'll think of a way.
You should join,
it's a good thing.
How much is it?
Don't be daft, the pure land sect
doesn't take money.
You just buy these when you join,
and their newspaper once a week.
- How much is all that?
- Not much at all.
Think I should?
Absolutely. It really works.
You go and tell them everything,
and you feel great afterwards. Really!
Because life's such a bitch!
- Time for a bath.
- Go on.
- Don't bother with that.
- It's all right.
- How about it, then?
- I'll think about it.
Thanks for the delicious rice cakes.
- Take some home.
- That's okay.
Hey, come here.
- I know a good job.
- What kind ofjob? Cleaning?
No, no!
Much easier and much better money.
Sounds good. What is it?
I'll tell you later. After your bath.
- I can't wait to hear. Call me later.
- I will.
I've settled down since you died.
But now nobuko's left me too.
I still have a lot of suffering to do.
Please lend me your strength.
I'll bring nobuko back
into the fold somehow.
Then life will be a little easier.
And the three of us will be together.
Well, I'm off for a bath.
O-wa-i-ya-re
I need some small change.
I hate the bath house
being so far away.
Nobuko!
Where's yoshiji?
- Isn't he at the house?
- No. Where could he be?
He said he might go into town.
Nothing to worry about.
But the calcium arrived,
and I don't know how much to use.
Ah, there he is.
I'll head back to the barn.
Okay, I'll wait.
- Where did you go?
- Nowhere.
Asao's looking for you.
Listen...
I was wrong.
Yeah, you were, wondering
who the baby's father was.
- Will you stop it now?
- Yeah.
Let me drive.
Nobuko, take good care of the baby.
We can't lose it.
You don't know whose it is.
What's it matter?
But it might be mine, right?
You're such an idiot!
Still saying "it might be"?
Well, I don't know
what I don't know.
You may not know, but I do.
I said I know!
Takasaki station has the best chicken.
Yeah, but utsunomiya's
isn't bad either.
It's always been that way.
Takasaki's was the best
even before the war.
All the stations have
better lunch boxes these days.
- It's the rice.
- Yeah, the harvests are good.
- It's true.
- I'm not very experienced.
No, / can see that you are.
Damn it.
Godforsaken place!
That idiot!
What the...?
Just my luck,
on top of everything else!
Where, oh where
has the bab y-sitter gone?
She went to town to buya dog...
Produced by
otsuka kazu & tomoda jiro
screenplay by
hasebe keiji & imamura shohei
cinematography by
himeda shinsaku
cast:
Hidari sachiko as Tome,
yoshimura jitsuko as nobuko
kawazu seizaburo as karasawa,
kitamura kazuo as chuji
kitabayashi tanie as madam,
harukawa masumi as midori
Directed by imamura shohei
 