Production: Nichiei Agency, Ltd
Production Assistance: Director's Company, Ltd
Er, will it take much longer?
With traffic like this...
I could walk from here.
Akebono Trading?
No no, no way.
Ma'am, don't be like that,
sit back and relax.
Akebono Trading's taken off lately.
Out of nowhere.
No one who goes there
asks for change.
I'm not so lucky.
I'm always fearing the worst.
The other day, I drove
sumo wrestlers. Three at once.
That was a big mistake.
They busted my suspension,
but wouldn't fork out for repairs.
They really screwed me.
So... how much longer will it take?
Traffic's hell at this hour.
Ma'am, don't ever cross
a sumo wrestler.
Remember that wrestler Fujinomaru?
Well, sumo's not my thing.
Three years ago, he killed
his senior stablemate and his lover,
but he got off on an insanity plea.
It was on the news. Turns out
it was actually premeditated murder.
You read gossip rags?
Damn, their bodies were a mess.
Every bone was broken,
snapped like pencils.
Man, that stuff freaks me out.
Moving on.
Families of victims of
ex-sumo wrestler A,
who committed two murders
three years ago, but was acquitted
after a psychiatric test,
are seeking a retrial.
They object to the prosecution's claim
that A was temporarily insane.
Police are considering whether to
re-arrest the now-rehabilitated A.
THE GUARD FROM UNDERGROUND
Makiko Kuno
as Akiko
Yutaka Matsushige
as Fujimaru
Hatsunori Hasegawa
as Hyodo
Directed by
Kiyoshi Kurosawa
Oriental Security Service
Oh, wait, ma'am.
Where are you going?
To see Mr. Kurume
in Section 12.
Section 12?
There's no such section here.
What's their specialty?
Art sales and acquisitions,
I heard.
Art?
Ah, the new Section 12.
Please forgive me.
- So, your name is?
- Narushima.
Ms. Narushima?
Narushima...
Ms. Akiko Narushima?
- Your first day.
- That's right.
So, did you bring a photo?
- Yes. Should I give it to you?
- Please.
It's necessary,
for security reasons.
Huh? Another newcomer?
Why don't they get out?
This is all I have.
It's rather big.
Business card size is best.
Well, it'll do.
I'll take care of it.
- May I go in?
- Sure, go ahead.
Well, I'll be seeing you.
Pleased to meet you.
A Lautrec?
Yes, I've heard of it, but...
Ah, I know. Mr. Sakakibara, that one
in the weeklies... Yes, I know it.
Huh?
1.8 billion yen?
Mr. Sakakibara,
that's a little too...
Picasso? 2 billion...
Mr. Sakakibara, we don't want to be
stingy, but that's new territory for us.
How about something more accessible
in the 20 to 30 million range...
No no, we're quick learners.
We've hired an expert for that.
Sure. Sure, sure.
Redon? One moment please,
I'll jot it down.
R-e-d-o-n.
Sure. Sure, understood.
Alright Mr. Sakakibara,
we'll call you back.
Sure. Thank you.
Much appreciated.
Kurume, a Redon sold at Sotheby's
last year for 800 million.
Sonovabitch...
That damn Sakakibara.
He was mocking me!
Oh, how about this?
A Laurencin for 60 mil.
Surprisingly cheap, isn't it?
No, steep! Yoshioka,
that under 30 mil list?
Er, it'll be ready soon.
Well, in the 20 mil range...
Oh, Chagall maybe?
Huh? A Chagall for 20 mil?
Only a fake.
Yoshioka, what auction?!
Will the buyer sell?!
A lithograph.
What?! A lithograph won't do!
Famous means expensive, huh?
But how can a Laurencin go for 60 mil
and a Lautrec for 1.8 bil?
Narushima, what's your take
as an art expert?
I was only a museum curator,
so I don't know about market prices,
but Lautrec and Laurencin differ in
historical status, so it makes sense.
Also, Chagall's lithographs
have exquisite beauty,
and deserved value as fine art.
Hey, art is like women.
No buyer, no value.
Yes sir.
By the way, you mentioned Redon on the phone
earlier, so how about this?
What do you think?
It's a favorite of mine.
It's been re-evaluated at last.
Van Goghs sell for over 10 billion,
so a Redon could for 1.
Narushima, do you know
what's worth 1 billion?
No, I just thought you might like it.
But a 1 billion painting's
worth 1 billion.
How would you know?
It's kids' stuff!
Hey, Yoshioka, I want that under 30 mil list soon.
Kurume's like that.
Irritable. Don't let it rile you.
No, I'm not bothered at all.
I'm still learning sales.
You'll pick it up.
Narushima, But maybe you shouldn't get used to
a cutthroat business like ours.
By the way, Narushima, have you met Hyodo in HR?
No.
Oh. But weren't you hired
on Hyodo's recommendation?
I was.
I only heard that though.
You'll meet him eventually.
He's scary.
Is he really?
A weirdo in a way.
Always acts alone,
and has no staff of his own.
He suddenly takes charge of
big jobs unrelated to HR.
Taking on art sales
was actually Hyodo's idea.
I see.
Compared to him,
Kurume's easy.
Promise you won't let
Kurume's tantrums get to you.
Hey, Nonomura, a client's waiting!
Come!
But I have to show Narushima...
That can wait!
Right, Narushima?
But she hasn't met Hyodo...
Hyodo?! He's HR!
Nothing to do with Section 12!
Nonomura, don't tell me
you're Hyodo's boy now?
Of course not, sir.
It's fine, please go.
I'll return the key.
But do you know where the security office...
- Just come.
- I'll be OK.
- Okay, sorry...
- Shut up and come!
Mr. Hyodo, our CEO's on the line.
Tell him I'm still asleep.
Security Office
Excuse me!
Excuse me? I came to return this key.
Can I help?
I'm returning this key.
Is that so?
No one's in there?
That's odd.
Anyway, I'll take it.
Thank you.
Ah, Fujimaru, you were in here?
How's it going?
Got the hang of it?
Oh, her. She joined Section 12
today. Akiko Narushima.
Her photo's too big,
so I stuck it in there.
Quite a classy lady.
Who's there?
Oh, Shirai probably.
Hey.
Mamiya, how about
the Japanese St. Leger?
I don't bet on horses anymore.
Ah, what a waste.
I got a tip from the top
of Central Betting.
I'm out.
Oh yeah?
I'm going to stake all my money on it.
So pay back that 9 mil already.
9 mil?
It was 8 mil a little while ago.
Like I told you, 15% interest
gets added monthly, yeah?
Win it back on the horses, okay?
Shirai.
Can you wait some more?
I can wait. I can,
or pay me back another way.
The deed to your house,
or something.
Like that.
Yeah, like that.
Shirai, let me introduce you.
He's new here. Fujimaru.
Fujimaru? Is that his real name?
Or a horse's...
You... trying to threaten me?
Are you crazy?
Of course not.
Then why this freak?!
Narushima, I think 1 billion
for a Redon is fair too.
You do?
Then again...
I can somehow talk Kurume into it.
But I'll need a list of 10 paintings
for 30 mil, and 5 for 100 mil.
As a start, quantity over price first.
That'll lower the risk.
OK.
By the way, tell me.
What's worth more?
A first-rate artist's mediocre piece,
or a second-rate artist's masterpiece?
I'd say the latter.
You would?
Yes. The status of an artist
can change easily with the times,
but the status of a masterpiece
doesn't change at all.
Got it.
Hey, everyone, try these Canadian sausages.
Food Section samples.
OK.
Try some.
- Takada?
- No thanks.
Thought so.
Wow, great!
How is it, Narushima?
Well...
Oh, thank you.
Okey doke,
I'll go make some coffee.
Ah, Yoshioka, for all of us.
Yeah sure, sure.
Shirai's late today.
Fujimaru.
Fujimaru?
I know you're there.
Yes, you're here.
Ah, Fujimaru, listen.
Be careful with this lever.
The switchboard's old and dangerous.
Don't ever switch it on, okay?
Anyway, Shirai sure is late...
Open it.
What the hell?!
What have you done?!
I know why Shirai
had to end up like that.
What's your game?!
What's my game?
That's for you to figure out.
Narushima, right?
Yes...
I'm Hyodo.
Oh, Mr. Hyodo!
Sorry for not visiting you.
That doesn't matter.
How's everything going?
Well, it's going.
I see.
Tell me something.
Yes.
A Christie's auction
is in NY this weekend.
Cezanne's Cracked Walls.
Is 8 billion a ripoff or a bargain?
What? Well...
The House With Cracked Walls?
It's a fair price.
Got it. Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
Mr. Hyodo, But Section 12 policy forbids
buying expensive artworks.
Section 12 isn't involved, okay?
OK.
It's not some top secret project.
Just a personal one.
So tell Kurume if you want,
or whatever. Fine with me.
No need to worry.
Are you sure?
But if you have 8 billion to spend,
Kurume might change his mind.
You believe that?
Unfortunately, Kurume's a no-hoper.
Whatever he does,
he's bound to fail.
Then, what about Section 12?
That's... up to you.
But I don't understand...
Section 12's all losers.
How!
Like Hanae Takada. She's ambitious,
but just too bigheaded to succeed.
How rude...
And Ken Nonomura.
A nice guy but just an errand boy.
The worst kind.
And Minoru Yoshioka.
His problem's obvious.
He's just a loser.
I'm sure you sensed it.
So Mr. Hyodo, you created Section 12
just to destroy it?
Why do such a thing?
For the company's sake?
What gives you the right?
I can't believe you.
I'm sorry.
I said too much.
No, it's fine.
Thanks for your Cezanne advice.
Narushima.
Narushima. A moment.
Sit here.
Insulin.
I'm somewhat diabetic.
Post Office savings accounts
give good interest.
Really...
Be good to your parents.
I will, thank you.
Relax.
Narushima.
There's nothing to fear.
Just sit there and watch me.
Hello, Security Office?
I'm in the File Room, but
the door's locked and I can't get out.
I'm sorry, but could you
open it for me?
I'd appreciate it.
Oh, Narushima's not with you?
She's not back yet?
Gone all afternoon.
Hmm. She takes her time.
Er, are you a guard?
Something wrong?
That door at the back...
Did something strange happen?
Someone was there,
on the other side.
That'll be the new guy.
He doesn't know the ropes,
but give him time.
- So that was it...?
- Yes.
Hey, Narushima, what's wrong?
She got stuck in the File Room.
Ah, we all did at first.
Thanks for your help.
I'll be okay now.
Okay, here you go.
Narushima, sit here.
What did I do?
Don't tell me you
tried something with her.
O-Of course not!
If she was just stuck, she was
gone for a strangely long time.
I've done nothing.
That's the truth.
You use the security cameras to peep.
- I do not!
- I know you do.
I know.
If you want to feel somebody up,
stick to old biddies.
My young ladies are off limits.
Got that?
Narushima, go home early
if you like.
No, I'll be fine.
When you get stuck,
call security's extension.
Yes, I did that, but...
Something else happened?
A security guard came,
but something seemed off.
A new guard?
Did you see him?
No.
Takada, have you?
I saw him.
He was huge.
He could probably break down a door.
He's that huge.
Two meters?
Not much of an IQ though.
He couldn't open the door.
Narushima, that can't have been nice.
- Nonomura, get that file for me.
- Sure.
- Narushima, could you do a gallery check up?
An update regarding the sumo wrestler
acquitted of murder three years ago.
Pressure from the victims' families
has urged police to re-arrest him.
He is currently being traced.
This is him!
Kurume in Section 12!
This jerk!
He's with other staff during the day,
but he always does overtime alone.
You know, I could keep an eye
on him using our monitors.
No need to kill him.
Death's too good for him.
Just beat him severely.
Severely.
Enjoying yourself?
Since I met you,
I've been enjoying myself.
Especially today.
What's that?
You stole it?
No. I didn't.
Someone left it for me.
Do you know why they did?
They're trying to test me.
However,
I don't have time for that.
Oh, this is the File Room key.
Right.
Excuse me,
I'd like to ask you something.
Has anyone found a lost earring?
An earring?
Yes. One just like this.
I see. If it's found,
I'll call you right away.
Please do...
Narushima, I saw the new guard
this morning.
Wow.
Man, he's big.
You'll be amazed.
Oh.
And, I just heard, he was a
sumo wrestler. No wonder he's big.
No kidding.
He was a sumo wrestler?
But I've never seen him on TV.
If he had been,
why would he work here as a security guard?
Good point.
He's a washout, huh?
Poor guy.
Actually, he's kinda weird.
Wears an earring on one side only.
Not stylish, just funny.
Oh yeah?
Hey, you two.
Cut the idle chit-chat.
Yes sir.
Excuse me.
Oh, the guard just went
to the basement.
He did?
Basement machine room entrance
No, no, that's off limits!
- Sorry.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
- You work here?
I'm from Section 12.
Section 12...
Never heard of it.
You can't fool me, lady!
What?
Um, have you seen a guard here?
Nope. They wouldn't come here.
I see...
If you see one, tell them.
Clean the breakers and switchboard.
My job's hard enough.
I came to do electrical work,
now I'm cleaning.
I'm very sorry.
Don't you apologize.
Hey, hold this for me.
Sure.
Well, I don't come cheap.
A few days' switchboard repair fees
would sink a small company.
Done. Thanks.
Actually, somebody was in here
somewhere. Guard or not.
That sounds bad.
The company outsources security,
so I don't know who to talk to.
Maybe call the security company.
Or better, the police?
It's not having my earring taken
that bothers me.
Your photo?
Yes...
I'm sure I'd be upset too.
But you gave up your photo,
and you dropped your earring.
Yes...
I guess I'm just being too uptight.
I know. Why not talk to
Hyodo in HR?
You mean that Hyodo?
Yeah. He'll help. He's eccentric,
but he's got connections and clout.
If you can't, I will.
No, it's okay. I've met him once,
so I'll tell him directly.
Hang in there.
Yes.
Mr. Hyodo, Narushima
from Section 12 for you.
Wake me at 6 p.m.
Seriously?
Nah, it's no problem.
Yeah yeah.
Okay, see ya.
Yoshioka's not coming back.
Really?
Everybody's so cold.
Today's your welcome party.
It's just you and me.
Sure, but I still have work to do.
Overtime?
It's dangerous to work alone.
That guard...
Hey Nonomura.
We're going.
Oh, but...
Narushima, you've got work to do?
Yes, a little.
See?
I'll keep her company.
Kurume, after you.
- Nonomura.
- Yes sir?
Let's go.
Yes sir.
Okay Narushima, sorry.
I forgot something.
Nonomura, you go ahead.
What? Go on ahead.
Yes sir.
Why...don't you do anything,
I'll do it for you...
Shut him up.
No need to kill him!
You know, right?!
Please, noooo!
Excuse me, I'm with Section 12.
Seen Kurume?
Kurume? I haven't.
I see...
Human Resources
Narushima? What's up?
Have you seen Kurume?
No. You should've called my extension.
But I can never get through.
What?
Oh.
My secretary's day off?
What's the time?
11 a.m.
11? 9 p.m. in New York.
Too late to call.
Sore throat.
No more cigs for me!
If you hear from Kurume,
please tell him to come to Section 12.
Yeah sure.
I'll be going now.
Oh, wait, Narushima.
Sorry, got something
I can drink? Anything?
Ah, that's good.
Hyodo.
Yeah?
Do you know about the new guard?
No.
Oh.
Something wrong?
He's extremely large.
You'll know if you see him.
That man, he wears
an earring of mine that I lost.
It's really creepy.
I'll look into it.
The security office is empty now.
Alright.
I'll sort it out later.
I'd appreciate it.
By the way, Narushima.
Tell Takada in Section 12 for me.
In Kurume's absence,
she's in charge. Okay?
Sure.
Great news, Narushima.
The dealer will sell the Chagall
for 25 million.
They will?!
Lots to do. Nonomura,
hurry up with that buyer list.
Hello, Akebono Trading.
Oh, Mr. Sakakibara!
Yes it's me, Takada.
Yes. No, Kurume
is taking the day off.
Yes, so let me help you on his behalf.
More overtime, huh?
So it seems.
Hello, Akebono Corporation.
Thank you for giving us a call.
Yes, we can do that right away.
Yes, it seems like it.
I'm really sorry to bother you.
Not at all.
Yes, of course...
Narushima, can we talk?
Sorry?
Can we talk?
What is it?
Trouble last night?
What? What do you mean?
Kurume isn't here today
because of last night.
He's human too, you know.
I bet he can't bear to
look you in the eyes again.
What happened last night?
He came to you,
while you worked overtime.
He didn't.
I know he did.
I knew, but I couldn't do a thing.
Really, he didn't come.
But he headed back to the office.
He did?
I should've tried to protect you, Narushima.
Nonomura, you've got the wrong idea.
Kurume never returned
last night at all.
Then...
...where has he gone?
Fujimaru! Why do that?!
That girl did nothing wrong!
Why... would you...
It seems you still
don't understand me at all.
No, I understand you.
All too well.
Sorry I interrupted you.
Fujimaru...
Let me go...
I-I won't do anything...
Forgive me!
For what?
J-Just...
let me go... please!
I-I'm begging you!
You said you understand me.
How is that?
M-My spine... My spine...
You're crushing it!
Trying to understand me
is beyond your tolerance.
I'm alive...
Thank you...
Want to call the police?
Even if you don't,
they'll come soon enough.
Why be so impatient?
I'm not...
I don't mean to be...
Honestly.
Burn me into your memory.
Of course...
Are we clear?
Don't ever forget me.
Okey doke,
I'll go make some coffee.
- Yoshioka, it's okay. I'll make it.
- No, don't worry.
- I will.
- Really.
Sorry. Go for it then.
Are you alright?!
I'll call an ambulance,
so please stay still.
Yoshioka! Oh my god!
Run! Oh my god...
W-Wait a minute!
What are you talking about?
Hey, Nonomura!
She's here after all.
You okay? I was wondering
why you didn't come back.
There's been a murder!
What?
That guard.
You know, the big one.
Watch out!
He might be there.
Narushima,
go back to the 4th floor.
Yoshioka!
This is brutal...
Call the cops quick.
What the...
No good. Line's cut.
Find an exit!
No good.
Let's go back to the 4th floor.
I'm worried about Takada...
It won't work...
Takada!
You came here?
It won't work! What's going on?
The power won't come back.
Forget that, let's run!
There's been a murder.
We'll be next.
What are you talking about?
That guard.
Don't be ridiculous.
Nonomura? Where is he?
Beats me. He came back, said he'd
go make coffee, then left again.
The kitchen!
What? Wait!
Wait!
What is this?
What is it?!
We're screwed.
What now, Yoshioka?!
Okay. Let's break a
2nd floor window and jump.
You're that guy.
Your reputation precedes you.
This is even worse though.
Do you know
what you're doing? Huh?
You don't.
Fine. So basically,
you're sick in the head.
I'll go call the cops.
Give me your key.
Okay, let's try this.
Put your key on this wagon.
Then you can go.
You can do that, right?
Come and get it.
I'd rather not.
Change of plans.
I'll look for a way out.
So long.
It's no good.
They're all locked!
That one?!
No good either.
Why no lights?!
Somebody do something!
No use!
The power's turned off!
- We're done for! We can't escape!
- Don't give up.
Hyodo!
Working late too?
All doors are locked.
I see.
He's a clever one.
He's killed twice.
We must do something.
Nobody else left?
No.
Okay. Come to my office.
It's the only door he can't open.
Hyodo, how long do we stay here?
Any good ideas?
I'm trying to think.
How do we reach out for help?
Wave out the window?
Only if somebody's looking
at this hour.
The phone line's cut,
so no fax either.
Hey. What about telex?
That doesn't use the phone line.
Unfortunately, this is HR.
No telex.
- Section 12 has it.
- Who'll go?
I'll go.
Yoshioka, don't go alone.
We'll all go.
Bad idea.
Narushima, I'm a fast runner.
I'll be fine.
He won't catch me.
But who should I send a telex to?
It's midnight.
New York.
Narushima.
I told you Yoshioka's a loser,
but let me take that back.
Great, it'll work!
Hyodo.
I know.
He's been gone too long.
We need to go help.
Might be too late.
I can't go alone. If he's hurt,
I can't carry him.
That's true.
Takada, listen.
Is it over?
Are we saved?
Not yet.
Oh...
Hyodo and I are heading out,
but you stay here.
This room is safe.
Keep the door locked.
We'll knock three times.
Then open it. Okay?
Damn. No telex now.
Oh! Yoshioka!
Yoshioka. Yoshioka!
Did you send a telex?
Good, good!
Way to go.
Who's there?
Narushima?
Hyodo?
Who's there?!
It should be three knocks!
No. I won't open it!
Wait! Don't go!
Stop!
Don't! No!
Don't!
You bastard!
Narushima! Quickly!
Stop. Please stop!
Why? Why do this?!
For what?
To understand requires courage.
I have courage.
Please tell me.
You were unlucky.
Meaning what?
That's no explanation.
I want to understand you.
You can't explain.
So stop this! Please!
You suddenly appeared before me.
This began from that moment.
I knew this would happen.
The time flowing within me
is unlike that of your kind.
What kind of time?
Desolate time.
That can't be.
You're human just like me.
Time flows the same for us all.
You're utterly wrong.
Try using your brain.
Fine. I don't want to
understand you anymore.
So leave me out of this.
Hurry back to your lair.
And never come out!
You're just like them.
You can't believe humans like me
exist in this world.
I won't believe it.
But here I am.
Here ends my explanation.
Don't ever...
...forget me.
Are you alright?
Yoshioka's alive.
Plus, we got a Cezanne
for 8.5 billion.
You see, we got a
strange phone call from New York.
Something about...
Cast
Makiko Kuno
Yutaka Matsushige
Ren Ohsugi
Takeshi Naito
Hatsunori Hasegawa
Producted by Toshiyasu Nakamura
Planned by Director's Company
Produced by Susumu Miyasaka & Takashi Ikoma
Screenplay by
Kunihiko Tomioka
& Kiyoshi Kurosawa
Cinematography / Lighting / Recording / Art Direction
Music Producer / Composer
Theme Song / Theme Song Composer & Lyrics
Editor
Assistant Director
Assistant Directors / Assistant Cameras / Assistant Lighting Technicians /
Assistant Sound Recordist / Assistant Art Director / Set Decorator
Costume Design / Hair & Make Up / Assistant Hair & Make Up / Physical Effect / Title Designer
Sound Recordist / Assistant Editor / Negative Cutter /
Assistant Negative Cutter / Foley Artist / Re-recording / Color Timer
Stylist / Assistant Stylist / Graphic Designer / Costume Assistant
Miniatures Cinematographer / Assistant Camera
Decoration Assistant / Vehicle Support / Still / Production Publicity /
Production Desk / Production Assistant / Production Administrator
Production Coordinator
Hoei Sangyo / Kodak Japan Ltd. / 8-8 STEP / Paper Mail / Universal Lighting /
NKL Special Machine / Hachiojijoato Car Renta / Cineman Brain / Tokyo Television Center / Tokyo Laboratory
Collaboration
Takatsu Sousyokubijutu / Keihan Shoukai / Daikatsu / Bijutsu Shuppan-Sha Co., Ltd / TEICHIKU ENTERTAINMENT / Nichion Promotion
Liberal Nakamura / Eleonora Scaramucci / Aggie Grey's / Itariyard Co., Ltd. / Maison de Toiles / Missoni Uomo /
Gianfranco Ferre / Example by Missoni / Tanaka Eiko-Do / ABISTE Tokyo Aoyama / WHY Co.,Ltd.
Directed by Kiyoshi Kurosawa
English subtitles by
Don Brown