Long ago, on the border between Mino
and Hida, where there is much snow,
there circulated among the people who
lived there a legend of the Snow Woman.
They say that one evening,
during a strong snow-storm,
the spirit of snow turned
into the terrible Snow Witch,
and roamed the mountains and plains.
And if a man accidentally spied her,
the Snow Woman immediately
took possession of him.
Common villagers believe this legend.
[Snow Woman]
Producer: Ikurou Kubodera
Writer: Fuji Yahiro
Cinematography: Chishi Makiura
Sound Recording: Yukio Unabara
Lighting: Shunji Kurokawa
Art Direction: Akira Naito
Music: Akira Ifukube
Editing: Hiroshi Yamada
Sound Effects: Nobu Kurashima
Action Director: Eiichi Kusumoto
Assistant Director: Atsuhiko Katsuro
Production Manager: Masanori Sanada
Development: Toyo Laboratory
Cast:
Shiho Fujimura
Akira Ishihama, Machiko Hasegawa
Taketoshi Nait, Fujio Suga,
Masao Shimizu
Mizuho Suzuki, Sachiko Murase,
Yoshiro Kitahara
Jutaro Hojo, Sen Hara,
Tatsuo Hananuno
Tokio Oki, Jun Fujikawa,
Yukio Horikita, Shinya Saitou,
Hajime Koshikawa, Kiyoshi Haruta,
Eijirou Yamada, Ken'ichirou Imura
Directed by:
Tokuzo Tanaka
At last, at last, I have found it!
This tree is remarkable!
It looks like a living being.
Truly! It stood here for many years.
And now... at last we found it
completely by accident.
Thanks! Thanks!
Master, the weather is terrible.
What shall we do?
This night will be very nasty.
Let's stay here until the night
is over. It doesn't matter.
But there will be much
to tell about after.
It is a very happy evening,
we have found the splendid material
for which we searched so long.
And the blizzard's howl sounds to me
as if it were a song of celebration.
Yes, we will obtain the
permission of the Bailiff,
and saw this tree as soon as possible.
At last I will begin the work.
My name will be known in Mino
mountains, and my work will remain
with the people for a long time.
And the people will remember for
thousands of years, that the goddess
Cannon was made by my hands.
You... so young and so beautiful...
I decided that I will not kill you.
But in return, you mustn't tell
anyone about what you saw today!
Even your most intimate people.
Even relatives, children, or your wife.
If you say even one word -
I will kill you.
Keep silent about this!
Swear!
Yes, yes, I swear!
I will not talk! I will tell no one!
I will be silent, please  don't kill me!
- What's happening?
Did you have a nightmare?
- It's all right.
I slept badly.
Are you hiding something from me?
What nonsense! I have nothing to hide.
I hope so.
You see, I know you well.
But I can't understand anyway,
what caused my husband's death,
and why you are sick since then.
I just forgot to put wood on the fire,
and he froze in his sleep.
The people who brought you home
the next day, said the same thing.
Well, if you know nothing more,
then I should believe their words.
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
The tree! They brought the tree!
The tree, which the master found!
What? My husband?
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Here is the village! At last!
Hey, heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Here is the tree!
They brought it at last!
Bonze!
The Prior of the temple said,
today they brought that good material,
which the deceased Shigetomo found.
He said that you are the successor
of the master. Set about the work
on the goddess Cannon immediately.
But I... What do you say...
I completely lack the experience
for such an important work.
Never mind. The deceased Shigetomo
has always praised you.
And the Prior insists that despite
your youth, your work is noteworthy.
Thank you for such complimentary words.
Yosaku, if you refuse this job it would
be extremely impolite. You must agree.
Yes, I will undertake this work,
which the master desired so much to do,
although I am not worthy of this honor.
I have taken advantage of your roof.
Please excuse me.
Oh, get out of the rain!
If you stand under such intense rain,
you will be utterly drenched.
Well, don't hesitate,
please, come inside.
No, I don't wish to impose on you...
Why? People shoud help each other
in situations like this.
Let me open the door for you.
It's an old house,
there is no need to hesitate.
Thank you very much for your care.
It is so unexpected...
It is a spring rain already,
nevertheless it is cold.
Here, please drink this hot beverage.
No, thank you,
I will continue on my way soon.
But you cannot go now, can you?
Where are you headed?
To the city of Gudze,
in the province of Katiman.
So far?
Such a young girl under such rain!
I wish you only good things.
Please spend this night here.
Mistress, this girl has gotten soaked.
Oh, forgive me, you must change
into dry clothes immediately!
Please, here you are!
Here is clothing, if you please...
Ah, you are so beautiful!
I look at you and envy you!
It looks like the hand of
a living person!
Is this the hand of the goddess Cannon?
Just a sample.
It is a very complicated work,
and I am very inexperienced,
so I must repeat it 10 times more.
It turns out well!
My master was an outstanding craftsman.
The hand is very bad.
It's beautiful.
I would like to have
such beautiful hands.
Your hands are beautiful!
I was entrusted to carve the main
sacred statue for our local temple.
To obtain this work is a great honor,
for any master of Buddhist statues.
But I am not sure that I have the
ability for this. So I worry very much.
Don't worry.
Surely, everything will be all right.
You are very gifted.
I undertook this work, risking my life,
because my master could not make it,
but I...
Surely, you will complete it!
Thank you, I don't know why, but
it seems to me that I lack courage...
It is late already. Good night.
No. I would like to look more.
If I will not disturb you...
Of course not...
Everything is all right now.
You saved me.
Do not worry.
Mistress, what is the matter?
I felt heaviness in my sleep at night.
But miss Yuki looked after me.
So everything is okay now.
I see. Excuse me, I slept like a log.
Never mind. You worked very hard,
and got very tired.
Miss Yuki's parents were doctors.
- She recognized all my symptoms
right away. - Really?
There is an excellent medicine for
this illness. I will go for it later.
Where?
This is an herb. I believe
it grows somewhere hereabout.
Here is the herb. A medicine.
There is a lot of it here!
Really. And here, and here.
Miss Yuki. Are you in a hurry to leave?
Couldn't you stay in our house,
until the mistress gets well?
Someone is waiting for you, probably?
Me... I have no one.
Really? Neither do I.
You too?
I did not know my parents.
My deceased master saved me
and raised me as his son.
I see...
But as for you, miss Yuki...
Do you have a fiance?
- Really?
- And have you already a bride?
Nonsense! Who would marry me?
Really?
Miss Yuki!
What impudence! I don't care if you are
just children, I'll show you no mercy!
Bailiff!
Children, what did you do?
Are these your children?
They scattered logs!
- It hurts! Ahhh... Forgive me, please!
- Such impudence!
- Mistress!
- Take that!.. And that!!
Hey, get out of here!
Mistress!
Who are you?
I am Yosaku. I once asked you
for permission to fell a tree.
I am master Shigetomo's apprentice.
- What? Master of Buddhist statues?
- Yes.
Mistress! Mistress!
My horse!
Mistress!
I will punish you later. Just wait!
Go!
I'm... dying...
- Mistress!
- Hold on!
Miss Yuki, your arrival here
was no accident.
I beg you, take care of Yosaku!
Yes.
Yosaku will surely become master.
But someone should help him.
Miss Yuki, please, marry Yosaku!
Yes... But...
I beg you!
It's an imposition...
but if you wish...
Thanks! Ah...
- Mistress!
- What? The old woman died?
- Yes. You need not punish her now.
It's enough! But what about the woman?
- The woman?
- The woman.
I ask you, what became of this girl?
She married Yosaku, performing
the dying request of the old woman.
Do you like me?
Yes, I do.
Since the first time I saw you.
And I do also...
Really?
Yuki...
Why is your body so cold?
Yuki? Yuki?
Where did you disappear to?
Oh! Your face is turning blue!
- I don't feel very well...
- What happened? Is everything okay?
Yes... It is better already.
- Let us return home.
- Yes... Let us return home.
Are you all right?
Let me give you a hand.
Oh, it is the Bailiff!
What an unexpected visit!
What happened?
Some pressing matter?
As you know, I was invited into
the capital by the high court Official.
I have arrived this morning.
Fortunately, I met there this man.
Who is he?
His name is Gyokei, he is a master of
Buddhist statues in the capital.
He belongs to the school of Unkei.
He is a very famous master.
Let me introduce myself. Gyokei.
By the way, he was the one
I wish to talk to you about.
I heard, your temple needed
the main sacred statue.
Please entrust its production
to master sculptor Gyokei.
I am very grateful for your proposal,
but I have already entrusted it
to Yosaku, Shigetomo's apprentice.
I understand! If Shigetomo made
the statue, it would be another story,
but this is too great an honor
for an unknown youth.
Besides that, I have heard that
five years have already passed since
you entrusted him with this work.
Five years have passed already,
but he has done nothing!
May I speak?
I have heard that it requires 4-5 years
to dry the material for the statue.
Yosaku is probably waiting
until the material is ready.
I understand!
But I say you entrusted an unknown
master with producing the main sacred
statue for the state temple.
What will you do
if he does not finish it?
He has not started to work yet,
so let Gyokei also do it.
We will look at their works,
and select the best.
Do you have any objections?
Well, it sounds very convincing.
I will agree.
I am so happy!
Because I've got a good wife.
I feel the same about you.
Also, you are a marvelous mother.
I hope... my son also thinks so...
You are a good mother. Moreover you are
still as beautiful as you were before.
Gyokei, he is your competitor.
Yosaku, Gyokei is a very famous master.
We have decided just now
that he will also produce
a main sacred statue for the temple.
But this work was entrusted
to you, wasn't it? Show us
what you are capable of.
- This woman...
- What?
I've hunted for women in the capital
for five years, but among them there
was none to compare with her.
She is even more beautiful
than she was before.
The Bailiff supports Gyokei.
But I will not lose to him!
I have changed in these five years.
Now, now, near the small
brook behind the house,
A snake lived before,
and a tortoise lives now.
A common tortoise,
but it steals people.
Yesterday it took four people,
and today - five more.
A family of nine people in all.
And these stolen people disappeared...
Taro doesn't sing!
Don't you know this song?
Then don't bother us!
Oh oh! His mom!
She will punish us. Let's run!
Taro.
Everything is okay, your mom is here.
Are you injured?
Mom, teach me to sing this song!
You are too young,
it is difficult for you!
- No. Teach me!
- Will you be able to memorize it?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Now, now...
near the small brook behind the house
a snake lived before,
and a tortoise lives now.
A common tortoise.
But it steals people.
Yesterday it took four people,
and today - five.
A family of nine people at all.
And these stolen people disappeared...
Now, now, now!
Mom!
You must win certainly,
otherwise I will lose my honor.
You are the famous Gyokei.
You produce such a splendid statue,
Yosaku won't be be able to compete with
you, even if he stands on his head.
Villagers usually know
nothing of high society.
Yes, that is so. They are like
the frogs that live in the well.
Yosaku competes with you,
but there are boundaries,
and he does not know his place.
It seems to me, he is poor, and has too
low a position for this kind of work.
But he is very self-confident. By the
way, his wife doesn't match him either.
Don't worry, everything will be ok.
It is unfair! Gyokei has apprentices,
but you have to do everything yourself.
Yosaku! Is Yosaku home?
Oh, Official!
What are you doing?!
We are arresting him for
cutting down a tree on the land
of the Bailiff. Do not resist!
This is unbelievable! He gave me
permission to cut down the tree!
Shut up! The Bailiff says
he knew nothing about it.
What are you waiting for?
Take him away!
Wait!
My husband obtained an order
from the state temple!
He must carry out this work!
You cannot take him away!
We will take him away, regardless.
Take him!
Wait!
The Bailiff is a merciful person.
If you want to save your husband,
you should serve the Bailiff.
What?
The Bailiff likes you.
You will obtain glory and wealth.
Villain!
What? You don't accept? Well, fine!
Then pay me the penalty for illegally
felling the tree: three gold coins.
What did you say?
I will sell you this tree
for three gold coins.
But if not, we will take away Yuki, and
she will not return while she lives.
- I will pay!
- Yuki!
You will pay?
Well, we will give you
five days, okay? Five days!
Yes, that is fine.
If you do not pay in five days...
The Bailiff will be waiting
for you impatiently...
Five days, five days...
You... How could you make this promise?
This is illegal... How can such
unscrupulous people live in this world!
Yes, it is illegal, but the Bailiff
has a higher position than we have.
But isn't there someone
above the Bailiff?
The Bailiff has a patron.
He occupies an important position
in Mino city.
I see... Patron...
You can't personally present
an application! You can just pass it
through the Bailiff.
But I can't. That is why I am here
in person. Please, allow me!
It is impossible!
The master is away now.
Then allow me to give it to his wife.
I think we will understand each other.
Impossible, impossible! Madam is busy,
because her child suddenly became ill!
Child?
Can you cure him?
If something happens to him
before the Master returns...
I... I cannot live!
May I report? There is a woman
before our gates, who says
she is the daughter of doctors.
She asks permission to see the child.
This way, please.
Will you be able to cure him?
Will my child get well?
I have a child the same age as yours.
I relate to your misfortune as
if it were my own.
I will save him,
even at the cost of my life!
Thank you! I trust you.
She is only a woman!
She is not a specialist in this field,
and she will not be able to cure him!
We were also unable...
Even though we have tested
all possible means and methods.
It is very difficult
to cure this illness.
I've never seen
such a terrible fever in this age.
If we could stop his fever,
it would save him.
Now, now, near the small brook
behind the house a snake lived before,
and a tortoise lives now...
When did you return? Where did you go?
You...
Why do you look so pale?
If I can cure the child of the patron,
then I will obtain a reward.
- Therefore you...
- I will cure him for sure!
Now I cannot care for you, but,
be patient a little, please.
I am okay. I am okay.
But you are so pale...
Don't worry. It is because of the work.
I have to go now...
Care for Taro, please.
I cooked dinner for you.
Yuki!
- Where is your wife?
- She went out.
And you let her go?
Well, good.
You have now only three days.
If you do not pay,
you know what will happen.
Yes, I know.
Well, that's good.
This is your goddess?! Poor work.
Looks like a doll!
You will not be able to win. You are
just the frog, that lives in the well.
I repeat. Three days. Is that clear?
He arrived! He arrived!
Wife! Is it true that our son
is at death's door?
Does he still breathe? Is he alive?
- Yes.
- Oh, thank goodness! He is alive!
Son!
- Sir!
- Son!
- So good, so good!
- What happened?
Everything is all right.
She saved our son, when even
the doctors proved powerless.
Thank you so much for saving our child.
Thank you!
I am so grateful that you saved him!
Please, accept this reward
as the sign of my gratitude!
Gyokei sad he will deliver the statue
to the temple tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
But what about you?
Is it not ready yet?
I have almost finished, but...
I still cannot do the face...
What? The face?
I racked my brains,
but I can devise nothing.
Yosaku, what are you saying?
The Bailiff requires
that you present your work.
I know. That is why I...
- Yosaku, What happened?
- No, I can't...
- Oh, Bailiff.
- Yosaku!
You have not forgotten?
Pay the three gold coins!
But I...
You can't? At last do you understand?
- Take him!
- Aye!
- What are you doing?
Yosaku has important work!
- That is not important.
- You?!
- Take the money and depart, please.
Yuki!
Taro!
- Forgive me. I will never leave
you again. - Don't leave me again!
Of course not.
But then other men will come
to take away my father.
No. No one will take him away...
Your dear father...
That is it! The face!
My face?
Now I know how to make
the face of goddess. Here it is!
This work is remarkable.
We expected it from a master
known in all of Japan!
Don't you like it?
Look at her face attentively.
In my opinion the face, which shines
of gold, is too bright.
Really, both bright, and beautiful.
Yes!
That's fine, but it is not enough.
It needs something more.
Something more? What can that be?
- Compassionate heart.
- Compassionate heart?
Look at her face attentively.
Do you see compassion in her eyes?
It's a pity, but it's impossible
to pray to such an image.
- Tell Yosaku, I am awaiting his work.
- Certainly, I will tell him.
Yuki! Yuki! Let's go
to the holiday ritual. Get ready!
To the holiday ritual?
In no way I can imagine eyes
for the goddess.
My last chance is to ask
the gods for help. Let us go together.
Yes... But...
I heard, the Prior said the goddess
must have a compassionate gaze.
But I cannot visualize this gaze.
Apparently,
I need to ask the gods for help.
Yes.
I have almost finished my work.
If you will also come,
let us ask the gods together.
Yes. Let us go together.
And let us also bring Taro.
Taro! Taro!
- Bubbles in the boiling water!
- Taro! Taro!
Where is Mom?
At last, my desire will be carried out.
Don't be afraid. You are even more
beautiful when you are afraid.
You have such white skin.
I've never seen a woman with such skin.
I have dreamed so long
of undressing you!
Do you tremble? It's very nice!
Thus, remove your kimono and show me
your beautiful skin! Well?
Do you cry? You shouldn't.
You! You!
Snow Woman!
I must kill anyone
who has seen my true appearance.
I am guilty! I am guilty! I... I...
- Where is Mom?
- Well, probably she has already
returned home.
Yes. She is probably already home.
Sir! Sir!
Snow Woman!
Mom returned!
Have you finally returned?
We searched for you so long.
Mom, where have you been?
Mom, What happened?
What happened, Yuki? Yuki!
Yuki!
Today I must finish my work
at all cost.
But I can't.
Because I see a dark shadow.
- Shadow?
- Why does this shadow follow me?
You see, I have almost
finished everything...
-  The Bailiff has been killed!
- They say his servants are also dead!
This was a strange death!
Yuki. They said the Bailiff
has been killed.
What? I did not catch...
No, I heard well. They said
that the servants are also killed.
Let us go and look.
It is not necessary to look. I have
already seen everything with my eyes.
Really? Who killed the Bailiff?
I saw you five years ago.
What are you saying to my wife?
You are a ghost!
I recognized you that previous time.
And I have seen you again last evening.
You killed the Bailiff
in the little house near the temple.
It was not a simple death.
It was done by a ghost.
You did it!
Vile ghost!
Shaman! I will not allow
such violence in my house! Get out!
It is your ghosty wife who must leave!
- Ghost?
- Yes! I will prove it to you!
There is a scar on her arm
from the boiling water I splashed
on her five years ago. Look!
Hey! Get out! Get out! I will not spare
you despite your being a shaman!
Traitor!
Yuki!
Don't be afraid! I will not allow
even one finger to touch you!
You are my only wife.
And Taro's dear mother.
No one can break our happiness!
Yuki, it seems to me,
that my soul was cleansed just now,
and I can complete the work.
- Really?
- Yes.
But this dark shadow
remains nevertheless...
- Yuki!
- Yes.
Yuki.
The shaman said that you are a ghost.
I do not believe this.
She also said there is a five-year old
scar on your arm,
but I do not believe
in such nonsense either.
But I recalled an event just now,
which occurred before our wedding.
When I look at your kind face,
I can't believe it ever
happened at all.
But I still fear, to recall
that terrible evening.
Yuki, I have one very bad memory,
which I have never told anyone about.
It was five years ago.
There was a terrible
snow-storm that night.
I saw the terrible Snow Woman,
who killed my master.
Yuki...
It was me.
You?
Despite everything,
you finally spoke of it.
You shouldn't have done that.
For all these years, I have prayed
for your silence so many times.
I...
Since becoming your wife,
I learned human happiness.
And when Taro was born, we lived
happily together, the three of us.
And I prayed only about that,
not to lose this happiness.
But finally you...
You talked about this!
Yuki!
I must kill you.
You have broken your promise!
I will kill you.
Take care of Taro now instead of me!
And complete your work,
and let it be excellent.
Yuki...
Mom!
Yuki!
Mom! Where are you going?
Don't leave! Mom! Mom!
Oh! Compassionate gaze...
Mom!
Mom! Mom! Don't leave!
Don't leave! Mom! Mom!
 