THE WIND WILL CARRY US
A film by Abbas KIAROSTAMI
Where's the tunnel then?
We've passed it.
When?
Someone's been sleeping!
Where is it?
We've passed it, back near Biston.
We're heading nowhere.
Read the address to see where it is.
How many times do I have to read it?
After the junction,
we take a winding road.
This is the winding road.
We're on it.
After this road, we head downhill.
Then there's a single tree.
There are a lot here.
- What's after that?
- Nothing.
I know what there is. Nothing.
- Nothing?
- There's a road near the tree.
I'll tell you what there is.
"Near the tree is a wooded lane,
greener than the dreams of God."
What's after the tree?
Read the address.
It says a tall, single tree.
There's a lot on this hillside.
Is it very tall?
Yes, it says it's very tall.
It must be different
from the others then.
The single tree? There are so many.
They're all on the hill.
That's what it says here.
I don't think this
will get us anywhere.
There it is.
There, look, a single tree!
- Where?
- Up there.
I see it...
What a big tree! Look at it.
He was right.
Jahan, take a look.
Where?
Too late now, you'll have to look up
through the roof
but you won't see it.
Or through the rear window if
you're brave enough to turn round.
It's so big!
We've passed the single tree.
And loads of others.
Two more up there. It's beautiful!
I said we're reaching
two single trees.
It would help
if we could ask someone.
Don't worry, we'll find someone.
We can ask them.
Slow down a bit.
- We may not find anyone.
- We will.
This is farmland,
they're out working.
We have to ask.
Don't worry, we'll find someone.
I can see a black spot
in the distance.
Over there. He can't hear us.
Wait, I'll go and ask him.
Ask that one.
Ask her.
Hello, ma'am.
Hello, I'm honoured.
How do we get to Siah Dareh?
200 yards after the junction,
turn left.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Look, it's behind the hill.
Wait till we pass that tree.
Look into the distance.
On the hill.
- Siah Dareh's over there?
- Yes, that's it.
It says:
"At the foot of the mountain."
Hello, why are you late?
- Why are you late?
- You've been waiting for us?
- Yes.
- Who told you to wait?
My uncle.
I see, your uncle is...
Mr Hashemi Masti.
It's a long way to your village...
It's not far!
Not far?
What do you think of your village?
I've lived here since I was born,
I know it.
We're your guests then?
Yes.
Do I turn left here?
- You were waiting for us then?
- Yes.
Since two p.m.
I've been waiting since school
finished for the day.
My uncle said:
"My friends are coming.
Bring them to the house."
- Did he say why we've come?
- Yes.
But you mustn't tell anyone.
- All right.
- Good boy.
If anyone asks, say we're looking
for lost treasure.
Good idea.
If anyone asks, say we're looking
for treasure.
Imagine I ask you:
- "What are they here for?"
- Treasure.
It could mean trouble.
Not at all.
What a beautiful village!
Yes, it's very beautiful.
You've hidden it well.
We haven't hidden it!
The ancestors built it here.
It was them then!
They built it like this
so no one would steal it.
Tell me, why do you think
they built it here?
Because I wasn't there.
You weren't here before then?
Did you arrive recently?
I think the car has a problem.
It's stalling.
It struggles on hills.
The gauge isn't working.
Yes, it has a problem.
Farzad, get out.
- Is there water here?
- Yes, over there.
Get out, guys, and check the car.
Try to find out what's wrong.
Has your car broken down?
Our car? It's given up the ghost.
Meaning?
It can't go on.
You know, a car is like a man.
It needs to rest and restore itself.
It's given up the ghost.
It's overheating.
Can it be mended?
Yes, it will work again.
Don't ask so many questions
or I'll give up the ghost too...
at this altitude.
I've forgotten my book.
- What?
- I've forgotten my book.
Don't worry,
the others will bring it.
I have exams.
They'll be coming up
to join us soon.
I have to study.
I'll tell them to bring it.
I have to study
to have a good grade.
What a pest...
Ali, bring him up the book.
Where is it?
On top of the dashboard.
People always come this way?
No, there are several
different paths.
It's a tough one.
This isn't the main path.
Where is it?
It's a long way off.
This path is shorter.
- Is that why we've taken it?
- Yes.
Wait, why are you going so fast?
It was the best way!
That's what you want.
All right, but aren't you the guide?
Are you ennoyed?
Not "ennoyed", "annoyed"!
Annoyed?
Not yet, but if you carry on,
I soon will be.
Welcome, engineer.
Hello.
- We're honoured.
- The honour's mine.
This is it.
Welcome.
This is one of the rooms.
What did she say?
If it's too small,
there are other rooms.
Thank you, we'll only be staying
a couple of nights.
Make yourself at home.
This is the bathroom.
Another bedroom...
That's good. Thank you.
- Where's the old lady's house?
- Who?
- The lady who's ill.
- You mean Malek?
Yes, son.
She lives over there.
You can see it from the roof.
- Which way?
- This way.
- Can we see it from here?
- Yes.
See that blue window?
Which one?
Over there, near the lady
sitting on the steps.
You can't see much from here.
Let's go up higher, I'll show you.
- Which way?
- This way.
Let's go.
Farzad.
Why don't you bring us back
the soup bowl?
I'll return it.
I need it.
Who is that lady?
That lady there?
No, the neighbour.
Mim Khamman.
What does that mean?
My aunt on my father's side.
- Hello, engineer.
- Hello, are you well?
- How's your family?
- Very well.
- Who's that?
- My mother.
- Are you well?
- Yes, thank you.
Are you Mr Hashemi's sister?
He sends his greetings.
He wasn't able to come.
I understand.
I'm at your service.
Farzad, help them bring the gear in.
All right.
Where are you going?
Is she your aunt?
Yes.
Why don't we go to your mother's?
She says that our house
is too small
and that you deserve better.
I think your mother's wrong.
Small things have their value too.
You're small but skilful.
I'm going to grow.
The house won't grow though.
You'll grow up and go to school.
- How far does your school go?
- Until 11.
You want to keep on studying after?
I'll go to Momenieh until I'm 15.
For the final years,
I'll go to Kermanshah.
Where is it?
Over there, look.
It's over there. Look.
The blue window.
- The blue window?
- And that's her son.
I see, he's her son.
Yes.
Where's the cemetery?
Up on the hill.
I have to go.
I'll take the others to Hammad's.
Are you worried about them
or your book?
My book. I have an exam tomorrow.
You'll come back?
Yes, I'm going to the fields
to get my things.
Where's the engineer from?
Tehran or Hamadan?
Get up, you've slept enough,
you layabouts.
Get up, I've brought fresh apples.
This is for Ali
and this one for Keyvan.
- Hello.
- Hello, are you well?
I have some fresh bread for you.
- What is it?
- Bread.
We have fresh bread.
What more can you want?
You won't have another chance
like this.
This is for me.
The big apple is for uncle Jahan.
How about that!
This isn't Jahan's apple.
I think it's yours.
Yes, yes, it's coming. Here.
All right.
- Have you had your share?
- Yes.
Where are you going?
To school.
- To school?
- Yes.
Do you have time
to show us the village?
No, I have exams.
I'll go with you to school.
All right.
- There's no problem?
- No.
Where's my camera?
Ali, where is it?
I haven't seen it.
Look in the glove-box.
- Wait for me.
- Farzad, put the bread there.
Hello, engineer.
Hello.
Farzad, wrap up the bread
or it will dry out.
Would you like tea?
Yes, thank you.
My colleagues are sleeping.
We'll have a walk and come back.
Off you go.
Which way's your school?
This way and that.
You have two schools then?
No, there are two paths to school.
Where's the square?
This way.
You don't mind.
Come this way, I'll get my camera.
What a handsome white village!
Why is it called "Black Valley"?
The ancestors called it that.
Can't you call it "White Valley"?
No, we have to call it by its name.
It has to stay that way.
That's how it is.
"When you're fated to be black...
"...Even holy water
cannot whiten you."
How do you know that poem?
Our teacher recites poems to us
from time to time.
For homework?
No. He recites and I learn them.
You must be a good student.
Yes.
Well done!
What grade did you get
in the third term?
We haven't finished our exams yet.
In the second term, then?
Twelve.
And the first term?
Ten.
When do the exams end?
They start today
and go on for two weeks.
- Good luck.
- Come in.
How is she?
Who?
- You don't know who I mean?
- Mrs Malek?
She's so-so.
What does that mean?
She's still in bed.
She doesn't eat, she doesn't speak.
Wait, I'll fetch it.
Here.
Just a second.
I'm tying my shoelace.
She can't recognise anyone,
she can't speak.
What did the doctor say?
That there's no hope.
- The doctor said that?
- Yes.
Who's watching her?
My mother, the neighbours,
the family, my young uncle.
Your young uncle?
He's called in three times.
His holidays are over.
My grandmother's better.
How old is she?
100... 150...
100 or 150?
100.
Special rate?
Yes.
After one hundred,
the rest doesn't matter.
Do you know that or not?
I don't know.
We grow old, you know.
I have to go, I have exams.
I'll be back.
Come back quickly. Don't forget.
Hello, Tajdolat.
Hello, are you well?
Are you looking for something?
My camera.
We left it here and it's gone.
You didn't lock the car.
One night has passed,
you expect it to be there?
Hello, good luck.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
It's a miracle it's still here.
The guys forgot it
and didn't lock the car.
Welcome.
Thank you. You're kind.
Here, even if your car's gold,
no one will touch it.
Opposite the school,
the students are curious.
It's best to lock it.
All right.
Are you in telecommunications?
Telecommunications? Yes.
This place
is a world of communication.
Why are you here?
Yes, that's obvious.
I've never seen a woman
serve before.
Where did you spring from?
What?
You have parents, don't you?
Who served your father his tea?
My mother.
Why say you've never seen
such a thing? All women serve.
They have three trades:
by day,
they're workers. In the evening,
they serve and at night they work.
Except for your mother.
Thanks all the same!
I've told you time and again
not to park here.
Park next to the engineer.
When you start it up,
you pollute the café.
You lose me my customers.
Where else can I park?
Where the engineer's parked.
You choke us when you start it up.
We swallow fumes instead of tea.
I park right here.
You can't. You have no right.
It's my café, my territory.
You can't park your car here.
What's wrong?
Park where the engineer's parked.
What's going on?
It's my café, my territory.
Leave him alone...
Mind your own business.
I go to a lot of trouble, I work.
Serving tea isn't that tiring!
There's a difference.
My tea relaxes you.
Who takes care of me?
Are you tired?
I'm the one who's exhausted.
I've been out harvesting
in the blazing sun,
in the full heat of summer.
Is serving tea that tiring?
So I'm not working?
I don't make efforts?
Your work isn't all that counts.
Remember the first day
that you served tea
to your future husband.
You appreciated it and so did he.
Those days shouldn't be over now.
You have to remember that day
for the tea...
The first days are different
from now.
Serving tea to your husband
is work now?
Is it the same?
Yes, but it's not work.
Whether you make tea or serve it,
it's work.
I serve you tea, it does you good.
But no one takes care of me
to help me relax.
I know you're exhausted.
Serving tea is work these days.
Don't take any photos.
I have three jobs.
I have three jobs, not you.
And the third is the hardest
and most important.
Don't take any photos!
- I should have kept it.
- I'll put it away.
- I said no photos.
- All right.
I won't do it again.
Don't men have a third job?
Only women?
We don't?
If men don't do
their third job,
they'll be dishonoured.
Their third job weighs
as heavily as a mountain.
It's a very hard job to do.
It's not as simple as you think.
Is that wrong?
- Mashti Hatam!
- What?
Come on, come on.
The engineer's
forgotten his camera again.
He's as distracted as me.
What's the news?
Nothing special.
Take care.
Mrs Parvin!
I'm bringing you soup.
May your wishes come true.
Is she well?
Yes.
Have you finished?
If you hear me, hold the line,
I'm going to higher ground.
I'm going higher up.
Hold the line.
If you hear me, I'm not hanging up.
I'm going to higher ground
so we can talk.
If we're cut off, call me back.
Yes, hello... It's you.
I thought it was Mrs Godarzi.
I told you not to call me.
I'll call you.
Godarzi calls me about work.
So why have you brought me
all the way up here?
I'm sorry, go ahead.
Really? When?
I can't be there.
Tell them you couldn't reach me.
How is she? Better?
Hello, are you well, father?
I'm listening. I'll be home soon.
I've bought it for you. It's red.
Put mother on.
I have to talk to her.
Listen, firstly I'm sorry.
Then, my condolences.
If someone asks for me,
say you couldn't reach me.
They don't know I've hired
a cell-phone.
I'll be back
for the seventh day of mourning.
I promise I'll be there.
Don't talk to me like that.
This is the wrong time.
All right. Is there anything else?
Take care.
Hello.
Why aren't you singing now?
You sing so well.
Go on, keep singing.
I dare not.
But why?
You're down there and I'm here.
We can't look each other in the eye.
I can't see you.
I can see you.
What are you doing down there?
I'm digging a well.
You don't dig wells on hills.
- I'm digging a ditch.
- Why a ditch?
For telecommunications.
Why are you alone?
Working alone makes things simple.
It's good, you don't have a boss.
What's that behind you?
Turn round...
To the left,
the one you touched.
Careful you don't break it.
Try to free it. Pull it out.
Toss it up to me.
He was tall!
It's your size.
Is it the left leg or the right?
It's a leg bone. It's not a shoe.
Are you well, Mrs Godarzi?
Thank you, you're very kind...
It's very difficult reaching you.
It was the same in Tehran,
always engaged.
Yes... We're ready.
Yes, they're ready too...
Everyone's ready.
Yes, if you don't mind,
when you call,
you have to wait a few minutes
until I drive up to higher ground.
Yes, that very place.
Yes, yes. All right.
Don't mention it...
Thank you... Good-bye.
Behzad... Behzad.
Hello.
Are you well?
- Why are you here?
- I've come to see you.
How did you know I was here?
When I brought the bread,
I asked Mim Kharaman,
"Where's Behzad?"
She said,
"He took a towel and went out."
You weren't down near the spring.
I tried the other side
but you weren't there either.
You weren't at the spring.
How can you cross?
There's a bridge.
You don't ask how I am?
Where were you?
We've had no news from you.
Nothing!
I work in the fields.
You're always working
or at school.
Or sleeping.
Mind you don't fall.
- You call that a bridge?
- Yes.
Your personal bridge?
All the children use it.
- How are you?
- Okay.
How's the invalid?
Who?
You still ask who?
It's obvious.
- Oh, Mrs Malek?
- Yes.
She didn't eat the soup
from Mash Hajer and the others.
How many cooks does she have?
They're not her cooks.
The soup is an offering.
All right.
Why?
If the invalid
eats one particular soup
the maker's wish will come true.
Do you have a wish too?
I have one, yes:
to pass my exams.
I have another one too.
What is it?
I want Mrs Malek to get better.
- To get better?
- Yes.
Can you find us some milk
for breakfast?
I don't have any cattle.
I'm alone.
Tell Farzad to fetch you some.
I don't understand...
Ask the boy, he'll fetch you some.
We're in the country,
we'd like to consume local produce.
I don't have any.
I don't have any milk or cattle.
I have a lot of work.
Where are the people?
Yesterday,
walking around the village,
I only saw children and old people.
The young men work the land.
They're farmers.
No one's idle here.
The old people and children
stay in the village.
Where are the young people?
I just told you:
they're working the land.
The corn and barley
are ready for harvesting.
The young people work
for three months.
In winter, they don't work.
They earn their living
over three months.
In winter,
they sit around drinking tea.
There's not a lot to do in winter.
Apparently, they're not that idle!
No, they do nothing.
They sit around the stove
for warmth.
They spend evenings together.
Certain produce is sown in winter...
And harvested in summer.
I don't know.
Your harvest will soon be ripe.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
How many children do you have?
Nine.
Well done, nine children!
Yes.
How many girls and how many boys?
Five girls and four boys.
See, you're not idle!
May God preserve them.
Thank you.
You don't want to get up?
We have to get up?
You don't want to?
Is there any news?
News, but not what you think.
But there is something.
She didn't eat the soup
sent by Mrs Hatcher and Mrs Terayn.
Meaning what?
Meaning...
Hold the line.
I'll go up the hill.
If we're cut off, call me back.
I can't call you.
Hello. Are you well, Mrs Godarzi?
Sorry, it takes a few minutes
to reach the high ground.
You can't foresee that.
One day she's well,
the next she isn't.
Her condition varies.
We're all waiting. We have to wait.
She has company.
Her son has come a long way.
He's waiting like us.
When will we be back?
In a couple of days maybe.
Good-bye.
I knew that warm voice
belonged to a warm-hearted man.
Hello. How are you?
It's deep!
Three metres, as stated
in the contract with the engineer.
I think you may be right.
Working alone is better.
It's harder...
but there are advantages.
- Do you understand me?
- No.
I mean that no one bothers you.
A boss. You don't have a boss.
Yeah?
He comes and disturbs us.
She brought me some milk.
There.
Do you want me to give you some?
No, thank you kindly.
She brought it for you.
I think Farhad dug Biston
on his own.
Do you know him?
Yes. He's a local,
he lives three miles away.
A local? Well done.
But it wasn't Farhad
who dug Biston.
I know.
Who then?
It was love. The love of Shirin.
Bravo. You know love too.
A man without love cannot live.
How are you?
I'm okay.
Where are you going?
As usual,
we're going to eat strawberries.
- Where's Jahan?
- Sleeping, as usual.
You'll bring him back?
You know,
he doesn't eat strawberries.
Who called?
- Mrs Godarzi.
- What did she say?
Greetings. She wanted news.
What did you tell her?
Nothing, that it was progressing.
Progressing? What is?
Eating strawberries is work.
- She didn't want any?
- No.
The strawberries are better
in Tehran.
Fresh air, fresh milk.
I haven't seen any milk.
We're not allowed milk here.
He's right.
Don't be long. Don't go too far!
No, we're just here.
Good-bye.
I have bread for you.
Are you well?
Thank you. That's kind.
You're welcome.
- How are you?
- I'm okay.
How is she?
Who?
You still ask who?
She's well.
- She's well?
- Yes.
How do you know?
My mother went to see her.
And?
My mother says she's well.
Has she eaten or not?
Yesterday evening,
she took her a meal.
She didn't touch it.
My young uncle fed her.
He's fallen out with my mother.
They don't speak.
Why? He wanted to feed her?
No. They fell out a long time ago.
Why is he your "young uncle"?
- How many do you have?
- Three.
- Are the others older?
- Yes.
Bravo. Where are they?
One is in Ahwaz,
the other in Kermanshah
and I don't know
where the third one is.
Don't they visit their mother?
Yesterday evening,
my uncle told my mother
that his holidays were over.
But they've fallen out.
How did he tell her?
My uncle speaks to her
but my mother doesn't reply.
- The others aren't coming?
- No.
Yesterday, my uncle
told my mother
that he has to go back.
He's leaving then?
Yes.
What about us?
I don't know.
I have exams that I have to take.
Apart from you,
we don't have anyone here.
I don't know. I have exams.
All right, off you go.
I'll see what I'll do.
Thanks anyhow.
Good-bye.
Take care.
All right.
Hello.
Have a good day.
I've brought water from the spring.
Thank you. I've brought fresh bread.
Thank you very much.
Put it over there.
I'll put it here!
I'll get breakfast.
I'll go and wake my colleagues then.
Yesterday, I asked
your sister to bring us milk.
She probably forgot.
It was me.
No, I spoke to your sister.
No, it was me.
- It was you?
- Yes.
She was pregnant.
I was pregnant.
It was you?
Yes, in person.
Seriously!
Yes, I've had the baby
and I've come back here to work.
Where is it?
- Is that your baby?
- Yes.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
How many children do you have?
Ten.
Five girls and five boys.
Five boys and five girls... Bravo!
Thank you.
Tell me,
can the factory still produce more?
How should I know?
Give the milk to the baby first.
Don't worry about my colleagues.
Are you well, Mrs Godarzi?
Can you hear me?
I can hear you too.
Good day. How are you?
What can I say? We're all ready.
Everything's fine.
Listen... Up here...
Yes...
We're getting bored too but...
It seems to be the only solution.
There's no doubt about it.
It could be any day now,
we can't say...
She hasn't eaten for three days.
No, there's no doubt.
We just have to wait.
There's no other solution.
Can I ask a favour of you?
Lengthen the crew's mission.
I promised them...
No, probably not.
Don't worry.
Good-bye.
Isn't that ditch finished yet?
I've hit a rock.
Good luck.
I can see, in fact. I can hear.
We've reached a dead-end too.
You're lucky, you have a pickaxe.
We don't have one.
We can't do anything.
I can provide you with a pickaxe.
Our problem can't be solved
by a pickaxe.
If it could, things would be easier.
One blow of a pickaxe would do.
Instead of a pickaxe,
you can offer me some tea.
Please, help yourself.
If you give me
your Juliet's address,
I'll ask her to provide us
with milk.
In the village,
knock on any door
and they'll give you milk.
I didn't find any.
Even at the sea,
there's no water for me!
Can't I ask her for some?
No problem.
She's at Kakrahman's.
Go to the village...
You'll find her there.
Kakrahman's house...
Ask anyone,
they'll know where it is.
Get in.
I'm not disturbing you?
You're welcome.
Sorry.
- Are you well?
- Fine, thanks.
Sorry to disturb you.
You're welcome, it's my route.
I'll take you.
I often see you on this road.
- You're not a local?
- No.
You seem to have problems.
One problem!
In any case,
every affair has its own problems.
Anything over a hundred years old
is considered an antique.
What are you talking about?
You don't work underground?
Because of this bone, you think
we're looking for treasure
or antiques?
I don't think that.
I'm almost sure of it.
You haven't come for the ceremony?
The cat's out of the bag!
Our crew was joking with the kid.
They said
that we've come for treasure.
We didn't want people to know
why we're really here.
His family lives in the village.
It's a small village too.
That's why he believed it.
Later, we told him the secret.
When I was little, I felt the same.
Whenever someone told me a secret,
I always wanted to tell others.
And in the end, I would.
I think I enjoyed telling it
more than I enjoyed keeping it.
That's interesting.
You're an educated man.
What do you think of this ceremony?
How can I put it? It's painful.
There have been two lines
on my mother's face for years.
- Lines?
- Yes, lines.
You mean scars?
Yes, scars.
They are marked during the ceremony.
The first scar
was for the death of my aunt.
My poor mother did it
to show her love to my father.
The second,
was for the boss of the factory
where my father worked.
One of his cousins had died.
So that my father
wouldn't lose his job,
my mother mourned a great deal.
She scratched her face.
I couldn't believe it.
There was a lot of competition
at the factory
between the men to hold
onto their jobs.
Need and necessity, you see?
Everyone played along.
There was a great deal of pressure.
They all needed work.
No question of showing pity
or giving in,
everyone displayed themselves,
pushed themselves forward
to please the boss.
Each wanted to show that he grieved
more than the others.
That he was with him.
That he was loyal...
That kind of thing
doesn't interest me.
When I think about it,
it's painful.
Let me tell you...
I think the origins of this ceremony
are bound to the economy.
What I just told you is engraved
in their memories. It has been
for years and for generations now.
You look on it from the outside.
It may interest you.
But personally...
May I get out here?
- Where are you going?
- To school, this way.
I'll drop you.
I'll see Farzad too.
He has exams,
I'll see what he's done.
Sir, thank you.
Thank you again. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
- Are those the exam papers?
- Yes.
- Don't be too harsh on them.
- I'm not.
Tell our little colleague
to come and see me.
Excuse me!
- What?
- Please do me a favour.
Don't tell Farzad
what we were just saying.
All right. Don't worry.
Go on, get in the other side.
Hurry up, get in.
- I can't come now.
- Why?
I need one more answer for the exam.
What is it?
The fourth question.
- You don't know the answer?
- No.
Why?
Because I don't.
What was it?
"What happens to the Good and Evil
"on Judgement Day?"
That's obvious.
The Good go to hell
and the Evil to heaven.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
No. The Good go to heaven,
the Evil go to hell.
Hurry in and write that,
then come back.
Off you go.
Help yourself to tea if you want.
What?
- You want some too?
- No, not for me.
Do you want tea?
No.
You're a coward if you come back.
Hello, Tajdolat.
May your wish come true. Mother says
the invalid ate the soup.
Put the bowl over there.
Hello, Farzad.
- Are you well?
- Yes.
- Where are you going?
- To school.
- I'll go with you.
- Come on.
Good-bye.
Did the exams go well?
Yes.
- How's the invalid?
- Well.
- Well?
- Yes.
Yesterday evening, she ate
Tajdolat's soup.
Tajdolat? The serving woman?
Yes. She ate it all.
- Have there been other signs?
- Yes.
She's speaking!
She's speaking?
Come and sit here a minute.
What do you mean, she's speaking?
My grandmother spoke to my uncle
yesterday evening.
She recognised him.
Then she asked for news
of the family...
My uncle wept.
He asked my mother,
"Am I a bad son?"
My mother said, "No you're not bad.
"You're just very busy."
Then they made up.
He said he was leaving
for Kermanshah
to ask for leave, then he'd be back.
Fancy that! He's left then.
Can you answer me frankly?
Yes.
Do you think I'm bad?
No.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
How can you be sure?
I know.
You're good.
Well, since I'm good,
can you get me a bowl
to fetch milk?
When I go to the fields,
I'll find one.
I want it now.
It will only take two minutes.
I'm late.
I have to go.
That lady will find you one.
Go on.
Mim Hamideh, hello.
Do you have a milk bowl
for the engineer?
Yes, by the window.
All right.
She says to bring the bowl back.
I have to go.
Off you go.
May God give you pride.
May God give you good health.
May God give you a long life.
- Excuse me.
- Don't mention it.
- Are you well?
- Yes, thank you.
Is Kakrahman's house here?
What do you want? Milk?
Yes, please.
I'd be grateful for some fresh milk.
All right.
I'm disturbing you.
Don't worry.
- Are you well?
- Yes, thank you.
What a fine house.
Make yourself at home.
Is this Kakrahman's house?
No.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was told to get milk from him.
It's next door.
Where is Kakrahman's house?
Next door.
Sorry, I didn't understand.
It's next door.
Thank you very much.
Is this Kakrahman's house?
Welcome.
Good luck.
I was sent here for milk.
Can you give me some?
Go down to the cellar...
Watch your head.
This way?
Go on down. Mind your head.
All right.
Why is it so dark here?
There's a hurricane lamp,
it's not dark.
Is there someone down there?
Yes, Miss Zeynab.
Zeynab, come here,
this gentleman needs milk.
It's so dark here.
Is anyone here?
Come in.
Can you milk the cow for me?
Wait, I'll do it.
It's so dark.
How can you milk in here?
I'm used to it. I work here.
You'll get used to it if you stay.
I'll be gone
before I get used to it.
We have a flashlight.
The electricity is off.
"If you come to my house..."
What?
"Oh, kind one, bring me the lamp
"and a window through which
"I can watch the crowd
in the happy street."
What?
Nothing, it was a poem.
How old are you?
Sixteen.
Sixteen. Have you been to school?
Yes.
- For how long?
- Five years.
Five years.... That's good.
Do you know Forough?
Yes.
- Who is she?
- Gohar's daughter.
No, the one I'm talking about
is a poet.
What's your name?
Can't you tell me?
It doesn't matter.
Okay, I'll recite a poem to you.
It will occupy us while you milk.
You won't answer me?
Go ahead.
I was saying that...
"In my night, so brief, alas
"The wind
is about to meet the leaves."
Do you understand that?
The two are meeting.
It's like when you went
to see Yossef.
At the well.
At the well?
Bravo.
"My night so brief is filled
with devastating anguish.
"Hark!
"Do you hear the whisper
of the shadows?"
Do you understand the shadows?
That means darkness.
"This happiness
feels foreign to me.
"I am accustomed to despair.
"Hark! Do you hear the whisper
of the shadows?
"There, in the night,
something is happening.
"The moon is red and anxious.
"And, clinging to this roof
that could collapse at any moment,
"The clouds, like a crowd
of mourning women,
"Await the birth of the rain,
"One second, and then nothing.
"Behind this window,
the night trembles,
"And the earth stops spinning.
"Behind this window, a stranger
"Worries about you and me.
"You, in your greenery,
"Lay your hands
- those burning memories -
"On my loving hands
"And entrust your lips,
replete with life's warmth,
"To the touch of my loving lips."
It's full.
"The wind will carry us."
The bowl is full.
Yes, yes...
"The wind will carry us!"
I'm one of Yossef's friends.
In fact, I'm his boss.
Thank you very much.
Raise the lamp
so I can see your face.
I haven't seen Yossef,
so at least let me know his taste.
You won't tell me your name
and you won't let me see your face.
At least light the ground
so I don't trip up.
How long did she study?
Who?
That woman whose poem you recited.
Forough?
I think she was in school
until the fourth or fifth year.
You know, writing poetry
has nothing to do with diplomas.
If you have talent,
you can do it too.
How much do I owe you?
Don't mention it.
Thank you very much.
Pay my mother.
Don't mention it.
Good-bye.
Good luck.
How much do I owe you?
Three hundred tomans.
- Here.
- You're welcome.
Thank you again.
Good-bye.
Why did you take the money?
Go and give it back to him.
He wanted to pay.
Sir...
You're our honoured guest.
No. Keep it.
Thank you very much.
Really.
You honour us.
Thank you again.
Each of us has a commitment.
I have one too, to my family.
I've come here to work too.
Listen,
don't confuse work and family.
We have to know, give or take a day,
when we'll finally return to Tehran.
You said it would happen
in the first three days.
You said, "Next week."
And then nothing happened.
Two weeks and still nothing!
- And now?
- I promise, within three days.
What if it doesn't happen?
She seems to be better now.
Her son left yesterday.
If she'd been in a bad way,
he wouldn't have left.
How do you know that?
We just know.
It's not something
you can hide from us.
She's better, this is useless.
You say that you know
but you know nothing.
First of all, her son
is a guard at Kermanshah.
He's gone back to warn his boss.
It's 45 miles away.
He can be back in a day.
If we want to go to Tehran,
it's 450 miles away.
450 miles, understand?
We have to go to Tehran.
450 miles in one day!
We didn't say we'd come back...
If no one decides for us,
we have to decide for ourselves.
I can't decide for you.
You decide.
I can't decide.
God's the one who decides.
Who drew up this shooting?
I can't strangle her!
What am I supposed to do?
We're not asking you
to strangle her.
What then?
How much longer
do we have to stay here?
What if the event never occurs?
And what if it does?
That means you're in contact
with God or the Angel of Death.
Who are you in contact with?
We can't stay here like this.
Who's to say that within a week...
I have a feeling
it'll happen in the next three days.
You keep repeating the same thing!
Look, Keyvan,
you know what?
Give me three days. Just three.
Perhaps it will happen.
- And what if it doesn't?
- Let's say it will.
We're wasting time.
Can't you plan things?
Plan things? No, I can't do that.
We say the same thing.
If you can't do it, who can?
Only God can.
If it happens, we shoot our report
and return to Tehran.
All right. We just need to know
what to do.
Say it takes three months...
- Behzad.
- Yes.
I've brought you bread.
Put it over there.
Listen, kid,
can't you hold your tongue?
I can.
Who told you to talk
about her son leaving?
I can't lie.
It's not a matter of lying.
Who asked you to lie?
They asked where my uncle was.
I said that he'd left.
They asked how he was
and you said he'd left.
We don't want anything
from your uncle.
They asked me.
I said that he had left.
They asked how she was.
It wasn't about your uncle.
Have they taught you anything
at school?
Yes.
You don't give an answer
until you're asked a question.
Yes, I've been taught that.
I don't want any more bread.
You understand?
If you have good news, come here.
If not, don't bother coming back!
All right.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Put the bread down there and go.
Hello, engineer.
My mother wants to know
if you want the milk cold or hot.
Warm it up.
Good day.
There's nothing more to say,
Mrs Godarzi.
As I told you before.
No, it's the same.
What?
No, we don't know what to do.
What does that mean?
That's impossible, Mrs Godarzi.
That means...
we pretend that we've done nothing
for two weeks.
Put him on, I want to talk to him...
I want to talk to him...
At least give him my message.
I simply can't do that.
No. Why do they want the material?
No, answer me.
Why do they want the material?
We don't want to use it as a pillow.
Yes...
In any case, that's impossible.
It sounds as if we're guilty!
I'll contact him myself.
I'll call... Good-bye.
Hello, are you well?
- Yes, thank you.
- What do you want?
Can I have a word with Farzad?
Sohrabi?
Yes.
He's sitting an exam.
I know. It won't take a minute.
Please call him for me.
Sohrabi!
You're wanted.
Are you well?
Yes.
Are you sitting an exam?
Is there a question
that you can't answer?
No, I know them all.
I want to apologise
about this morning.
Do you remember the first day
when you asked
if the car wasn't working?
I answered, "It's given up
the ghost." Do you remember?
That day, we were driving uphill.
The car gave up the ghost.
Yes.
It had worked too hard
and gave up the ghost.
Yes.
What did I say?
A car, just like men,
can give up the ghost.
And I'll say it again now...
Men, like machines,
can give up the ghost.
Right?
You haven't worked this morning.
You're not tired.
Yes, but...
you know that's not always the case.
Sometimes, when you're idle,
you give up the ghost.
You understand?
You go crazy doing nothing.
You blow your top!
All right, forget it, it's over.
Let's be friends again.
Shake my hand.
Shake my hand...
If you can hear me, hold the line.
I'm going higher up.
Hold the line.
I'll see you later.
Come on, Behzad.
Forget the cemetery,
come and eat some strawberries...
Hold the line.
I'm listening...
Hello.
He told you that?
Did you give him my message?
Did you repeat my very words?
Unfortunately, I can't do anything.
Yes...
No...
Good-bye...
Sir...
One of your neighbours
is buried alive.
Go and help him...
Where?
Up there, in the cemetery.
Sir...
One of your neighbours
is buried alive.
Where?
Up there, in the cemetery.
Yes. Help him if you can.
A shovel... Take it and go.
It will help.
I don't have one.
Sir! Sir!
Have you seen my friends anywhere?
They bought three baskets
of strawberries and went.
Three baskets of strawberries?
Where did they go?
Up there somewhere.
Run...
Run, Farzad. Come on, get in.
I'm in a hurry. Get in.
- Hello. Okay?
- Yes.
- Did you sit your exam?
Get in, let's go.
No, I'll walk.
You're still mad at me?
I apologised.
- Come on, get in.
- No, I'll walk.
I'm going up.
Don't you want to come?
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Have you seen my colleagues?
- Yes, they went that way.
Which way? Over the hill? Where?
I don't know.
They went through that gate.
- Towards the hill?
- I have no idea.
- Did they have the gear?
- They had their bags.
- Thank you.
- May God preserve you.
Farzad, I'm going up the hill.
Want to come?
No, I'm not coming,
I'm going to the fields.
Come on, get in...
No. I'm going to the farm.
- Come on, I'll bring you back.
- No.
Why haven't you got out?
Go on, get out.
Take the wheel.
Give my colleagues the keys.
Don't forget.
Will he make it, doctor?
Yes, he just needed oxygen.
Ajab and a respirator
will put him right.
We've sent him to town.
Oxygen will save him.
- Where are you going?
- Down there.
There's a sick woman.
Perhaps you could see her.
All right.
- Do you mind?
- No, no problem.
It's a miracle he survived.
He was lucky.
The stone got stuck
before it struck his head.
Then some stones gave way.
He was trapped,
as if he was in a tiny cell.
He needed oxygen.
If he gets oxygen,
he'll pull through all right.
He was covered in dirt.
"If my guardian angel
is the one I know,
"he'll protect glass from stone."
Yes, that's a fine poem.
So the "glass" remained intact?
Yes, it remained intact.
He'll be saved.
- Doctor, do you mind if I smoke?
- No, you should mind.
- What?
- You should mind.
Not me. It's no concern of mine
if you smoke.
The air is so pure here.
It'll take more than your cigarette
to pollute it.
I only measure my strength
with my lungs.
If you're in good health, carry on.
Doctor, what's your speciality?
I don't have one. That way,
I look after the whole body.
If I specialised,
I'd be limited.
You must have
a lot of patients then.
Almost no one.
I have to ride around,
looking at nature's beauty,
calling on people,
doing the odd circumcision,
giving jabs,
piercing ears, etc.
If I'm no use to others,
at least I make the most of life.
I observe nature.
Observing nature is better
than playing backgammon.
Or doing nothing.
This is the place, doctor.
Idleness leads to corruption.
Well, well, it's our invalid!
She's my friend.
She's as old as Methuselah.
Hello, are you well?
It's been a while!
I have things to do.
I'll come back. Are you staying?
You haven't seen my colleagues?
No.
Madam.
You left the baby!
I went to fetch you some milk.
You haven't seen my colleagues?
No. I only saw them this morning.
This morning.
And this afternoon?
- Did they have the gear?
- No, they had nothing.
I've prescribed her some pills.
Give them to her
to ease the pain.
We don't have a car
to get to the chemist's.
Give her medicine.
There's none left.
What's the matter?
It's her prescription.
Whose?
The invalid's.
The old woman? I'll fetch it.
Can you drop me off?
Yes, of course.
Good-bye. Drive safely.
I'm like a general without an army.
Where do you want to go?
I'm going to the hospital.
Are you worried about your car
or about the victim?
What do you think?
I think that before we get there,
the victim will be up and gone.
No, I beg of you,
give her the medication.
They're painkillers.
Two tablets in the morning
and two at night,
dissolved in water.
You said two in the morning
and two at night?
Yes.
When you go to the chemist's,
you have to be very determined
or they won't give you everything.
Is it hard to come by?
That's not the issue.
Chemists are like that.
She's suffering, poor thing.
We can't do anything.
Let her take this and sleep.
Doctor, what's wrong with her?
Oh, excuse me a second.
Speak louder. It's windy.
I can't hear you.
How do you know?
I said, how do you know?
I can't hear. Speak louder.
We were cut off.
You were saying, doctor...
What's wrong with her?
Nothing,
she's just old and weak.
She's just a bag of bones
and she's not very well at all.
Old age is a terrible illness.
Yes, but there are worse illnesses.
Death...
- Death?
- Yes.
Death is the worst.
When you close your eyes
on this world,
this beauty, the wonders of nature
and the generosity of God,
it means
you'll never be coming back.
They say that the other world
is more beautiful.
But...
who has come back from there
to tell us
if it's beautiful or not?
"They tell me she is as beautiful
as a houri from heaven!
"Yet I say
"That the juice of the vine
is better.
"Prefer the present
to these fine promises.
"Even a drum sounds melodious
from afar...
"Prefer the present..."
Hello.
Director and editor:
Abbas KIAROSTAMI
Photography:
Mahmoud KALARI
Sound:
Jahangir MIRSHEKARI
Screenplay:
Abbas KIAROSTAMI
Based on an idea by:
Mahmoud AYDIN
Music:
Peyman YAZDANIAN
Produced by:
Marin KARMITZ - Abbas KIAROSTAMI
With: Behzad DOURANI
English subtitles: Ian Burley
Processed by C.M.C. - Paris