The city is shocked
by the missing baby cases.
Within three months,
18 babies have gone missing.
No findings have been reported
by the police.
The police commissioner...
We've arrived in no time.
Please stop! Yeah.
Here I am!
Something's wrong.
Oh, no! Damn!
Forget it.
Be careful.
Look!
Very stylish architecture.
Let's go inside.
This way please.
This house is elegant,
and there are no other houses
within 1,000 meters.
Only five minutes' drive
to grocery stores.
-So many pros, what are the cons?
-Of course there are some.
But it's not that bad.
The only con is...
There's not much decoration.
That's how you put it?
But the structure is fine.
There was just a little fire.
Let me show you something.
You can hear the birds sing!
After you move in, you will love it more.
What do you think?
Damn!
I asked the owner to have it renovated
before listing it.
Now my time is wasted. Shoot!
I'm lucky!
God, now no one will buy this!
-Let's go!
-Don't move!
Darling, buy this house. I like it.
It has character.
Character? Really?
You know what kind of house I like.
I know.
Then make a deposit first.
Quiet.
Tried to steal my car? You do it yourself.
Yes, I'll do it myself.
Wow, that's incredible!
Of course, my husband is a cop.
Move!
I am.
Eighteen babies have gone missing
in the past two months.
It looks like the work of one person.
So far, no missing baby's family
has received a blackmail letter.
Nor has any political or terrorist group
claimed responsibility.
Commander, these cases are so strange.
Shall we approach Wonder Woman?
Though she helped us before,
we still don't know who she is.
We can't reach her after all.
All missing babies are male. I think
it has nothing to do with blackmail.
NEXT ONE...
Hey...
Maybe it has to do with a cult.
Did you see anyone rushing out?
No.
Commander!
YOUR CHILD WILL BE NEXT
Come with me.
Nursery is upstairs.
Operating room over there.
I'm worried about our son.
Let's take him home now.
Lau!
The doctor doesn't recommend for us
to bring our newborn baby home so soon.
-Lau...
-All right! Leave him here.
Why not call Wonder Woman for help?
Sorry, we have no way to contact her.
I've sent more men here.
It makes no difference to have
the baby at home or leave him here.
-Please watch my wife.
-Yes, sir.
A bus just got into an accident.
The beds in this ward might be needed.
We were alerted about it.
Stay here, Lau. You can go.
Lau, it's my son they're after.
What about
swapping the baby?
Using whose baby to swap?
That's too immoral, right?
It's your son they want,
they will find him anyway.
Yes, if others find out about the swap,
it'd be no good.
Let's face it.
Face it...
Sorry. Officer Lau said no one's allowed
to enter without his permission.
All right, then!
What's wrong?
Babies are falling down!
Catch them!
My son!
Catch our son!
Which is our son?
Either one!
Which one?
Wonder Woman!
She's coming down.
Its blood was left on the wall.
Go get it tested.
The baby is not ours!
It's a baby girl.
A girl? It's my daughter!
Thank God she's okay.
I was terrified.
-Get somebody to collect the blood sample.
-Yes, sir. Come with me.
-Hello?
-Tung, another baby is missing.
I'll be home late tonight.
-All right.
-Are you upset?
No. Go do your job.
You just love to fight.
I'll chop your head off next time.
Guard the door.
Master, here is the baby boy you want.
Take the 19th prince inside,
together with other princes.
Yes, Master.
San.
Your heart is beating too fast.
Not quite.
Memory does you no good.
You can't have feelings and emotions.
I don't have any.
I'll wait for the next propitious day.
And among the babies,
I'll choose one to be the King.
China must have a King.
Either you climb up by yourself
or you fall down! No one can help you!
Climb up!
Ching, climb up!
Don't fall down! Climb!
Another nightmare?
May I come in?
I'm working.
You know I don't like to be disturbed.
I've been dreaming of
the invisible suit in the past few years.
Last night, I dreamt it finally worked
under the sun.
Has it always been kept in the safe?
Yes. Why?
The police called today.
They asked me how one could be invisible.
They wanted my opinion.
Before the invisible suit is finished,
you don't want others to know about it.
I want to keep it a secret forever.
Because this invention
may easily be used as a weapon of war.
Then what is the purpose of
this invisible suit to you?
When I'm glued to my work,
I feel happy.
Aren't you worried that I might steal it?
No!
People don't steal from themselves.
You want some coffee?
Yes, please.
Miss.
The dates of birth of
those 18 babies you gave me...
Are they related in any way?
Strange.
They all have a royal destiny.
All destined to be emperor!
Emperor?
Who would want to snatch
so many little emperors?
Sister!
You want some? Come over, then.
Come on.
Are you talking to me?
No.
Sister, may I kiss you?
Why are you smiling?
Am I? Not really.
Go down!
Go over there!
Oh, God! Who are they, Lau?
Three armed robbers with records
just robbed a armored vehicle.
They were chased to this chemical plant.
Eight hostages inside,
including the driver and the guard.
So, what do we do?
-We'll force them out.
-Give me one!
Get ready!
Fire!
Don't panic, they're only tear bombs.
Wear a mask!
Come out!
Damn! Get out!
Give me the gun.
-Don't shoot!
-Listen, you all!
There are many more hostages inside.
Get me a helicopter within two hours
or I'll kill one every five minutes.
Good morning, everybody!
Who's she?
Professional shooter, Chat.
Sir, don't call me that.
I only kill those that deserve it.
Call me Thief Catcher.
The police won't hire you.
Hire?
Sir, I'll do you a favor this time.
It's free!
Get them!
I surrender! Don't shoot!
Rescue the hostages.
Come on.
Take them over there.
Check if there are others.
Go.
I'm married.
Stupid.
Looks like I'm the only one
who can get your son back.
Pay me 500 thousand if found alive,
150 thousand
if you don't mind that he's dead.
I only take gold. Call me if interested.
My phone number!
The one who used the newspaper
to place the ad wasn't here for babies.
-Put everyone on alert.
-Yes, sir.
Mrs. Lau, you may go.
Please show me your pass.
What brings you here tonight?
I promised the head nurse
to come help every week.
The old lady upstairs...
Won't do physiotherapy
until you come, right?
So you know.
I'm so busy,
I'm afraid I can't take care of you.
-Be careful.
-You, too.
You're the one who placed the ad?
You're a cop?
Listen.
I'm going to kill all babies tonight.
What are you doing?
No!
Stay away, or I'll kill her!
Calm down!
Drop that or I'll kill her!
You drop it first.
I'll kill her.
Okay, I drop it.
Go inside!
I'll kill her!
Those doctors killed my son.
This is revenge!
-I'll kill all the babies.
-Dr. Wong, please come to the ER.
Dr. Wong, please come to the...
I'll kill all the babies!
You're bleeding! Wipe it off.
I'm fine.
You think we can break down the door?
No way. It's so thick.
Let me try.
The keys are just outside.
I almost can get them.
Keep cool.
The lunatic won't be back that fast.
I'm only worried about the babies.
You heard what he said just now?
Let me try.
Why don't you go?
Roger.
Stay calm. Speak slowly.
-One person only?
-Yes.
Why are you so late? Are you a new guy?
-Take him outside.
-Yes.
Don't move! Get up!
I won't leave any babies alive!
Honey!
I've subdued the lunatic.
-I know.
-Thanks for informing me in time.
-I didn't come for nothing.
-Come.
-Any reward?
-No!
-Don't keep the old lady waiting.
-I'm coming.
Naughty! Laughing at me?
Are you going home with me?
No. The real one hasn't turned up yet.
What?
Why so surprised?
You're so nosy.
I'll take you out for a ride!
Let's go.
Officer Lau, a baby was taken.
Don't shoot! The baby might be there!
Don't shoot! Attention, don't shoot!
I'm leaving!
Go after her!
The Thief Catcher?
Stay awake.
There's more fun to come.
Isn't it fun?
So there you are. Catch me!
Take a rest first.
Can't believe it! Lagging behind!
What a shame!
So sinister. Not even a noise?
A woman.
A bitch!
Hey. Hey.
Stop. Stop. Stop!
Tell me, why did you steal so many babies?
What? You blame me for that?
You look pretty smart.
So you're Wonder Woman?
-And you're Thief Catcher?
-Don't get in my way, then.
How can you use the baby as bait?
How despicable!
That's enough!
Put the baby down first.
Let's see if you can make me!
That was just a warm-up. Ready now?
Wait...
What is it?
The invisible thing?
Something else is here?
It seems to be on my side.
The baby!
Be careful!
How's the baby?
Wait, who are you?
Everything's fine now.
All right, don't try my patience!
Who are you?
Let's go, Chat!
San, it's you?
Let's go! Don't pull me.
I can walk on my own.
Hello? I suspect it was
the Thief Catcher you hired.
How do you know?
Ask her to bring the baby back at once!
Call the doctor.
-How's the baby?
-Save him!
You can count on me!
To the ER!
Doctor, how's the baby?
Sorry, it's too late.
-Call the parents.
-Yes, sir.
Ching, don't go!
Master hates dummies like me.
I'll miss you!
Take care of yourself.
Don't cry.
Ching!
Let her go!
Kneel down.
Tung, you must stay here
and finish the task
that I want you both to do by yourself.
You're going to uphold justice for me.
On your own.
Tung, why are you crying?
I'm not.
Tell me why.
It's nothing.
How's the case today?
The stolen baby fell and died.
It's been 10 years. You're still great.
Where did that monster
get the invisible suit?
He has orders to steal more babies.
Will you interfere?
No, thanks.
When I escaped from that cave,
you spared me after you caught me.
Now I take good care of myself.
Why did he snatch so many babies?
He'll choose one to be King
during the next sun eclipse.
And the rest of the babies
will become killers, like us?
Master will turn them like our generation.
San, do them a favor.
Simply kill them.
For three years,
that monster corrupted me.
After I escaped from him,
I spent 10 years returning to normal.
I don't want all babies becoming monsters.
Pretend that you know nothing.
Don't interfere.
If Master gives the order,
I'll kill you as well.
Then do it now!
You won't be lucky next time!
Can I pretend that I know nothing?
You're not Ching anymore.
From now on, you are San.
Get the invisible suit within 10 days
and kill the doctor.
Do it or die.
What are you doing?
It's dangerous in here. Leave, please!
What's so dangerous?
You're always in here.
Are you keeping something from me?
What don't you know?
The invisible suit belongs to me, too.
Yet I didn't know
that it can stand UV light.
No, it still can't.
If it can, you'll be
the first one to know.
What have you been working on
the past few days?
I'm working on this plant.
They were dead before,
but they're alive again.
Any flowers?
Yes. In a month's time.
Ching.
Will you put them under the sun everyday
and water them at night for me?
Lucky stars.
You taught me how to make them.
You shall see the flowers bloom.
Get the invisible suit within 10 days
and kill the doctor.
Do it or die.
Your men detained me for over two hours!
Don't blame me for that.
It was an accident.
Accident? The baby died because of you!
What? I didn't push the baby down.
It's all Wonder Woman's fault.
You may go now.
But don't fool yourself.
Don't make a scapegoat of me!
Okay, I'll keep an eye on it.
Mainly keep an eye on my son, miss.
Don't worry, I'll help my client.
-Thank you.
-I'm asking for trouble.
Well done.
Why are there so many bird cages?
Oh, no! This will alert the monster.
Hey!
Damn. I took a needle.
Let's see how long you can survive.
Do you know who the female intruder was?
No.
I have someone in mind.
But she should have died 10 years ago.
Right!
I killed Chat myself.
Now only Wonder Woman could get in.
She's been meddling with our plan.
She's probably the intruder.
Let me kill her, Master.
Leave such things to others.
Kau.
Kill the woman.
And if necessary, die with her.
You monster.
I won't let the poison get to my brain!
This case is not related
to the previous cases.
We promised the mayor
that it wouldn't happen again.
Here's your deposit!
What deposit?
I quit your son's case.
We'll talk later. I'm in a meeting.
No! There's nothing to talk about.
You must have known something.
For the babies' sake, please tell us.
What's the point of telling you?
If you could handle it,
you wouldn't have to hire me.
-For justice, you...
-To hell with justice!
I almost got killed!
You got the child killed!
Tell me what you know.
You think I'll listen to you?
You will.
When that doll fell down just now,
you saved it without a second thought.
Yes, I killed the baby.
But I'm dying, too.
Let's call it even!
Won't you leave me alone?
I only want to die peacefully here.
I want to know who snatched the babies.
Don't hurt the Invisible Woman!
She's only a puppet.
That old monster!
I won't let his needle kill me!
Don't do that!
Go away before I lose my mind.
No.
You'll die!
If it's for a good reason, it's okay.
I can only block the needle for now.
But I can't get it out.
Okay. I'll help you
to get the babies back.
If we are to succeed,
we must get San to help us.
-The Invisible Woman?
-Yes.
We must be careful.
Because the monster found me
entering his cave last time.
He thought I was you.
So, he's sent Kau to get you.
Officer Lau, a madman's holding
hostages in the train station.
He's destroyed the computer system, too.
A cargo train is speeding
toward the station now.
-When will the train hit the station?
-In about five minutes.
I've got it.
All units get ready.
Watch out for the mines!
Don't step on it!
Don't move!
Watch out! There are mines!
Go now!
The train will crash in one minute.
Get inside!
Save the hostages in there first!
Why don't you go?
Run!
Watch out! It's crashing!
I got it.
Go to hell!
Run!
Run! Go!
Supervisor, how can we stop the train?
The computer system has been destroyed.
We can't stop it now! Run!
LEE RIVER
CHAK FUNG
Run! The train is here!
Catch it!
Let's go!
Honey.
What did the doctor say?
If you're lucky,
you could walk within six months.
Otherwise?
Otherwise...
You may become a cripple.
Cheer up.
As Wonder Woman's husband,
I'll stand by you.
When did you find out?
At the station,
when you looked at me,
unwilling to go in.
No more snickering from now on
and no more hidden tears.
Just tell me everything.
Okay?
Oh, darling.
Hey! There are flower buds!
What's wrong? Sit down.
No, I just got a clue.
I must write it down now!
Sit down first.
Get out now!
How long have you known this?
I've known it since I started
working on the invisible suit.
I discovered that it emitted toxins.
So I've always told you
to stay out of here.
But the plant have buds now.
That means I'll be all right.
Come on, get out of here.
We're partners.
How can I leave you like this?
Where are my glasses?
You're wearing them.
I will not die
before the suit is completed.
I can smell the fragrance of your hair.
Let's look at the flowers outside.
I'll be all right.
You get out of here!
Let me in!
I'll stay even if you can get in.
The suit will be ready
when the flowers bloom.
You've promised
to take care of them till then.
Did you forget?
San.
You still go to see that monster?
You think he will let the doctor live?
He'll kill him once the suit is completed.
You're poisoned by his needles?
If you help us,
Wonder Woman and I can kill him.
If you fear death, how can you help her?
I won't thank you anyway.
You saved my life.
But to protect the doctor,
you let that monster control you.
You know you've harmed so many babies.
You can deceive others, but not yourself.
Wonder Woman can help you now.
See you at the same spot tomorrow.
I'll wait till you come.
You have to come.
I can't wait, hurry up.
I've done it!
Ching. Ching!
Ching!
Lucky star.
Ching, I've completed the invisible suit.
Why you still haven't got that suit?
It doesn't work under the sun yet.
Without it, the King's army
may be weakened.
It will soon be finished.
Give the doctor a few more days.
Get it anyway
before tomorrow's sunset.
Kau will help you then.
Master, in your plan,
all my work is so inconsequential.
If I find a King among those babies,
you'll be honored for your services.
All princes should be asleep.
You should go to sleep, too.
The 18th of September.
Today,
I finally solved the UV light problem.
But it's the end of my life, too.
From the first working day,
I knew I would die of toxins.
If Ching weren't here,
I wouldn't be able to face my life.
If she knows that I only hope
to take her hands
and see the blooming flowers with her,
will she still kill me?
The day will come soon.
Get the invisible suit anyway,
no matter what,
and kill the doctor!
Doctor, I'll never return to you.
I won't leave until I see you.
Believe me,
you are in great danger.
Leave the lab now.
Damn it!
Even Wonder Woman is late!
I shouldn't have said
I'd wait until she showed up.
Should I leave or not?
Great. You're here!
Master sent me to kill you.
Wait, San.
Go ahead. I won't let you go this time.
You can kill me without conscience?
I must execute Master's order.
But I can promise you
that I'll do you a favor after you die.
Wait! Maybe I'm not the one
who will get killed.
It could be you.
Tell me your last wish now!
-Take care of the doctor for me.
-The doctor?
Save the doctor for me.
San, what are you doing?
She's not coming to kill you.
She came to kill herself.
You give up your life to save him?
My life?
I am just a beast to kill.
A beast doesn't have feelings
or sacrifice itself for another.
Life is more meaningful than death,
if you can face yourself.
I simply can't face myself.
I can't face him, either.
San!
So you're all leaving?
Damn it! Can't you stand still?
My bike is better!
Wait for me!
San!
You can change yourself from now on?
So what? I'm still San!
You can be another Chat! Like her.
Too late! Leave me alone!
Shit! Even a bike can't catch up to them?
Go!
You've shunned the past.
So this is your true self!
Then I don't deserve to live!
No!
Oh, God!
You two are in great trouble.
How lucky. Brace yourselves!
Tung?
Ching?
Let go of my hand, or we'll both fall!
No!
Grab it!
I can't hold on any longer!
I won't let go! We must stay together.
It's you!
You two knew each other?
I don't remember.
The past is not important.
What's important is the thing
you want to do now.
So tell me, what do you want to do?
Master sent Kau to kill the doctor.
I need to go save him.
The doctor?
Give it to me.
The invisible suit is UV light-proof now.
Nobody can find it.
No!
Ching.
I want to tell you a lot of things.
It's all inside the gift box.
No matter how hard you hit, it's useless.
He won't quit till he gets what he wants.
No!
You can't give it to him.
I've got nothing left.
I can't let him die.
Sorry.
I know Master can't make you kill me.
It's not that easy!
Wait...
Idiot, here's the tape.
Come and get it!
Goodbye!
It's too hot to stay here.
San, it's better
to have this thing destroyed.
Let's go!
You guys go.
-What about you?
-Leave her alone.
Where are we going?
To save the babies from the cave.
Just the two of us?
Let me get my weapons first.
May I look at the blooming flowers?
All the babies are here.
Don't touch anything.
Babies will die if there's a fight.
Monster, come out and die!
Beware, it's full of methane here.
Monster, you like methane
more than oxygen.
I'll kill you.
How dare you two come here?
Attack her.
Supernatural powers?
You kneel down? Where are your guts?
I can't help it. My legs went limp.
You think you can beat me?
It's no use kneeling. Guards, get them.
We've got no choice now.
You get Master, I'll get the others.
Go!
It's your honor to die before me.
Oh, no. Maybe the methane is
having an effect on me? What do I do?
I can't fight him.
Don't let him concentrate.
I'll kill you this time.
Tung, go with Chat.
No, I'll fight to the end!
No.
You'll get poisoned if you stay.
Let's go!
Get some oxygen first.
Go to hell, all of you!
He's been blown to pieces this time.
Why did this one blow so late?
He's still alive!
To hell with you!
He's afraid of light.
Throw some more.
Does my face still look good?
What?
I don't know if you're all right.
But you scare me.
He isn't dead yet?
How can it be?
His body is gone,
but his mind still there.
He's taken control of me.
Let me help you.
Stay away!
I can't control myself.
Go. Quick!
Go with Chat!
-What do we do?
-Let's go!
Ching.
Don't make me do it again.
You bastard!
Go to hell!
Go!
You son of a bitch!
He's controlling my mind! Go!
We won't leave you behind.
I'm so glad that I could see you again!
I'm sorry!
San!
-San!
-Ching!
Monster, I'd rather die than let you win!
China must have a King.
What's important is today, not the past.
China must have a King!
Let's watch the flowers bloom together.
Doctor!
Ching.
You won't die.
Hey!
Get to the ground first!
Otherwise I'll die!
Are you all right?
I'm okay. Where's Chat?
I've got something good.
Take one. We can't look too shabby
in case reporters show up.
Come on, put it on.
The police has solved
the case of the missing babies.
Most of the missing babies
have been found.
Our reporter is reporting
live at the scene.
We hear that three unknown
heroines solved the case.
How are they connected to the police?
They are close friends of the police.
What are their identities?
No comment.
Do you know when they will appear again?
Whenever they are needed.
What are their names?
Yeah. What are their names?
They are called The Heroic Trio.
When did we get that name?
How do you know that?
Where does the name come from?
It's top secret, sorry.
It's just an improvisation.