Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
THE FABULOUS BARON MUNCHAUSEN
Adapted from works by G.A.Bürger and G.Doré
Conceived and scripted by K.Zeman
Dialogue and Narration
Cast
Set Construction
Editor
Sound Designer
Costume Designer
Make-up Artist
Production Assistants
Animation Crew
Animation Assistants
Assistant Directors
Production Manager
Cinematographer
Music
Production Designer and Director
Produced by
'FROM THE EARTH TO THE MOON'
Allow us to introduce ourselves.
Mr. Barbicane,
President of the Gun Club.
Captain Nicholl.
Michel Ardan.
And who am I?
I am Cyrano.
Cyrano de Bergerac, the poet.
What remains a puzzle to me,
however, is your name.
And where you come from...
From Venus? From Mars?
From Jupiter, perhaps?
Going by his attire,
his home is the moon!
Gentlemen, an authentic,
actual Moonman!
Come, join us!
With glasses charged, let us
celebrate this rarest of moments!
In this enchanted landscape,
cursed by cold and silent as dust,
where one can wait centuries
to meet a soul!
The Baron!
The famed Baron Munchausen!
A man after my own heart!
A fellow adventurer!
The impulse that draws him
to the stars is pure imagination.
How I love it!
Baron Munchausen,
dear friends, is flattered
that he may be the first
to raise a toast
to the health of the first Moonman!
- Let the goblets ring!
- To friendships new!
- Let the stars all sing!
Our new friend
is not enjoying himself.
His lips have not touched the wine!
Tell him take off his helmet!
What if he cannot?
Worse still,
what if he does not
know what wine is?
That very fear, my friends,
gives me a notion.
Look! The old, good Earth!
Does he not deserve to taste
our great discovery?
I will go there, now, at once!
And happily take our Moonman with me!
Show him how humans live!
Let him see how we dress!
Let him experience what love is,
and how we love!
Let him know the taste
and smell of adventure!
Let the Moonman know
what it is to live on Earth!
So, my friends,
on to adventures new!
My wondrous travels with this
Moonman were about to begin!
Once my new friend put on clothes,
the creature looked quite human.
Nearly a man. Almost.
He had a strange name:
“Tony” or some such.
Quite a likeable fellow,
but unfortunately
had something
of the schoolmaster about him.
So my entire manner,
and our unusual
mode of transport,
seemed totally irrational to him...
in short, bizarre.
He insisted on talking about
science and technology...
I must stress once and for all
that I am not interested in
such trifles, my moonfriend!
But I am not from the moon!
I'm from Earth.
Out of the question!
Why out of the question?
I never saw you there!
Behold, the first postilions
of approaching Gaia!
So that's your world?!
Witchcraft!
Yes, and are they
not wonderful?
I don't put much
store in magic.
That one doesn't put
much faith in it either.
She's using your science
as backup!
And down there!
That's your style 100%!
Following the laws of science
to the letter!
The Bosporus, the Golden Horn!
We'll land directly in front
of the Sultan's palace!
Thus shall I address the Great Sultan.
Musical... but quite difficult to follow.
The language of high diplomacy!
Why did I decide to land
in Turkey of all places?
Why? 'Tis the Land
of the Crescent Moon!
I had little doubt that my Moonman
would appreciate this small,
diplomatic gesture.
Few would believe this modest chamber
was the heart and brains
of a great Empire.
But so it was.
Here is where the Great Sultan
tirelessly entertained
the obligations of his rule.
I was convinced amazement
would lighten his noble brow
when I presented a living Moonman!
I felt at home in all this splendour.
Let the Moonboy see
how finely Earthlings live!
I just introduced you.
He fears for his throne.
I apologised. Of course, you have
no idea what a throne is!
A throne is... well...
simply a throne!
It needs oiling.
- Look!
- You're playing with fire.
I gather today's audience is over.
"Our ship was lost in a storm
and captured by pirates,
"who sold me to the Sultan.
"I saw you yesterday...
a true knight.
"You are unafraid,
even of the terrible Sultan!
"So it occurred to me
that I might turn to you
"with a plea to rescue me.
"You are my only hope
"and I remain, yours truly,
Princess Bianca Di Castello Nero."
She turns to you?
Congratulations!
He holds her against her will.
It's a violation!
I shall challenge the Sultan!
The Sultan?
You really are from the moon!
It must be a kidnapping
...a perfect kidnapping!
That too is an act of violence!
Nonsense!
It is a work of art!
The art of winning the lady
of one's dreams.
A true knight never uses
means more peaceful
than sword, dagger
and a length of rope!
Tonight we turn the palace
upside down!
The ducks die too!
Blood will flow, oaths made,
fires started...
The scene is set
for the drama of love!
But the path to our first adventure
was not easy.
It did not bother me,
but the Moonman fared worse
than a sleepwalker.
And this oaf wanted
to save a princess!
You whistle like a little boy.
- What should I do?
- Act like a man!
- Will that help?
- No, but it's more appropriate!
We don't whistle when we're in love,
we fight! In love we...
...in love we float on air.
Check!
Mate!
Well, well. The Moonman
shows his true colours!
To be fair, he hasn't done badly,
but why should I fight my way
through ten thousand bashibazouks
so he can snatch the spoils of victory
from under my very nose?!
Well, no matter, beardless boy!
When Baron Munchausen
enters the arena of love,
he'll cut you down to size!
The wild Turks screamed
like devils.
Doubtless this frightened
the Princess and the Moonboy.
This game of catch
did not affect me, however.
My concerns for the Princess
were of a different order...
I'd seen how the charms of a Venetian
rose could fatally attract even the moon.
And worse, how she was
entirely enamoured of him.
No! The pale seducer shall
not steal her from my world.
For as long as I am Baron Munchausen,
he shall not take her!
For three days and three nights
that infernal chase persisted,
our path strewn with
the bones of exhausted steeds
while dark scavengers rejoiced
in the foul feast!
My friend, Oceanus!
What a fantastic sight it is!
And that ship... Is it Turkish?
The ship is Dutch,
carrying Turkish tobacco.
- A merchant ship.
- Excellent!
He can take us
back to Venice!
Ahoy! Ahoy there!
- It's no good, they can't hear us.
- They're too far out.
Then we must catch them!
Beg pardon!
Horse and man overboard!
Of course, who else but
the Baron Munchausen!
Two horses and three men overboard!
Two horses and two men.
The third man is a woman!
A skiff in the water,
a cabin for the lady,
hay for horses...
and burgundy for the men!
Now for a happy trip to Venice!
And now, friends,
let me offer you the most precious
thing I have.
Karsiyaka?
Tramapasmatan?
- Javan. .?
- Ladokeyech!
- What?
- La-do-key-ech.
Heavenly!
The Turkish navy!
AH hands on deck!
Damn! Well, that's torn it!
What does this mean, Baron?
You stole the Sultan's
treasure, didn't you?
A single pearl!
But quite the finest!
One, two, three, four, five...
One thousand, four hundred and
twenty-seven guns aimed at us!
Prepare to fire!
I might have known!
Now the sharks will smoke my tobacco!
But the Captain had forgotten
that on board
was a man who always had a plan!
As a veil of tobacco smoke
slowly engulfed our ship,
the lines of the Turkish fleet
tightened their deadly grip.
Five hundred cannon to our left,
five hundred cannon to our right.
A famous admiral to the left,
Another to the right.
No sooner had Turkish tobacco
rendered us invisible to Turkish eyes,
than the impetuous Admiral
Hassan gave the order to fire!
The Great Eunuch couldn't
be seen to hesitate.
To prove himself a man,
he unhesitatingly threw
himself into the fight.
As you may judge,
I was the only one
in control of this battle
of the colossi!
To cut a long story short, the Turks
blew each other to splinters
and my fabulous wit celebrated
another triumphant victory!
True, a few stray shots did sink
our ship, but that was to be expected.
After all, what are lifeboats for?
When the pungent curtain
of smoke finally lifted,
we beheld a theatre of destruction,
a stage littered with the pitiful
relics of the magnificent fleet.
The final act of this tragedy
was a pas-de-deux.
Both Admirals, as soloists, played
their parts with admirable feeling.
Bravo! Heroes!
I could do nothing about the fact
that we escaped on two boats.
In one of which sat the Captain
and Tony,
in the second, my humble self
and the Princess.
Night overtook us, the moon
rose over the salt waters
and I had the Princess all to myself.
Tony's boat disappeared.
Baron, are there lovers on the moon?
The moon, my dear,
is by nature a curious place.
- It is completely covered...
- In silver lilies...
forever sweetly chiming!
She made it sound so beautiful.
Damn that Moonman...
still on her mind!
If only she knew that
the true face of the moon
was just as uninspiring
as its residents.
Such a pity she did not
understand my fabulous world.
The monster swallowed us whole.
In its belly was a lagoon
larger than Lake Geneva.
Our only light came from
the lanterns of a shipwreck
that the beast
swallowed long ago.
What a beautiful sight!
Still, the air not being the best,
I decided to let
the Princess sleep on.
I am Baron Munchausen.
You are very welcome to stay.
Kindly enter, distinguished guests.
My presence on board, was
a compelling reason to celebrate!
The sorry castaways willingly opened
the last remnants of their
liquid reserves.
I could see that under their
bony chests lay hearts of gold.
It was a burden to explain
to this noble and gentle creature
how we were trapped
in the stomach of a fish.
But I admit that to travel
twenty thousand leagues under the sea
alongside my beauty,
was a welcome adventure to me!
The monster sailed a goodly
piece of the world with us.
First it went to the North Sea.
During its sojourn
in the realm of eternal ice,
it ventured right under the North Pole.
We could tell as conditions in
the fishy darkness chilled appreciably.
Our fish was quite the traveller,
scouring the seven seas with us aboard!
The Red Sea!
The Yellow Sea!
The Black Sea!
What insightful deductions!
Such deep geographical knowledge!
What would we do without our Admiral?
Just once, when we sailed into
muddy waters, his wit failed.
But mine never waned!
This journey will never end!
A storm! Luckily we are protected
by tons of blubber.
Storm on, Oceanus!
Do thy worst!
Well, I'll be, my Princess, that's
no storm! Those are sixteen-pounders!
Do you know what that means?
You hear the cannons?
We are approaching the civilized
shores of our dear Europa!
The shy beast foolishly
turned its back
on the monuments
of our civilization.
So much the better!
At least I could use the time
to wrangle the Moonman
from the heart of my Princess.
How do you like me, Captain?
A harpoon!
I think it time one changed
into one's travelling attire!
You dance like the wind!
- The floor is dancing with me.
- And me?
You too!
My arms will hold you steady forever!
We are saved! We've landed!
The fish has dropped anchor!
Hey, you there on the rock!
- Hey, hey!
- You there!
What are you doing there?
Dry land at last,
and I end up here!
Down on the island there's
nothing but madness!
Do you hear that?
He's lit an infernal cauldron
inside the ship!
The sorcerer!
That Moonman!
Tony?!
Go down to the bay and see! He's
trying to power a ship with steam!
How fickle is the heart of a woman!
She just has to hear
that ridiculous name 'Tony'
and instantly she forgets the
time spent at my side.
I saw that all my efforts of the past
weeks were in vain.
Where am I?
You're with me.
My steam engine.
But for a single component
the steamship could have been
born a hundred years earlier.
I needed a screw.
A single screw, can you believe it?
I understood that boy. He wanted
to be another Munchausen.
To travel in a boat driven
by steam... Mon Dieu!
Such nonsense required
a hefty imagination!
But when two people do the same thing,
it's never quite the same thing.
No-one loves a wild ride
more than I...
But generally, I prefer
to stay on terra firma.
I loathe to go flapping
about in the clouds...
I was quite enjoying my air-trip,
when a terrible thought flashed
through my mind:
I had left my Princess to the mercy
of that lunatic fantasist!
I must get back at once!
And the quickest way possible!
Heavens above!
I barely wet my lips, but
I wish you could have tasted it!
It was pure wine!
A whole sea of Melnik
white - and perfectly chilled!
What a pity Bianca was not there!
She would be bound to get
a little jealous!
The mermaids swam right past me,
practically caressing me
with their scales!
But their aquatic charms
tempted me not!
For, as with all womankind, as soon as
a man pays no attention to them...
they show their fangs!
This did not disturb me,
I had often seen an innocent fish
turn predator!
No monster has yet
grown big enough teeth
to eat Baron Munchausen!
Suddenly, my heart started pounding.
This had to mean
my beloved was near.
I listened to the beating of my heart
bringing me ever closer to the ship
and the Princess Bianca...
I must not arrive too late!
Long into the night I told
of my undersea adventure.
Everyone listened electrified.
All but these two.
They were not interested.
I fail to see how a princess could
be so interested in such trivia
about machinery and the like!
- Can you read the stars?
- A little.
I wonder what he will say now!
The stars say your eyes are
deeper than the heavens!
Really, my dear inventor,
that isn't even original!
Young men always say that
to a girl under a starlit sky.
For a thousand years,
the same old thing!
The stars will no longer be
a mystery to us.
There will be no mysteries anymore,
except the mystery of love.
...The horse I rode
swam rather than galloped
while perhaps a million
varieties of fish coursed
along the seabed ahead of me,
at unbelievable velocities!
Perhaps a million...
Is it a million or not?
This is supposed to be
a ship's log, Baron!
Indeed! One million, two hundred
and fifty-six fish, exactly.
Fifty-seven!
And gentlemen, I'm not just pulling
that out of my sleeve!
As we sailed on,
I could see with my own eyes
the Princess preferred to listen to
that teller of tales from another world!
Why did the romance
of my adventures not affect her?
The romance of war,
duels and chivalry?
Fortune then smiled on me.
The commander of this fort was
my old friend, General Ellemerle,
a soldier to the core!
Volleys of champagne were
loosed at once to mark our meeting!
Unfortunately, the enemy did
not spare the volleys either,
so our host was forced to return
to more quotidian pursuits.
Splendid! Your strategy
is admirable!
If only I knew where
the enemy was!
Would you allow me to find out?
If it's not an inconvenience...
A trifle!
Look!
Bravo! Bravissimo!
How fast! How brave!
How uncomfortable!
When I had plotted the position
of the enemy in the greatest of detail,
I said to myself I really had
no more business there.
And since enemy shot was
whistling past me thick and fast,
it was but child's play to catch
one back to our citadel!
As a boy,
I used to love fairy tales.
And I know you love them still.
Here, I have drawn one
for you. Take a look!
This is as old a castle
as anywhere on Earth.
In the middle of the castle
yard is a dry well,
above the well a large gilded tower.
A beautiful Princess
is held prisoner within.
A young wanderer falls in love
with the Princess
and wants to rescue
her from the old castle.
So he gets rid of the guard,
enters the armoury
and throws all the gunpowder
down the well.
He waits until the moon
is directly above the castle,
then strikes a light...
and the well turns
into a fiery missile
that flies up to the moon!
You tell a beautiful story.
What a pity it's just a fairy tale!
Why should love and beauty
be just in fairy tales?
Travelling to the moon, throwing
gunpowder into a well,
need not be a dream either!
- To future battles!
- To future adventures!
- May you never see defeat!
- May you never be beaten!
I, Baron Munchausen,
shall never be beaten.
The very name Baron
Munchausen is unbeatable!
It is immortal! Nothing
I can do about it!
Such is my fate...
What fate is that,
if it fails in love?
The Princess Bianca and you...
That naïve girl cannot interest
a chevalier like me,
who has known the rare lace
of the most renowned beauties
in the world.
Lace with royal monograms.
Queen Margareta of Estremadura,
her sister Maria-Luisa of Austria,
and the other one!
Why, they all offered me their
hand - and bed - from their high thrones!
And of course, a considerable
number of court ladies,
to whom it was enough just
to signal with my little finger
and they would fall into my arms!
But they have not always found
their way into my heart so easily.
The Marquise Di Rimini, for example,
employed much more subtle means
to win my affections.
I was insatiable,
busy by day and night...
One beauty after another
fell passionately
under the spell of my
manly eloquence!
Then there was the most beautiful
woman in the world,
once celebrated by
a little-known artist.
Secretly, I also painted her,
and, certainly to much greater effect!
But which of all was
the most passionate?
Excuse me, the discretion
of a chevalier of refined manners
prevents me from
recounting further.
I indulged in recalling these women,
so as not to think more
of the Princess Bianca...
The one beauty in this fortress,
surrounded by so many
dashing chevaliers.
And at that very moment, the enemy
again began his infernal concert.
General, there isn't a speck
of gunpowder left in the whole fortress.
The deadly machinery of war had been
turned overnight into harmless toys.
I had as yet no idea
that this cunning action was
the work of our very own Moonman,
who looked on as if
butter wouldn't melt in his mouth.
Certified Turkish tobacco!
Yet again my interventiveness
proved decisive.
The generals disappeared
and the soldiers without their generals
simply went home.
A strange victory,
but a victory nonetheless.
And therefore worthy of
a formal celebration!
The festivity was, alas,
disturbed by harsher tones...
The General informed the Princess
that Tony had been arrested.
It was thanks to him that
the gunpowder had vanished.
A court martial awaited him,
and then the firing squad!
Mesdames, Messieurs,
s'il vous plaît!
Excuse me, Baron, but you
brought him here!
Excuse me, General,
but we won the battle!
Excuse me, Baron,
what do you mean by battle?
No artillery, no cannon fire?
With that battle we cheated history!
All due to him! That man will be
tried and sentenced!
He's a dangerous fantasist.
You said a dangerous fantasist?
Now I've heard that somewhere before!
A dangerous fantasist!
That reminds me of...
Tony!
The young man is from the moon,
from another world...
He fell from the Heavens?
Good, we'll send him back.
A point, General,
where is your evidence?
Remember, like in the fairytale,
there's a full moon!
When the moon is directly overhead
the fortress, we can start...
Interesting instructions on how
to blow a fortress into the air!
The well is full of gunpowder.
All it would take is one spark and...
The Baron is an excellent shot,
he'll help us for sure.
She thinks I cannot
see her, the Princess.
Fair Princess, the Officer
of the Fortress Guard,
at your service, to take you
safely to the General!
Fortress regulations are clear.
Duty before emotion!
Stop it now, young man!
Stop!
Don't you understand an order?
You won't play games with me!
Tony!
Be grateful that
I've rid you of this rogue.
He wants to beat you
at everything.
He boasts that he sailed
not one, but all the seas.
Maybe he comes from a world where
that is nothing unusual.
And he says that he flew
faster than a cannonball.
Why not?
Doubtless he was in a hurry!
The boy is, as you say, a fantasist.
If he has indeed any fantasy,
then let us see it now!
Greetings, friends!
Old Cyrano welcomes you!
Hither! To me!
You've come just in time.
The hour is about to strike!
Luna till now belonged
to the poets, to the dreamers,
to daring fantasists and
adventurers in powdered wigs.
To fantasists in frock coats,
and those in bizarre helmets from
the pages of our latest novels.
And of course to lovers, to
them Luna was always most dear!
Thus gaily I doff my hat
and let it fly unto the stars!
Let it welcome, on our behalf,
all such brave fellows
already on their way into
the welcoming arms
of the Universe!
THE END