Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
THIS FILM HAS PARTICIPATED IN
THE ART FESTIVAL OF 1955
NIKKATSU PRESENTS
FOREVER A WOMAN
Screenplay by TANAKA Sumie
Plot by WAKATSUKI Akira, NAKAIYO Fumiko
Producers  KOI Eisei
and SAKAGAMI Shizui
Photographed by KUMENORU FUJIOKA
Edited by NAKAMURA Kimihiko
Sound by KAMIYA Masakazu
Music by TAKAYORI SAITO
Assistant Director NAKAJIMA Yoshitsugu
Starring
YUMEJI TSUKIOKA
MASAYUKI MORI
RYOJI HAYAMA
YOKO SUGI
SHIKO OSAKA
TORU ABE
MIEKO TOIBOUCHI
KINUYO TANAKA
Executive Producers
HIDEO KOI and SHIZUO SAKAGAMI
Directed by
KINUYO TANAKA
Uncle! Hurry!
We're back!
Come on, Noboru.
Your mother's here.
Really? Grandma's here.
Grandma!
Grandma! Anything for us?
Sure. Here's a surprise.
Sweet rice cake.
Sweet rice cake!
Hi, Mom!
You're late.
Wash your hands first.
Your feet are dirty.
Come to the well.
Drug.
It's bad for your health.
Never mind.
To Mrs. Fumiko Shimojo.
Wash them.
What are you doing?
More quickly, or your
husband will be angry.
He's always angry, anyway.
Because business is slow.
He handles too many things.
Fumiko!
He wants you. I'll go home.
Get my parasol for me.
Your brother will get
married. I'm glad.
If you could be happy too,
your late father would be...
Fumiko!
Go to him.
I brought some rice.
I'll see Grandma off.
Me, too.
Thank you. Let's go.
Please stop!
No more!
You're like your mother.
She preached to me now, too.
She's worried about you.
Our kids are still little.
She wants you back.
She's rich.
You're young and beautiful.
We're back.
We saw Grandma off.
Mom, I'm hungry.
Me, too.
Rice cake!
Wait.
Have some.
Good morning.
Tell Mr. Hori I'll attend
the meeting of poets.
Give this to him.
Give me a lift.
Sure. Come on.
I'm leaving.
Aiko, play outside.
Let me carry it.
Where are you going?
Must I tell you each time?
You go out, too.
I don't have to go.
Why not?
You want to be a poetess.
Me a poetess?
No!
You'll be a good one.
Too good for me.
Do I look so proud?
Answer me.
Do you hate me?
Get my socks.
What a cheap couple,
arguing like this!
We're finished.
I'm a petty broker
who earn little.
You can't get
easy money nowadays.
Now even my wife preaches.
My overcoat.
Where are you going?
The back of my husband
Blown by the wind
Exits from my sight
Ruined by the drug
Asleep all day
My husband has gone
Beyond my reach
Well?
I think they're good.
A bit exaggerated.
Very good.
Mrs. Shimojo's poems
are strange.
Someday you'll understand.
They tell the truth.
Women's truth.
You hate your husband?
No. My poems exaggerate.
The Tokyo Daily News is
interested in our group.
Write good poems.
Good.
Let's choose some for them.
My children are waiting.
I must go now.
Sure. Go back to them.
Leaving?
My kids are waiting.
Your husband?
Hasn't he come yet?
He went to the doctor first.
Fumiko! Leaving so soon?
Hello, Hori.
They're waiting.
To the doctor?
I'm fine.
Did they like your poems?
I have little time for poems.
They said my poems
exaggerate.
Your poems describe your
hardship well.
They make me sad.
I don't mind.
Let them criticize me.
I tell the truth in my poems.
You're too sensitive to
ignore their comments.
But you were happy
as a student.
We played with a ball.
Did I change so much?
My wife often talks
about you.
You used to be a tomboy.
You must tell her...
I'll be a good wife.
Don't pity me.
I'll write good poems
that make you happy.
I'm sure you'll like them.
Keep well.
- Welcome back.
- My kids?
In the room.
I went to your house today.
There was a guest.
A guest? Who?
I didn't look in.
Hello, Seiko.
Hello.
You're lovely.
You're as pretty as ever.
No, not anymore.
Your husband has a guest.
You'd better go home.
He'll be angry again.
He doesn't miss me.
He hates a poetess.
Children, let's go home.
They can stay with us.
Thanks, Mom.
Be good, children.
Goodbye.
Leaving?
Eating again?
You eat all day.
What gluttons!
So were you when
you were little?
I'm back.
It's me.
Dear!
Sorry, I'm late.
Not at all.
You had a guest?
Who was it?
You lied to me!
That woman!
You still have her.
Shut up!
A good wife, huh?
No love affair, huh?
Enough!
Notice of divorce
Noboru, come here.
Take care of him.
Certainly.
I feel rather relieved.
He's ready.
Your lunchbox?
He has it.
Don't be late for school.
Aren't you coming with me?
I'll go later.
I want to go with him.
Noboru, let's go see
your father.
We'll be going.
Thank you.
Aiko, play with me.
What'll we do?
Mrs. Shimojo won't come.
You sent your wife?
The Short Poems magazine
wants fifty poems.
Mr. Otsuki of the
Daily News said...
...we could send some
to the magazine.
It's our chance.
A debut in the central
circle of poets.
Let's try hard.
It makes me nervous.
Hori, I think your last poem
is very good.
I don't know.
Your wife's poem, too.
Sorry I'm late.
Welcome.
Fumiko can't come today.
Her daughter was
missing. She was pale.
But the girl turned up
at her ex-husband's home.
She sent her brother
to get her.
Life is hard for her.
She must have been worried.
Has she changed much
since the divorce?
She looked all right.
She must be lonely.
But bitter experiences
help her write good poems.
She used to exaggerate
in her poems.
Experience brings reality.
Mr. Yamagami,
this poem by Fumiko...
Please read it.
A blue workdress going
away in the wind
It carries the sorrow
of a mother
Welcome home.
I was surprised.
It might happen again.
Your ex has a new wife.
Noboru must be lonely.
Hello.
Aiko?
Taking a bath.
Give this to her.
Thank you.
Please go in.
Yoshio, take her.
Mom.
You'll catch cold.
From Seiko.
Thanks.
Take a bath.
No.
Strange.
You like baths.
Is something wrong?
Go to the doctor.
I'm all right.
You're stubborn.
So your ex didn't like you.
I never wanted
to marry Shimojo.
After our first meeting, you
insisted I marry him.
Will you eat this?
You saw Noboru?
Dad, too?
No. There was a lady.
I'll wear a tuxedo.
A Japanese kimono is better
for your wedding.
No, I'll wear a tuxedo.
A bride is most beautiful in
Japanese wedding attire.
Sis, I want to wear a
tuxedo at my wedding.
Isn't it nice?
What does your bride say?
You like it, too?
Aiko, let's go upstairs.
Go upstairs.
I'll bring your cake.
This is nice. I'll wear it.
Please accept my humble gift.
Thank you very much.
Be a good girl.
Ask your mom to change
your kimono.
No, Aiko.
Don't do it,
or I'll punish you.
Why not change your kimono?
It's your brother wedding.
I hate to be watched.
Suit yourself.
Why not obey me?
I'll take you out.
Why doesn't she
attend the party?
Because she's a divorcee.
She had a hard time.
She's afraid of rumors.
The bride!
She's coming!
Here's the bride!
How beautiful!
Let's go out.
Let me see the bride!
No.
I'll be a good girl.
Is it warm enough?
Yes.
Shall I wash you?
No. You must go now.
Hello, Fumiko! Welcome!
Can I come in?
Sure. Why not?
You're always
welcome to our house.
Fumiko's here, dear.
It's your brother's
wedding day.
I can't stay in that house,
so here I am.
You're heavy.
Have some.
Thank her.
Thank you.
Good girl.
I'm going to a
teachers' meeting.
Leaving now?
I'll be back soon.
Let's eat supper.
Wait for me.
Good girl.
Fumiko.
Mrs. Shirakawa found you a
potential groom.
My husband said
you could marry him.
But even if he has no children...
...consider well this time.
Let's not discuss it.
Aiko, I'll bring you a surprise.
Don't be long.
I won't.
Dear, take your medicine.
How is he?
Not very well.
Maybe he worked too hard.
See you later.
Goodbye.
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Hi, Aiko! Welcome!
Say hello.
Hello.
I remember this.
What a tomboy!
And you were a daredevil.
We three liked skiing.
I was happy then.
How nice! Your honeymoon!
Kinuko looks happy.
Lake Doya.
It was during the war.
Not entirely happy.
The lake was beautiful.
You should see it.
I'll send my poem about it
to the magazine.
I want to see it.
Hori.
Do you really think
I should get married?
It's not easy to live alone
with your child.
I'm sick of a married life.
But you failed only once.
Don't give up.
Let everyone in the
world say so...
...but not you.
She's gone to sleep.
Don't catch cold.
Fumiko.
It began to rain.
Kinuko has no umbrella.
I won't visit you again.
Why not?
You'd be embarrassed.
I complain to you.
I'm afraid Aiko
will catch a cold.
Thanks.
Hori.
You dislike selfish women like me.
You're strange today.
I shouldn't be envious of
my brother's marriage.
I hate myself
for all my misery.
You're gentle, but fiery inside.
Your poems tell the truth.
Listen.
What if I make a confession?
I attend the poets' meetings
only to see you.
I'm sorry.
I'm selfish.
So my ex hated me.
I'll marry again, not for love
but for a living.
Ridiculous.
It was so from the start.
I married the man I was
first introduced to.
I didn't know love.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't complain to
somebody else's husband.
Anyway, keep well.
Don't waste your talent.
I have none.
You do.
I'll send your poems
to the magazine.
My poems?
Don't make a fool of me.
I'm worried about your health.
I hope you will be
truly happy with Kinuko.
Your happiness is mine.
Here we are.
Thank you.
Wake up, Aiko.
You must be warm
with his muffler.
- Say goodbye to him.
- Goodbye.
Don't let hardship beat you.
Write good poems.
Take my advice.
Fumiko.
Here.
Yes.
I see.
Sis!
It's bad! Mr. Hori's dying!
A report from the hospital.
Will you go? I'll get a taxi.
Hello.
It's you! Hello!
Ma'am!
You won.
Let's play catch.
Here's some cake for you.
Mom?
You're supposed to be a man.
Sis!
Your poems Mr. Hori sent to
the magazine were chosen.
Who said so?
Mr. Yamagami heard it from
the Daily News man.
He wants to see you.
Fine.
Hori, thanks.
Good news!
You've grown big.
Good night.
You're a good boy.
Aiko, go to sleep.
Sleep beside me.
All right.
How nice sleeping together!
Can I keep staying here?
From today on?
Sure, don't worry.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
The go-between is here.
Your mother wants you.
Where are you going?
I won't go anywhere.
Take care of him.
Noboru, I'll read
a book for you.
I can't convince her.
I believe she knows,
what she's doing.
As the go-between, I must
take the boy to his father.
He must live with his
father, after all.
If he stays here too long,
it won't do him good.
What's the matter? Fumiko!
Sis! What's wrong with you?
Get the doctor!
Operating Theatre
Thank you for coming.
How's Fumiko?
Much better now.
Three persons died after
my daughter came here.
If she dies, I...
She won't die. I pray
for her every day.
Mrs. Hori's here.
Hello.
Oh, you look fine.
I feel bored every day.
She is very spoilt.
Be patient.
My husband's keepsake.
A gift from him.
I'm so glad.
Such a precious thing!
Thank you very much.
How's my boy?
He's an urchin.
Does he bother you?
No. He's very well behaved.
Does he mention me?
He often asks me about you.
Shall I bring him?
If you get a little better.
No, Kinuko.
I wouldn't be able to sleep.
Your poems are popular.
"Lost Breasts". What a title!
It's clear that I can't
think of marriage anymore.
Who are you?
Where's my mom?
Oh, it's you. She's not in now.
She's gone to her treatment.
Come in and wait.
Where are you going?
To school.
Mom, get well soon.
I am praying to God for you.
It's good?
Very.
Eat this.
For you.
From our son in Tokyo.
What is it?
Wait.
A kimono.
Our son's wife sewed it.
He'll bring his child
here next month.
Finish your meal first.
I'm not hungry.
How do you feel? Fine?
Yes, very.
Her first book of poetry on a deathbed.
Excuse me sir...
May I look at the paper?
"Lost breasts" is a book of poems
by Shimojo Fumiko.
She has breast cancer spreading
throughout her body...
...and was admitted to the
Sapporo Hospital, in a critical state.
How are you?
Mr. Otsuki is coming
from Tokyo to see you.
Mr. Otsuki?
The critic who praised
your poems.
Of the Daily News?
No. I won't see him.
He's worried about you.
He called me many times.
He's on the train now.
Wire to the train.
I don't want to see him.
The 15:06 express for
Asahikawa is leaving.
Next stop Sapporo.
My daughter is missing.
It's been a long time.
A long trip.
Thanks.
Thank you.
How is she?
Alive. I told her
you're coming.
To the office?
No. I'll see her first.
Sapporo Hospital.
Like a weed
floating in water
I'm swaying
in the ocean of life
My children playing in the sun
And the flower bulbs
Invite the same sadness
She's really impossible.
She worries me so much.
I'd rather welcome
her activeness.
Even if she wanted
to see her son...
If you sneak out again,
I'll give you an injection.
Her condition is critical.
Her lungs are infected.
Pneumonia can finish her.
It's a miracle
she's still alive.
She has tremendous
willpower.
I'd hate to lose her now.
I shouldn't have
called you.
My boss told me to see her
and write the truth.
As I wrote she might die
any moment.
I prayed for her survival.
I even forgot my job.
This way.
It's gloomy.
She described it in a poem.
As if in a convent,
quiet prevails
Is it to torture me
in my despair?
It's that.
This is her mother.
Mr. Otsuki from Tokyo.
Thank you for coming so far.
Wait a minute.
Fumiko, Mr. Otsuki's here.
I won't see him.
He came from Tokyo.
Reporters are inquisitive,
that's all.
He wants to see me dying.
Send him away.
X-RAY
I'm very sorry, but she
doesn't feel well today.
I see. We'll be back
tomorrow.
Thank you.
This is the trophy she won
for her poems.
Thank you.
See you later.
It's wonderful.
You won it, Fumiko.
Desk?
She's seriously ill.
I want to see her and get
some of her new poems.
I'll be staying.
Time for therapy.
Hello. Just a moment.
It's the reporter.
I'll see him.
Make him wait.
Wait a while.
Please come in.
Come in.
I'm Otsuki.
Thank him for his
consideration.
Be seated. Excuse me.
I'll get tea for you.
I'm leaving immediately.
Thank you for coming all
way from Tokyo to see me.
Are you here in Hokkaido
on business or something?
Business? I came to see you.
To see me die?
In Tokyo, I didn't know
how things were here.
I read your article
in the Tokyo Daily News.
I'm ready to die.
You needn't.
You don't like to
hear it from me, but...
It's not only me.
All the poets in Tokyo
are interested in you.
And all the critics said
you're promising.
They're interested
because I'm dying.
You wrote I was seriously
ill and would die soon.
You want to make sure of it.
You think that's a reporter?
I respect your talent.
Your first book isn't
for your poems.
If you're satisfied,
I must say you're stupid.
You're right. I'm stupid.
That's why I write poems.
But I'm going to die soon.
Poems can't help.
But you are alive.
Don't give up
so long as you live.
Any new poems?
No.
I can't write any.
Why not?
I lost my breasts.
What can I write?
What can I say?
I don't want to be
known as a poetess.
I'm just a woman.
As a woman...
...losing my breasts saddens me.
Everybody has sadness.
Without it, you can't
write good poems.
You must write more poems.
You want my new poems? Why?
You want my last poem
for your newspaper?
I'll never die!
No new poems!
As long as you live,
I'll be glad.
My visit won't be wasted.
This is our first meeting.
I'll come again tomorrow.
I won't die so soon,
not tomorrow.
Get well.
Sapporo has good beer.
Let's drink it later.
We'll have a party
for your book.
I'll drink for you.
SHIMOJO FUMIKO'S POETRY BOOK
CELEBRATION OF ITS PUBLICATION
As Fumiko is ill...
...we postponed this party.
But having Mr. Otsuki
here in Hokkaido...
...let's hold it tonight.
To Fumiko's new book
and her recovery!
Thank you.
It's a pity
she can't be here.
You women should be careful
about breast cancer.
Men get it, too.
Men, too! Really?
This book has been published
by Mr. Hori.
If he was alive...
...he would be very glad.
It's true.
I wish he could see it.
Mr. Otsuki, thank you for coming
from so far away.
You are welcome.
I thought she'd be worse,
but she didn't seem to be.
- I didn't think it was breast cancer.
- It's too late now. It's a pity.
She must be happy
being congratulated like this.
This is my last wish.
I can die without regrets.
Is it warm?
Yes. I feel fine.
You suddenly wanted
to take a bath.
But I know how you feel.
You're very nice.
I'm grateful to you.
I'll never forget.
I'll be scolded.
It's okay if you get well.
I'm sorry.
Kinuko.
Look, my breasts were here.
This is how I look now.
If you're through, come out.
I wanted to take a bath
where your husband did.
I got cancer as my punishment.
I loved him.
Hello.
Who... It's you.
Come in.
Wait here.
Worried?
Relax.
She troubles you.
No.
Let her alone for a while.
She sounds happy.
She changed
after the operation.
She's like a child.
Sometimes I think she's
trying to destroy herself.
Fumiko, are you through?
Can I open it?
What's wrong?
It's a long bath.
Mr. Otsuki and Yoshio are here.
Sick?
Dizzy?
Feeling pain?
Wait.
- Stay still.
- Okay, okay.
Why come to see a sick
woman like me? What for?
You reported I was dying
in the newspaper.
You want to make sure?
As long as you come to see me...
...I won't write.
Rest quietly.
Sis.
Mr. Otsuki, when will
you leave for Tokyo?
Tonight.
Fumiko.
If my report was wrong,
I'm extremely happy.
Try to live.
The 21:52 train for
Hakodate is leaving.
Passengers have to go
to platform 2 or 3.
If anything happens,
I'll call you.
Thanks.
Otsuki!
I'm glad I came in time.
This is from Fumiko.
- Is it for me?
- Yes.
After dying
I fly everywhere lightly
On your shoulders,
for instance
Unable to return.
Better follows. -Otsuki
What's funny?
So you've come for my poems.
If you like.
Sit down, please.
Your mother?
Out for a bath.
Open it.
All my new poems are there.
Why keep it a secret?
I don't want anybody to see them.
You're mean.
When you really go away...
...please do me a favor.
What is it about?
Throw the poems in Lake Doya.
Do it for me... Please.
- Lake Doya?
- Yes.
I always wanted to go there.
I still do. I can die
for a sight of that lake.
Don't mention dying.
I want you to be more
eager to live.
You're spoiling yourself
by being ill.
To live is never easy.
We all struggle for it.
I refuse to be pitied.
A sick poetess isn't rare.
I try to look fine
for visitors.
I send them away
without worries.
Or I'd feel more miserable
about myself.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Anything you want?
Just you. I want you.
Good night.
Now that Fumiko Shimojo's
days are numbered...
...she should write as many
poems as possible.
The sentence "I hope you get better"
has lost all sense.
All I can do is...
...stimulate her desire
to write poems.
Maybe it's not my duty
as a reporter, but...
...please understand
and let me stay here.
To: Chief Editor.
Hello.
Thank you for last night.
I'm sorry I was out
for a bath.
Come this way.
You look tired.
Fumiko had trouble
breathing last night.
I couldn't sleep.
If there's anything I can do.
Thank you.
I want to go home today.
The nurse will care for her.
But she'll be lonely by herself.
Don't worry.
The old lady in your ward
will move today.
Is that so?
Here's Mr. Otsuki.
Hello.
Welcome.
How are you?
Do you feel like it?
Eat it later, dear.
For you.
Mother.
Come on, let's move.
Goodbye.
And thank you.
You're very kind.
Please take care of her.
Morgue
Fumiko! Fumiko!
When I die, I'll die
just as I am.
I won't ask God to help me
die a good woman.
Because I know there's
no God to rely on.
Be quiet. Go to sleep.
I can't.
Get me some pills.
Please.
No. The doctor said
they'd harm you.
Please! Sleeping pills!
No!
Please!
Hold on to me.
Have you slept well?
Strange.
I lost my breasts and
my chest got burned.
But I could sleep well.
Mr. Otsuki, a call for you.
From your Tokyo office.
They want you back immediately.
I see.
I'll be there.
Are you leaving tomorrow?
I wish you wouldn't.
People visit me...
...then go away.
It's nice having
a place to return to.
Unfortunately I have none.
I'll end up here.
If I can't stop you...
And if you must leave...
I won't be able...
...to run after you.
I'll be back. Wait for me.
Try to live.
This is goodbye.
What is it?
Say nothing.
Stay still.
This is the happiest
day of my life.
Yet...
As a woman, I'm miserable.
Why is it so?
Because I'm bad?
Sleep with me.
I can die in your arms.
Say hello...
...to your people for me.
These days were...
...the happiest in my life.
Thanks to you
I could live longer.
I was happy every day.
I'll live to write more poems.
I'll send you good poems.
I'll write in the paper
you'll live long.
Go...
...while my eyes are closed.
Try hard.
I'll be back.
No visitors
Mother...
...wash my hair, will you?
Hair?
Doctor?
Yoshio.
Yoshio, get it.
Give it to my children.
They'll read it when
they grow up.
To Noburu and Aiko.
Children, accept my death.
The only thing
I bequeath to you.
Sis, Mrs. Hori is here.
Hello.
Noboru.
Aiko.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to live long
to watch over you...
...to see the days when
you're happily married.
But I can't.
Thank you, ma'am.
Let's go.
Your mom's gift.
Mother!
Stay calm... stay calm.
Mom, get well.
I'm coming. Try hard to live.
-Otsuki
Mom?
Gone. That way.
Mom!
Children,
accept my death.
The only thing
I bequeath to you.
THE END