THE FEAR
Who is it?
Me.
Why do you lock yourself in?
For fear of thieves?
What do you want?
So you're here for 4 days only?
The Histology Professor became ill and
the exams were postponed for a week.
So I managed to come over for a few days.
In some 20 days I'm finishing studies.
That means you're coming back
with the diploma.
Wheat looks good this year.
We had rains last week.
Most of it was brought down by the wind.
Did you find her?
She's nowhere.
Perhaps she went to the fields?
I asked the field guard.
She's not in the stable either.
The earth has swallowed her.
Now we have worries with Chrysa, too.
I won't come at noon.
I'm busy.
Chrysa gives me extra work today.
- Leave it mother, I'll do it.
- You rest. You're only here for 2 days.
Does he sleep with you now?
I saw him come into your room last night.
When he's drunk.
He only comes to humiliate me.
- He won't come at noon.
- Said he's busy.
You know what with.
A good thing you'll finish
and be back soon.
He's started selling off
parts of the fields.
Selling off?
The field guard confided it to me.
For some time now, he's been going
down to Thebes.
This place is no good for him anymore.
Recently he was away for 3 days.
Having a ball with some hussies.
Where's that girl?
She hasn't done this before.
How are you getting along with Anestis?
You can never tell
what he's thinking about.
He's wandering in the fields all day
like a wild beast.
I'm worried about this boy.
Never speaks.
Let his father care for him.
I won't meddle anymore.
I'm his stepmother and
may be misunderstood.
Where's Anna?
Said she'd walk in the fields.
I would have seen her if she had.
She may have gone down to the village.
She took the horse too.
You expected her to walk down there?
She might have got together
with that mechanic again.
I won't stand for this.
You mind your business and
don't think evil.
Well, yeah...
If father catches her...
You set the table already?
You're late.
What about Chrysa?
Hasn't shown up yet.
What if she fell into a channel?
A shepherd was found drowned
the other day.
Ah, that shepherd again...
Don't speak of adversity, mother.
A good thing they brought us
these fish from the lake.
MYSTERIOUS DISAPPEARANCE
OF DEAF MUTE GIRL
Where have you been?
Where? I went to get hay for the cattle.
I've told you to take these off
when you walk in here.
She's giving me a hard time, that slut!
Now we're in the papers too.
What does this mean?
Self-slaughter means suicide.
Read it from the word go.
Our fellow residents are obviously
overwhelmed with emotion by the
mysterious disappearance of the deaf
mute girl Chrysa Kavanari
who was adopted daughter to
well-known land owner
Dimitrios Kanalis
whose residence she disappeared from.
Many support the possibility
of an accident
while another number of residents
are expressing a suspicion
that it might be a case of self-slaughter
or a flight of the missing girl
which reportedly was subjected to
maltreatment
by the Kanalis family.
Lastly, a third category of residents
are overwhelmed with the belief
claiming this as being a miracle.
As known as it is, the deaf mute girl
has often revealed
through gestures and inarticulate cries
that she envisaged the Madonna
who through signalling
exhorted the girl to follow Her.
The Constabulary are conducting a search
for the discovery of the missing girl.
What came upon that poor child
so as to do this?
Hope it has no consequence on us.
We, maltreating her...
I know who spreads these rumours.
One day I'll smash his head!
Talking about Santo, father?
You stay out of this.
I saw him with his son, the mechanic.
They were talking with others and
when they saw me they quit their talk.
We found her in a chapel far away.
We fed her, she was starving.
Go away, boys.
We tried to find out why she left
but we couldn't.
I can't understand it.
My wife went down to her room today
but she was not there.
Sir Dimitris, will you tell her
to say something for us?
Mother of God appeared before her,
that's why the girl was scared off.
She's scared stiff!
Take care of her.
She's the lucky charm of your house.
Hand me a cigarette.
Has your father caught you out smoking?
My mother did.
The other day I had trouble with
my own father.
My uncle told him I spoke to a girl.
What if I did?
No, he said, such things are immoral.
If I hear of such things again,
I'll cut your legs off.
So, I'll leave next year and
go work in Athens.
Lots of women there if you want them.
My father does not allow me to leave.
He wants me in the fields.
Suits him fine...
He has money to pay for women.
You fancy women.
You're a little...
...cowardly.
They'll go with married men more easily.
My father's rich too.
They all act as if they know nothing.
In their own interest.
You could do it with one of the girls
working in your fields.
But you're brusk and you scare them.
You're not cunning enough.
If anyone sees me...
Those ones mock you behind your back.
They say you're a...
...virgin.
Lambros was chased by Tasia's father
with a rifle.
You have to do your thing
in a sneaky way.
My uncle...
They'd gone to church.
My cousin was alone at home.
I pretended I didn't know
the others were away.
I went in.
She gathered something was on my mind
and she blushed.
She made me some coffee.
Her hands were shaking.
She asked me...
if I liked the coffee.
I put my hand on her leg...
A nice dress, I told her.
Is there lace on your petticoat?
She started to tremble.
I threw her on the sofa.
Shame on you, shame! she kept saying.
You're creepy...
You're quite a creeper.
Like a dove she purred.
Finally she burst into tears.
Not a word about this to anyone,
or you'll be ridiculed, I told her.
Even murder may come out of it.
She said nothing.
She banged herself on the sofa
like an animal being slaughtered.
With your cousin, people won't
suspect easy.
And you can visit without
being misjudged.
Have you seen a woman naked?
No.
Don't let any of this slip
out of your mouth. Only you know it.
I won't take any risks.
You think I won't get my hands on you?
I saw you, you're Kanalis' son.
You, bastard!
Ravenous!
How did your face get like this?
I got scratched somewhere.
Why give me this look, mother?
Where's Chrysa?
Wasn't she going to the church?
What are you trying to hide?
Mother...
- I'll tell you, mother...
- Let me see!
- Let me tell you.
- Stand back I say!
Enough, mother.
Don't look anymore!
I didn't mean to, mother, I didn't!
I tried to push her and she fell, mother!
Scum!
Don't tell father anything.
What'll become of your soul, dirty dog?
Come out here, you!
This animal's got to hide for 2-3 days.
Until the scratches leave his face.
Then I'll notify the police that
Chrysa's disappeared again.
Get lost, out of my sight!
If this became known,
we'd have to leave this place.
We'd be lynched.
We've got property.
There's also Anna.
Why stand there like a scarecrow?
Shine me some light here.
Good evening, Sir Dimitris.
Hi Nicolas.
One of my calves is ill.
I saw light and thought I'd ask you
about that irrigation system we
talked about the other day...
The way he carries on he'll probably
get us burned in the end.
A woman asked me about the bell.
I told her we heard thuds one night
and we worried about thieves.
Did she believe you?
Dunno.
The scoundrel...
He nailed a bell to the door!
He's scared of his shadow too.
The other day when your cousin came,
I had another fright attack.
He shut himself in his room...
Her eye caught him.
I didn't know what to say.
He must leave here after this thing
starts being forgotten.
What I really care about is that
Anna must not know any of this.
She'll be staying here now.
She's bound to know in the end.
She was upset when she heard
about Chrysa.
You know how much she loved her.
The wretched one!
Why the hell was he ever born?
Don't swear.
He's to be pitied as well.
What do they say in the village?
They believed her to be found again
like the first time.
There's also some of them mumbling about.
Today they were collecting donations
for the new church.
I gave them a thousand.
Are waters deep in the lake?
Where were you?
For a walk at the lake.
Aren't you going too far?
Eat now while they're hot.
Father, want some?
They give me indigestion.
They never did before.
Will you eat some, mother?
I'm full.
The policeman came at home.
He asked father for a complementary
statement.
Everybody wonders what became of Chrysa.
They searched at the river in case she
fell into a channel and got carried away
at cliffs, caves and monasteries...
They should have found her somewhere.
Living or dead.
He asked for your statement too.
He said when you go by the village
you should visit his office.
I gave a statement.
He may have something more to ask you.
Were you at home when the sergeant came?
I was here.
Planting scarecrows.
I thought I saw you running
behind the stable.
Blackie...
Take me out of that house.
I can't live in there anymore.
- What have they done to you, Anna?
- I can't tell you.
I cannot!
Why didn't you tell me about these?
When I told you I saw them at the lake
you took it out on me.
It's your fault. Hoggish idiot!
Why beat me? Because she
makes out with the mechanic?
If I'd told you, you'd have caught them.
Then, she'd tell on us.
She knows all about us.
Although she doesn't say so.
She came fishing for me, the day the
policeman came at home.
What are you up to, father?
Father...
Slut...
Turn in and sleep.
It's 4 o'clock.
Now come inside, it's chilly.
Better accept it.
There's nothing you can do.
Is that so?
Our daughter will be in command
from now on!
Behind a stack of hay.
Like a bitch!
They're in love.
The mechanic will marry her.
My daughter...
Santos' son?
Is that what bothers you?
Can't you think of how disgusted Anna
must be with us?
I'm ashamed to look at her.
Let her marry and go...
So that I won't feel her eyes nailing me.
Stop it now.
I'm praying for my child to go away.
She'll never set her foot
in this house again.
I know it.
I won't see her again.
You wedded them already...
It crosses your mind that I might ever
accept this marriage?
You know only too well, you cannot
do otherwise.
This makes your heart beat, I guess.
You never liked me.
All this time, you've playing a comedy.
You got a chance to paddock me.
Even in bed, I'm sure you're mocking me
for being a fool under your gowns.
You're raging with anger 'cause
you can't walk out on me again.
So that you can gamble and
go around with whores.
You walked out from the first moment
you married me.
Still in my wedding dress
I already was a grass widow.
It took a disaster to remind you
that you had a wife and a home.
You recovered your tone.
Just as you did to your first wife.
But God pays you off.
All these years you never said a word.
So you raged with anger.
Cause I never spoke anything out.
You said it all tonight.
You poisoned my life and now you're
poisoning my child's life too.
You and that wastrel son of yours.
My son's sticking in your throat
cause he's another woman's son.
Heavenly fire will consume you
if you ever say that again.
You know very well I never treated him
any different from Anna.
I'm finished.
My son a murderer.
My daughter...
that I was so proud of...
that I saw to her studies...
she humiliated me.
Tell that son of a bitch to come
and ask for her.
Tell her I'd rather have her marry him
than go around with him and ridicule me.
Act like other people told us.
She's clever and she'll see me through.
Too late anyway.
We'd better send that other one to
Athens so he doesn't chase after her.
He's crazy with fear that
one day she'll give him away.
He's drinking cup after cup.
I'm afraid he'll get drunk.
I went through hell to have him
come to the wedding.
He says he can't meet with people.
Long live the newlyweds!
Anything wrong?
You look cheerless.
I got so tired these days.
Hey, Anestis...
Don't sulk, your time will come too.
Tasos!
Play a tune for Anestis to dance!
I don't dance.
You shouldn't say so
at your sister's wedding.
Dance.
Stand up, Anestis!
Stand up, you...
THE END
English subs by never4ever for KG
synched: kekazzz
synched by kekazzz for YTS