You've reached 02.503.16.12.
Leave a message after the beep.
Honey, it's me.
I've just arrived.
I'll be home in half an hour.
See you.
THE STRANGE
COLOR
OF YOUR BODY'S
TEARS
Edwige?
Honey?
Honey? Are you there?
I've arrived safely. I'll cal you tomorrow.
I am going to sleep.
Love you.
Honey, it's me. We are making progress.
We should be able to sign pretty soon.
Love you.
Honey, it's me.
I've just arrived.
I'll be home in half an hour.
See you.
Have you seen my wife?
What?!
- I don't know her!
Yes?
- Edwige?
You've got the wrong person.
I told you I don't know her!
It's almost midnight!
Edwige...
Yes...
I am looking for my wife.
She has disappeared.
Come upstairs.
7th floor.
Sit down.
How do you know my wife?
I don't know her.
Turn right here, is my husband, Paul.
He was a doctor. He also disappeared.
It happened a couple of days
after he had retired.
Who are you calling?
- The police.
You want them to think you are crazy?!
Honey?
Honey!
I am up here!
- Paul! Come down!
- There is no light.
Hand me some matches!
Hurry up!
Paul?
Yes!
- Paul? - That's incredible!
- The people who live there are ...
- Come down now!
- Give me some matches!
- No, come down!
I don't even see the way out!
Give me some!
Honey!
Paul!
Paul...!
I wiped off the drop of blood
and I appoached the hole.
I saw an eye staring at me,
filled with hatred, madness, fear...
I saw ....
Get out of here!
What are you doing here?
And you?
I live downstairs.
Are you the neighbour of
the crazy old woman?
Did you come up here because of her?
Barbara.
- Dan.
I am looking for my wife.
Dan Kristensen?
- Dan.
- Inspektor Vincentelli.
- Vincentelli.
- Dan Kristensen.
Your wife disappeared just like that,
Mr. Kristensen?
How do you know?
- You called the police last night.
Don't you remember?
- Yes... Yes.
A burglary?
- No... I broke the chain...
Beatiful apartment...
I am working in the
telecommunications business.
So, when did she disappear?
- I left for Frankfurt on Tuesday evening.
- Do you often go on holiday without your wife?
- I often go abroad om business.
- I am in the telocommunications business!
- Have you called her?
Every day since Tuesday
and she's never home!
Have you left any messages?
- Yes!
Do you have children?
- No.
What does your wife do?
Nothing! She can afford anything she wants!
How does she spend her days?
- I often go abroad on business
- I work in the telecommunications business!
- Is everything all right between you two?
- Yes, of course. Look!
Are you the last person to have seen her?
- Yes..
No, you have to ask the other tenants!
These people say you are loud!
Do you drink often? My wife has disappeared.
I am worried! Worried...
I worked for a man
who worried about his wife,
like you...
She left me a souvenir...
She hadn't disappeared,
it was he who was afraid of disappearing.
- I quit! - You have done a good job.
I need you.
- You have nothing to fear!
Give me my money!
Pardon.
Sir!
Sir, Sir, Sir!
- What?
Will you take my sweets?
- I don't any sweets! Go away!
Take my sweets, please!
Give me back my doll!
What has it got to do with my wife?
What are you intending to do
about my wife?
As long as i don't have any evidence,
I can't do nothing!
And the door that was locked
from the inside yesterday?!
People disappear every day and often
it's less serious than one might think...
When can you come to fix the chain?
Very good... Ok... Thank you.
Freedom online, hello. - Dora!
Dan?
- I am back from Frankfurt.
I am going to take couple of days off.
I won't come in before Monday.
You can cancel all my appointments.
Are you ok, Dan?
I don't know where Edwige is.
I need to rest.
I'll cal you, Dora!
Hello? - Dan, if you need anything, I am here...
No.
- I can come over.
It's complicated enough already!
I'll call you, Dora!
Yes!
Hello?
Somebody is in my apartment!
I wasn't dreaming...
Somebody was here, watching me...
Your less is about to expire
and everybody is complaining about you!
Mister Dermont, my wife's disappeared!
She may have good reasons!
I don't like to sniff around my tenants,
but I advise you to be more discreet.
Free at last.
I just have to get rid of
that despicable man, Dan.
Now that I have discovered my true nature,
I know my vice as they call it,
is nothing other than my pleasure,
and my pleasure will be
to make him suffer.
Are you sure?
Do you know my wife?
I want to get to know you.
So you like mysterious phone calls?...
Edwige?
Honey...
Hello? Hello? Vincentelli?
I've been waiting for you for hours!
What have you been doing?!
Who is it?
- It's me!
Open up! Quick!
What is it? What do you want from me?
- I want help you!
Somebody is in your apartment...
...and wants to kill you!
What?
Yes, locked...
And I had put the security chain up
that I'd had fixed.
Are you sure? - Yes...
- So how could anybodyut your wife's head
in your apartment?
There is no sign of a break-in, Mr. Kristensen.
But I told you,
when returning from Frankfurt,
the security chain had been put...
and yet... there wasn't anybody
in the apartment.
somebody threatened me on the phone...
Wait...
Free at last...
I just have to get rid of
that despicable man, Dan.
Now that I have discovered my true nature,
I know that my vice as they call it...
...is nothing other than my pleasure,
and my pleasure will be to make him suffer,
as much as he made me suffer
during all those years.
His adoration is the worst of all gifts,
his gaze is the worst of all prisons.
He can keep my image to get lost in it,
there is nothing to find...
Is this your wife's voice?
There is a man with a beard
who sneaked into my apartment.
I know where to find him. He lives on the ground floor.
Are you sure it's him?
- Positive.
This is Mister Thys,
the tenant of the ground floor.
Does he live with anybody?
- Not since his sister died.
Does he have a beard?
- I don't know,
not to my knowledge.
Why are you asking me all these questions?
Is this still about Kristensen?
Mister Kristensen's wife has been found decapitated
with a stab wound at the top of her skull.
The suspect has a beard.
Is there a man with a beard living here?
No. I wouldn't know...
I'm afraid of what's inside me..
Something was inside me
and changed me...
My body became a stranger
and took over...
Sometimes I resist
but I feel the strenght...
As if there was another person
that lived with me inside me...
His strength becomes mine...
I couldn't control him any longer... I don't know what's true anymore...
He wants tome control me,
Sometimes it comes out of me... but it's always coming back...
I believe that I live in a constant nightmare.
I do not want to be ... more open ...
The desire silent ... or resist ...
How long can I go on resisting?
I know he'll be back..
How much longer can I resist?
Delivery service.
And? And Kristensen?
And ...
Come closer. I am the one
you are looking for.
You put me in danger.
- Do you hear me? - Yes!
All the apartments are connected.
I live in other people's places
when they are out.
There are old walls hidden behind
new ones in this building.
Walls from before it was spl,t
into apartments.
There are many ways to get into your place.
- Are you still there? - Yes!
Because of you,
I have to get away from this house.
I know a few secrets of the people
who live here.
Your wife knew some, too.
She knew some of a certain Laura.
All of this started as a game
that went further and further.
Your wife pushed the limits of her body
to find what was hiding inside.
Instead of finding
what she was looking for
she discovered Laura.
Laura...
Laura's secret tormented your wife...
Laura ... Your wife wanted to escape...
However ...she got caught
where Laura had found a new way...
where Laura keeps her secrets...
Vincentelli.
Leave a message after the beep.
Hello?
This is Dan Kristensen.
I... I am calling to tell you
I've found the man with the beard...
Behind a wall...
Laura...
- Laura?
Yes, Laura.
I saw her behind the walls.
She is a brunette with long hair.
- She turned towards me. - What are you talking about?
- Do you know her? - I knew a Laura.
She used to live here...
At the time she was a brunette...
but know she must be rather white-haired.
I doubt she is still alive.
Where is all this blood coming from?
- I cut myself.
It won't heal over.
Now that you know the old hallways
of the building,
You can't stay here any longer.
You can't just come in like that.
I want you to leave...!
"Your dark side is the most
beatiful thing you possess
and it will always belong to me. Sorry for your loss."
So you like mysterious phone calls?...
Laura...
You're crazy!
If hadn't shot, he'd be dead!
Somebody switch off the sound,
it's awfull!
Dora?...
It was you...
You're throwing away my flowers, darling?
Don't call me "darling" any more...
We broke up over 20 years ago...
Don't be mean!...
Please, put your clothes back on!
Now that she's gone, I can take care of you
- Like before. - Give me back my keys and leave!
I don't want to see you any more!
No!
THE STRANGE COLOR OF YOUR BODY'S FEARS