Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Scene 1.
Estuary of a great river
in the gulf of Thessaloniki...
around 1919.
A light mist wafts slowly
over the muddy earth...
that extends as far as the eye
can see, bare as a steppe...
A crowd of people appears,
walking slowly...
holding bundles and suitcases.
Their clothes, worn and dusty,
betray an old nobility.
A man of around 40
leads the way, with his wife...
a sickly woman. ..
and between them, two small children...
their son, a boy not more
than 5 years old...
and a little girl,
barely more than a baby.
Every so often the little girl
reaches out dazedly. ..
For the boy's hand.
As they approach the river,
the mass of humanity stops abruptly
as though someone
on the opposite bank...
shouted to them.
Hey! Who are you?
Where are you from?
We're Greeks.
Refugees from Odessa...
The boats brought us out
in Thessaloniki.
We were quarantined
for one month in the port...
eating out of cans...
Then the authorities
separated us.
They told us to go east.
You'll come to an ancient
column and a river...
From the column to the river
the land is yours.
The Bolshevik revolution
was spreading everywhere...
The Red Cavalry galloped...
the foreigners were fleeing...
The city's Greek community emptied.
We were the last ones left.
The Consul shouted:
Don't you realise
you're in danger?
And as though reliving a nightmare
the man begins to describe
the flight of the Greeks
from Odessa...
when on Saint Stefan's Day,
the Red Army entered the city.
As they left on the last ship,
they could still hear...
cries of desperation,
names in the wind, gunfire.
Then the man said:
"A cloud of smoke rose...
and the beloved city
disappeared
The little girl still searched
for the boy's hand.
The little girl next to my son
isn't ours...
We found her
crying in the turmoil...
over her mother's body,
on Pushkin Avenue...
if you've heard of it...
What's your name?
Eleni.
TRILOGY
The Weeping Meadow
a film by Theo Angelopoulos
Eleni's back!
- How do you feel, little one?
- Better, Auntie.
- Danae! Finally!
- I'll tell you everything.
- Unbelievable! And the twins?
- Adoption. I'll tell you later.
Eleni...
I brought your books.
Are you feeling better?
I'm thirsty.
Most of our people,
those who were unable to endure life...
here on the river
and went back to Thessaloniki...
are now leaving again.
America, Australia, Athens...
This land is killing us.
We should have left too in '22...
when those peasants came
from the Orient...
Your brother Spyros
wouldn't hear of it, Cassandra.
Danae, the girl's delirious...
If Spyros found out anything,
he'd kill her.
It's pointless.
The girl's not of our blood.
Have you spoken to your son?
- He's in a daze.
- Of course! After what he did!
Couldn't you have prevented it?
By the time I found out,
it was too late.
Good thing I came up with
that story about her being sick...
and took her to my sister
in Thessaloniki...
for the last months...
Then we found that good woman.
You know her husband's
a merchant. Childless.
No, no, the twins
are in good hands.
Spyros!
And your son, behind his father
as though nothing happened.
Hello, brother!
Eleni!
- Eleni!
- I was expecting you.
I was in the cellar,
behind a door.
I heard my mother
and the women whispering.
My head buzzed.
- Does it hurt?
- Not any more.
I didn't know what to do
while you were gone...
I'd go down to the river
and look at the water.
Remember we used to say
we'd follow the river...
to find the source?
I wrote you a letter.
Eleni...
I want to say that...
you know...
I care a lot about you.
Eleni!
The bride has gone!
Hallelujah!
Eleni!
Oh Lord, save thy people
and bless thine inheritance...
To our Rulers grant victories
over the barbarians...
and by thy Cross
protect thine own Estate.
The bride has gone!
Spyros!
Eleni wasn't for you!
She was raised
like your daughter.
This marriage was not
appropriate for you.
Poor Spyros. Ever since Danae
died in the great epidemic...
he's been eaten up
by loneliness.
He yearned for the girl.
I stood behind her
in the church...
The wedding ceremony ended.
The priest said "Amen"...
and suddenly I saw her
turn around...
Her face shone pale
like the Virgin.
She said to Spyros:
"I've forgotten something"...
And she ran out...
I ran after her.
I managed to see her lift
the skirt of her wedding dress...
and disappear down the road
leading to the river.
A car!
The whole village
is looking for you.
Was it you
playing the accordion all night?
Where are you going?
Spyros!
A boy has come from the river.
Our brothers want you
to go there.
Spyros!
Thanks! So long!
Come along!
Hell, you've got to spend
the night somewhere!
Don't be scared!
You're under the protection
of a fiddle...
a guitar, a clarinet
and a noisy fourth instrument!
- Good night.
- I'm sorry it didn't happen.
- Good night, Nikos.
Good night.
"Thessaloniki,
city of refugees."
Isn't that what they call it?
A wound that will not heal.
This theatre is my home.
- Good evening.
This is where the authorities
brought us in early '22...
after the destruction
of Smyrna.
The courtyard of miracles.
85 families.
Good evening, Amy.
I'm having no luck with
this game of solitaire.
Courage !
Our good girl.
- Good evening, Irini.
- Good evening, Nikos.
- I see you have company.
- Good evening.
That prima donna
you can hear singing has a sister.
She doesn't talk to me.
She prays.
She lies with the Book
of Revelation in her hands...
open at the same chapter...
her finger pointing
to the same passage...
and my mother asleep as always.
Good night, Mum.
My music will be in its place
and the lamp lit as always.
"Nikos, the fiddler,"
as I'm known on the streets...
is also a graduate
of the Smyrna Conservatory, but...
You'll stay here...
until you decide where you'll go,
what you'll do.
Are you cold?
The women will take care of you.
As I said, kid.
I heard you play.
That's gold you have
in your hands. Don't bury it.
Good night.
- Good night.
I still can't believe
we're in a theatre!
M'! boys!
How many times
have I said it?
Watch your posture.
Body upright, back straight...
feet in front.
Keep your hands nicely
poised over the keyboard.
Work together.
Listen to each other.
You have the melody, Yorgos.
Louder, more outgoing!
Always in secret...
like a thief!
"And I heard a great voice
out of the temple...
saying to the seven angels,
'Go your ways and...“
Hey, where did you disappear to?
We went for a walk downtown.
Good night.
Alright. We'll talk in the morning.
The offer stands, kid.
- Good night.
"And the first went, and poured out
his vial upon the earth...
and there fell a noisome
and grievous sore upon the men...
which had the mark of
the beast...
and upon them which
worshipped his image
Eleni!
- What is it?
- Nothing, mother. Go to sleep.
- What's going on, Nikos?
- Nothing.
Eleni!
You can't stay here
any longer.
Let's
I know you're here!
Come on!
Go to the neighbourhood
with the sheets!
- The clothes we borrowed?
- Go! Go!
Eleni!
I know you're here!
That woman you're holding
in your arms, my son...
that's my wife!
You've shamed me.
I no longer have
any pride or honour.
Everyone pities me.
I know you're here,
goddamn you!
Eleni!
Eleni...
Are you awake?
Good morning, Costas.
Good morning, Mrs Coula.
The house next door flooded.
And I've got a leaky roof.
- Good morning.
- Good morning. Just a minute.
- Did you sleep well last night?
- It was a little difficult.
Christ, what a downpour that was...
all night long.
We're late.
Katerina!
Katerina! I brought you
the recipe.
- Good morning, Frosso.
- What good morning!
I've been hanging clothes
since the crack of dawn.
- Good morning.
- 'Morning.
Welcome to the musicians' hangout.
D'you mind waiting here
for a while?
Come along, my girl.
America!
You didn't answer me.
I sold a ring of my mother's.
What?
I couldn't see you
in other people's clothes any more.
- What's the matter?
- I don't know.
I feel strange...
as though someone's watching us.
Father!
Zissis!
We're leaving!
- Good evening.
- An ouzo, boss!
- Regular? Double?
- With this weather? Double!
- Coming right up!
- Double. Dry.
- Come on in, guys.
- 'Evening.
Nikos, the fiddler.
Nondas, the bouzouki player.
Achilles plays
the toumbeleki.
It's not a great gig, guys...
something on the fly...
but for want of anything better...
How about it?
You need to ask?
When do we leave?
Tonight. We'll just make
the night train.
- So? What will it be?
- We're out of here!
- An ouzo.
- Coming right up.
Let's see now.
What have we got?
Clarinet, toumbeleki,
bouzouki, violin...
- and...
- Accordion?
He's coming. If he agrees...
- Good evening.
- Hello there, kid.
You wanted to see me?
I got us a gig-
We're missing an accordion player.
How about it?
It won't be for long.
That way you can see
if you've got what it takes.
I'm out of here.
I've got to get ready.
I'd like it to be you.
You!
I can't forget that night
when I heard you play...
for the first time.
- Good evening.
- Hello there.
Nikos has proposed
we go with him.
We were leaving anyway.
He came again last night
and prowled around.
Goddammit!
Then a train went by
and he disappeared.
As though it took him with it.
Nikos!
Closed!
- I've been had.
- I'll go ask next door.
And now what do we do? What?
What do we do indeed?
Nikos, guys, the joint's closed.
That's what they said.
Sorry, kid,
your first road tour backfired.
I'm here because you said
I've got gold in my hands.
We lost.
He said we lost...
but at least
let's go back in style.
In style.
My hat!
I've lost my hat.
I've lost my hat!
I'm leaving.
I wouldn't want...
I wouldn't want to play
in tavernas and at weddings.
That's not music.
We came from the Black Sea and
Asia Minor seeking a homeland...
and they're carting us around
here and there like animals!
They're turning this
into a camp.
They're bringing army units
from the south.
That's all we needed!
A war!
Hello, guys.
- Where's the kid?
- Upstairs.
Hey, kid!
Hello, guys.
How's it going?
I'm listening.
Markos is looking for you.
You know who he is.
He's putting together a band
and wants an accordion player.
He heard about you.
- Markos? Me?
- Yes.
I've been wanting to tell you for days
but because Nikos...
you see, the fiddler
has a soft spot for you...
I didn't want to and...
Come this afternoon
so he can hear you play.
- OK?
- OK.
I just came for you.
Markos...
Sit there and get ready.
Markos! He's here.
What shall I tell him?
He's listening.
Markos asks
what's that you're playing?
Something of mine.
Kid!
He asked me to tell you
it's been a long time...
since he heard such a sound...
He's getting ready to go
on tour in America...
to play for the Greeks there.
What do you say? Interested?
America!
I think I'm dreaming!
Don't get carried away.
It's not for tomorrow.
It takes time.
Eleni!
Watch out!
Thanassis! What happened?
Long live the popular front!
General strike!
Would you like to dance?
I'm waiting for the boat.
Eleni!
- You thought I betrayed you?
- Yes.
You really thought
I betrayed you?
Yes.
How is that possible?
America!
Alexis!
Paulina! Wait!
Wait! Paulina!
- Good morning.
Hello.
Boys!
Boys! Come here!
Yannis... Yorgos...
won't you say hello?
Won't you say hello?
He's angry“!-
They were hard times.
I don't know if you can
understand that.
Maybe we do.
The other kids at school
have a name.
What name do we have?
Eleni... your mother...
and I thought...
we'd take you for a stroll.
I want to think about it.
He's angry“!-
Paulina! Wait!
Good evening.
- Good evening.
One coffee,
easy on the sugar, please.
What a shame!
He isn't here.
Is this the musicians' hangout?
That's right.
But no one's here now?
And what do musicians do here?
Musicians?
Musicians...
Musicians are spread out
all around here...
and they wait.
Then some people come...
on the street
we call them customers...
who own a taverna...
or are looking for a musician
to play at some party...
They walk in front of
each musician...
and cup their hand
behind their ear...
as though they're saying:
I'm listening. Play!
And they take their pick.
Someone picks a fiddler.
Another a clarinet player.
Another a guitarist...
And what do you do?
Me?
And you, Mum?
You called me "Mum," Yorgis?
The party organizations and
trade unions who are fighting...
to defend the interests of the people
have decided...
to form a popular front.
Comrades! Comrades!
Only if workers rally
and fight under the flag...
of the popular front
will the people's demands be met.
The popular front calls on
all the antifascist...
Nikos!
I had to tell you.
- Markos asked for me.
- So I heard.
Good morning.
I knew you'd leave some day.
You're special.
Guys! The gendarmes!
Let's
This way!
Everyone's afraid the General
will stage a coup...
with the King's consent...
and no one's talking.
Days of 36...
dark nights...
I miss you, kid.
I said cut it out.
I'm thinking.
Nikos, the dance...
it looks like it can't happen.
What do we do?
Shall we break it up?
I'm bringing the drinks
and I'm not asking!
What's going on, you guys?
People got tired of waiting.
They all went home.
It's deserted out there.
- Can't you see?
- What are we supposed to do?
The old beer hall.
That's where we'll hold
the dance!
I just thought of it!
In the old beer hall!
- In that old dump?
- So what?
Wine we've got.
Music we've got.
And there's that old piano there.
You go out there
and tell them.
OK.
I will.
Saxophone!
I'm someone condemned
to creating in the mud!
The tavernas don't want us.
They're afraid of the police.
So we decided to hold
the trade union dance...
in the old beer hall!
We'll have music!
And we'll have wine!
And we can sing without
the wind carrying off our voices.
We're expecting you there!
There's a lot of people coming!
Music!
Get chairs!
Chairs, guys!
It's nothing...
a friend turned informer!
The strike will take place!
Music!
I heard...
that this kid can make
even the trees dance.
I want him to play for me.
He knows what.
Music!
I killed him.
Father's sheep.
- What is it?
- I hear voices.
The basement's flooded.
The village is drowning
in the river.
There are boats floating
in the square.
What shall we do?
Hey!
A boat!
For the love of God.
I have children!
A boat!
There's a boat waiting downstairs,
under the balcony.
I don't know who sent it.
Wake the boys!
Boys! Wake up! Let's go!
- Where are we going?
- We're leaving, we're leaving.
Eleni!
Omnipotent, dark curse
that has yet to run its course...
Nikos!
What we were afraid of, kid,
it's happened.
Our feeble democracy
committed suicide.
Fascism is spreading
over the skies of Europe.
They've arrested
all the guys from the union.
I've nowhere to go.
Onward for a new Greece!
Onward with a Greek heart!
Onward proudly, bravely
with the boys of Greece!
Falangists!
Onward, for our past glory
in time will live again!
When I woke up and didn't see you
beside me, I was afraid.
I wanted to look at the sea.
It's your first day outside.
I longed for this day.
All these months I went and
saw the children every day.
All this time you were silent...
I trembled at the thought
of losing you...
So much happened.
I was suffocating.
Nikos!
I hid him for as long
as I could!
- You're here, kid?
- I'm here.
I wanted to say goodbye
to you too.
- Third whistle, Markos.
- We're leaving.
Leave a boat for the kid.
He might still make it.
We're leaving.
Have a good journey!
Write to us!
Take care of yourselves!
Have a good journey!
They left!
Markos and the others left.
There's a boat waiting for you.
Don't be mad at me, Yorgis.
Is America far away?
Yannis, Yorgis...
You take care of your mum.
I didn't have time to finish it.
New York, 5 March 1937.
My little Eleni...
We arrived in America
with our hearts in our mouths...
after facing danger
a thousand times on the ocean.
At Ellis Island,
they put us through a fine sieve...
Disinfections, humiliation...
Slowly, tortuously,
everything was done in darkness.
I woke up in a dirty room
that smelled of vomit.
Markos was snoring next to me.
This is America?
We began playing in some dive,
but dissension soon set in
among the band.
There is no progress on the papers
for you and the kids.
My aunt won't even hear of it.
I found an old Italian teacher
to give me piano lessons...
to forget the ocean
that separates us...
Eleni!
Who is it?
Who's there?
My children!
Our soldiers march on
with a smile on their lips!
You idiot, Mussolini,
you'll have no one left...
When we march into Rome itself
we'll raise the Greek flag!
Astoria, New York.
30 October 1940.
We heard the news here.
I cried.
I had hoped the war
wouldn't spread to our land.
Will our country hold out?
The Nazi war machine
follows Mussolini with iron steps.
I decided to enlist
in the American army.
It's the only way I can become
a citizen and bring you here.
But when? When?
America still hasn't entered the war,
but it won't be long.
I'm afraid of the dark days to come.
Write to me.
I am sickened at the thought...
that this might be
the last letter to reach you.
Where are you taking me now?
You're getting out.
You've got a son who is
a soldier, right?
I was notified
by the army command...
you're to go by there,
today even, for news of him.
What are you trying to say?
I heard you're from
a border village...
that was lost years ago
in a flood.
What are you trying to say?
There's also a letter
that came for you from America.
It took 4 years to get here.
It was found near the body
of a dead American soldier...
after the last battle
in the Pacific.
Ladies, the sad duty of greeting you
has fallen to me.
Your husbands, brothers, sons,
lie behind you...
on the field of honour.
My boy!
My Son!
Yannis!
MY Son!
No!
Don't sleep!
Wake up!
Wake up, sweetheart!
Wake up, my Yannis,
for your mother!
I was cleaning
the commander's office...
when the soldiers
brought her in.
I never expected to see her again
after so many years.
You treated her unjustly then.
I know.
It's been weighing on me.
I'll go get some water.
Guard...
I have no water...
I have no soap...
I have no paper
to write to my children...
The uniforms change...
You wear gray, guard...
Guard, you wear black.
My name is Eleni.
I'm here for harbouring
an insurgent.
Where are you taking me now?
Guard...
I have no water...
I have no soap...
I have no paper
to write to my children...
The uniforms change...
The Germans wear green...
Are you German, guard?
My name is Eleni.
I'm here for harbouring
an insurgent.
Where are you taking me now?
I was there too, in December of '44,
in the square...
where people were celebrating
the liberation.
Where are you taking me now?
The uniforms change.
Are you English, guard?
How much does a bullet cost?
How much does blood?
All uniforms are
the same, guard...
Guard...
I have no water...
I have no soap...
I have no paper
to write to my children...
Where are you taking me now?
My name is Eleni.
I'm here for hiding
a wounded guerrilla...
Guard...
I'm in exile...
I'm a refugee and
exiled from everywhere.
A three-year-old girl
crying on the quay...
I have no water...
I have no soap...
I have no paper
to write to my children...
She's fallen asleep.
You go. I'll stay.
Damn civil war.
You had two sons, my girl.
What did you say?
You had two sons.
What are you saying?
Yes, ma'am.
Keep your head down.
This is a forbidden zone.
Keep your head down!
This is where the battle
took place.
The army on this side...
and the guerrillas
on the other side of the embankment.
I'm looking for Yorgis!
I'm looking for
Captain Yorgis!
Who wants me?
Don't you recognise me?
I'm Yannis, your brother.
The war, Yannis.
The war's changed us.
It's Mum, Yorgis.
We've lost our mum.
They found her
huddled up in the cell.
Ah, Yorgis!
Ah, Yannis!
They parted
and the battle continued.
AH the guerrillas that escaped
disappeared across the border.
Your other son, ma'am,
lies over there...
in the ruins of that big house.
Where are you going?
There are patrols!
March 1945,
Kerama islands.
American base in the Pacific,
25 miles west of Okinawa.
My Eleni,
I've had your letter of 1 December 1944
in my pocket since yesterday...
It's a miracle it even got here...
after so many months of
going around the world.
I laugh and cry.
Thank God you are well
and our country is now free.
I celebrated by getting drunk
alone in my tent.
You complain I've forgotten you.
How could that be?
AH these years
not a moment has gone by...
when I haven't thought of you.
We're here
in these strange islands,
in the mud of a yellow river,
rotting with our guns in our hands,
day in and day out...
60,000 commandos,
60,000 men about to die...
waiting to ship out
for the hell named Okinawa.
Last night I dreamed that
we set off together...
to find the source
of the river.
An old man led the way.
As we walked on,
the river became smaller...
and broke up into
a thousand small streams...
Suddenly, high above
under the snow-capped peaks...
the old man showed us
a piece of land with wild grass...
in a shady and damp place.
Every blade of grass held
little drops of dew...
that fell every so often
on the soft earth.
"This meadow," said the old man,
"is the source of the river."
You reached out and touched
the wet grass...
and when you raised your hand
a few drops rolled down...
and fell on the earth
like tears...
My Yorgis!
My boy!
My sweet boy!
Get up, my Yorgis!
I don't have anybody any more.
Nobody to think of.
Nobody to wait for at night.
Nobody to love.
You were him...
and you were you.
Translated by Elly Petrides
 