KILLER
Directed by:
Deredzhan Omirbaev
"God doesn't exist
in an age of change"
Ancient Chinese wisdom
We can begin.
Dear listeners,
Your Own Time
brings you now
our regular feature
"Guest of Honor".
Our guest today is a member of
the Academy of Sciences,
research director at the
Institute of Mathematics,
doctor of mathematics,
Professor Kassymov.
Here's my first question,
Mr. Kassymov.
Is it difficult to be
a scientist nowadays?
Are you waiting for someone?
For my boss. I'm a chauffeur.
He's here for an interview.
Thank you, that's fine.
Indeed, haute couture is unbelievable.
So you prefer haute couture...
It's much prettier
and of course, it requires a lot of work.
Hours of work go into a dress
before it can be put on show.
- Is that the way out?
- Thank you.
- Which is the way out?
- That way. - Thank you.
- Where's the way out?
- Over there. - Thank you.
That way.
Thank you.
- Where's the way out?
- That way. - Thanks.
The troubles of our day reside
less in material problems,
my colleagues, for example
haven't been paid for 6 months,
than in psychological problems.
In fact, all our moral
guidelines have disappeared.
Hence this feeling of inconstancy
and instability in our lives.
No one knows any more what
tomorrow will bring,
as the pace of change is so rapid.
Nothing around us stable any more.
Working hours, weekends, vacations,
wages, futureplans for one's profession,
nothing makes sense,
and it seems to me,
it can't carry on
like this much longer.
We can't all become
speculators or shopkeepers.
Someone has to produce things.
It's hard to work properly when
everything is collapsing around you.
The great ideals are abandoned
and they can be stolen without risk.
If I don't steal,
someone else will.
This is called the primitive
accumulation of the capital.
Berik Karakoulovitch,
let's tackle a more concrete subject.
Science, a domain
in which you excel.
We know that many scientific
centers today are closing
or are in danger of closing.
So my question may seem brutal
but it has to be asked.
What's the point of science
in a country where almost all adults,
as you said, live of commerce?
You're free, Marat.
Go to the maternity.
Is it a boy or a girl?
A son. Good.
Be here at five, as usual.
Thank you, Berik Karakoulovitch.
- Hello.
- Hello, Tasmira Moukatovna.
- After you...
- Thank you.
You'll see him at home.
Have you thought of a name?
I tried, but I couldn't find one.
They say he takes after me
I think he's more like you.
Let me see him again.
Don't say you're
not in the wrong.
Do I call the cops?
I couldn't brake in time.
Give me your ID.
Marat, what if we sold the apartment?
It would pay for the
repair of the two cars.
Know what it's like changing
apartments all the time here.
We have to go see the
family and ask their advice.
Go see Aunt Saoule
she's your sister after all.
Hi Aibek,
is your mom home?
What's up?
Aibek?
What're you doing?
Get back to your room.
Serik, what happened?
Ask your sister! She'll tell you.
We were ripped off. A month ago
I put our money in a trust and
now we learned they were crooks.
We? You gave them
the money, you moron.
You knew what I was doing
and you didn't stop me.
Don't you think at your age?
Why do I have to tell you
what to do?
I'm sick of looking
after you. Idiot.
- That's enough now.
- Marat...
Listen Marat.
I know people who lend
money with interest.
- But at what rate?
- I think it's 1% per day.
That's 30% per month.
That are the rates.
But it will help you
to come through.
Think so?
Don't care about tomorrow.
You've got a visitor. Who?
What do we do, Marat?
The garage called me today.
The car's ready
but they want their money.
You time's up, you know
I don't have it yet.
That's what I thought.
Unfortunately,
I can't wait any longer.
I need my car, to go to work,
everyday.
Hi Marat.
Hi Oleg.
- Am I late?
- No. What's with your eye?
- I banged it. - That's what I thought.
Let me introduce you.
Marat.
Erjan Chakenovitch.
He can help with the money.
Oleg explained things.
If you're serious, let's go.
Marat! Where did you and Oleg serve?
Karelia, in Petrozavodsk.
That's far away.
In which division?
Inland.
I served in East Germany
a long time ago.
Those were the days.
Heard the one about the new Kazakhs?
No.
Nazarbaiev tells the new Kazakhs.
Our invaluable brains
and arms have gone.
Only your gold teeth remain.
Bravo.
Hello.
What?
Oh hello.
Here's the money you asked for.
Oleg said you know
the conditions.
There you are.
- Thanks. You're doing me a big favor.
- Don't mention it.
If I need you, I'll call.
Sorry, I had no choice.
These days, it's the only thing
people understand.
Let's shake hands.
What happened?
Berik Karakoulovitch
killed himself in his office.
What?
Didn't you know?
They closed down the laboratory
and gave the building to a bank.
Put the car away
and look for a new job.
- Look.
- Ok, give it to the captain.
This should be noted
in the report.
In the Gospel according to St. Matthew
Jesus said ironically:
If the flesh is born of the spirit,
it is a miracle.
If the spirit is born of the body
it is the miracle of miracles.
The history of mathematics shows that
the miracle of miracles is impossible.
Take the key moment in mathematics
when it made its first steps,
the most important for mankind's
emerging logical demonstration.
This very basis excludes any
possibility of practical applications.
Thale's thesis
established clear truths
for all men of reason,
such as that one saying the diameter
divides the circle in 2 equal parts.
It wasn't to check the truth of these
theses that required a genius,
but to understand that they
required a demonstration.
In other words, the practical value of
these discoveries is non-existing.
Mathematics became a Science
in the 6th century B.C.
In the religious circle
of the Pythagoreans.
Their goal was simply,
to permit the fusion
with the divine,
by grasping the world's harmony,
by expressing it in numbers.
So you're sure you want to leave?
The road may be dangerous.
Aren't you afraid?
Have you got a better idea?
I don't want to become
a street seller.
Where will you find the money'?
Borrow it again?
I have no choice.
I'll be okay if I sell the car.
Does Aijan agree?
Aijan? I don't care if
she agrees or not.
I have to run or
I'll get trouble.
Finish eating and wait at the back.
I'll come with some food.
Are you calling from Germany'?
What? You're already in Russia.
Which one?
Why a Nissan? You want a BMW.
What year'?
No, he's not sick.
Look be careful!
There's a lot of theft.
All right.
In how long'?
We'll see. Ok, bye. See you soon.
Catch him up.
The Bastards.
That's the third they've stolen.
If we look at our lives
in simple terms,
we're like passengers,
lost in a long tunnel.
We can no longer see
the light at the entrance
and the light at the
other end is so weak
that we look for it all the time
and keep losing sight of it.
We're not even sure
that there is an entrance and an exit.
All around us,
due to confusion,
or the exacerbation of our feelings,
all we see are monsters,
depending on our moods
and our wounds,
like in an exciting,
exhausting game of kaleidoscopes
What to do?
Or even what is the point?
You don't ask questions
like that here.
Well, to return to
the subject in hand.
The first time you
borrowed 4,000 dollars.
Today that makes with 42 days'
interest 1,680 dollars.
A total of 5,680 dollars.
Then, you borrowed 5,000
to go to Germany to buy a car.
Plus 28 days' interest,
1,400 dollars.
In all, you owe 12,080.
Is that right?
Yes, that's right.
You have a 2 room apartment.
A prefab building in a good situation.
At best, we could get 7,000 for it.
How will you find the rest?
Erjan! Dana's calling.
Listen to your father, my girl.
You must finish your studies
and find a job over there,
you hear'?
Whoever comes back
from the States these days?
Why did I spend all that
money on your studies?
Don't be silly. Listen to me.
You're bored.
How can anyone be bored
over there?
Excuse me.
Where is Erjan Chakenovitch?
He's asleep.
Asleep?
He's from the South,
he always sleeps after lunch.
He said Oleg will be in touch.
I think it may be far more
serious than you thought.
Your child is suffering from
intracranial hypertension.
That's why he cries a lot.
He needs an ultrasonic scan
and urgent treatment.
The sooner the better.
I'll give you the address
of a good masseur.
He's rather expensive,
but he's good.
I think that 20 sessions
should be enough.
Last month, he charged
10 dollars per session.
Aijan, here's the address.
What for'? We can't afford it.
On, hi Oleg.
You know how things are.
Why did I leave?
Because he'd fallen asleep.
Ok, I'm coming.
What if I can't manage it?
Look. You don't know Erjan
Chakenovitch. He's though.
Listen to my advice.
Don't mess with him.
If you're successful,
he'll not only forgive
all your debts,
but you'll also get
10,000 from me.
What has this journalist
done to you?
To me, nothing.
But to Chakenovitch's friends, a lot.
I'm not involved.
I'm just carrying out orders.
It seems that he ran them down
in an article.
About a factory they
want to privatize.
Something like that.
What difference does it make?
- Who is it?
- Oleg, the beer's here.
So unload!
I'll be right out.
Anyway-
Here's the guy's photo.
He's a journalist.
He writes for a famous newspaper.
Here's his address.
He goes walking by the river
near his house in the evening.
I'm sure you know
you have to leave this there,
so there's nothing
to connect you.
I'll be right back.
Got the time?
5:45
Thanks.
Autumn started early this year.
It's only October
and the trees are bare.
On the one hand it must be nice
to live in a warm country.
No winter, so
no need to spend money,
on heating, warm clothes,
and so on.
On the other hand,
no winter means no spring.
How can they live
without spring?
No way. I wouldn't swap spring
for anything in the world.
It's better to endure the harsh winter,
and then see the spring arrive.
Dad.
We've been waiting
for a while.
Maybe he already
took out the trash.
Do we wait all night?
We'll wait a while.
He usually takes it out
around this time.
- Is it midnight already'?
- Not yet.
There's still some light.
They turn it off at midnight here.