UNTAMED
Hideko Takamine
Ken Uehara
Daisuke Katou
Masa Mori
Mitauko Miura
Tsutomu Higashino
Tatsuya Nakadai
Seiko Miyaguchi
Hide Shimura
Directed by Naruse Mikio
BEGINNING OF THE TAISHO ERA
That's the new wife
who arrived last night.
She's younger than the last one.
Are you on your way somewhere?
I dropped by as
I happened to be passing.
I'll pay a visit to your place later.
Now, you can leave the store
anytime you want.
Yes, thanks to you.
Sick and tired of weak women
like your ex-wife, right?
Yes. As long as a wife is healthy
and works hard, I have no complaints.
Shima is the one for you, then.
I have to earn back the money that
I spent for my ex-wife's hospitalization.
And for sending her
to the seashore and all.
Shima has worked like a horse for her
adoptive family since she was seven.
How did you get
that scar on your hand?
My mother burnt me with tongs
when I was little.
I was adopted for a long time.
Though I went back home from time
to time, I always felt isolated there.
It must have been tough.
Not at all. I had a better
life at the adoptive family.
Is that right?
Your husband is a handsome man.
You two will look great
walking down the street together.
His ex-wife favoured things
that were cheap but chic.
She owned quite valuable stuff things
like combs, hairpins, and the like.
If you can get all those,
it will be quite a fortune.
You put on too much make-up!
I'll lend you Okayo's kimono.
Go change into something more sober.
I can't wear any. They're too old
fashioned, although the quality is good.
I can't wear something a woman
ten years older than me wore.
You should loosen
your belt a bit, too.
I used to be a gardener for nobles.
My family has always been important.
He doesn't work unless
he's in the mood for it.
That's the problem with him.
He has a real artisan spirit.
He also has asthma.
That's too bad.
When is her brother
going back to the mountains?
He came here to buy some trees, so...
Please, come visit us at our store.
Thank you. We feel relieved
that she married you.
She once escaped from a wedding.
She didn't like the groom that
her adoptive family decided for her.
She is so selfish.
She troubled the adoptive family a lot.
The Mizushima's are really upset with her.
I didn't know you disliked men.
- She tries to look prudish.
- Want your face slapped?
Stop it.
Anyway, I'm happy that a decent
man like you married her.
But what if she fails
to serve you properly?
She is such an odious wretch. You can
punish her to make her work hard.
I'll get it.
Hello? My husband?
What's that?
He's not home yet.
Who is it? Hello? Hello?
You can lock the door.
Good night.
Is that you?
Why lock the door?
How long must I keep knocking for?
Because you didn't answer me.
I didn't know what time
you'd be home.
The master of the house has to call
out his name to enter his own place?
Listen...
I think something is
happening with my body.
I might be pregnant.
I think it's too early.
I doubt it's mine.
Why?
You were married once, right?
Married to whom?
Don't pretend you don't know.
I really don't know.
You know that I sneaked out from home
on the night before the wedding.
But, why do your legal documents
say you married,
though you escaped from the wedding?
My parents registered it
without telling me.
It's not a question of
if you liked the guy or not.
It's the fact that you were married.
I don't know what document they made.
If you doubt it, go check with my family.
He's a dummy who used to walk me
to school and home when we were kids.
I don't care about it.
But, you slept with him, right?
No. My adoptive family
also adopted him.
The family planned to marry us
in order to keep their family line.
Everyone laughs at me,
because of you.
What do you mean?
Are you jealous?
Don't insult me!
Is that's why you are out
drinking every night?
You don't believe me?
If so, it's so heartless of you.
The night before the wedding, I ran away
to my sister's and I never went back there.
Everyone called me a betrayer.
Stop whining. Go to sleep.
I'm visiting the factory
in Hokkaido, tomorrow.
What time are you leaving?
Early in the morning?
Stop sobbing.
You get a lot of calls from a woman.
You can't blame me
for having married or whatever.
You're really giving me all these things?
- They are wasted in a closet anyway.
But...
Sis. Look at this letter.
Came to him from the woman.
From Hokkaido?
He often sends her
a kimono or perfume.
That's not cheap.
She wrote to thank your husband.
Is she a geisha?
He doesn't really go to Hokkaido for
the factory. He visits her everyday.
"Soon, the master of the
paper mill is taking me to Tokyo.
"Then, I can see you there everyday.
I want to see you.
I'm dying to be with you.
"Hope you know how I feel."
He's an idiot. Every time he gets
back from there, he hums.
So embarrassing
in front of the workers.
He must have learned how to fool
around while his ex-wife was sick.
No matter how well I take care of the
money, he spends it on her, it's no use.
But, you have a nice ring at least.
I'm married off to a poor man.
I'll give it to you.
It won't suit an old wife like me.
It's cheap stuff, anyway. Take it.
Thanks.
I'm just a replacement wife.
Why shouldn't I be allowed to have
some freedom sometimes?
Why didn't you take me
instead of her then?
This is only between us though,
I've been crying.
Why?
His mother comes even to our bedroom.
Sorry to hear that.
His mother has problems with her legs
and back. She spoils her only son badly.
She doesn't let him work,
keeps her eye on him day and night...
and even stays with him
till he falls asleep.
She's worried you might make him sick.
Me? Make him sick?
Because you are so...
Don't say that.
Since I was around...
It's always nice
and quiet around here.
Tsuru is here, too.
Is he?
If I knew how she was,
I would have married you...
How could a daughter of
the Kanna be interested...
in the son of
a canned food manufacturer.
You didn't have enough passion.
If only we could start all over.
Tsuru's wife is here.
What did she come here for?
You don't have to stand up for her.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Tsuru, you shouldn't be so cranky.
You are mature enough
to take this, aren't you?
Have you got used to here, yet?
I don't know much because I'm from
the countryside. He always scolds me.
Look at her.
She thinks she's a city girl, putting
too much make-up on her swollen face.
Don't be so mean to her.
My face gets swollen because...
I don't sleep well.
Working at the store and the kitchen.
Too tired to be his whore at night.
I didn't say that.
Cut it out.
You, too. Stop talking back.
Women shouldn't talk back like that.
Tsuru, why don't you help her
with some proper clothes to wear?
Shall we have some tea over there.
Unfortunately my wife is out.
Go home.
Your belly is sticking out.
Stop it. Please, come inside.
Is it hard to be an accountant?
She's terrible.
She gets so proud of herself
for getting new suppliers.
But they don't have any money.
Ends up with more work for me to do.
Whatever women do
they always end up with nothing,
and men have to make up for it.
Take it easy till she gets used to it.
He blames me for all those
he can't make money with.
I wanted you to hear this
in front of her.
You forget your own shortcomings.
Tell me! What are your complaints?
She's common.
It sounds good that
she was adopted at 18.
But, in fact she was like
a maid to the family.
I set up your marriage.
She suddenly became
the wife of a rich man.
She thinks it's a waste
if she doesn't spend my money.
You said that my clothes
smelt like mud.
She was adopted by farmers.
It's hard to become like a city girl.
Our store, The Shinsyo,
is ruined since she came.
You ruined it, too,
going out every night.
What?
You are even.
Shima, you sound a bit mean to him.
I understand you have your complaints
but you should compromise a bit.
Go home. You shouldn't
leave the store for so long.
Let her stay.
She hasn't been here for long.
Sorry if I disturbed you.
I'm leaving.
Are you leaving so soon?
Look at her dress.
Don't be so mean.
You are going home, right?
I'm visiting them again.
He won't be there any more.
He'd still be there.
- Just apologize to him.
- That's not my way.
You don't need to go back
to fight again.
- What's wrong?
- My clog thong got cut off.
- Is it OK?
- Yes.
I was suspicious of that girl, Oyu,
more than the woman in Hokkaido.
She disgusts me with her horny voice.
Depressing story. It's the fate of a
wife who has a handsome husband.
How can he be so open about it?
If I work hard, he gets scared
that a woman will control him.
He's scared as if his head
was about to be shaved or sold.
Yes.
He does whatever he wants but he
wants to save his face at the same time.
He calls me "Peak Belly".
I didn't have my belly stuck out
when I was born.
If I work, men complain that
I'm not sexy enough.
I'm not a Geisha.
I can't be all over him all day long.
I hate a sissy man like him.
I can go alone from here.
My workers are waiting for me
at the store.
I don't have time to complain.
Welcome, I'm back.
Good night.
What are you doing
at this time of night?
Writing a letter to that woman?
Give me that!
Let me go!
You scratched me.
I didn't know
you were violent like this.
I'll tell you something.
If you do everything your way,
the business will be finished.
This business belongs to my ex-wife.
I'll lose face
if I lose the business.
I don't know whose child
you are having but
I'll do you a favour
to raise him a great man.
A favour? This is your child.
You listen to Oyu's
complaints about me.
What?
Does it annoy you if I buy a Kimono
while you buy them for other women?
Shut up.
Go downstairs and sleep there.
I will.
I mean right now.
Don't be so rough with me.
What are you doing?
You idiot.
- Get out of this house.
- I will.
I've never heard of a woman fighting
physically with a man like she did.
Taku, good that you didn't marry her.
He came here to ask if
we could take Shima again.
Did she get kicked out?
Her baby died because
she fell on the stairs.
Her husband has had enough of her.
She's no use here.
Taku has a wife already.
She doesn't get along with her mother
since she lived here for 10 years.
She has nowhere to go.
Will you take her, please?
She ran away from the wedding.
We can't face Taku's parents
if we take her back here.
I will make her work harder,
so please.
Your son moves around on his trips.
You must worry a lot.
Is his wife is still in her country?
Do you want one?
It's so far.
There are only mountains.
You can find interesting things to do
if you get used to living there.
You can survive almost anywhere.
If I find a job there,
I will work hard.
And, I'll come back.
Eat this on the train.
Thank you.
I don't want to wait here alone.
The trees I brought from Tokyo
don't suit the land here.
They almost died before being sold.
Then I couldn't have sold them
even at the rice mill.
What are you going to do?
I'm leaving for Chiba again.
Chiba?
Well... Take care.
I came all the way
to the mountain country
to work here to pay back
my brother's debt.
Soon he'll come to take you
back from working here.
I feel sorry for all the trouble
that he caused you and
the master of the rice mill.
That's because he started gambling.
Yes.
Your brother did a good job
with the rice mill garden.
He's too good for the countryside.
I heard that he came here
because of some woman.
She had a husband in the Ueno mines.
My brother's lover, you mean?
Her name is Okana.
You know so much.
She moved to Chiba recently
after having divorced her husband.
To Chiba? He didn't think of
coming back here, then.
- Madam, where do I take this?
- Upstairs.
Wait.
The master of the rice mill came to
my room. So, come to see him later.
Good evening.
Excuse me.
Can't you wait to hear "come in"?
Sorry. I came to greet
the master of the rice mill.
Thank you for all the things
you did for me this time.
I can't say no to your brother.
It must be hard for you
that he left here so soon after you
came here to ask for his support.
Well...
OK, get back to work.
I can't find a pin
for the handkerchief.
Here, I have one.
Did you put extra snacks
in my lunch?
Yes, I did.
Look for them yourself at lunch.
Can I visit my mom
after school today?
No. You can go next time.
Why not?
Would we catch her sickness?
You're too small to go there alone.
You won't be able to return by night.
- Old scumbag.
- Watch your mouth!
Ask your dad to take you there
when your dad visits her again.
Now hurry up and go.
Crooked old nose and belly.
What are you thinking?
Thinking really doesn't help me much.
It's good that you are healthy at least.
Is your wife still sick?
I'm not sure.
Since you told me that you
wanted to read something, here.
Thank you.
The master of the rice mill is leaving.
Is that so?
What is he to this place?
We owe him a lot.
We'll set it upstairs next time for...
That's a good idea.
Shima, I received this
from him for you.
Oops. You also have big breasts.
So big I have to tighten them with
cotton clothes. It's embarrassing.
Not at all. They're great.
Stop that.
Come again soon.
Are you taking a bath?
I'm going to bed.
No. You shouldn't.
What should I do? My father
always writes the same thing.
He thinks I'm prostituting myself.
I wish I could go to Tokyo with you.
Shima, Madam is calling you.
It shouldn't be so bad
if we put her in the room...
But, still people talk about them.
What if his wife finds out?
So, we should do something about them.
Madam, did you call for me?
Come in.
It's about you two. People will
start talking about you soon.
They might blame me for this.
I'm not his real mother
that is why I let this happen.
So, can you go to Tarumo for a while?
This is my special treat for you.
It's a motel with
a hot spring in the mountains.
The customers are mostly the neighbors and
sometimes someone comes from the city.
The work isn't so hard.
His wife is coming back soon.
We can't let you stay
in the same house.
It's not good for his kids, either.
Shima!
How did you come here?
Let me carry that.
No, I'm fine.
You'll get wet.
Actually...
What?
Your father visited us from Tokyo
so I had to take him here.
He's here?
When did he get here?
Early this morning.
He wants to take you home.
I told him that you worked here.
He said he would come here alone
to take you home.
Then, what?
He's taking a rest at the motel.
Is there a way not to see him?
I already told him you were here.
Damn.
Anyway, you should meet him
and talk with him.
I gave him my word that
I would never ask him for help,
and that I would live a great life.
I hate to see him now.
It can't be helped.
I'll see him then.
We'll see how it goes.
They'll be back soon.
I'm glad you came.
But, you really didn't have to.
There is nothing to worry about here.
But, since you came, why don't
you sit in the hot spring and relax.
How can I relax?
I don't care how you are as long
as I can drag you home.
You can't take me home like that.
Please, come inside.
Get ready to go home.
What should we do?
My dad is too stubborn.
I thought about...
what happened between us
and he should be upset.
It's all my fault.
He has every right to hate me.
Your words don't solve anything.
How can you say that now?
It's raining hard.
You can't leave tonight.
Have something to drink.
I'll prepare your meal, too.
Actually...
We are from a family of gentry.
I'll pay you back right now.
Here, I have 50 ryo.
It should cover most of it.
No, I don't need it.
Shima worked hard for it.
Father.
I didn't sleep with him for money.
I thought about the best solution.
How about her having
a house somewhere?
I'll ask the master of the rice mill
to help me for the money secretly.
He is our benefactor.
Or, she can do some business
going down the mountain.
You want to have her
as your concubine?
Well, my wife got better
with the medicine from Tokyo.
She's coming back soon enough.
I have to ask Shima to be patient.
I would never become
a concubine, even if I die.
But, I have a responsibility.
We both are responsible.
I don't need you to do all this for me.
I won't be a concubine.
I can manage to live by myself.
You already are a comfort woman.
Shima, make up your mind.
You and I will never
get to a conclusion.
Get someone over here,
someone who can really talk.
Listen to me. Since people here
took care of me so well,
I don't want to leave them
just before it gets busy.
So, I'll stay here till June
and I'll be...
home by mid-August.
The longer you stay,
the worse it will get.
I have to say good bye
to Madam and the neighbors.
I can't leave without asking them.
You understand that, don't you?
He wouldn't listen to me at all.
I won't go anywhere.
Whatever it takes, I'll stay here.
Once my wife comes back,
I can't come here often.
Even if I see you once a year,
I'll be happy.
I feel sorry for you. Maybe,
it's better if you go back to Tokyo.
It's not good to keep you
as a comfort woman for so long.
Is that what you really think?
Maybe it's better to end this.
You look angry
but it can't be helped.
I can die for that.
If you do such a thing,
people will talk.
Are you afraid of rumors?
Though you pushed me away
this far into the mountains,
are you still afraid
of your reputation?
I left everything behind for you.
You don't even want to get a scar?
I'm trying to do the best for you.
Enough of excuses.
If you can tell me to break up,
you don't really love me that much.
You're just full of excuses.
What's wrong? Are you drunk?
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Feeling better?
What time is it?
It's late.
Why are you getting up?
I have nothing to say.
I've never seen a woman drunk
that bad.
That folding screen.
Did I do that?
Yes.
What happened?
Well, you did it with your arms.
Was I out of control?
Madam came here to check what
was going on. It was embarrassing.
How much does it cost if
I want to pay for the damage?
In two hours, day breaks.
I'll go pack my things, now.
I wonder how much
the folding screen costs.
I'll take care of that. Don't worry
about the money. Just apologize.
Take the sweets that
I brought you on the way here.
If you don't find a place in Tokyo,
come back here anytime.
Thank you.
Auntie, Mr. Ogata is here.
- Good day..
- Hello. You're early today.
Another battle started.
Then, we'll be making
more army suits for a while.
I guess so.
Good for you, too.
We've done those.
Already? You're five times
faster than the others are.
You are also making more money.
I wouldn't ask more
if I had a husband.
She told me she would do sewing or
anything if I would let her stay here.
Now, she's complaining
the job is too easy for her.
It's no use if I learn how to
play the shamisen now.
Why don't you come to learn how to use
the sewing machine in our factory?
No women work there.
It's not a problem for me.
It doesn't matter at all.
Give me one.
Should I really go to the factory?
Here is your money.
With a wife like you,
I'd have no money problems.
- You are right. Why don't you
marry me then? - No thanks.
This is the picture of the girl
that I told you of before.
- How old is she?
- 18.
Three years younger
than Shima, then.
Don't compare her with
a woman who's divorced.
You haven't married before right?
Good that a guy can
still have a chance after 30.
He's still young as a man.
She is 10 years younger than I am.
You are leaving early.
I'm going out.
Where?
Well...
Mineko!
Tonight is the last night for us
to stay together
and that I can talk to you.
17th of January,
everyone, please remember.
I wonder what the moon
and the sea will be looking at
this time next year.
Tonight, the year after next, and
tonight this month in three years,
I will never forget about tonight.
How can I forget you.
Mineko, I'll promise you
that I will shadow the moon with
my tears on this night next year.
Don't say that, Kai.
I will never forget you
as long as I live.
Why did you leave me if you say so?
Well because...
I don't want to hear...
What's the matter?!
Maybe the film was cut off.
Damn.
I'll write you when
I come out to Tokyo again.
We can go to see
the city together next time.
I didn't like the way we left
the mountain with that argument.
I'm glad I saw you again.
Because your aunt is your father's sister,
you can feel relaxed there, right?
As long as I make money for myself.
She lives on the money that her
daughter makes working as a Geisha.
Please, be patient. Someday,
I'll find the right mountain.
Then, I will come for you.
Don't you have to go now?
I hate to see you off at the station,
so I won't come with you.
That's OK.
I'll say goodbye from here.
I wish I could take you with me.
I can't live far
in the mountains anymore.
We'll see each other
in Tokyo again, then.
It's the night of Tanabata,
but we can barely see the stars.
This is not much, but take it.
- I don't need your money.
- I wish I could give you more.
I don't need it.
I'm making money myself.
Though you work all day,
you don't make that much, do you?
- I don't really need it.
- You can buy the kimono belt for this.
I don't want to be your concubine.
Piece of cake.
Men are slow.
You finished?
If the office doesn't take them,
it's no use to be faster.
They didn't?
They didn't.
Why not?
- They pick on little stuff.
- Like what?
"It is not the right material,"
or "the stitches are too loose."
Can't you even negotiate with them?
You're not negotiating the right way.
They are officers.
I can go with you.
Maybe it's better if a woman goes.
If it's you,
they'll be grinning at you.
Tap their nose and come back.
Stop joking.
Well, we should try at least.
We don't know what to do
with those if they don't take them.
You're coming with me.
Put them in the carrier, then.
It was easy.
Some officers can talk.
From now on, you
should do the delivering.
They were surprised,
they'd never seen a female tailor.
I don't think there are any others.
Let's take a break.
I think I can be a tailor.
You worked for 20 years
in Nagoya before, right?
*
If you stay here,
you won't get anywhere.
But, you need capital.
How much?
To run your own shop...
Do you think you can get the capital?
If I can, do you want to
go into business with me?
Me?
Yes.
Will you really do it?
You are the worst looking
guy I've ever met.
At the office, too.
You just stood there like a big truck,
I thought you were
one of the officers.
But, you look like you're reliable.
Is that you, Oyu?
It's been a while.
I wanted to see you, Shima.
- I heard you're a tailor now.
- Yes...
with western dress making in Chiba.
Is that so?
If you want a dress made,
we'll take your order anytime.
Western dress.
That sounds modern.
You look so different.
Why?
You've become much prettier
than before.
I don't have time to
bother about that though.
Maybe if I'd tied my hair more...
I've lost a lot of hair.
Sounds disheartening.
That's a really nice wig.
I've became a Geisha since then.
Is that so?
You look great.
Though if I waited with my mouth
open, nothing would fall in.
I made the capital selling
my wedding goods.
It was right to leave Tsuru, though.
He was such a wimp.
He has a problem with the
woman from Kitamura town.
Would you like to go have
something hot?
Why did you get a divorce?
Well, I can tell you
because it's over.
When Tsuru asked me for money,
I sold my Kimono for it.
You liked him, didn't you?
He's such a handsome man.
I'm leaving the money here.
Thank you.
What are you doing now?
- Me?
- Yes.
I left my husband since Tsuru
told me I could move in with him.
But, he dumped me
for one of his maids.
In the end he got kicked out
of his adoptive family.
Get a hold of yourself.
Don't let guys control you.
You have to make them men.
I still have to visit
a couple of stores for orders.
You do?
Drop by at my shop anytime.
- Thank you for the coffee.
- Bye.
- Welcome back.
- I'm home.
How can you be sleeping?
You're useless.
Hey! Wake up!
I wonder how you managed
to pay your taxes before.
You really annoy me.
Shut up.
*
We have only three days left
till New Year.
We have to sell our dresses otherwise
we won't be able to pay the salaries.
We can't run a business this way.
We still have to pay for the
sewing machine by New Year's eve.
Get up and work.
*
Make me some tea.
I am fixing this for my customer.
Everyone, be patient.
You'll have to work all night long.
Though you get cranky,
we can't build Rome in a night.
Let's take a break.
I expected having a store
would mean more.
How disappointing.
If we pay your salary,
we don't have much left.
But, we can't work like you.
Think what if you had to work
and do the household like I do.
Any business takes time to get settled.
Take it easy.
Where can you find people playing chess
in the store before New Year's eve?
Stop it.
How could you?
You, bastard.
Calm down.
She gets cranky
at this time of the month.
Don't take it out on us.
What? I walked all the way
to the pawnshop to save money.
Look at you. You take a nap
whenever you get a chance.
If you worked harder
I wouldn't have to hire others.
How can you say that in here.
Get back in.
Calm down.
She gets so hysterical.
Let's get back to the chess.
You, bastard!
Have you woken up yet?
Stop it.
Did you wake up?
They finally took the sewing machine.
That's why I told you
we should have...
I was going to stay at my aunt's
but her daughter is back.
I can't stay there.
We could ask the landlord if
we could stay here a bit longer.
Have you been waiting long?
I didn't expect it to be so bad.
I can't find a job anywhere.
I'll go back to my home.
You know how difficult
it is in the countryside.
That's why I told you
we should have worked harder.
Don't keep saying that.
Let's go to Shaga.
Your friends are there, right?
It'd be like as if you
came back from the West.
What are you going to do
if I go back there?
I'll make money in Tokyo.
Ask your boss
at where you used to work.
I didn't work for the wages,
they paid me in advance.
I can't take you to the factory.
You can go by yourself, can't you?
Maybe. I heard there's
a position available now.
Try, then.
Where will you go?
I'll look for a room on
the second floor for rent.
If I can't find any, I'll go to my
aunt for a couple of days.
Are we going to separate?
Not much we can do.
Let's get out of here.
- Welcome home.
- Hi.
Your husband is here.
Is he?
Hi, I'm home.
Welcome home.
- Where are your clogs?
- There.
Why did you put them there?
The bottoms have been scuffed a lot.
I was going to see you tomorrow.
Why?
Take a look at this.
I bought you this for you.
The temperature has dropped lately.
Those are nice stripes, aren't they?
I had to let it out a bit
here and there.
Did you buy this?
It must have cost you a lot.
Not at all.
I got a good discount.
The pawnshop owner asked me
to do some sewing jobs.
I got this jacket for the work.
- Are you working on these?
- Yes.
Have you eaten?
I bought you sardines.
I wanted to eat them with you.
It's been a while since we ate together.
I'll cook them right away.
It seems like a honeymoon.
Mrs. Ogata?
Yes.
Is it here already?
What is it?
A sewing machine.
Sewing machine?
Thank you.
You bought it finally.
It's a monthly payment.
I haven't tried it out yet.
I told them I had to try it
out to see if it works.
And if it's any good, I'll buy it.
That's a good idea.
But, it might damage the tatami mat?
No, it won't. If I do I'll make a
lot of money and pay you back.
I can live with you soon.
Yes.
It's smooth.
What's wrong?
I was thinking about the future.
Monthly payments aren't easy.
If I can't pay, I'll ask
them if I can pay it next month,
complaining the machine
doesn't work well.
We can't survive this world
if we are nave.
I don't want to end my life
being a wage earner.
We have to own the store.
How about having a store in Izu?
Izu? Maybe that would work.
I can borrow irons from the factory.
Then, all we have to do is
to earn the capital.
Dad, that's not the way.
This way.
Good morning.
- Are you going to see the city?
- I'm taking my father to see Tokyo.
Have a good time.
Excuse me.
Is madam here?
Well...
The guest from the countryside
was drinking all morning?
What's wrong?
My body is sore.
You must be tired.
You work too hard.
I can't stay in bed.
I have things to be done by today.
I hate summer.
Business isn't too good in the summer?
Right.
I can't have stamina
with a small income.
True.
How can I have energy left for nights.
Then, your husband is
pretty tough at it?
Well, he isn't really.
Are you sure?
Can I borrow a bowl of Soya source?
I'll give it back tomorrow.
Sure.
You are the only one who
lends to me so generously.
We have to help each other.
Your husband daydreams because
you don't spend time in bed with him.
Excuse me?
I can find someone for him.
it would be easier for you, right?
Are you joking?
He's not a gentleman
to have a concubine.
Here.
Thank you.
Sorry if I said too much.
I have to go out.
But, there's deep-fried chikuwa
and pickled cabbage for lunch.
Yes.
Junkichi, put this away, will you?
Madam.
Jien was waiting here for a while.
Grandpa from the countryside?
He was complaining
you were out all morning.
I can't believe that.
He said you were not like a woman.
He doesn't know how hard I work here.
It's for Mrs. Ogata.
Madam.
I'll buy you dinner tonight.
Something good is coming up.
Thank you.
I'd like to have a meal from the
western restaurant, the Tsunoki.
Sure, work hard.
Are you sick?
What's wrong?
I don't know.
They told me to be careful.
I'll see a specialist doctor in Tokyo.
I might stay here for a while.
I need to get some injections.
You've got your wife's illness.
It was good I didn't marry you
after all.
Just kidding. I'll go take care of you
if you get a lung disease.
I doubt it.
Why not?
You once thought of dying
in the mountains.
That's really an old story.
You weren't that mean before.
It's not only me who's changed.
Well, you got older, didn't you?
Drop by at my shop with
the old folks from the mountain.
I'll take them around.
You became a nice woman.
You must be joking.
It's true.
You became a nice madam.
You are a successful woman.
Not quite so yet. It's still hard.
Will you invest some money?
Why not? If it's a favour to you,
we'll dig the gold mountain.
We should order some clothes.
Summer suits for me.
And winter suits for you, right?
Make a good one.
I will. Thank you.
Madam, please advertise
our clothes to your neighbors.
I will.
If you send me the samples,
we can find you good connections.
Thank you.
Well, please have some more.
I should go upstairs and say hi.
You don't have to.
Stay away from there.
Why don't you want
my father to go upstairs?
Well, he's drunk and...
How can I get drunk
on two bottles of beer?
Don't make an display of yourself
because of your ex. or whatever.
What are you talking about?
- It is that man, right?
- Shut up. Fool.
How could you leave my father alone?
I'm sorry.
Please be patient.
*
I can't keep running up
and downstairs all night.
Shut up. What a wife!
You can work hard,
but how could you...
tell your father-in-law
to stay back here?
You just want to drink more, right?
You drink out every night.
Why not go out to drink tonight, too?
You can charge us for what you drink.
You don't mind if I charge my drinks?
I don't tell you not to drink.
Well, let me tell you something then.
Did you come here to see Tokyo?
I sent him over here.
If you plan to stay here, I can't treat
you like a guest all the time.
You don't want me here, right?
Calm down.
What a wife.
Hang in there.
I can't stay here alone just for
the injections, so I'm going back.
I'll take these for my kids then,
thank you.
Do you want to come with me?
You'll get bored with life
in the mountains.
People change as time goes by.
If the economy gets better,
things will get better.
The location isn't good for business.
So, soon we'll move.
We'll try our luck once more.
That sounds good, too.
Since you made a fortune,
will you lend me some money?
Sure.
I'll pay you back
with interest per year.
Onoda tailors.
Please visit us.
What is it?
Some tailor that just came
back from the west.
We'll give you discount.
Onoda tailors.
You can't do this here.
We have a regular tailor here.
Take it easy.
We have a regular tailor...
But let me...
Onoda tailors.
Please.
Please come visit us.
Make a turn here.
Turn here again.
Are you OK?
Sir, your pattern is old.
We don't make them anymore.
Really?
- Well, I'll leave it to you, then.
- You will?
Junkichi. Did you give some tea
to the guest upstairs?
I did.
Good.
Sorry she isn't back yet.
Don't worry about me.
- That's a nice record player.
- Nothing special.
We don't have much of
a collection yet.
I want to collect
all the Naniwa songs.
Is that so? That's nice.
Really sorry to keep you waiting.
Maybe I'll learn instead of her.
That's nice. Men arrange
flowers better than women.
I told her to learn it since
she's getting to know more people.
It's embarrassing if she
doesn't know these things.
But, she's always out.
Welcome home.
I'm back.
How uncomfortable.
But, Sir was right.
You do look younger.
Really?
You look like a magician
from Hawaii at least.
I'm sore from riding a bicycle all day.
Sore where?
You don't have to ask.
Is it so?
Are you making a pattern?
Yes. Mr. Ogata's pattern is old.
Really?
Do we have a guest?
Your flower arrangement teacher.
No. Don't say that...
It's nothing.
I've always adored you.
We'll finish here today.
- Well, see you.
- Thank you.
You are back.
This is for the month.
I don't have time for this.
Don't come back.
You're such an idiot.
You get your beard in a twist over
a woman who has the skin of a goldfish.
What?
Damn all this!
What are you doing?!
Bastard!
It's miserable.
She works so hard. But, she told me
you were one out of a thousand.
Stop joking, OK?
You don't have to be so patient.
I can find a good girl for you.
- Here, have some.
- With pleasure.
I didn't know you knew his wife.
I found it out just now.
*
This is a daughter of the Kanna Family.
Her father helped me a lot.
I've been a friend with Shima's
ex-husband since we were kids.
She got so jealous.
Really.
She gave me a lot of trouble.
I had a sip, but...
Thank you.
I had to get out of my husband's house
because she lied about me and her ex.
She's smart with money.
She's like a man right?
Yes, she's just like a man.
See, I know her.
I'm never without scars.
Here. Here. And here.
How terrible.
I'm sorry for you.
I know a good house in Hakusai.
I'll leave it to you.
I can make dresses.
I can get you customers, too.
Well, you are gentle with people.
Maybe you're good at it.
Maybe.
It really doesn't matter though.
Please.
Here.
Thank you.
Well, I'm taking this...
It was really terrible of you
leaving me alone in the mountains.
I was going to pick you up later on.
But, my master got sick
and I couldn't go anywhere.
You should return
and ask your wife to come back.
I'm thinking about that.
A man's life is tough.
You are all cowards.
I heard the master of the Hamaya
in the mountains was really sick.
You mean him?
I heard from someone.
Really.
How bad is he?
He's in bed, I heard.
Call for sweet sake.
I'm leaving.
Have another drink before you go.
The sake vendor's here.
Order one for each of us.
You should go see him.
Right. I also have to pay him back.
Welcome home.
She was waiting for you.
Did she go out?
Yes, to the mountains.
To the mountains?
What for?
To pay some money back.
What?
She was waiting for you
for a long time,
but she just left because
she didn't want to miss the train.
Why?
Taking money to the mountains...
What's the rush?
The master in the mountains got sick so
she thought he might need the money.
Since we can manage to run the business,
she thought she had to pay him back.
Junkichi, make a fire.
Are you the madam here?
You are Shima from Tokyo?
I am very sorry.
I had no idea.
We should have let you know,
but we were pretty busy, then.
We couldn't be troubled to send
a telegram to one of our ex-maids.
Since I didn't know about this,
I brought these for him.
What are they?
Some cakes and sweets.
He loved them.
I didn't know that.
Thank you, anyway.
Is his grave far?
It takes about half day.
You'll miss your train
if you don't go now.
I'll give you this.
This much money?
Take it.
Your master gave it to me once.
Is it OK?
I wanted to pay you back, but...
I'll say good bye here.
To Hakusan.
Welcome back.
I told people I would visit
my country home for a week.
That's great.
Go get changed.
I sewed this.
It's well done.
I'll do it.
Who is it? Umeya?
Hello?
My bag!
Shima!
How did you know about here?
Well, come inside.
You wear a wig well
on your balding head!
I wanted to see you
and have a talk with you.
I hate foul women like you.
You do?
If you don't want your husband to
cheat on you, take better care of him.
Because you are so uptight,
your husbands leave you.
If you want shit on your head,
I'll give it to you.
So, say "thank you."
How thoughtful yet stubborn.
I'll teach you how to bow.
You brute!
Someone help me!
Welcome!
- Can I have an umbrella?
- Which one?
This one?
It's terrible rain isn't it?
I'll take this. How much is it?
1 yen and 30 sen.
- Can I use the phone?
- The phone is over there.
Hello?
Junkichi?
Is the bastard home yet?
Can you pass the phone to Mr. Kimura?
From Madam?
Mr. Kimura?
I have to ask you for some advice.
Can you bring my bag over to me?
I might leave the store.
I want you to do the pattern...
and I want to run
a new store with you.
So, I can close the store now?
Close before the bastard comes back.
Let's talk more at the hot springs.
Really?
Can you also take Junkichi with you?
He's been working hard so
we should give him a day off, too.
So, I'll see you at the station.
Thank you. Here's your change.
Take it. It's for the phone.
Thank you very much.
THE END