THE BEAST
Troubled dreams are in fact
a passing moment of madness.
Your misogamy is beyond a joke,
my dear Rammondelo.
Not at all. I simply want a long life
for my nephew.
You yourself were married
and you're still very much alive.
Yes, thank God.
My marriage to the Duchess Florence
was extremely short lived.
Barely two months.
Mathurin will not last that long,
he will die immediately,
and the boy wants to live.
If not for his father or his uncle,
at least for his horses.
Enough!
Your morbid hatred of womanhood
has nothing to do with my son's shyness.
Let me carry out my plans.
Lucy Broadhurst will marry Mathurin.
Listen to what
Mrs. Virginia Broadhurst wrote,
and what my son replied.
"My niece Lucy is anxious
to meet Mathurin,"
"and this wish is not prompted by
reason only, although the two fortunes..."
Love by correspondence!
Perhaps.
History tells us of many similar cases.
Mathurin answered yes.
What? Answered?
He writes letters now?
Mathurin the scribbler!
With his left hand?
Don't make fun of the poor boy.
You don't want to admit
that Mathurin has become an adult.
You don't realise that for some time
he has been lying to you.
He was writing to Lucy.
He realised
that you wanted to ruin this house,
that your warnings betray your desire
to destroy our family.
- My family.
- It's you who are preparing his death.
There will be no execution.
You've not read everything.
Thank you.
Lucy's father wrote in his will,
"I leave my daughter,
my only heir, quite free,"
"but these conditions
must be respected in all events:"
"Firstly, she will marry Mathurin,
only son of the Earl de l'Esperance."
"Secondly, the marriage will be blessed
personally by Cardinal Joseph de Balo,"
"brother of Duke Rammondelo de Balo."
I hope the Cardinal
will not refuse his brother
to say his grand-nephew's nuptial mass.
- Try asking him.
- Oh, no!
Since my son's birth
I haven't spoken to your Cardinal.
It's you who must ask him now.
No!
Yes you will, Uncle.
If not, the secret you've hidden
for 45 years will be revealed.
You poisoned your wife,
Duchess Florence de Balo.
You're joking!
I have proof.
Show me.
You recognise this bottle?
Your fingerprints are still on it.
All right, I'll call Joseph.
But you're making a mistake.
- I'm never wrong.
- Your son was never baptised.
Joseph will see the priest.
He's coming in half an hour.
I couldn't have him baptised
when he was small.
Now it can be done!
But nothing will change
the nature of your son!
- Mathurin?
- No, my Lord.
He wants to be alone.
- Call him now!
- Very well, my Lord.
...four hours to get his agreement.
Impossible,
he's not in the Vatican, but in Africa.
Don't complicate things.
I won't hesitate to call the police.
It's impossible.
Don't complicate things.
Quiet, Father,
you're upsetting my horses.
- Mathurin?
- Yes, it's me, Mathurin.
The priest will be here soon.
Come in!
Good morning, gentlemen.
What's happened?
Loosen his collar.
And open this window.
Theodore, Modeste, please.
Ifany, go with the Duke.
Some sleep will do him good.
Father, don't hurt Mathurin, I beg you.
But we are here to bring joy, your Grace.
My uncle is needlessly excited.
- Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Spring is the cause of our excitement.
We, frail humans, we are like animals,
we suffer the laws of nature.
Alas!
Happily, we have this intelligence,
this heavenly gift,
which enables us to fight our instincts.
- Good morning, Father.
- Good morning, Sir.
Wash your hands and wait for us.
- Coffee? Brandy?
- No, a drop of white wine. Theodore...
Oh, forgive me, my Lord,
I haven't introduced them.
Theodore, an excellent singer,
and Modeste, a promising organist.
- Beautiful boys! You prefer sweets?
- Thank you, my Lord.
Excuse me.
No, thank you, I have a toothache.
Ifany!
Give the Father some port.
Pick up that snail.
Horrid little beast!
Throw it away.
- Then come back.
- Yes, Sir.
A real dump, this place!
- Not happy?
- Yes, I'm very happy.
It's more than 10 miles.
How many kilometers?
Sixteen kilometers.
Wonderful France...
Beautiful France, and always so desirable.
Rome? The Vatican?
Cardinal Joseph de Balo's secretariat?
Yes, that's right.
His Excellency the Cardinal,
if you please.
This is Roberto Capia,
the Cardinal's secretary.
His Excellency the Cardinal has not yet
returned from his mission in Africa.
When will he be back?
We expect him at any moment.
Who is speaking?
The Duke de Balo, the Cardinal's brother.
His Lordship and Mr. Mathurin
are in the bathroom.
Oh. Wait.
- Take this to his Lordship.
- Yes, your Grace.
I baptise you...
This is a beautiful park for the French.
Today in France,
they are sold for building houses in.
It should be in the corner of the park
that Mathurin experiences his romantic disorder.
I understand, that that lake
harbours thousands of mosquitos all year round.
Aunt Virginia,
you speak as if you don't want
Mathurin for my husband.
I didn't say that.
Shit! Trees blocking the road.
Lucy! Come back! It's a jungle!
I am coming aunt Virginia.
Go back!
Look, aunt Virginia!
This is a sad picture.
Sad?
Nature is mysterious, but never sad.
I'll have the column restored.
And painted white.
There is the chateau !?
Don't do that.
Aunt Virginia!
Leave me alone! I am no child anymore!
Turn down.
Turn around and go back to the park!
Later you can do what you like.
But not now...
and not when I'm with you.
I'm sorry, aunt Virginia.
This is the last time, you'll lose your way.
I'm sorry ma'am.
But I don't know France that well.
Come in, ladies.
Thank you, miss.
Come in.
Come in, ladies!
I am the Duke de Balo.
Virginia Broadhurst.
Lucy Broadhurst.
- Maybe you are the Cardinal's brother?
- That's right.
But it is not I
who is the master of the house here.
Is Mr. de l'Esperance away?
No, not at all.
He's washing his son.
He's "washing" Mathurin?
I assure you they are in the bathroom.
They will be out very shortly.
Would you rather wait in your rooms?
They are ready for you.
We'll wait for Mr. de l'Esperance
and his son here.
Well then, sit down
and I'll keep you company.
Does his Excellency Cardinal de Balo
know about the will?
Madame, for any queries about the will,
and the marriage of your niece,
Lucy Broadhurst, here beside us,
with Mathurin, my nephew's son,
please speak to his father.
Is it true ghosts haunt this house?
Who... Who said that?
Our cook, a Frenchwoman,
the old Juliette.
I've never seen a single ghost here.
But the Countess
Romilda de l'Esperance
did describe ghosts in her book,
two hundred years ago.
That's her! Romilda de l'Esperance.
She never wrote anything,
she only left... a drawing in her herbal.
Herbal?
Here it is! The famous album.
Be careful turning the pages, my child.
The dead leaves are very fragile.
Dead leaves?
Yes, Romilda's little hands
stuck in these leaves
gathered in the park two centuries ago.
Look at page 115B very carefully.
No, that's 115A.
115B.
"The scale... 6,600 yards..."
It's easier with a magnifying glass.
"I met him and overcame him..."
"Romilda de l'Esperance."
It's Romilda's corset.
It was found at the bottom of a pond.
Traces of claw marks...
Can you see them, ladies?
Yes, indeed.
Ifany!
Goodbye, ladies!
So hilarious, Rammondelo of Balo
The Marques of  L'Esperance is washing his son.
The man, you are going to marry, tomorrow.
Very touching, that a father should
love his son that much.
We ought to clean ourselves too, aunt Virginia.
We?
Mathurin and I.
How dare you tell this to your aunt?
I'm sorry, aunt Virginia.
What beautiful handwriting!
Look aunt Virginia.
An autograph from...
Good morning, ladies.
Silly stories, don't believe a word.
"Since time immemorial, every 200 years,"
"the same day, same time,
when Mercury moves away from the sun,"
"a beast arrives at our house..."
blah, blah, blah...
Pierre de l'Esperance.
Virginia Broadhurst.
Lucy Broadhurst.
The jewel of our families and our pride.
I am happy to welcome you to my house.
Please forgive the lack of comfort.
My niece loves the country.
I like forests and animals.
You'll find a brotherly soul here.
I'm sure the date will be memorable
in the lives of our children.
Ifany!
My boot...
Oh, Ifany...
I'll get my son, he's dressing.
Oh, the men of today!
I suggest...
The Father of our parish...
I suggest you go to your rooms
and rest for a while.
Your luggage will be brought up.
"The Cardinal's secretary hung up
when I said my name."
- Take up the ladies' luggage.
- Yes, my Lord.
Thank you.
Cardinal Joseph de Balo
will be arriving soon?
We expect him any moment.
I spoke to him again this morning.
He said what a joy it would be
to say the nuptial mass
and bless our children.
This way, please.
I've come to help with the bags.
What?
Luggage.
This luxury, Dadio...
one Rolls Royce and a black chaffeur.
And you? One chateau and a black slave.
No slaves here.
I am cheap, it's true, but I am no slave.
You work here for nothing, I'm sure.
As of tomorrow, you are going to be rich.
There are other pleasures
beyond money in this world, Dadio.
"I appoint my sister in law,
Virginia Broadhurst,"
"executrix of my will."
Philip Andrew.
"Sermons Chosen
from the Mysteries of the True Religion."
"The Maid of Orleans"
"mock-heroic poem in 18 verses"
"by Voltaire."
She's a serious girl,
well-brought up,
very pious, and...
of a rare beauty.
I'm afraid, Father.
But of what?
You're baptised now, like everyone else.
The original sin has been washed away.
I don't know anymore.
When she was far away, I felt brave.
Now I'm losing my memory.
I've forgotten everything you taught me.
All your advice seems useless.
You can't change me,
I'll always be Mathurin, Papa.
I'm ugly.
What are you talking about?
Look...
You look like me.
Look! You are handsome.
No, I'm afraid, I'm afraid!
Your uncle, the Cardinal de Balo,
will celebrate the mass,
and you will feel like a newborn baby.
You'll see. Don't cry.
Lucy is resting in her room,
her aunt too.
You, wait for them with the priest
in the drawing room.
I'm with you,
Uncle Rammondelo too, everyone...
You're lying, Rammondelo...
No, it's the truth,
they won't speak to pagans.
You must tell Joseph of this capital event,
Mathurin's baptism.
They hang up as soon as I say my name,
as if I was Mathurin's father.
Your brother thinks you're an angel.
It'll be worse when he learns
the truth about the Duchess.
Pierre, think a moment,
it's not too late.
You're losing your son for a sum of gold.
He's innocent.
The house is crumbling,
the ground is barren.
It's the beginning of the end.
Fate has sent Lucy to save us.
If you oppose this,
you'll be responsible for the disaster,
and you'll be punished.
Hello! Hello!
This is the Cardinal de Balo's secretariat.
Rammondelo de Balo,
the Cardinal's brother.
You see, I wasn't lying.
Hello, telegrams.
Hello, this is 228-2845.
- A telegram, please.
- Who to?
To Cardinal Joseph de Balo.
Vatican.
- The text?
- The text...
"Mathurin baptised today. Stop."
"Great joy to invite you"
"to be with us for this happy event."
Signed Rammondelo de Balo.
Who's this?
Some very grown-up people.
I borrowed them from a friend.
Ifany!
Show Clarisse the dresses.
- Where did you put them?
- Yes, they're up there.
Father, may I go out for a moment?
I must get a dress for the mass.
- Yes, but the children first.
- Yes, of course.
Please, Father...
leave the ladies in peace, they're resting.
Forgive us, my Lord.
Whenever Modeste sees a keyboard,
he can't help touching it.
I understand, it's stronger than him.
That's it. You know... music...
Father...
Cardinal de Balo is coming any minute.
I need you and your testimony.
Mathurin's baptism followed church rules.
You alone can prove it?
Is that right?
Yes, indeed, yes...
Our friendly relations with the parish
go back a long time,
don't they?
Yes, we've never been enemies.
I was always convinced
that Mr. Mathurin
would, one day, become a Christian.
And a Christian donator.
Mathurin, what will be your first act
after the wedding?
Tell the Father.
I will repair the church roof
and order a bell
whose tone will be chosen by Lucy.
It will be like the Vatican's bells.
God will reward you.
Lucy Broadhurst
is known for her kindness,
and her piety is unequalled.
- Smoking again?
- Yes.
Ifany!
- Stéphane's afraid, he's trembling.
- I wasn't afraid! Not true!
You smell so good,
and your clothes too...
"Your Mathurin..."
- The grey room.
- Yes, my Lord.
- No telephone call?
- No.
Pierre, if there's a meal, let me come.
I want to be near him
maybe for the last time.
There will be no meal
until the Cardinal comes.
If you're hungry you'll eat here.
You will not leave the telephone.
If Rome calls,
knock on the door with this stick.
Mathurin...
"Dear Lucy..."
"Allow me to disturb your rest."
"I would be happy
if you could come down"
"and we could meet
with your aunt and my father."
"You cannot imagine the joy I feel"
"at the thought
of what is about to happen."
"My heart is beating."
"Your Mathurin."
- Six people today.
- My Lord, I've already set six places.
Well, tidy up here!
Make some space!
The Cardinal appreciates good food.
As a child, it was his favourite place.
It is a pity that his duties
leave him so little time for his family.
But aunt, a vocation is everything.
His Excellency
certainly has more important duties
than blessing a marriage.
There is no doubt in my mind.
Yesterday,
the Cardinal had to make a decision.
He certainly...
Just a little.
...made the right one.
From his point of view?
From... his point of view, yes.
Do you think the Cardinal's absence
could be due to personal reasons?
A feeling of hostility towards us
or towards you?
I don't think so.
We've always been on good terms,
as we are with the church here.
Father can confirm this.
The promise of a donation
by Mr. Mathurin and Miss. Lucy
to our church assures us of this.
What donation?
We agreed with Mathurin by a letter
to give the village church a bronze bell.
Bronze, the symbol of the everlasting.
Its tone will be chosen by Lucy.
Tone?
The tone will be like a Roman bell.
If I'm not mistaken,
the will stipulates no deadline
for the date of the marriage.
"...as soon as possible,"
"but no later than 6 months after my death."
It is the first of May,
we have another forty-eight hours.
May I see it?
Just a moment.
"...the nephew of Rammondelo of Balo,"
"a pleasant and healthy young man,"
"with no unsavoury habits."
It's quite true he smoked,
but he soon learned
that tobacco was a poison.
He fell from his horse
and broke his hand.
It's true that I broke my hand
and that I smoked a great deal.
Then I stopped.
At first my hands trembled,
and my whole body.
But I met a doctor, a vet to be precise,
who visits our horses.
He gave me a wonderful cure.
I chew... I chew,
I don't smoke anymore.
I chew all day like a squirrel.
Be quiet, Mathurin!
You'll wake your uncle.
I fear that your father
may have made a mistake.
Why do you always have such
a tragic way to see things?
You must understand that champagne
does not change the cosmos!
Ifany!
Look after Mrs. Broadhurst.
The case, quickly!
No, thank you,
I've got some pills in my room.
My aunt is so nervous.
We should take her to her room.
And you too Lucy...
you too must go and have a rest.
Of course, aunt Virginia.
Modeste, light the way
for the ladies on the stairs.
Hello.
- Anyone there?
- His Lordship will be down soon.
What beautiful children of honour!
- What is your name?
- Stéphane.
My name is Marie.
Such pretty names.
- What parish do you come from?
- I don't know.
They're the children
of my Parisian friend.
Clarisse!
This is really not the time
to be playing with dolls.
Take them upstairs.
What about the Cardinal?
- Don't undress them, they can wait.
- Very well, Daddy.
Fate is not being kind to us.
One must hope, one must have faith.
Only the Cardinal's arrival
can make any radical change.
- Still no news?
- No, no news.
The telephone is silent,
my uncle won't leave it.
The Cardinal may knock without warning.
Let's believe in miracles.
Father, I'll call you when necessary.
Go home.
No, if I may, I will try
to find a corner here to wait for him.
He is having a tiring journey,
let us be travellers too.
Joseph, I beg you, stay in Rome!
If you come, Mathurin will die.
This boy is my only joy.
Without him I'll be the next to die.
Joseph, listen,
I'll tell you the truth about his baptism.
Pierre baptised him because...
Hello? What's going on?
Rammondelo! Rammondelo!
Why aren't you responding?
Hello?
Answer...
Someone shouted?
No, it was an illusion.
Oh, but you're awake too?
It's the noisy spring in your chair
which must have woken me.
I suggest, Father,
you go to a room upstairs.
My Lord, we're very comfortable here.
Besides,
his Excellency will be arriving soon.
Certainly. I'm going to call again.
Sleep peacefully.
I will come and wake you.
He's dead and fell out of his bed!
Who fell? Who? Tell me!
Mathurin...
I didn't do anything!
He had too much to drink!
Take him.
Come and help me.
Now pick him up.
Carefully, carefully...
Put him there.
Don't touch him!
I'll call the doctor.
Take him to the drawing room.
Poor boy, he drank too much.
Careful of the plaster...
In the name of the father,
the son and the holy spirit.
Ifany!
Put him in the armchair.
On my desk.
Father, watch over his body and his soul.
I'll call the doctor.
I didn't do anything!
The beast!
Mrs. Broadhurst!
Hanany, get us out of here! Quick!
Don't go! Don't go!
Bestiality, that is to say,
copulating with an animal,
is the most odious crime
because it debases man,
created in the image of God.
It is most contrary
to the laws of nature.
That is why Leviticus...
punished by death
not only the guilty man or woman,
but also the beast itself.
Should simple caressing of a beast
be considered a sin of bestiality?
Unchaste caressing of a beast
should not be forgotten at confession.
For example, as if to defile herself,
a woman has a dog or cat
lick her vulva,
or if she touches
the sexual part of the animal
until it ejaculates.
That's why Vernier advises confessors
to ask women,
particularly those of a lustful nature,
if they have acted shamefully
with an animal.
Often in this way,
shameful secrets are revealed.