WHEN THE TENTH MONTH COMES
A gift from your son.
Why hasn't he written in such a long time?
He's been ill and in the hospital.
He didn't want to make you worried.
Has he recovered yet?
Yes, he's been discharged
from the hospital.
My dad sent me this gun!
Tuan, is your mom back yet?
Yes, she just came back today.
Tell her I'll visit her tonight.
I will.
Let's visit Duyen tonight.
His unit is stationed
in the Central Highlands.
Couldn't he at least have sent
a letter back with you?
You went all that way to visit him,
and failed to bring me back a letter?
Grandpa! My gun!
Let me have a look at it.
What's wrong?
It's not shooting anymore.
What happened?
- Here, let me fix it.
- Stop crying, Sweetheart
There are more presents for you!
Shhh, quiet now.
Were you a good boy for your Grandpa?
Here's a present for you.
Go on - take it.
Mom, sharpen it for me!
Wait. I'm talking to Grandpa right now.
Here's a knife, sharpen it now.
Thanks.
Did your husband say
when he'd get leave?
He's letting others in his unit
take leave before him.
You know, many soldiers have been far
from home for decades without leave!
That's true...
Duyen, you've just come home?
Are you tired from your journey?
Whose baby is this?
This is Thang's little one.
He and his wife just moved down south.
Once they're settled
they'll send for the baby.
For now Grandma's the babysitter!
A gift for you from my husband.
Oh, your husband is so thoughtful!
He didn't have to get me a gift.
When he heard that Dad has been ill,
he was really worried.
He even wanted me to come home early!
But when I told him you were taking care
of him in my absence, he felt reassured.
Have you been taking
your medicine regularly?
Yes.
Getting him to take all his medicine
was quite a chore, let me tell you!
Whining all the time about
when you'd come back...
Finally I said - she'll come home safely
only if you stop talking about it!
If you keep harping on about it, she'll probably
have an accident on the way home!
That shut him up.
How can I not worry about
my girl traveling all alone?
He thought you might stay down south for fear
that someone would steal your husband!
Anyone home?
Yes! Please come in.
Come in everyone.
Please sit down.
We heard that Duyen just returned.
How is everything?
How's Tuan's Daddy? Is he well?
Thanks for asking. He's fine.
What rank is he up to now?
He's just a soldier.
Just a soldier?
But how many stars and stripes?
Please have some tea.
Did you by chance meet up with my eldest son
while you were down South? He's also a soldier.
The South is a vast land,
I'm sure the chances of that are slim!
Have some tea.
Thanks.
Drink up everyone.
This tea is from the South.
How do you like it?
It's not as good as tea from Thai Nguyen.
Grandpa, look at my new shin!
Anything interesting happen in town?
I bought you a copy of "The White Ship".
I had to stand in line forever to get it!
Why is it all wet?
When I was coming home on the ferry,
a woman got sea-sick and fell overboard.
I jumped in to rescue her,
and forgot to take off my satchel.
If I was still a student,
I'd surely get an award for my actions!
So make her give you an award!
Who was it?
Duyen. She just returned from
visiting her husband.
Duyen from the theatrical troupe?
I'm not sure.
When the tenth month comes,
Rice ripens in five-ton fields.
Is this the same poem you read
to me the other day?
That's right.
This morning I met with the editors of
Arts and Literature magazine.
They said that after some revision,
they would publish it.
A poem like this needs revision?!
They said it wasn't realistic enough.
Farmers can now harvest 7 or 8
tons of rice from one hectare.
But in my poem I wrote:
"Rice ripens in five-ton fields".
You'll become a famous poet soon!
Then you'll probably give up teaching,
and leave this school forever.
You're so awkward!
How can I give up teaching?
Writing poetry is just my way of
sharing myself with others.
Sharing yourself with others?
Why don't you write letters
to people instead?
You think it's easier to be
truthful in a letter?
I can't talk to you at all!
Thom, where are you taking my poems?
They're all wet, I'll rewrite them for you.
Comrade Tran Dinh Nam has deceased.
The Fatherland has lost a faithful son,
his unit has lost a brother-in-arms,
and his family has lost a dear relative.
Due to fierce fighting on the front,
the Unit regrets it cannot send a
representative to visit the family at this time.
Hello.
Duyen! Please come in.
Are you feeling better?
Yes, thanks.
My father-in-law asked me to thank you,
and invite you to visit our house.
No need for thanks.
Please sit down.
You really scared me this afternoon!
Did you by chance find a
piece of paper that I dropped?
I found this.
Is this it?
How can this be true?
You've just come back from visiting him.
When did he die?
Almost a year ago.
And they just told you now?
His unit was preparing the letter of death
just as I came to visit.
I just thought he'd had
an accident, or was ill.
I never imagined that...
My God.
So on the ferry...
Does his father know yet?
Please don't tell anyone.
Duyen, I'm the first to hear this bad news.
Allow me to express my condolences.
Can I escort you home?
I prefer to go alone.
Still playing with kites at your age?
People will laugh at you!
Who will laugh?
I will!
Can I have it back please?
If you promise you won't
continue with such childish games.
My friends all make fun of me!
What do they say?
They say you're still a little kid.
Promise me?
I promise.
Can I have it back now?
Oh, they're watching us.
Come with me.
No, I'm afraid.
Afraid of what?
My grandma says that in the old days,
on the 15th of the 7th lunar month
there was a ghost market here
where living and dead people could meet.
What a silly story!
This is a temple dedicated to a past hero,
famous for defending the country.
He was chosen to become
our village's protector spirit.
Don't do that!
Let's get out of here.
My last kite.
Tomorrow I have my military health exam.
I've talked to my Dad.
He'll soon visit your family to
make plans for our wedding.
We'll marry before I join the military.
Good day to you!
Who are you?
I'm Khang.
Our teacher?
Please come inside!
I've brought some special tea
for you to try.
You're bringing me gifts?
Duyen's husband also sent me some tea.
Please have some.
Whose picture is on the altar?
That's my oldest son.
He died in Quang Tri in 1968.
After Duyen moved in,
his wife remarried with a widower.
She was afraid the villagers
would speak ill of her.
But I said, just ignore them.
To find love again is a precious gift.
Right.
Grandpa, look at my drawing!
Tuan, say hello to our guest.
Hello.
Hello, boy.
How lovely!
What have you drawn here?
It's a chicken.
Have a look.
Grandpa, remember to make me a kite.
My eyes are going bad.
Wait for your Dad to come home.
Your Dad was the best kite-flyer
in the whole village!
Tuan's Dad just sent him a box of crayons.
Now he spends the whole day drawing!
The wall is full of his artwork.
Do you know how to fix guns?
Sure I do.
Let's see what's wrong with it...
Ah, I see. Just a minute.
Finished.
Thanks!
Fire off a shot.
Great!
Grandpa, the chicken laid an egg!
Tuan, bring me a bucket of water.
Water the tree.
Your Dad planted this when
he came home on leave.
It will bear fruit soon,
and your Dad still hasn't come home.
Let's save the fruit for
when Dad comes home.
Right, we'll save it in your stomach!
Hello.
Duyen, please come in.
I came for a visit the other day,
but you weren't home.
Yes, my father-in-law told me.
Have some water.
I have a favor to ask you.
Sure, anything. I'm happy to help.
My mother-in-law's death anniversary
is coming up.
My father-in-law is hoping for a letter.
Would you write one for me?
Me?
Yes.
You'd like me to write a letter
from your husband?
Yes.
Duyen, you can't hide this
from your family forever.
They have to know
the truth sooner or later.
But maybe they've made a mistake.
Maybe he's still alive somewhere,
and hasn't been able to contact anyone.
It's not hard to write this letter.
But it won't be easy to write it so that
everyone believes it's really from him.
Please try for me.
Here are all of my husband's old letters.
It will help if you read them.
In early August, Pol Pot's forces invaded
several locations along the southwest border.
They have attacked locals
and damaged property.
An alert has been raised
among our armed forces...
You should have skipped your meeting.
Dad will yell at us for being late.
How could I skip
such an important meeting?
Finally, we've been waiting forever!
Hello everyone.
Why are you so late?
The provincial official has arrived!
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I had to attend a meeting in town.
It's all right.
Bring some more food.
You've arrived! Please join us.
Duyen, bring some more food in here.
Sit down.
I wanted to come earlier, but my husband
had to attend meeting with the town council.
Don't worry about it,
Duyen and I took care of everything.
Bon apetit everyone!
Where is Duyen?
Eat with us, please.
Where's Tuan?
He ate with the other kids earlier.
Grandpa, a letter came from Dad!
A letter from Dad!
Where's the mailman?
Invite him in to join us.
He's gone already.
Hai, please read the letter
out loud for everyone.
Dear Father,
My unit will be moving to the
southwest border region.
I have time enough to dash off
a brief letter before we move out.
I hope this letter makes it to you in time
for Mother's death anniversary.
Because of work, I can't make it home
to burn incense on Mother's altar.
My wife and Tuan will do so on my behalf.
Recently, when my wife visited, I was happy
to hear her news about the whole family.
I do worry about your health as you get older
while I'm far from home.
Duyen, please take care of
my Father in my place.
I know that my absence
is difficult for you.
Tuan, did you receive
Daddy's presents yet?
Your Daddy misses you very much.
Please behave yourself.
Don't be naughty for Grandpa and Mommy.
When I come home,
I'll make you a great big kite!
I hope that elder sister's family is well.
Is Lam still working for
the provincial authorities?
Duyen told me that Hai is taking
college entrance exams.
How did he do?
Good news everyone!
He was accepted!
That's great news!
He's as smart as his father.
Give my regards to Mrs. Hien,
Mrs. Dieu and our neighbors.
Father, I wish you good health.
Duyen and Tuan,
I wish you peace and happiness.
What a thoughtful son.
Duyen, come a moment...
Tell your husband to ask for a discharge.
I'll have my husband find a job for him
in his department.
Neither of you give a thought
to the future!
I have good news for everyone.
Our village has been chosen as the first to
participate in the “adopt-a-parent” program.
That's really wonderful to hear!
Program participants will “adopt” parents
whose children died in the war.
They'll take the place of the deceased.
What a great idea!
Dad is lucky to have you for a son-in-law!
A son-in-law is never the same as a son.
Say goodbye to your Father.
For the past ten years I've
worked hard to raise our son.
Our son has grown up.
Please watch over him,
and help him to do well in his studies.
Say goodbye to everyone.
Goodbye, Mrs. Hieu.
Goodbye, I have to go home now.
Dad, we have to get home.
Hai will leave for college
tomorrow morning.
Hai, do your best to study well.
I don't have a gift,
but here's a little money for your travels.
Thank you.
You spoil him so!
Work hard in school, son.
Well, we'd better be leaving soon, too.
I have more meetings this afternoon.
Leaving already?
Yes, we're off.
Sis, take some leftovers to the kids.
No thanks. Leave them for Tuan.
Goodbye.
No pushing!
Order, order!
Careful, or you'll fall.
Remember everyone,
tomorrow class will start early.
Did your father-in-law get the letter?
Yes, he did. Thank you.
Did it come in time
for the death anniversary?
Yes.
No one suspected anything?
No. Please write another letter soon.
Hurry up, it's almost your scene.
Smile! You look like you're at a funeral.
I told you to replace me.
I don't know if I can perform.
This is no time to argue.
Hurry up, get ready.
We have provincial VIPs
out there tonight.
The aggressive enemy forces
seek to swallow our country.
But our people will never surrender!
Our land belongs to our people.
Anyone who dares attack us
will be ground into pieces.
Brothers and sisters!
It's me, Vuong Tru.
I'm on the King's mission to find
volunteers to defend our country.
Khang, let's leave.
Let's watch for a while longer.
It's so boring.
Ok, ok. Let's go then.
I don't want to go back home.
So where should we go?
Anywhere but home.
Truong Vien, my husband!
Our country faces troubled times,
like a bird flying in peaceful skies
meets suddenly with a fierce storm.
I will endure my loneliness while you
pay noble service to our country.
Is that the woman who was
on the ferry with you that day?
Xuan Phuong, my love!
I can withstand any hardship
in order to fight the enemy.
But it will be difficult to be far from you,
my dear wife.
And my beloved mother,
with her hair turning white.
Please take good care of her
in my absence.
Please go in peace.
My love for you is engraved in my head.
I will take care of your mother
like a true daughter.
I will face all hardships bravely.
Truong Vien, my husband!
This war is like a tidal wave,
causing great destruction.
Please keep this pearl
as a rememberance of me.
My father gave me two pearls
for my dowry.
Now these two pearls
must be separated!
We must now follow two different
currents in the river of life!
Dear wife, I will long remember this day.
My husband, I will long for your return.
I will take care of your mother.
Think of the fight ahead.
Don't worry about us at home.
Today we must say farewell
to each other.
We will soon be separated by
a terrible distance,
one in the North, one in the South,
longing for the day we'll meet again.
Our love will stay strong
in the face of storms.
My pillow will lie alone on our bed
throughout the long and cold nights.
A woman alone is like
a bending willow-tree.
Every day looking to
the horizon with longing...
The seasons will pass. Dead flowers and
leaves will return to the earth.
But my loyalty to you
will remain steadfast.
What should we do now?
Go get Hai, we'll do his scene now.
Hai!
Order please!
Due to some difficulty,
we cannot continue this scene.
We'll follow with a comedy scene.
Don't be afraid.
I'm just a fellow villager.
You look like a Cheo theatre character.
That scene about seeing your husband
off to the battlefield?
It's been happening the same way
for generations.
Who are you?
I told you, I'm a fellow villager.
I once went off to the North
to fight off enemy invaders.
Are you the Village Spirit?
I'm neither an angel nor a saint.
I once went off to war like your husband,
and left behind a young wife like you.
Do you know my husband?
Before he went away
he offered me this kite.
Did you forget?
I remember, he burned that kite here.
Now I return to you this keepsake.
Is my husband truly dead?
He now lives on only
in people's memories.
I live to this day for that same reason.
Venerable Spirit, please let me
meet my husband just once more.
I myself have no magic powers.
Only this ground is sacred.
Please live on in peace.
Duyen...
It's me.
Are your joints
still bothering you, Father?
Since Duyen returned,
I've been doing much better.
Letter delivery!
Another letter from Nam, Dad!
He's been writing so often these days.
It's a private letter for Duyen.
Well, sometimes husbands and wives
have private matters to discuss.
I'm just happy we're getting
letters from him.
Hey.
What is it?
Stop what you're doing for a minute.
Read this letter.
Do you see?
I have great admiration for you, Duyen.
I hope that you will face the truth.
A real ladies' man!
I've noticed that something has
changed about Duyen lately.
But who wrote this letter to her?
We need to find out.
He has to be from this village,
not a stranger.
We can ask the
commune authorities for help.
This is a private matter.
If we let the commune know about it
it will make our whole family look bad.
My poor brother!
He believes absolutely in his wife.
This is not just a family matter.
Protecting the honor of a soldier
is a community responsibility.
The local authorities have
to help in this case...
How can we ourselves
catch them in the act?
This handwriting looks familiar.
I'm sure I've seen it before...
Yes, in my son's school exercise book!
I'll have him bring the book here.
Suu, are you home? Suu!
I'm studying Dad.
Bring me your school exercise book.
Right now!
You shouldn't draw pictures
in your exercise book.
Yes, the handwriting is teacher Khang's.
This man is not from around here.
All right, please hold on
to the letter for me.
If it really is Khang's doing, you can
report this directly to the Department.
I will find a way to solve this problem.
I have many friends in the Department.
We need to solve this issue immediately!
How did you get a hold of this letter?
Surely because Duyen doesn't
want to hide anything from us.
You know that her husband is
off fighting at the front...
Protecting the honor of our soldiers
is our responsibility.
No, I don't believe it.
It can't be.
She hasn't told you about her situation?
What is there for her to tell?
No, there's nothing.
You admit that you wrote this letter?
Yes.
Good, so everything's is clear.
This is really hard to believe.
He's such a good person.
This is obviously his letter.
You're his rector,
don't you recognize the writing?
Go away and play, kids.
But read the letter again carefully.
I don't see anything scandalous in it.
Asking to have responsibility for
someone else's wife and children?
That is scandalous!
Please return the letter to me.
It's our responsibility to keep this letter.
Can you catch me?
Wait for me, Mom!
Faster!
This is a good place for kite-flying.
Teacher Khang made it for you?
Yes.
When the tenth month comes...
Hurry up Mom!
Wait just a minute...
Now, when I let go,
you hold the string and run.
It's flying!
Take the string and run!
Let me see, let me see...
What is it?
Pass it on.
Put it away, teacher's looking!
Give it to me.
Who drew this?
Suu drew it, teacher.
Suu, it that right?
Go out for recess everyone.
Suu, you stay here.
Who told you about this?
My Father did.
Your Father?
Go on out for recess.
He's just a kid, it's not his fault.
Where there's smoke, there must be fire.
My grandma told me that in the old days,
on the 15th of the 7th lunar month
there was a ghost market here by the temple
where living and dead people could meet.
Nam, Nam!
Do you have something to tell me?
Why are you silent?
Have I done something wrong?
Then why do you look so sad?
I want those still living to have happiness.
Happiness?
Only living people can bring
happiness to each other.
I've completed my role in the living world.
No, you're still with me,
I still feel you near me everyday.
What remains of me is
something intangible.
I have kept your death
a secret from everyone.
Father still believes
you are coming home.
Let Father be at peace... I
I'll come to him.
Khang!
Who are you looking for?
I'm looking for him.
Have you found him yet?
He just disappeared...
What are you doing up so late?
Today is the fifteenth
of the 7th lunar month.
I forgot to tell you to burn incense.
Please go to bed Father.
What's wrong?
When the tenth month comes,
Rice ripens in the storm-softened fields.
I leave behind me days of longing,
filled with loss and hardship.
While the autumn sky
shines bright and blue...
Khang, Khang!
I intended to say goodbye,
but you were still asleep.
Khang, answer for me one question,
then you can leave.
Go ahead and ask.
Are you in love with Duyen?
Are you running away
because you're afraid?
I need to ask you a favor.
Please give this letter to Duyen.
Go ahead and read it first,
then you'll understand everything.
I have to go if I want to
catch the early train.
I'll write later, once I'm settled.
Goodbye Thom.
Duyen, I've been wanting to meet you
for the past few days.
But I am afraid of making trouble for you,
so I decided not to contact you.
I am returning your husband's letters.
I've memorized every word of them.
And I understand.
Nothing can take the place
of those lost to us.
You've kept your painful secret from
everyone, for the benefit of the living.
But I cannot hide my own sentiments.
I hope that even after such a great loss,
you and Tuan will find happiness.
Wherever I end up, this small village
will always be in my head...
Have you seen Duyen?
I just saw her over there.
Duyen, hey Duyen!
What's the matter?
Go back home right now...
Your Father won't take his medicine.
He told me to come and find you.
I'll go right away.
Go quickly!
Poor girl.
What's the matter Father?
Send a telegram to your husband.
Tell him to take leave and come home.
Take this medicine first.
You have to be strong for
when your son comes home.
Duyen, come out here for a moment.
Duyen, he's not doing well.
You should send the telegram
for your Father's sake.
Or maybe you don't want him
to come home?
Afraid the neighbors will gossip
about you to him?
Please don't be suspicious of me.
Just let me think how to handle this.
It's up to you.
Will you stay here with Father?
I'm going to call my sister-in-law.
Hurry.
Can I get a lift?
A lift please?
Give me a lift into town?
What's your name?
My name's Tuan.
What are you going into town for?
To send a telegram to my Father.
What does your father do?
He's a soldier.
Is that so, little General!
Yes, I'm telling the truth!
My Grandpa told my mom to send a
telegram asking my father to take leave.
But my mom was too busy.
So I'm going instead.
What's your father's name?
My Father's name is Tran Dinh Nam.
Tran Dinh Nam?
What village are you from?
Trung Nghia, where you picked me up.
You playing hooky from school today?
I haven't started school yet.
My mom told me I'd start school
after the harvest season.
What a clever boy!
Have you seen Tuan anywhere?
No, where did he go?
I don't know. I thought he might have
come to visit teacher Khang.
Duyen, please come in.
I'm in a hurry.
Duyen, Khang has left the village.
He left early yesterday morning.
Where did he go?
He was transferred to another school.
Duyen, wait.
He asked me to give you this letter.
I was just getting ready to bring it to you.
Please step down, little General!
We're here!
Oh, we're back at my village!
We'd like to come to your village
and visit your family.
Then I'll help you send your telegram.
Okay?
No, I won't go, I won't!
You tricked me!
Have a break, everyone.
Let me talk to the boy.
I used to be in the same unit
with your father.
We fought together.
You know my father?
Yes.
Your father won't be coming home.
He sacrificed his life on
the southwest border front.
Are you telling the truth?
I'm a soldier.
I always tell the truth.
You would have found out sooner or later.
I don't want to hide the truth from you.
Why are you still alive?
Tuan, wait for me.
Wait!
Please don't tell my Grandpa.
Promise me.
Ok, I promise.
There he is!
Who's here?
Tuan's home.
Tuan, come see your Grandpa.
Tuan, where have you been?
I went to bring my father home
to see you.
Dad!
Have something to drink.
How is he?
Very weak now.
Dad...
You're home.
He won't last much longer.
How sad.
Mom...
Duyen, stay calm.
He couldn't be here,
but we're here instead.
I hid the truth from you, Father.
Calm down, calm down.
Father, this isn't right!
Duyen, I'm a good friend
of your husband.
I've wronged you, Father.
No, you've done nothing wrong.
Let your father pass in peace.
Duyen, I've been waiting for
you and Tuan.
Thank you.
He'll be in my first-year class.
Would you like to be
in my class, Tuan?
Yes.
Don't worry, he'll be fine.
Do you know where Khang is now?
He told me he'd write
when he was settled.
He misses this school a lot.
When you have his address,
let me know.
Okay.
I'd like to thank him.
I know he'd like to hear from you.
Time to go to class now.
Go on, sweetheart
Written and directed by
Dang Nhat Minh
Director of Photography
Nguyen Manh Lam and Phan Phuc Dat
Production Designer
Nguyen Van Vy
Music
Phu Quang
Script Advisor
Van Linh
Sound
Dao Van Bien
Editor
Hien Luong