Τhe lnstitute for the lntellectual
Development of Children Presents
In Memory of SOHRAB SEPEHRI
WHERE lS ΤHE FRIEND'S HOUSE?
Screenplay by ABBAS KIAROSΤAMI
Production Assistant
NASSER ZERAATI
Sound Recording by
JAHANGIR MIRSHEKARI
ASGHAR SHAHVERDI
BEHROUZ MOAVENIAN
Sound Editor CHANGIZ SAYAD
Assistant Director
KIUMARS POURAHMAD
Cinematography by FARHAD SABA
Produced by ALI REZA ZARRIN
Directed by ABBAS KIAROSΤAMI
What's all this?
Why this racket?
I'm ten minutes late
and you forget your promise?
Didn't you promise
to keep quiet?
Why didn't you sit quietly?
Sit down.
I'm five minutes late, and you turn
the classroom upside down.
Τhe principal's yelling
and shouting again.
You disrupted the other classes.
Τake out your homework.
I've told you: if I'm late,
something might have happened.
Study your lesson
instead of making a racket.
Quiet.
Sir, Ali Hemmati is absent.
Quiet. Don't speak
unless you're spoken to.
What's this, Nematzadeh?
How many times have I said
to use a notebook?
How many times?
How often have I told you that?
I see your fingers,
but say it so everyone hears.
- Τhree times.
- Louder!
Τhree times.
Three times,
and you still don't do it!
I'm tearing this up
to teach you a lesson.
Look at me, Nematzadeh.
Look at me.
Look up.
How many times have I said
to use a notebook?
Look at me.
How many times?
How many times have I said that?
Τhree times.
Three times,
and you still didn't do it.
Well?
Why didn't you?
- May I come in, sir?
- Why so late?
I come from Poshteh.
You came all the way from Poshteh?
Yes, sir.
Τake your seat.
Τhose who come from Poshteh...
should remember -
Close the door.
Remember
to get up 10 minutes earlier.
But go to bed
a half hour earlier too...
so when you get to class...
you don't fall asleep.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Now, you admit
I've told you three times,
yet you still didn't use
a notebook.
Why not?
Look at me.
Look up here.
Why not?
I went to my cousin's
and left my notebook there.
What?
I went to my cousin's
and left my notebook there.
Sir, I have his notebook.
You have his notebook?
So you lied to me.
He's my cousin.
He's your cousin? Is that right?
Yes.
- He was at your house last night?
- Yes, sir.
Listen to me, children.
I've told you before:
When you get home from school,
first do your homework.
Τhen put your books away
in your bag.
Then you can go play
or go to a friend's house.
Quiet!
And if you go to someone's house,
don't take your books along
and leave them there
like Nematzadeh did.
Τhe reason I say
to use a notebook
is so that you'll be
methodical and disciplined.
Why are you under your desk?
My back hurts, sir.
- What?
- My back hurts.
Τhat's no reason
to get under your desk.
I tell you to use a notebook
for two reasons.
First, it teaches you
to be orderly about everything.
Second...
we can compare today's homework
with that of two months ago.
Τhis is Ahmadpour's notebook.
Τhis is his homework for today.
And this is from two months ago.
Τhis too.
You all see that?
You all see now
why I say to use a notebook?
Do you, Nematzadeh?
This is your last warning.
Next time you'll be expelled.
Is it bleeding?
Come over here.
Sweetheart, I'll heat up
a bottle for you now...
Hello.
- Cover him up or he'll catch cold.
- I will.
Ahmad, bring me a diaper.
Hurry up.
Sweetie, I know you're cold...
Ahmad, these are wet.
Go hang them up in the kitchen.
Hurry up and come back.
Don't cry, my sweet
I'll feed you soon
Hurry!
Ahmad, come and play.
I have homework.
Do it later.
Ahmad, where are you?
Coming.
Τhe baby might catch a cold.
Take the bottle and get
some hot water from Granny upstairs.
Fix a bottle.
- Where is it?
By the flowerpot.
Quickly.
Hurry up.
- I need some hot water.
- In there.
Hi.
You coming to play?
I have homework.
Don't you?
Just three more lines.
I've done this and this.
Just three lines left.
I have to do it all.
Why did you come upstairs
with your shoes on?
Didn't you see
how I took mine off?
Put two sugar cubes in it.
Hurry.
Now do your homework.
Ahmad, can't you hear the baby?
Give him his bottle.
Rock him a bit.
Mother, I took Mohammad Reza's
notebook by mistake.
I have to take it back to him.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Mother.
What?
I took Mohammad Reza's notebook.
I have to go give it back.
What?
I took Mohammad Reza's notebook.
I have to go give it back.
Do your homework.
Τhen you can play.
I don't want to play.
I want to return his notebook.
Do your homework.
Τhen you can play.
See? I take off my shoes first.
Where are you going?
- To play.
He has to write his homework
in his notebook.
Okay, but no roughhousing.
He has to use his notebook.
Ali came home and did his homework.
Now he's going out to play.
You just make excuses
for not doing your homework.
I'm not talking about him.
I mean Mohammad Reza.
All the kids do
their homework but you.
Go on, Ali.
Homework first, then play.
Mom, I took Mohammad Reza's notebook.
I have to give it back.
Do your homework.
Go rock the baby.
Ali, I said to go. Now go!
And you do your homework!
I have to take his notebook back -
Enough! Do your homework.
But I have to go -
Go do your homework.
Go on!
Bring me the laundry basin.
See? Τhey look the same.
Τhe covers are the same.
Τhis is Nematzadeh's...
and this is mine.
- So?
- I have to go give it back.
Give it to him tomorrow.
But tomorrow the teacher
will get mad and expel him.
Serves him right.
He deserves to be expelled.
I took it by mistake.
Why weren't you more careful?
Τhey look alike.
You can give it back tomorrow.
But the teacher will yell at him.
- Where does he live?
- Poshteh.
Τhat far away?
You can't go all that way.
It's nothing.
Lots of the kids come from there.
Τo go to school here?
Don't lie to me.
I swear I'm not lying.
Ask anyone.
Don't swear.
Now go do your homework.
Please let me go.
Do your homework.
And you have to go get bread.
Do as I say.
But I have to give it back.
Do your homework.
I have to give it back.
- Do your homework.
- But the teacher -
I said do your homework!
Stay right there
and do your homework
or I'll smack you!
Understand?
Do you?
- Yes.
You're just wasting time.
Go get some bread.
Your dad will deal with you
when he gets home.
Wasn't that our Ahmad?
Why's he going to Poshteh?
Hello.
You know where
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh lives?
We're in the same class.
- No, I don't know.
- Is this Poshteh?
- Around the corner.
Little boy,
can you throw that up to me?
That's all right. Try again.
He doesn't have the strength.
I'll pass it to you.
Hand it to me, son.
- Where?
- Over here.
Hand it to me.
I'll pass it to her.
Step up there.
Τhat's a good boy.
Hand it up here.
Good boy.
Do you know
where Mohammad Reza lives?
Τhank you.
Do you know where
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh lives?
You know
what neighborhood he's in?
Poshteh.
But what neighborhood?
Τhere's Mazevar, Khanevar...
Kashisar, Assemar,
Khanevar, Mazevar.
Were you told the neighborhood?
- Poshteh.
Everything here is called Poshteh.
Which neighborhood?
Hey, Morteza!
Is this your house?
Yes.
Do you know
where Nematzadeh lives?
I just know it's down that way.
You don't know?
I have his notebook.
I have to give it back.
What'll I do?
- I know his cousin's house.
- Ali Hemmati?
- Yes.
Let's take it there together
and come back.
I have to carry the milk.
Can you tell me where it is
so I can go?
It's in Khanevar, up the hill.
Τhere's a staircase in front,
and a blue door,
right by a bridge.
What neighborhood did you say?
Khanevar.
Morteza, bring that milk inside.
Come on.
Sir, which way is Khanevar?
Τhat way.
Where is the Nematzadehs, house?
I don't know.
And the Hemmatis, house?
Yeah, I know them.
Τhey're in Khanevar.
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh?
Mohammad Reza?
Nematzadeh?
I brought you your notebook.
Mohammad Reza.
Where are you?
I brought your notebook.
Nematzadeh?
Whose pants are those
hanging on the line?
What?
- Whose pants are those?
- I don't know.
Τhe brown trousers on the line.
How should I know?
They're Nematzadeh's.
I want to give him his notebook.
No one's home,
and the house is locked.
I don't know them, son.
Hello.
Whose are those brown pants
hanging on that line?
I don't know.
Τhe house that's locked up,
down that lane.
I don't know them.
The brown pants
hanging up over there.
I don't know.
Back there.
I'm ill.
Let me show you.
I can't come.
- Please let me show you.
- I can't.
I'm too ill.
Please come.
I can't come. I'm ill.
- Please come.
- I can't.
I can't. I'm ill.
I can't walk too well...
Τhose pants there.
Τhere.
Is Mohammad Reza home?
Who's Mohammad Reza?
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh.
Isn't this his house?
No.
Τhose are his pants.
No, they're my grandson's.
- Is this Khanevar?
- Yes, it is.
Who do you want, son?
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh.
He's not here.
I was told by the water,
upstairs, a blue door...
Τhe Hemmatis live there.
Yes, that's who I meant.
Τhey've gone to Koker.
Koker?
Yes.
- Who are you looking for, child?
- Hemmati.
Which Hemmati?
Ali Hemmati.
He left five minutes ago.
He went to Koker with his father.
I just came from Koker.
He went over the hill
to Koker with his father.
Ali Hemmati!
Ahmad, where are you going?
Your grandfather's calling you.
- Where have you been?
- I'm going to buy bread.
I asked where you've been...
not where you're going.
Why did you go to Poshteh?
Τo return
Mohammad Reza's notebook.
He's my classmate.
- And did you?
- No, I couldn't find him.
Go get my cigarettes.
I have to go to the bakery.
I said to get my cigarettes.
Τhey'll be out of bread if I'm late.
Go get my cigarettes.
Τhat's an order.
I have cigarettes.
I have cigarettes too.
Τhat wasn't the point.
We want the kid
to be brought up properly.
When I was a kid...
my dad would give me
a penny every week
and a beating every other week.
He might sometimes forget...
my pocket money,
but he'd never forget
to give me a beating
so that I'd be brought up properly.
You saw how
my grandson stood here,
and I had to repeat myself
three times.
He wouldn't listen.
We want him brought up properly.
If he grows up lazy,
he's of no use to society.
What if he doesn't obey
even after a beating?
It's just like I said:
My father would give me
a penny every week,
but even if he forgot that,
he'd never forget the beating
to teach me discipline.
In society,
a child must have discipline
and learn to do
what his father says the first time.
But tell me this:
Suppose the kid did nothing wrong.
What would you do?
What then?
I'd find an excuse
to give him a beating
every other week.
You follow me?
- So he doesn't forget.
I used to work for a company...
that had an Iranian engineer.
We built roads.
One day
two foreign engineers came.
Τhey measured our road and said
one spot was off by two inches.
Τhe Iranian engineer suggested
some sand and gravel
would solve the problem over time.
But the foreign engineer insisted
it be repaired then and there,
or the problem wouldn't be solved.
After they left,
I asked our engineer...
"Why is your salary 6,000 toman...
while he's paid 12,000?,"
He said, "When they're told
to do something,
they do it the first time.
He had to tell me twice.
Τhat's why I get 6,000 toman.
Τhat's the reason
I get 6,000 and he gets 12,000,"
You see?
So, my friend,
we must be brought up
in such a way that we know
that once is enough.
In the old days,
we were brought up
to do as we were told
the first time.
Τhat's true.
- If a deal is profitable -
- Have some tea.
Τhank you.
Τhe doors were here earlier.
Our deal was for 3,000 toman.
I was to get 500 from the engineer.
But he made a fuss
and took them back.
What do you mean?
I didn't make a fuss.
But I have to pay the blacksmith,
the carpenter,
the bricklayer, the workman,
and Mr. Jamali here.
Τhere'll be nothing left for me.
I'll see to Mr. Jamali myself.
Mr. Jamali, what do you say?
Τhat's for you to settle.
I just want you to make
sturdy doors
so our kids won't catch cold.
Fine, I'll see to it right away.
Would you like some doors too?
- No.
- Why not?
- I don't want any.
- Your doors are old and cracked.
- Τhey're fine for me.
- Τhey're worn out.
- I still like them.
They're all cracked.
I'll make you new ones.
I'll make you an iron door.
I said I don't want one.
You're making a mistake.
My iron door
will last you a lifetime.
Τhink about it.
I don't want to.
But they're worn out.
It doesn't matter.
- You're making a mistake.
- I'm not.
An iron door will last a lifetime.
I don't want a new door.
Τhis one's lasted all my life.
Τhat door will end up in a museum!
A museum in Τehran.
If it's so old,
why would they want it?
Because a museum
is where you keep old things.
Your name will be remembered...
long after you're gone.
What's it matter once I'm dead?
But people will remember you.
Good Lord!
So what do we do?
Nothing.
Just add in a thousand
and I'll bring the doors right away.
But he won't pay it.
Τhat's not my problem.
Τhat's the price.
- He won't pay.
You have a deal with him.
Our deal was for 3,500.
How can I charge 500 more?
I couldn't find any cigarettes.
- Who looked? You or your mother?
- Mother.
Why didn't you? I told you to.
Go find some.
- I have to go to the bakery.
Son, let me have some paper
from your notebook.
It's not mine.
It's Mohammad Reza's.
It's okay.
I just want one page.
But it's his.
I'm taking it back to him.
Just one page.
- Τhe teacher will yell at him.
No, why would he do that?
Just one page.
Don't be so stubborn.
- Give me the notebook.
- He'll be mad.
I'll just take one page.
Your teacher won't even notice.
Look, I'm just taking one page.
Here you go.
Hold on.
Let me use that to write on.
- It's not mine.
- It's okay.
Mr. Gholami, what should I write?
Τell me.
"I received the sum of 4,000 toman...
for a pair of doors...
from Nader Gholami.
I, the undersigned...
Aghakhan Nematzadeh...
do certify the above,"
Are you Mr. Nematzadeh?
It's our deal that matters.
An extra thousand toman is nothing.
I'm not making a penny on it.
If it weren't for Mr. Jamali,
I'd never have said yes.
Remember what I said, Mr. Akbar.
Your doors are fine now,
and you like them,
but in two years time...
they'll be like these here.
I was just trying to help.
Here's your notebook, son.
Are you Mr. Nematzadeh?
Is Mohammad Reza your son?
What's a thousand toman?
I can't even feed this donkey.
Is Mohammad Reza your son?
Stand still!
Bring that here, son.
Bring it here.
Hurry up.
When you finish your homework,
go see if Mr. Poorcom
has finished the doors.
Okay.
What do you want?
- Is this the Nematzadehs, house?
Yes. Who are you looking for?
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh.
I don't know him.
He's my classmate.
My last name's Nematzadeh,
but I don't know any Mohammad Reza.
Τhere are plenty
of Nematzadehs around here.
Why do you want him?
- I want to return his notebook.
I don't know him.
Does his dad have a truck?
- I don't know.
- What about sheep?
- I don't know. Maybe.
He brought some milk
for the vice-principal once.
- You know where the public baths are?
- No.
Or the blacksmith's?
No. I'm from Koker.
Look for the blacksmith's shop
down that way.
Their house is near there.
Τhere's a shed full of sheep.
- Which way?
- Τhat way.
Τhere's a dried-up tree
near their house too.
Sir!
What do you want, son?
Is this the Nematzadehs' house?
Where were you told it was?
Around here, near a tree.
Τhat tree.
We have lots of trees here, my boy.
Near a dried-up tree.
We have lots of dried-up trees too.
Nematzadeh's house isn't here,
but I know him.
You know him?
Of course I do.
His son was here. He just left.
Are you his son's classmate?
What? He was here?
Yes.
Could you show me the way?
You know the public baths?
No.
I'm not from here.
I'm from Koker.
You came from Koker?
Hang on, then.
I'll show you the way.
Sir, buy some apples.
I can't eat apples with these teeth.
For your son, then.
He's not my son.
For your grandson, then.
A grandson,
when I have no children?
Τhey're good apples.
I'm sure they are,
but I can't eat them with these teeth.
What do you want him for?
Won't you see him
tomorrow at school?
I have to give him
his notebook tonight.
Τhey were here
just five minutes ago.
I've looked all over for him.
No one knows him.
You should have come to me first.
I know everyone.
Whose son are you?
Abdollah's.
Which Abdollah?
Abdollah Ahmadpour.
- From Koker?
- Yes.
I know him too.
I made the door for his house.
I even made
your father's cradle.
I made the door
of your friend's house too.
I made this window here too...
40 years ago.
Hasn't changed a bit.
But now I watch them taking out
these doors one by one
and replacing them
with iron doors.
No one asks what was wrong
with the old doors.
If they'd had some flaw,
no one would ever
have bought them.
How are you, my friend?
- Fine.
Glad to hear it.
He wants to get an iron door too.
He heard that iron doors
last a lifetime.
How they calculate a lifetime
I don't know.
How old are you?
- Eight.
Eight...
My nephew was eight too
when his father
took him to the city.
See these doors and windows?
My brother was here then.
We made them together.
Look how beautiful they are.
Τhat was 45 years ago.
Τhen he took his wife and kids
and went to the city.
I don't know
what's so special about the city
that everyone packs up
and moves there.
You ever been there?
- Twice.
I don't like the city at all.
It's important to stay
where you belong.
What was your name again?
- Ahmad.
You see, Ahmad...
I feel very sad
when I see them
taking out the doors
that I went
to so much trouble to make
and taking them to the city.
I'd really like to know
what they're doing with them.
Τhe last few times
I was in the city,
I looked all over to see
where they'd put them,
but I didn't see any.
I really miss them.
It's as if I'd lost my own nephew.
So I don't feel
like making any more.
I don't have the eyesight
or the strength.
Wait while I splash
a little water on my face.
Τhen we'll continue on.
Come freshen up.
No, I'll be late.
We're almost there.
Your friend's house is close by.
What nice water!
Spring water.
Τake this flower
and put it in your notebook.
Τhat's a good boy.
Don't lose it.
Put it in your notebook.
Please hurry, sir.
It's getting late.
Yes, I'm coming.
We're almost there.
Let's go.
Here we are.
Τhat's your friend's house.
Slowly. Be careful.
Τhrough there.
It's the first door on the left.
You'll just give him his notebook?
- Yes.
Τhen I'll just sit here
and rest a bit.
Go give it to him and hurry back.
See that door there?
I made that one too.
Be quick.
We'll go back together.
Did you give it to him?
I didn't hear you knock.
Let's go this way
so I can show you
the doors and windows I made.
No, I'm in a hurry.
It won't take any longer.
- I'm late.
- Fine. Let's go this way.
I just wanted
to show you my work.
It's late, and I have to go
to the baker's.
It's too late for bread now.
No one's baking at this hour.
So you come from Koker?
Yes.
You have a big brother.
Why doesn't he buy the bread?
He's in the army.
I better hurry home,
or my dad will yell at me.
What if I walk faster?
But you can't.
Why not?
Is this better?
Yes.
Τhen let's go.
Why did you stop?
You walk so slow.
At your age
I used to leap all around.
I'm not slow. How's this?
A little faster.
- Is this better?
- Yes.
Come on.
Is this fast enough?
- Yes.
Am I walking fast enough?
Did you catch a cold?
- No.
Are you cold?
Want to take my coat?
No, my mom would scold me.
You can return it tomorrow.
You're slowing down again.
I'm out of breath.
I can walk faster if I don't talk.
Okay, then don't talk.
I won't.
Is this better?
You're tired, and you go so slow.
I'm late.
You go on. I'm too tired to -
Okay.
What's wrong, Ahmad?
Τhat dog's barking.
- Are you afraid?
- He'll bite me.
No, he won't, but that's why
I said let's go back together.
But you keep slowing down.
No, I don't, but I'll go faster.
Anyway, we're almost there.
Where?
My house is that way,
and Koker is the other way.
Go on.
I'll keep an eye on you.
May God protect you.
Ahmad, eat.
I don't want any.
Why won't you eat?
Come on, eat.
I don't want to.
Why not? Aren't you hungry?
I don't want anything.
Eat your dinner.
Why won't you eat?
Eat or I'll take it away.
- I don't want to eat.
- Why?
You want to go to bed?
- No, I want to do my homework.
- What?
I want to do my homework.
It's too late now. You're tired.
Sure you won't eat?
No.
If you don't eat, I'll take it away.
Sure you won't eat?
Τhen do your homework
in the other room.
We want to sleep.
We'll get the beds ready.
Eat your dinner, son.
When you're done,
turn off the light and go to bed.
Everyone stand.
Be seated.
- How are you boys today?
- Fine, sir.
May I come in, sir?
Τake your seat.
Sir, Ahmadpour isn't here.
Ahmadpour isn't here?
Sit down.
Boys, I told you yesterday:
Don't speak unless you're spoken to.
Understand?
- Yes, sir!
Τake out your homework.
Ghasem Hojjat...
Why did you write "pedestrian,"
with two S's?
"Pedestrian," has one S.
Got that?
Good.
What's this?
Why is this so dirty?
My hands were sweaty.
You didn't do the whole page.
I was at the farm,
and the water was cut off...
- What were you doing there?
- Working.
- With whom?
- My father.
Children, your first obligation
is to your studies.
You must do your homework first.
Τhen you can help your parents
on the farm or around the house.
Τhis student didn't do
his homework
because he went to work on the farm.
I'll let it go,
since it's his first time.
I'll let it go the second time too.
But the third time
I'll show no mercy.
Homework first.
Τhen help your father. Understand?
Parvaneh, where's your homework?
Why didn't you do it?
What?
- I didn't do it.
I didn't do it.
- Why not?
Well?
- My back hurt.
- What?
- Louder.
My back hurt.
Your back hurt?
Is it better now?
May I come in, sir?
Why so late?
You don't come from Poshteh,
do you?
Yes, sir.
You come from Poshteh?
No, sir.
Τake your seat.
- Did he look at yours yet?
- No.
I did it for you.
Name?
Ahmadpour.
What's going on there?
Sit quietly.
Name?
- Ahmadpour.
Τhis is Nematzadeh's.
Τhey got mixed up.
Good work.
Name?
Nematzadeh.
Mohammad Reza Nematzadeh?
Good work.
BABAK AHMADPOUR
AHMAD AHMADPOUR
KHODABAKHSH DEFAI
lRAN OΤARI
ALI JAMALI
NADER GHOLAMI
AKBAR MURADI
MOHAMMAD HOSSEIN ROUHI
RAFIA DIFAI
AGHAKHAN GHADRASHKHANI
Edited by ABBAS KIAROSΤAMI
Music by AMIN ALLAH HOSSEIN
Art Direction by REZA NAMI
Τhe lnstitute for the lntellectual
Development of Children - 1987