Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
A TOHO FILM
WOMAN IN THE DUNES
This is terrible.
Is this an inspection?
Inspection?
Not really.
Were you expecting one?
You can stay as long as
it's not an inspection.
I'm collecting insects.
Huh?
Bugs. I collect bugs.
I specialize
in these sand bugs.
So you're not
from the prefectural office?
Prefectural office?
Don't be absurd.
I'm a schoolteacher.
A teacher?
I see.
The certificates we use
to make certain of one another:
contracts, licenses,
ID cards, permits,
deeds, certifications,
registrations, carry permits,
union cards,
testimonials, bills, IOUs,
temporary permits, letters
of consent, income statements,
certificates of custody,
even proof of pedigree.
Is that all of them?
Have I forgotten any?
Men and women
are slaves to their fear
of being cheated.
In turn they dream up new certificates
to prove their innocence.
No one can say
where it will end.
They seem endless.
You criticized me
for arguing too much.
But the facts
speak for themselves.
Teacher man!
What'll you do now?
Do?
I'll  be back tomorrow.
But the last bus has left.
You're right.
There must be
some place to stay.
In this village?
If not here, then maybe
near the highway?
You gonna walk?
I'm in no hurry.
No need to go so far.
If you want,
I can ask around for you.
You can see it's a poor village,
but if you don't mind -
You'd do that?
I'm very grateful.
I won't be rushed
in the morning,
and I'd love to stay
in a real home.
Thank you.
Careful. There are deep pits
on both sides.
Hey, you old hag!
Whatchya doin'?
You've got a guest!
The ladder's beside the bales.
You sure it's okay?
Don't worry.
It's very informal here.
In that case...
A rope ladder?
That's what we use
out here in the boonies.
This is quite an adventure.
Don't lean away from the rope.
Hold on tight.
Don't look up.
You'll get sand in your face.
This way, please.
Please.
Thanks for your hospitality.
Dinner will be ready soon.
Great.
Could I take a bath first?
Yes, but -
Never mind then.
Please wait
until the day after tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow?
I'm afraid not.
I only have three days off.
I beg your pardon.
You only have one lamp?
It's all right.
I'll be finished soon.
It's a pain
not having electricity, huh?
Help yourself.
Thanks.
Clams and bream -
looks good.
Nothing beats
local delicacies.
What's that for?
- The sand seeps in.
Why?
Is the roof damaged?
No, it's the same
with newly thatched roofs.
How can that be?
Bugs, even worse
than woodborers.
Woodborers?
Yes. They make holes
in the wood.
You must mean termites.
No. They're this big,
with hard shells.
Could it be a saw beetle?
Saw beetle?
The reddish one
with long antennae.
No, these are bronze-colored,
like a grain of rice.
Then I guess
it must be a woodborer.
If you're not careful,
even a beam this big
will get spongy and rot.
From the woodborers?
No, the sand.
How so?
I guess it draws moisture.
Nonsense.
Sand is naturally dry.
But it really makes things rot.
You must be kidding!
Use your common sense.
A desert is dry
because it's all sand.
Have you ever heard
of a damp desert?
Sorry, but could I have
some tea?
But it does rot.
They say
if you leave sand on clogs,
they'll rot in two weeks.
That's ridiculous.
The wood rots,
and so does the sand.
We found soil in the ceiling
of a buried house
rich enough
to grow cucumbers in.
Okay, whatever you say.
- More?
- No, thanks.
Thank you.
That was delicious.
This is terrible!
When it's windy...
two feet of sand
can pile up in one night.
See?
Even the futon is damp.
Where is everyone?
Your family.
I live alone.
Last year a storm swallowed up
my husband and daughter.
Swallowed up?
The sand roared down
like a waterfall.
He went out
to save the chicken coop.
And got buried?
It was a horrible gale.
That's awful.
That's really awful.
It's the sand.
Are you here for research?
Yes.
That reminds me:
Are there any insects
like this around here?
It's called a tiger beetle.
Here it is.
I want to find others
like that one.
This species has many variants.
If I find a new variant,
I'll get my name in a field guide.
All I'm good for is
catching bugs by the tail.
Hey, we brought
the helper's tools!
So there's someone else
here with you after all.
That's a good one.
But he just said something
about a helper.
He meant you.
Me? Why?
Don't worry about it.
There must be
some misunderstanding.
Do you still need the lamp?
Yes, if you don't mind.
That's all right.
I'm used to the work.
Man, this is foul.
No, don't.
- Want help?
- No, not on the first day.
The first day?
That again?
I'm only staying the night.
You always shovel at night?
Yes, the sand's moist.
Makes it easier.
Basket's ready!
Thanks!
Here it comes.
Let me help.
Clear!
Can't be easy for them either.
This village has real local spirit.
What kind of spirit?
Love of our birthplace.
I see.
A good thing, indeed!
- Just how long do you work?
- Until morning.
Morning?
The sand won't wait.
Clear!
What a wreck!
Ouch!
That's strange.
The ladder's gone.
Ma'am.
Could you wake up, please?
Sorry, but could you
get the ladder?
It's not there.
I'd like to be on my way.
I only have three days off.
I can't dawdle.
Wait a minute.
That was a rope ladder!
It can only be lowered
from above.
Shit! It was a trap!
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
What do you mean?
I asked what you meant.
I'm sorry.
That's not enough!
I've got a job.
I can't waste time.
But you do understand,
don't you?
Understand?
What's there to understand?
But you know...
this life's really too hard
for a woman alone.
What's that got
to do with me?
The north winds will come soon.
There may be sandstorms too.
You're holding me captive?
I'm terribly sorry.
Is this a joke?
I'm not some homeless bum.
I'm a respected teacher.
I'm registered with the city.
You'll be in trouble
when I'm reported missing.
Illegal confinement
is a serious offense.
If I fall behind,
my house will be buried.
Fine! Let it be!
You can't drag me into this!
Then the house next door
would be next.
They can all get buried,
for all I care!
And what about you?
Why do you cling
to this place?
You must be mad!
Look.
You don't owe
those villagers a damn thing.
I can't share
your sense of self-sacrifice.
Let them deal
with the sand scientifically,
with tree fences or something.
They calculated
that it's much cheaper this way.
Fine! Whatever you say!
Just call the man in charge!
I'll tell him
how stupid all this is!
What are you waiting for?
There must be
some way to call them.
Bang on the oil can
or something!
Why don't you say anything?
It's not impossible.
I'm going with
the natural slope of the sand.
Son of a bitch!
What's that sound
A little bell
Splish, splash
What's that sound
A demon's voice
Splish, splash
What's that sound
Mister, are you awake?
How do you feel?
Could be worse.
Let me wipe your back.
Stop that! It hurts!
It hurts?
Yes.
Shall I massage you?
Are you serious?
I may have broken something.
If you're so concerned,
call a doctor.
Isn't my underwear dry yet?
You shouldn't wear
anything in bed.
Why not?
You'll get rashes from the sand.
Rashes?
The sand draws moisture.
Keep quiet!
Don't resist!
You'll have
to endure it a while.
Now we can both say
we've been deceived.
You reap what you sow.
Men aren't dogs.
You can't put them on a leash.
Hey, What's going on?
Hurry up down there!
We're waiting!
Pull me up!
I'm not letting go!
She's tied up inside!
If you want to help her,
pull me up!
No.
They haven't won yet.
The battle's just begun.
They're going to be
in big trouble.
There's nothing to fear.
I've got the upper hand.
This is actually
a good experience.
Maybe I'll write about it
when I get back.
It's shochu.
How thoughtful...
giving me booze
to celebrate in advance.
A coup d'etat, huh?
People can't sit still
for a minute.
Want a cigarette?
No.
Smoking dries my throat.
- Water, then?
- I'm fine for now.
Feel free to ask.
I have nothing personal
against you.
Does it hurt?
We must be careful.
Rations only come
once a week.
Rations?
Yes.
Only to households
with a man.
The village council
pays for them.
Tell me something.
Has this happened
to men before me?
We're so short of people.
Who else was abducted?
Let's see.
Last fall,
a postcard salesman.
A postcard salesman?
He worked for a company
that made travel postcards.
Any others?
This year...
there was a student
carrying out a survey.
Three houses over.
He's still there.
They pulled up the ladder
on him too, huh?
Young people don't want
to stay in the village.
The pay's better in the cities.
Movie theaters and restaurants
are open year-round, right?
This is lunacy!
What is it?
Does it hurt?
Would you please scratch
behind my right ear?
Like this?
I'm sorry,
but could I have some water?
Water, please!
I'm begging you!
This is all that's left.
When's the next ration?
That's enough!
Not so much!
Shut up!
This is your own doing!
Shall I untie you?
But get this straight:
It's not out of sympathy.
I've just had enough
of your pitiful face.
There's one condition:
no shoveling unless I say so.
You promise me that?
Yes, I promise!
I'll promise anything!
If I suffer, you suffer.
Give that some serious thought.
Where are you going?
Run for it!
Can't we do something?
It's because we haven't
shoveled any sand for two nights.
Water!
I'm talking about water!
Aren't you thirsty?
I was nice enough to untie you.
You could cooperate a little.
Well, you see...
if we just started
working again -
Give me a break!
Who's got the right to force me
into such a rotten deal?
You have to use
the right man for the right job.
I'm a teacher,
and something of a scholar.
They could at least
put my abilities to better use.
We could, for example...
think of some way to exploit
the lure of the dunes.
My fascination with the sand
is what brought me here, after all.
I'm serious.
That postcard salesman
probably came
for the same reason.
Advertise the area.
Develop it into a tourist resort.
Make the sand work for you,
not against you.
But a resort needs
a hot spring.
Well, that was just one idea.
Maybe there are special crops
that grow in the sand.
Yes, the Youth League
grows a few things,
like peanuts and tulips.
They said
the tulip bulbs were so big
that they showed them
at an agricultural fair in Tokyo.
If you saw them -
That's enough!
Even a monkey could be
trained to do this work.
A monkey?
It'll make you sick.
My breath feels like it's on fire.
This is futile.
If it wanted to...
the sand could swallow up cities,
even entire countries.
Did you know that?
A Roman town called Sabrata...
and that one> in
The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam...
both completely buried
under particles
an eighth of a millimeter wide.
You can't fight it!
It's hopeless!
What are you doing?
No!
I'm gonna make a ladder!
You can't do that!
Shall I... brush off the sand?
But...
aren't all the city girls
prettier than me?
Nonsense!
Give me the cloth.
Damn it!
My blood's gonna rot!
What a dirty move!
What should I do?
Do something!
My blood's gonna rot!
You see...
if we just started
working again -
Fine!
I give in!
You win!
What's the matter, mister?
The water's come!
It's my turn.
Hold your left hand lower.
Try using your right hand.
You won't get as tired.
I haven't slept much.
Rest if you want.
It takes getting used to.
This must be how
it would feel if my muscles...
were made of cement.
You'll tire easily
until you're used to it.
I wonder
if I'll ever get used to it.
You will.
I don't get it.
Doesn't all this seem
pointless to you?
Are you shoveling sand to live,
or living to shovel sand?
I know it's not
as fun as Tokyo.
I'm not talking about Tokyo!
How can you stand
being trapped like this?
This is my home.
Then demand your rights.
Me, I'm just biding my time
until I'm rescued.
Rescued?
Of course.
If I miss a week of work,
they'll come looking for me.
They'll see the book
left open in my room
and find the loose change
in my coat pocket.
They're bound to be suspicious.
But you'll live like this forever
if you don't speak up.
But they're buried here.
They?
My husband and daughter.
So you mean...
you'd leave
if they were dug up?
I'll help you do it!
You know how to make them
lower the ladder.
There's nothing for me to do
on the outside.
You could walk around.
Walk around?
Yes! It's great
to walk around freely!
Isn't it exhausting,
just walking around aimlessly?
This isn't funny!
Even dogs go crazy
chained up all day!
And we're human beings!
But you see,
if it weren't for the sand,
no one would bother
about me.
Isn't that right?
Not even you.
Look, here's one.
Don't do that!
This is what brought me here
in the first place.
It's the tiger beetle
I was telling you about.
Got any scissors?
Scissors?
I just want to trim
my whiskers.
I should have some.
They may not be very sharp.
They sure are rusty.
It's because of the sand.
- These are no good.
- No?
Not even close.
Let's ask for a razor
when they bring the rations.
See? The sand makes
my whiskers all scratchy.
That sand just ruins
everything, doesn't it?
Hey, hurry up!
All right! Thanks!
Where's your husband?
Stomachache.
He caught a chill.
Or maybe you gave him
too much lovin'!
Clear!
Need help with the bath?
No bath tonight.
I'm dead tired.
But I'd really like one.
No, you're sick.
I'm sticky with sweat.
Night sweats.
I was too sick to sleep.
I guess I could heat it up.
- Please. I'll help.
- That's okay. I'll do it.
What are you thinking?
Nothing.
I'll take your picture.
Stand there.
I'd rather not.
Come on.
Smile.
You want to go home,
don't you?
Why do you ask?
A radio might take
your mind off things.
You could hear
about the world.
Why bother?
You'd know
what's happening in Tokyo.
I began collecting insects
to get away from all that.
Compared to that
unfathomable way of life,
getting my name in a book
is at least something tangible.
But a radio would be
a nice diversion.
Very well.
Shall we finish off
that shochu?
- You're still sick.
- It helps you sleep.
I'm sleepy enough
without it.
Come on, have some.
I really can't.
Come on.
I feel like celebrating today.
- The water's boiling.
- Come on.
What's gotten into you?
Go ahead, drink up.
It feels good
to finally have a bath.
You're terrible...
making me work like this
when I'm so tired.
Help!
Someone help me!
Here, grab on to this.
Please pull me out
with this rope.
You fool. We can't pull you out
like some kind of root.
We'll dig you out.
Grab on to the board.
Good thing
we came by in time.
There's a lot of quicksand
around here.
Even the dogs stay away.
How many people
have fallen in before?
Hikers and others
don't know it's here.
If we dug, we might find
something valuable.
Two or three cameras for sure.
Be quiet.
I'm sorry.
Shall I make some tea?
What time is it?
I don't know.
Maybe around 8:30.
I failed.
Complete and utter failure.
Do you have...
a wife?
In Tokyo.
That's no concern of yours.
You're right.
But it's too bad.
If I'd succeeded...
I was going
to send you a radio.
A radio?
You want one, don't you?
That's all right.
You don't have to do that.
I can do piecework
and buy one here.
I failed.
Shall I wipe you off?
I didn't know the geography,
that's why.
But eventually
they'll come looking for me:
my friends...
the union...
the school board, the PTA.
They won't let me die here.
Come. Let me wash you.
What's that?
- My last hope.
- Last hope?
It's a crow trap.
I place the bait on top
of the newspaper.
If a crow goes for the bait,
it'll get sucked into the sand.
Crows are very clever.
Hunger makes them stupid.
Why do you say
it's your last hope?
'Cause it is.
I'll tie a message to its leg
asking for help.
They're not coming, you know.
It's been almost three months.
Who?
Your rescuers.
They probably think you ran away.
Ran away?
That you got sick of your job.
Impossible.
I left my bankbook lying around.
I left an open book on my desk.
Anyone could see the room's
practically screaming for help.
What's there for you?
What do you mean?
In Tokyo.
Why do you think
I said to go see it?
This is too much.
Hey, your rations!
Wait a minute! Wait!
Can't you let me out
once in a while?
Thirty minutes, once a day,
to see the sea?
I promise not to escape.
Twenty minutes!
Even ten!
I've been good
for three months!
Please, I'm going crazy!
The village council
will discuss it and let you know.
Please!
You can keep me under guard!
You're working terribly hard.
Twenty more
and I'll earn 1,000 yen.
“You're being
such a good sport.”
“I keep smiling
through thick and thin!”
I won't be made a fool of!
I refuse to die like a dog!
What good's a radio?
Soon it'll be too late.
They don't care about you.
I know that much.
People only care
about themselves.
Here we are,
ruthlessly exploited,
yet happily wagging our tails.
Before you know it,
they'll abandon us here.
Never!
All the sand is here!
The sand?
What good is that?
It's the source
of all your troubles.
- It sells.
- Where?
At the factories in town.
Are you joking?
It's illegal to use sand this salty.
Under the table, at half price.
Hardly a bargain
when a darn or building collapses.
That's other people's business.
That's right.
But someone's
getting rich off this scam.
Why help them?
The union does
the buying and selling.
They treat us very well.
I'll sift the sand.
Living here is like
building a house on water
when a boat
would make more sense.
Such rigid thinking.
It has to be a house
or nothing at all.
But don't you want
to go home too?
That's different.
Even if it's only a lie...
it helps to have hope...
that things
will change tomorrow.
I'm so frightened every morning
when I go to sleep
that I'll wake up alone again.
That really frightens me.
Put them in here.
Hey, mister, working hard?
What's he doing here?
It's too early for the basket.
You said you wanted
to see the sea?
Yes.
Please! Will you let me?
It's a possibility.
Please.
I've learned my lesson.
Just an hour a day?
Okay, but show us
some you-know-what.
Both of you come out...
where everyone can see you.
“You-know-what”?
Yeah, you heard me.
You know, with your old lady.
Like this, man!
We all discussed it.
We all agreed.
This is what you gotta do.
Hey, what's taking so long!
Hurry up!
What should we do?
It's ridiculous!
But it's my only chance.
Just ignore them.
Look, we don't have
to take it so seriously.
What?
We're not perverts!
Who cares?
We're living like animals anyway!
Come on!
We can just pretend!
You idiot!
How did this happen?
That's odd.
It hasn't rained a drop
in over three weeks.
It must be capillary action.
That's it.
If I can perfect the technique,
we'll never worry about water again.
Evaporation at the surface
draws up underground moisture.
The entire dune acts as a pump.
It's as if we're sitting
on top of a suction pump.
I may be able to devise
an even better tank.
This is awful!
I can hardly breathe.
It's almost December.
Well, then.
That again?
Food's scarce when it's cold.
A crow's more likely
to take the bait.
Men!
Sometimes I want to be
the one to set a trap.
If only the radio would arrive,
we could hear
the weather report.
I'm afraid.
I'll bury this
while the water's heating.
Just another day now...
Help!
Someone help!
No... no.
- What's wrong?
- She's in pain.
It's a baby.
A baby?
Since when?
October.
- Any pain here?
- Yes.
- Nausea?
- Yeah.
What about here?
It may be
an ectopic pregnancy.
How do you know
these things?
He used to shoe horses
for the veterinarian!
Never mind that.
Just call a doctor quick!
He wouldn't get here in time.
Doctors nowadays...
Have them bring
the three-wheeler.
Here they come.
I'm afraid.
Has the wind died down?
Yes, quite a bit.
- How do we get her up?
- Wrap her in the futon.
Let's go.
Put a board under her.
Here's your radio.
The radio, huh?
Bad timing.
Shall I open it?
Want to take it?
Wrap it up with her
in the futon.
Have you got another board?
Take one
from the shelf out back.
The one below that.
Okay. One, two...
Lift!
No... no.
Listen.
Wait.
Did you say something?
Never mind.
Some other time.
No...
Okay, pull her up.
No.
No... no!
Pull her in closer.
Take it slow. Don't rush.
There's no need
to rush away just yet.
I have a return ticket.
I'm free to write in
my own origin
and destination.
Besides,
I'm bursting with the desire
to tell someone
about the pump.
And who better to tell
than these villagers?
If not today,
maybe tomorrow.
I'm sure I'll end up
telling somebody.
I can think about escaping
the day after that.
TOKYO FAMILY COURT
MISSING PERSON REPORT
NAME: JUMPEI NIKI
DATE OF BIRTH:
MARCH 7, 1927
MISSING OVER SEVEN YEARS
LISTED AS DISAPPEARED