My son, our family owes
a lot to the cyclo taxi.
We work hard, day and night.
Eating and sleeping in the street.
Pedalling all the time.
Some mornings, the backaches
nail you to the bed.
I don't know where it all leads.
This has been my life.
When I die,
I'll have nothing to leave you.
If you can,
see if you can find
something more worthy.
You're late!
Look again
and see if I'm right.
"The People's Committee
makes loans
"in line with the policy
"of fighting poverty. "
Where is it? Show me!
How old are you?
Eighteen.
Parents' occupation?
We're very poor.
Answer me, your parents?
My mother died in childbirth.
My father too, an accident...
How did he die?
A truck... he died instantly,
with two passengers.
At Hang Xanh intersection, right?
Yes.
Who's left?
My grandfather, my sisters.
They study in the morning
and work in the afternoon.
What do they do?
The eldest delivers water to the
market, the little one shines shoes.
And your grandfather?
He repairs tires.
Who rents you
the cyclo taxi?
The boss lady in Cholon.
Her name?
I don't know
How much per day?
5,000 dongs.
And the deposit?
200,000 dongs.
Okay, we'll consider your file.
We'll let you know.
Yes.
These days it hurts
when I piss.
What about you?
Me too. It burns.
You've got to drink, it helps.
It makes you sweat, wears you out.
A doctor warned me,
take anything to build muscles,
you end up impotent.
Yeah, right!
Who can afford a doctor?
Better to see a butcher.
Shoe shine, sir, shoe shine?
You free, kid?
Cyclo!
Number 8, Le Loi Street.
How dare you steal our clients?
It's her...
This is our turf.
If you want to live, get lost!
Beat it, you're on our turf!
Yes, you're my little fish.
So, how much?
It's a good day.
26,000.
5,000 for you,
21,000 for me.
No problem?
The thugs
took a passenger from me.
Careful, each turf has its gang.
You hungry?
Want to eat?
Wash him,
give him something to eat.
Go with him.
He was born that way,
he must be your age.
Take care of your tooth.
You see, I told you.
Okay, that's enough, get out.
Come on Grandpa, it's late.
Yes, let's go home.
Bring tobacco for grandfather.
Is your shoulder better?
It gets worse every day.
Do you have any balm left?
Hardly any.
I'll bring some back for you.
Grandfather, take the scale
they sent us by mistake
and change jobs, it'll be easier.
See how it's done.
Someone comes, you wipe.
You invite him to try,
1000 dongs per person.
We shouldn't.
The scale isn't ours.
Yes we can,
we've waited long enough.
No one has claimed it.
Your shoulder's hurting.
You can't keep pumping tires.
Let's wait awhile.
On the old riverbanks.
Leaves and flowers fade.
The sun dies, icy, shuddering.
Hesitant, I cross the hamlet.
My childhood, I remember you.
I remember your graceful silhouette.
You gazed at me, radiant, tender.
I remember the sun was setting.
On your ivory cheeks
your rippling hair.
Put him to bed.
Tomorrow, I'll come see
if you're dead or not.
Get up, little brother.
Go wash up!
If I, the Heron,
die by boiling.
May it be in clear water.
To ease my children's suffering.
Follow them!
And not a word to anyone.
Bom has a fan
made of palm leaves.
The Rich Man says, I'll trade you.
Three cows and nine buffalo.
I don't want your buffalo.
I'll give you
a pond full of fish.
I don't want your fish.
I'll give you
a raft of precious wood.
I don't want your wood.
I'll give you
a bird...
Tomorrow, come to the icehouse.
I'll tell you what to do.
Go now and be discreet.
What's the matter?
Who is it?
Why?
He stole my cyclo.
Don't be stupid,
he works for the boss lady.
Let's go!
Wait here!
Don't go out.
Except to eat
and don't lock the door.
Close your mouth, it stinks.
Do you have any money?
No!
We stayed up all night again.
Let's go to sleep.
Can I sleep here?
Another time.
I don't want to do it.
I came
because you wanted me to.
I called, no one answered.
Can I come in?
Don't touch her.
It's her first time.
Would you like to pee?
You want to piss?
Peepee, you get it?
Understand?
Go on, pee!
Drink... go on, drink!
Drink and pee.
Pee, please!
Drink again!
Again, drink up!
That's enough! Piss!
And do it standing up!
I brought you two friends.
People
are singing your praises.
You're a Samaritan.
You tried to save a drowning man?
The boss is happy.
She sent you this reward.
Damn, you're disgusting.
She wants to see you,
for another job.
What?
What did you say?
I don't dare.
I didn't ask your opinion!
You dare refuse?
What does he want?
Say it again!
Open your mouth!
Open it!
This is a taste.
Next time it'll be straight.
Sabotage!
250 tons of mouldy rice.
Do you know who did it?
Imagine yourself in the headlines?
That's a life sentence!
Nameless river.
I was born sobbing.
Blue sky, vast earth.
Black stream water.
I grow with the months,
the years.
With no one to watch over me.
Nameless is man.
Nameless is the river.
Colorless the flower.
Perfume.
Without a voice.
O, river! O, passer-by!
In the closed cycle.
Of the months, the years.
I can't forget
my debt to my roots.
And I wander.
Through worlds.
Towards my land...
His father won't let me work.
I'm bored.
I'm going round in circles.
So I busy myself
with small tasks.
Is Papa well?
He just came home.
When he leaves, I feel so alone.
You're thin.
When he was little, his nose bled.
Does it still happen?
Yes. Sometimes.
I'll show you a photo.
What are you looking for?
He's still here?
He's our son.
Please, speak to him.
He came with his whore?
Please!
What are you looking for?
He was five years old.
Stay and eat with us.
- Mama...
- No, he won't let me.
We were starving...
No rice...
People dying everywhere...
We loved each other deeply.
At 16, or 17.
We drank alcohol
to forget our hunger.
A bit of shrimp paste...
on the end of a nail...
and we drank...
It lasted a year...
Then the child was born.
He came out backwards.
Too late... almost dead.
The doctor said "Abnormal. "
Coward. He was a coward.
The father left us.
Why coward?
He was only 17.
Younger than his son is now.
And then...
How much for a bottle of gasoline?
5,000.
And this?
10,000.
Not bad! And all alone!
You're a real pro!
No cop can catch me.
I know all the shortcuts.
Sure, you're a cyclo driver.
You like skirts?
Women's underwear?
That's all there was.
You sure you're a guy?
Show me!
That's my gift. Take it. For real.
I want to join the gang.
What did he say?
What did you just say?
I got a shock, too.
Which gang were you talking about?
I want to be like you.
Take him to Mr. Lullaby!
Look at my hands? See?
In 1956
I was 17
a bullet cut the nerve
my hand stiffened up.
And look at this...
A bullet, through the neck.
It came out the back.
Guess which hole is bigger?
And then this
here
in 57, a bullet
shattered my shin.
You know why
I'm telling you all this?
I know what you're thinking
faced with death.
I understand you so well.
Autumn wind blows.
Sleep my child, sleep.
The night is long.
I'll watch over you.
Until the night is over
Listen carefully to
the art of syncopation.
Sleep, my child, my beloved.
My little one.
Keep it as a souvenir.
Take it!
Ah, for an iced tea!
Waiter! An iced tea!
Why don't you love me
as much as them?
Let's go!
Stay here. He'll be back.
Come in!
Have a seat.
I just stopped by.
They were wondering
where you were.
I've had it a long time.
Now I have to sell it.
Do you know what this is?
It's the AK-47.
A famous singer.
Have you heard her songs?
No!
Then listen.
Basic notes.
And here's her song.
Little sister, Hanoi, old streets.
You're all that's left me,
orchid scent.
alstonia flower.
Rain whispering down
deserted streets.
Waiting for a woman,
windswept hair, tender shoulders.
You're all that's left me,
winter tree.
icy abandoned street.
Slip of winter moon.
Old abode
where the voice of a piano echoes.
Late into the night
a bell still chimes.
You're all that's left me,
color of time.
The evening fades,
your hair flutters.
Evanescent.
The poet wanders in vain
through the streets.
Suddenly realizing
he has lost his way.
You're all that's left me,
old streets covered in moss.
Every creaky old rooftop.
In my topsy-turvy memory.
Floating
over the waves of West Lake.
Suddenly twilight has fallen.
When it fell, I don't know.
You're all that's left me,
orphaned winter tree.
Stop or I'll break the vase.
I think I'm pregnant.
Who's the father?
Is that a betel palm flower?
What's inside?
I don't know.
It's the first time.
But you looked for it all day.
Will you take me
to the countryside?
What are you carrying?
Pork.
Take that off.
Where does this come from?
From Slaughterhouse 43.
Listen carefully.
I'm going to pierce the skin.
If I find nothing,
I'll give you a pass.
Father!
I dreamt about your death, Father.
You died a second time,
to save me.
This morning,
I feel strangely calm
as if I'm living in your body
in your silhouette
your walk, your gestures.
These bony fingers
this rough hand.
Is it yours or mine?
I feel your muscles
flex in my arms.
This skin, it's yours
burnt, toughened
defying the heat,
the cold, the years.
These veins, you called them
the paths of life.
Now, I understand.
I need to ask a favor.
I've always obeyed you.
Now I'm afraid.
Here's the money you gave me.
If it's not enough.
Let me take another cyclo.
I'll pay you back bit by bit.
Old man, where are you?
What did I say about the paint?
Remember,
you old bastard?
This is a pistol.
Here's the safety catch.
Now you can shoot.
Now it's locked.
You just load and shoot!
From behind
like this.
From the side, like that.
Always two shots. Understand?
Don't throw away the gun.
No one will come near you.
Leave slowly,
once you're outside, run
toward your gun hand.
At the bridge
throw the gun in the stream
and disappear into the crowd.
Don't worry,
it's worse with a knife.
If you're nervous, take these pills.
Here's two. Try one.
It's great!
You won't be afraid of anybody.
Take the second,
before you go to work.
Just one at a time
or you flip out. Understand?
Dawn in my soul.
A bit of sun for each home.
A bit of light for everyone.
Under the canopy, a leaf trembles.
And the dew remembers the clouds.
And the earth exhales a huge wind.
And life shivers, shivers.
Kite of my childhood.
Fragile hope hanging in the sky.
Hearts open, human abodes.
In a world
where no one is excluded.
No, don't break it!
Bastard! She was a virgin!
He said he didn't know.
He suggests
we forget about it.
He shelled out 600 dollars.
That's more than for a virgin.
He said the cuts weren't his fault.
A taste of dust
longan peel
stolen.
A hand
warm
washes my face.
Papa.
Green glow
of live shrimp.
The market closes
mama comes home.
Cold rice
punished...
in secret, at night.
Mama feeds me.
Stifling heat
of searing afternoons
stench of rotten starfruit.
In the rain.
I shiver
fried fish
rice gruel.
Lemon leaves
grapefruit rind
ivory-colored water
my brown skin.
Fish face!
What did I say?
Why do you love paint so much?
Where did you find this color?
Our family doesn't use it.
Come and eat!
Invite the lady to eat with us.
Wake up! Are you awake?
Listen...
Yesterday, you screwed up.
Mr. Lullaby
should have rocked you.
But someone up there spared you.
It's sticky, I'll help you.
The year of the Pig
begins today.
I wish you peace
health
a normal life, like everyone else.
We won't meet again.
When you go, leave the door open.
My little one... he's dead.
Oh, God!
Why?
Yesterday, the cat came back.
We thought he was dead.
He's even more handsome
than before
so handsome,
nobody recognized him.
I remember my father
right before he died.
It was a Sunday
the only day
he took a nap at home.
The cat was sleeping in the sun.
A gash across his face.
My father slept
swinging his leg.
I was a child.
I remember watching
my father's knee, for a long time.